<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101546" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft plans four new titles for kids.</title>
<headline>Microsoft plans four new titles for kids.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp's holiday sales push for children's software will focus on four new titles based on previous hits, a company executive said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Among the new products are Scholastic's Magic School Bus Explores in the Age of Dinosaurs, the fifth title in the series, and Nickelodeon 3D Movie Maker, a spinoff of the 3D Movie Maker product with the addition of licensed characters.  </p>
<p>Microsoft also is launching Creative Writer 2, an updated version of a 3-year-old product that now allows children to publish their own Internet Web pages, and P.J.'s Reading Adventures, a bundle of three CD-ROMs including one that was available previously.</p>
<p>&quot;What we're focusing on doing is creating experiences that kids really love and that parents like also,&quot; Paul Bloom, a Microsoft group marketing manager, said in an interview.  </p>
<p>&quot;In some cases that's going to involve updating and evolving products that have been on the market for a while but that's nothing new in the software industry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Microsoft executives previously have said they intend to cut down the number of new consumer titles they issue and concentrate instead on products that are among the top 100 retail best-sellers.</p>
<p>Bloom said the four previous Magic School Bus episodes have been &quot;phenomenally successful,&quot; ranking within the top 20 titles in the $400 million children's category.</p>
<p>&quot;We have very, very high hopes for Dinos,&quot; he said, referring to the new title.</p>
<p>The Magic School Bus and 3D Movie Maker products retail for about $45. The other new titles will sell in stores for about $35.</p>
<p>			     -- Martin Wolk 206-386-4848</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
