<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="104461" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UltraData sees Q3 loss, lower revs.</title>
<headline>UltraData sees Q3 loss, lower revs.</headline>
<dateline>PLEASANTON, Calif. 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ultradata Corp Wednesday warned investors that revenues and earnings for the third quarter ending September 30, will be below analysts' expectations largely as a result of a lower than expected decision rate in the company's target market.</p>
<p>In a statement, the company said third quarter revenues are expected to be approximately $ 8.7 million, compared to $9.1 million in the third quarter of 1995, resulting in a loss for the third quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>The supplier of on-line information processing systems for credit unions said actual results could vary materially.  </p>
<p>According to First Call, analysts had expected the company to post a profit of $0.18 a share. A comparative third quarter figure from the year ago period was not immediately available.</p>
<p>Ultradata said a significant portion of the company's business is derived from substantial contracts with large organizations that have lengthy decision-making cycles.</p>
<p>Although the company's contract win rate percentage for credit unions making new system purchase decisions in the third quarter met its expectations, the number of targeted credit unions making such decisions in the third quarter was considerably less than anticipated, it added.  </p>
<p>Moreover, sales of software application modules to existing customers were also below expectations, partially as a result of one large customer deferring a software order decision at the end of the third quarter.</p>
<p>A substantial portion of the company's revenue has been recorded at or near the end of the quarter during each quarter of 1996, the company said, adding that a portion of hardware expected to ship during the third quarter was not shipped, as a result of difficulties encountered in integrating a new hardware distributor.</p>
<p>&quot;The company's ability to achieve its revenue plans, both in the near term and in the long term, depends on the company's continued ability to sign new customer contracts and to complete such contracts on schedule,&quot; it said. &quot;There can be no assurance that sales will continue to occur at historical rates, or in accordance with the Company's expectations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PLEASANTON, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
