<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="104670" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Group seeks new Datametrics board.</title>
<headline>Group seeks new Datametrics board.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of Datametric Corp shareholders said it is seeking the election of a new board, a move designed to maximize shareholder value, according to Securities and Exchange Commission filing released Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our group believes that a new board...together with current management will provide a fresh perspective as well as new financial and business resources, which will inure greatly to the benefit of all shareholders of the company,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>In a meeting with Sidney Wing, chief executive officer, on September 27 and followed up with a letter dated October 4, the group said it asked Wing for support in seeking the resignation of the current board, electing new members who support the shareholder group and implement new business initiatives.</p>
<p>The group of shareholders is made up of a group of shareholders including James Haber, the sold general partner of Infiniti Investment Fund LP.  </p>
<p>The shareholders also told Wing they retained Belmont Capital Inc to undertake a complete strategic and operational examination of the company immediately after the election of the board, the filing said.</p>
<p>Belmont Capital is a financial and management advisory team.</p>
<p>The shareholders hold about a 10.8 percent stake in the company in order to establish an equity interest in Datametrics, the filing said.</p>
<p>The shareholder group was expected to make several proposals at the company's board of directors meeting held October 7, the filing said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
