<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110852" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft sees online as $1 billion unit.</title>
<headline>Microsoft sees online as $1 billion unit.</headline>
<dateline>REDMOND, Wash. 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp expects annual revenues generated by its online businesses to top $1 billion by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Microsoft group vice president Pete Higgins, in a briefing for reporters and analysts late Thursday, estimated total online industry revenues, including subscription fees, advertising, Internet access charges and transactions, would grow to &quot;well north of $10 billion&quot; and possibly as much as $15 billion by 2000 from about $4 billion this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We think it's a reasonable thing to think we can get 10 percent of that business,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;That's what we're shooting for,&quot; Higgins said.</p>
<p>The figure would represent a relatively small portion of Microsoft's $8 billion in annual revenues, expected to grow to more than $10 billion in the current fiscal year ending June 30.</p>
<p>But Microsoft Chairman Bill Gates acknowledged that the intensive investment in content and high-profile partnerships with General Electric Co's NBC and others moves the technology company into the media business.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, we are doing media things,&quot; he said. &quot;We hire writers and editors and graphic artists.&quot;  </p>
<p>But he said despite the unique partnership with NBC, which includes a cable television channel, Microsoft has no strategic plans to get into traditional media.</p>
<p>&quot;From purely a percentage point of view, you won't see them shift our industrial code over to the media business,&quot; Gates said at the briefing. &quot;They'll keep us in that software category even in the most extreme case for the next decade.&quot;</p>
<p>Higgins said he expected transaction fees to account for an increasing proportion of online revenues, growing to as much as 30 percent by fiscal 1999.  </p>
<p>Among the new services expected to generate significant transactions fees is Expedia, an online travel service for consumers that will launch this month and catapult Microsoft into the travel agency business.</p>
<p>The service, a companion to a business travel service being offered in partnership with American Express Corp, will allow consumers to book airline tickets, hotel rooms, and rental cars from a single Internet site.</p>
<p>Higgins also identified interactive gaming and advertising as potential sources of significant online revenue. He said advertising on the MSNBC news site was sold out for October, and executives said Slate, the online magazine edited by Michael Kinsley, also was &quot;on plan,&quot; with advertising sold out through the current quarter.</p>
<p>Microsoft Thursday  unveiled a new version of its Microsoft Network service for use on the Internet's World Wide Web starting in November.</p>
<p>Also on Thursday, Laura Jennings, a Microsoft Network vice-president, said company executives did not expect the service to become profitable for &quot;at least three years.&quot;</p>
<p>Microsoft executives said the relaunched Microsoft Network would have versions available for six &quot;focus markets&quot; outside the United States -- Canada, Britain, France, Germany, Japan, and Australia.</p>
<p>The company is developing separate content for each market the programming available with the U.S. edition. All six internaare scheduled to be launched by April 1997.</p>
<p>-- Seattle bureau 206-386-4848</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="REDMOND, Wash."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
