<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112925" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Have you hugged your Microsoft today?.</title>
<headline>Have you hugged your Microsoft today?.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>BUENA VISTA, Fla.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. is arguably the most successful technology company on earth but despite its sales trophies, fear and loathing seems to grow about the behemoth from Redmond, Wash.</p>
<p>The company has now entered into competition with many of its own customers by directly providing services on the Internet that were once the exclusive preserve of such &quot;middlemen&quot; as banks, media companies, phone companies, service providers, magazine houses and online organizations.</p>
<p>At a conference sponsored by the Gartner Group research firm last week, the concern about Microsoft was palpable among industry heavyweights as well as rank and file attendees.</p>
<p>&quot;Does Bill Gates own the Internet?&quot; Gartner analyst David Smith asked in a overflowing seminar that went on to show the company seemed to be employing a strategy to that end.</p>
<p>The world's largest software company used to busy itself by selling software programs such as Windows, DOS, Word, Windows, games and, well, Windows. They got so good at this job that they now own most of the software real estate on most personal computers around the world.</p>
<p>After first eschewing the Internet, the increasingly popular global computer network, Microsoft was forced to rethink its strategy after the mind boggling growth of the Net in the corporate and personal worlds.</p>
<p>About 10 months ago the company decided to launch a multi-pronged attack and now has its fingers in a wide array of areas of the Internet market.</p>
<p>Rather than just providing tools for other people to browse and publish on the Net, Microsoft is out there dishing up actual content and providing services, acting like an Internet service provider.</p>
<p>Just recently, Microsoft announced a relaunching of its online service, the Microsoft Network, with the obvious aim of boosting its 1.6 million subscribers and vaulting from its number three position.</p>
<p>Is industry leader America Online, with its six million subscribers, nervous? Most likely.</p>
<p>But just look at all of Microsoft's other actions. It has launched a high-profile online magazine called Slate, teamed up with NBC on a news service and launched Cityscape, which will likely offer information in direct competition with your local newspaper.</p>
<p>IBM Corp. Chairman Lou Gerstner told the conference that bankers were saying in private that they were worried about Microsoft entering the banking business through Microsoft Money. With Microsoft Money, consumers can keep track of their check book and gain access to their bank accounts.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not the intention of IBM to go into competition with its customers,&quot; Gertsner proudly told the conference. &quot;IBM won't disintermediate its customers.&quot;</p>
<p>Netscape Communications Corp. has found itself in a bare-knuckle showdown with Microsoft over Internet browsers, which help computer users navigate information on the World Wide Web.</p>
<p>And while Netscape is estimated to control somewhere between 70 percent and 80 percent of the browser market with its Netscape Navigator, Microsoft has somehow convinced virtually every online service provider to embrace Internet Explorer rather than Netscape Navigator.</p>
<p>Netscape President James Barksdale put on a gentlemanly face at the conference regarding his struggle with Microsoft.</p>
<p>In an extraordinary panel he shared with Gates, he referred to the CEO of Microsoft as his &quot;learned colleague.&quot;</p>
<p>At one point Barksdale also said that, as a means of survival, he had searched for a competitor to keep him on his toes.</p>
<p>&quot;And I found a wonderful competitor that keeps us working awfully hard,&quot; he told the conference to uproarious laughter.</p>
<p>Gates, however, maintained that it was a big world out there on the Internet and that the company was just playing along in an arena dominated by many big players, some much bigger than Microsoft.</p>
<p>Indeed, IBM's research and development budget is about the same as Microsoft's total revenues.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no one entity that is going to control the printing press of the future, which is the Internet,&quot; Gates predicted.</p>
<p>But analyst Smith at Gartner said Microsoft's strategy has been quite intelligent because, since embracing the Internet, it has sought to extend its reach by promoting its own Net technologies and standards.</p>
<p>&quot;Microsoft's strategy around the Internet is to embrace and extend. And what comes after embrace and extend is engulf,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>To comment on this weekly column: russell.blinch@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENA VISTA, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
