<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114792" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SoftKey signs new distributor pacts in Asia.</title>
<headline>SoftKey signs new distributor pacts in Asia.</headline>
<dateline>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>SoftKey International Inc said Monday it had signed exclusive deals to localize and distribute all products from SoftKey, and its Learning Co, MECC and Compton's units in South Korea, Taiwan and China.</p>
<p>SoftKey, a leading developer of discount software titles, said it had signed agreements with Daekyo Computer Systems Co Ltd of South Korea and a unit of the MiTac Group in Taiwan.</p>
<p>The company did not disclose specific financial terms, but said the &quot;multimillion-dollar agreements&quot; will contribute to SoftKey's existing international business by significantly expanding SoftKey's presence in the Pacific Rim.  </p>
<p>&quot;SoftKey has experienced phenomenal growth in international markets over the past year, largely as a result of our efforts in Europe,&quot; said David Patrick, president of SoftKey's International Division.</p>
<p>&quot;These two exclusive agreements should give SoftKey a substantial foothold in Pacific Rim markets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company said the new distributor partnerships will focus on localizing SoftKey products to correspond with regional educational teaching methods and to reflect local cultures.</p>
<p>A leader in multimedia education in Korea, Daekyo Computer Systems is part of Daekyo Group, which has interests in trade, broadcast, publishing, computer distribution and education.</p>
<p>SoftKey said its products will be distributed through Daekyo's extensive network of consumer retail and educational outlet, and its correspondence-education business, which boasts more than 1.5 million members.</p>
<p>MiTac's distribution network covers consumer retail and educational outlets throughout Taiwan. It is developing a similar infrastructure in China.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAMBRIDGE, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
