<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116438" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Netscape to set up European online web.</title>
<headline>Netscape to set up European online web.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Netscape Communications Corp said on Tuesday said it plans to install a European Web to expand its online presence in Europe and allow easier access to the Internet and the World Wide Web.</p>
<p>Netscape also said that it agreed with 16 European media companies to provide automatic delivery of selected multimedia content to electronic mail-boxes.</p>
<p>Netscape announced a deal with Cable and Wireless Plc to deploy Intranets at C&amp;W companies and clients across the world.  </p>
<p>Intranets are private, usually corporate, networks linking personal computers. Internets are looser networks of personal computers linked by public telephone lines. In a statement released at a video link news conference that included company officials in New York and at its headquarters in Mountain View, California, Netscape said the new installation would provide software download sites and would create what it called a &quot;European General Store.&quot;</p>
<p>The company offered no financial details.  </p>
<p>Netscape said its new European equipment would address a complaint from many European users of the Internet, that it was slow, and became overwhelmed later in the day when U.S. subscribers were surfing the net.</p>
<p>&quot;These sites will permit more rapid access to the Netscape Web site and allow faster software downloading for Europeans,&quot; Netscape said in the statement.</p>
<p>Netscape has already installed a web site in Paris with France Telecom, and plans to install sites in London and Munich in the coming months.  </p>
<p>The company said the European General Store will sell Netscape products in Europe, including Russia, and throughout the MIddle East and Africa.</p>
<p>Netscape said the automatic delivery of content to electronic mail boxes -- via Netscape Inbox Direct -- included Axel Springer Verlag of Germany, Liberation of France, De Telegraaf in Holland, The Mirror Group in Britain, and Milano Finanza Editori of Italy.</p>
<p>Netscape has dominated the world market for Internet browsers with an 80 percent market share, but has been irked recently by Microsoft Corp's effort's to move in on this market. It has complained on anti-trust grounds about Microsoft to the U.S. Justice Department.</p>
<p>Earlier today, Netscape unveiled a new corporate strategy to &quot;embrace and integrate&quot; Microsoft's systems in its own open network environment for corporate offices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
