<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120389" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Informix tools sales hurt EPS.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Informix tools sales hurt EPS.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Informix Corp's application tools sales fell 18 percent in the third quarter from a year earlier and, though tools are only a fifth of its business, they hurt results, its chief financial officer said.</p>
<p>&quot;That obviously affected the EPS,&quot; said Howard Graham, Informix CFO, in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>Analysts' mean estimate was $0.18 a share for Informix's third quarter, First Call said. It reported $0.17 a share.</p>
<p>Analysts expected revenues of $245-to-$255 million.</p>
<p>&quot;It puts a drag on your top line growth when a fifth of your business is shrinking,&quot; Graham said.  </p>
<p>Informix reported revenues of $238 million in the quarter.</p>
<p>However, Informix's databases, which make up 80 percent of its business, grew sales by 50 percent from a year ago, Graham said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our database growth continues at an outstanding pace, faster than anybody in the space,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Informix's competitors are Oracle Corp, whose database sales grew by 41 percent in the most recent quarter, and Sybase Inc. Sybase reports third quarter results this week, but its sales growth has been considerably slower than that of Oracle or Informix this year.  </p>
<p>Graham blamed the application tools sales decline on the market, noting that Oracle's tools sales slipped as well.</p>
<p>The tools market softness is due in large part to strength in two other areas of the larger database arena, Graham said.</p>
<p>One is the popularity of &quot;datawarehousing,&quot; a method of storing data that doesn't require applications to use the information but instead can answer queries. The datawarehouse trend helps Informix, which sells datawarehouse products.</p>
<p>Secondly, companies like PeopleSoft Inc and SAP AG which sell applications for use on all databases are growing fast, taking away demand for application tools.  </p>
<p>&quot;None of them write in a database vendors' tool set. They are writing applications independent of a database tool set,&quot; Graham said of PeopleSoft, SAP and others in that market.</p>
<p>So a growth in applications for databases does not translate to a sales growth of tools for a specific database.</p>
<p>By December, Informix will start selling for general availability its Informix-Universal Server, the latest technology in database software which handles video and sound data as well as numbers and letters.</p>
<p>Graham said the universal server would boost revenues, but it was tough to project by how much.</p>
<p>--BARBARA GRADY, SAN FRANCISCO BUREAU  barb.grady@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
