<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123751" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: White House rejects critique of new code policy.</title>
<headline>White House rejects critique of new code policy.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration rejected on Thursday criticism from 20 U.S. legislators of its new policy to relax export restrictions on computer encoding technology.</p>
<p>The legislators, Democrats and Republicans, sent a letter to the administration this week attacking the new policy as probably unworkable and needlessly restrictive.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look, there is a critical mass of industry that is working with the federal government to develop this system,&quot; Heidi Kukis, a spokeswoman in Vice President Al Gore's office said.  </p>
<p>Under the administration policy announced Oct 1, U.S. companies could export powerful encryption programs only if the programs included a feature known as key recovery to allow the government to read encoded messages.</p>
<p>&quot;The policy has always been based on the fact that development of a key recovery system will be market driven,&quot; Kukis said.</p>
<p>After the administration unveiled its new policy, a number of prominent hardware firms led by International Business Machines Corp formed a consortium to propagate key recovery systems.  </p>
<p>Software firms and online services have opposed key recovery, however.</p>
<p>In the last session of Congress, legislators introduced several bills to relax U.S. export laws without requiring key recovery features, but the measures did not pass.</p>
<p>Kukis pointedly rejected one charge in the letter and repeated in a press release from Sen. Ron Wyden concerning the administration's new policy.</p>
<p>The Oregon Democrat and the letter said the Clinton policy granted the Federal Bureau of Investigation &quot;veto power&quot; over applications for exporting encryption programs.  </p>
<p>&quot;Wyden's statement is incorrect,&quot; Kukis said. &quot;The FBI does not and will not have veto power over dual use encryption exports. It's irresponsible to suggest that they would.&quot;</p>
<p>Rather, the FBI will have a seat on a committee to review export applications along with the departments of Defense, Commerce, State, Energy and Justice and the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, Kukis said.</p>
<p>&quot;The only person who will have veto power is the President himself,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>--Aaron Pressman, 202-898-8312</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
