<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129312" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SEC head warns California may become lawsuit magnet.</title>
<headline>SEC head warns California may become lawsuit magnet.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Securities and Exchange Commission Chairman Arthur Levitt is encouraging California voters to oppose a ballot measure he said may make the state &quot;a magnet&quot; for shareholder lawsuits.</p>
<p>In copies of a letter dated Oct. 17 and released to the media on Friday, Levitt told U.S. Representative Anna Eshoo California's Proposition 211 might disrupt a balance between investors' rights and protecting companies from frivolous lawsuits.</p>
<p>&quot;Proposition 211 may skew that balance,&quot; he said in the letter. &quot;If adopted, the proposition would actually encourage litigation by adding a new private right of action to California's securities laws which is broader than that existing in any other state.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;California state courts could become a magnet for class action suits, giving this local rule a nationwide impact,&quot; he wrote. &quot;Thus I share President Clinton's concerns and join him in encourating California voters to oppose Proposition 211.</p>
<p>Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole also opposes the measure, which has become a hot political potatoe among the typically apolitical chief executives of Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>&quot;Without safe harbour protection, companies will likely refrain from providing forward-looking information,&quot; Levit said of protections put in place by the 1995 Litigation Reform Act that Proposition 211 would strip away.</p>
<p>The initiative on the state's November 5 ballot would roll back federal legislation enacted late last year and make board directors of companies personally culpable to pay damages in shareholder lawsuits.</p>
<p>Opponents of Propositin 211, including major high tech companies based here, argue the legislation could impact any company which has a shareholder or a customer in the state.</p>
<p>Espoo, a Democrat, represents Silicon Valley in Congress.</p>
<p>Proponents of the ballot initiative argue the legislation can help protect pensioners from cases of financial fraud.</p>
<p>But opponents, who have raised tens of millions of dollars to battle the initiative, charge it is primarily backed by securities lawyers who specialise in shareholder class action lawsuits and who would benefit directly from its passage.</p>
<p>Last week, Microsoft, International Business Machines Corp., Compaq Computer Corp. and Dell Computer Corp. came out in opposition to measure.</p>
<p>The opposition of the four prominent high tech companies is noteworthy in that they are all based outside California and their main operations are outside California.</p>
<p>Microsoft Chief Operating Officer Bob Herbold said passage of Proposition 211 &quot;will adversely affect all public companies doing business in California, whether they are incorporated there or not, by opening the door to frivolous lawsuits.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Proposition 211 would actually hurt shareholders, by making it harder for public companies to attract strong directors, who can manage companies well and protect shareholder interests,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
