<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129720" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IPO SPOTLIGHT - Infinity Financial seen up at open.</title>
<headline>IPO SPOTLIGHT - Infinity Financial seen up at open.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Infinity Financial Technology Inc's initial public offering looks set for a modestly successful debut this week, even though long-term concerns will prevent it from being a runaway hit with investors.</p>
<p>&quot;It should come at a premium of two to three points at the opening, provided the broad market holds,&quot; said David Menlow, president of Springfield, N.J.-based IPO Financial Network Corp.  </p>
<p>He said that institutional investors were beginning to pay more attention to the kind of risk-management software offered by Infinity because &quot;this sector represents high profitability&quot;.</p>
<p>The company is offering 2.5 million shares at an estimated price of $13 to $15 per share. The lead underwriter is Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, we're positive about this,&quot; said Kathleen Smith, portfolio manager at Renaissance Capital Corp in Greenwich, Conn. &quot;(It) looks like they'll continue their revenue growth at about 50 percent.&quot;  </p>
<p>Infinity Financial reported revenues of $24.7 million in 1995, up from $12.6 million in 1994.</p>
<p>Smith said that catastrophic trading losses at firms such as Sumitomo Corp, and tightening of the regulatory environment in Europe will serve to increase the attractiveness of Infinity's products.</p>
<p>The company develops, markets and supports object-oriented, client/server platform and solutions software for financial trading and risk management.  </p>
<p>Others are less positive about the company's future prospects. In the face of intense competition, particularly with many large firms setting up in-house risk management systems, Infinity's ability to maintain a hold on its niche position could be shaky, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;What Infinity does is pretty narrowly focused,&quot; said Steven Tuen, analyst at IPO Value Monitor. &quot;And with a lot of competition, this may lose some of its appeal.&quot;  </p>
<p>Another potential problem confronting the company is its exposure to non-dollar denominated sales, said Manish Shah, editor and publisher of the IPO Maven. According to the prospectus, 70 percent of its total revenues came from sales outside North America in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;One would like to see some kind of steady revenue stream in dollars&quot;, said Shah.</p>
<p>He said &quot;the initial hype could lift (the stock) in the first couple of months- it could go to the 20's,&quot;  but that concerns about valuations may then set in and the stock could slip below its offering price.</p>
<p>Shah cited the case of C*ATS Software Inc, a provider of derivative risk management systems and a competitor of Infinity's. It made its debut last year at $12, but the stock is now languishing at around $4-3/4.</p>
<p>Infinity Financial plans to use the proceeds of IPO for additional working capital, and perhaps to fund future acquisitions of businesses or products.  According to the prospectus, it does not intend to pay dividends in the foreseesable future so that it can plow back earnings into the development of its business.</p>
<p>- Kamalakshi Mehta, New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
