<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130730" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Microsoft CFO sees sales rise.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Microsoft CFO sees sales rise.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp Chief Financial Officer Mike Brown Monday said he expected the company's revenues to rise sequentially in the next two quarters from the $2.3 billion reported for the three months ended September 30.</p>
<p>In an interview, Brown also said he thought the company's cost of goods sold could decline &quot;a little bit&quot; in the long term from the 10.9 percent of revenue just reported, already down from 16 percent a year ago.  </p>
<p>&quot;We'll grow a little bit in December and then a little bit more in March, I think,&quot; Brown said. &quot;I'm very happy with the general revenue trend, and I was very pleased with the pattern of costs in the quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>Brown said revenue in the December quarter would be driven in part by holiday season cyclicality, while the March quarter would get a boost from the release of the company's Office 97 suite of business applications, an upgrade to one of the software company's core products.  </p>
<p>Brown said cost ratios were falling because of increased use of CD-ROMs for distributing software, rather than more costly diskettes, and because of the growing popularity of enterprise software licenses over sales through the retail and reseller channels.</p>
<p>Brown also said the company's spending on research and development was &quot;right on target,&quot; with its announced plans to spend $2.1 billion in the current fiscal year ending June 30.</p>
<p>In addition, he said unearned revenue on the company's balance sheet -- up to $651 million as of September 30 from $560 million three months earlier -- would rise further as a result of growth in the &quot;subscription&quot; model of sales, such as licenses and upgrade.</p>
<p>					-- Seattle bureau 206-386-4848</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
