<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134069" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP loses steam in third quarter.</title>
<headline>SAP loses steam in third quarter.</headline>
<dateline>WALLDORF, Germany 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's high-flying business software group SAP AG, reporting its highest-ever revenues for the first nine months, said on Tuesday growth rates had slowed and shaved forecasts for the full year.</p>
<p>SAP, the world's leading maker of client-server software that control core internal operations for companies, said profit on ordinary activities in the first nine months of 1996 rose 33 percent to 509 million marks.</p>
<p>Sales during the same period also rose 33 percent to 2.4 billion marks.</p>
<p>But the momentum had slowed significantly from the growth in sales of 38 percent registered in the first half of the year, causing the company to curb expectations for the year.</p>
<p>SAP had forecast sales would rise to around 3.8 billion marks for the full year, up from 2.7 billion marks in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The moderate growth in the third quarter means that the previous sales target is no longer achievable,&quot; said SAP chairman Dietmar Hopp. &quot;We now expect 1996 revenues to be 3.5 billion marks.&quot;</p>
<p>Trade in SAP shares on Tuesday had closed ahead of the announcement. SAP shares were up 30 pfennigs at 271.50 marks in bourse trade. In computerised IBIS trade, shares closed down 2.40 marks at 272.50.</p>
<p>Revenues from software products in the first nine months rose 30 percent to 1.63 billion marks. Sales for its flagship R/3 system rose 39 percent, while sales for its mainframe R/2 system slipped 14 percent.</p>
<p>Turnover from consulting services rose 45 percent to 501 million marks and training revenue rose 26 percent to 208 million marks.</p>
<p>The United States is now the company's largest market. Sales in the first nine months there rose to 841 million marks from 596 million the year before.</p>
<p>Sales in Germany edged up to 658 million marks from 603 million, while turnover in the rest of Europe advanced to 535 million marks from 397 million. Asian sales grew to 299 million marks from 169 million and revenues in Africa rose slightly to 39 million from 25 million.</p>
<p>The company's flagship product, the R/3 software system, has revolutionised the way businesses share information internally.</p>
<p>Independent analysts, citing the company's still unchallenged leadership in its sector and growth in the United States and Asia, had been expecting sales to advance around 40 percent.</p>
<p>Used to stellar growth in profit and sales over the past two years as the market for client-server software has exploded, Hopp sounded disappointed with the results.</p>
<p>&quot;The rather moderate growth in the third quarter was unexpected and attributable to just a few countries,&quot; he said in a statement. &quot;Nevertheless we continue to see very strong demand for R/3.&quot;</p>
<p>Hopp said SAP had expended much of its efforts recently on development and that it would now re-focus on sales.</p>
<p>Paul Wahl, SAP chief executive for North America, said the company had added 70 new employees to its sales force there.</p>
<p>&quot;The market opportunities for SAP in North America remain strong and as we continue our expansion into the mid-market and new vertical industries we will continue to realise significant growth,&quot; Wahl said in the statement.</p>
<p>SAP's group workforce increased by 1,614 employees to 8,471 at the end of September. Of the total increase, 1,144 new staff were added outside Germany.</p>
<p>-- William Boston, Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WALLDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
