<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134008" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP cuts outlook as results disappoint.</title>
<headline>SAP cuts outlook as results disappoint.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's high-flying business software group SAP AG on Tuesday unsettled markets with an unexpectedly sharp slow-down in growth in the third quarter that forced the company to revise full-year forecasts.</p>
<p>SAP, the world's leading maker of client-server software that controls core internal operations for companies, said profit on ordinary activities in the first nine months of 1996 rose 33 percent to 509 million marks ($332 million). Sales also rose 33 percent to 2.4 billion marks.</p>
<p>But the momentum slowed significantly from the growth in sales of 38 percent registered in the first half of the year, causing the company to abandon its prediction that sales would rise to 3.8 billion marks in 1996 after 2.7 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The moderate growth in the third quarter means that the previous sales target is no longer achievable,&quot; said chairman Dietmar Hopp. &quot;We now expect 1996 revenues to be 3.5 billion marks.&quot;</p>
<p>Trade in SAP shares had closed ahead of the announcement. SAP shares were up 30 pfennigs at 271.50 marks in bourse trade. In computerised IBIS trade, they closed down 2.40 at 272.50.</p>
<p>The company's flagship product, the R/3 software system, has revolutionised the way businesses share information internally, making it possible for them to decentralise access to large amounts of core information and oversee processes.</p>
<p>Analysts, many of whom had expected sales to advance as much as 40 percent and were anticipating even faster profit growth, were shocked by the news.</p>
<p>&quot;This is really something. Just a month and a half ago the company was touring around the country at one roadshow after another and gave no clue that anything was wrong,&quot; one Frankfurt analyst said.</p>
<p>Analysts were reluctant to comment on the figures ahead of a telephone conference with the company.</p>
<p>SAP was vague on the reasons for the slowdown in growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The moderate growth in the third quarter was unexpected and attributable to just a few countries,&quot; Hopp said. &quot;Nevertheless we continue to see very strong demand for R/3.&quot;</p>
<p>He said SAP had expended much of its efforts recently on development and that it would now refocus on sales.</p>
<p>Analysts said it was too soon to say whether the slow-down was effecting SAP alone or a problem throughout the industry. They said it would be necessary to look at earnings reports from SAP competitors Baan NV, PeopleSoft and Oracle Systems Corp.</p>
<p>Revenues from software products in the first nine months rose 30 percent to 1.63 billion marks. Sales for its flagship R/3 system rose 39 percent, while sales for its mainframe R/2 system slipped 14 percent.</p>
<p>Turnover from consulting services rose 45 percent to 501 million marks and training revenuew rose 26 percent to 208 million marks.</p>
<p>The United States is now the company's largest market. Sales in the first nine months there rose to 841 million marks from 596 million the year before.</p>
<p>Sales in Germany edged up to 658 million marks from 603 million, while turnover in the rest of Europe advanced to 535 million from 397 million. Asian sales grew to 299 million marks from 169 million and revenues in Africa rose slightly to 39 million from 25 million. ($1=1.5323 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
