<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137056" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Institutions seen dominating flex options in U.S..</title>
<headline>Institutions seen dominating flex options in U.S..</headline>
<byline>Gregory Crawford</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Institutional investors are likely to be the big players in flex options on individual U.S. shares that begin trading Thursday but some early interest is expected from curious retail customers.</p>
<p>&quot;Sharp investors will figure this out pretty quickly and take advantage of it,&quot; said Marty Kearney at PTI Securities in Chicago.</p>
<p>&quot;It's nice to be able to pick something a little more to your liking,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Flex -- short for &quot;flexible exchange&quot; -- options allow investors to set their own strike prices and expirations, giving them the opportunity to tailor options closer to their hedging and speculative strategies than standard options.</p>
<p>&quot;The beauty of flex is the customization of whatever the player is looking to do,&quot; said Price Headley, director of research at Cincinnati-based Investment Research Institute.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (institutions) is where you're going to see interest in the flex product because you're looking at institutions that have big exposures they want to hedge,&quot; he explained. &quot;The flex is more geared to hedging.&quot;  </p>
<p>Analysts said the new options will have the best chance of success if the exchanges stick to listings that already have solid liquidity in the existing options and the shares.</p>
<p>Scott Kilrea, designated primary market maker for options on Telefonos de Mexico on the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE), predicted a flood of queries for quotes when the flex options open for trading on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically it will be firms holding positions in OTC (over-the-counter) options that just want to price them,&quot; he said. &quot;Maybe it will be the risk control people who do it, but they'll be essentially valuing stuff.&quot;  </p>
<p>Telmex is one of 15 stocks on which flex options will be available on the American Stock Exchange (AMEX) and one of the 10 on the CBOE.</p>
<p>Other stocks scheduled for flex options on both the AMEX and CBOE include American Online Inc and Grupo Televisa S.A. de C.V.</p>
<p>Some other FLEX options on the CBOE will include Coca Cola Co, General Motors Corp and International Business Machines Corp.</p>
<p>On the AMEX, flex options will include American Express Co, Intel Corp and Philip Morris Cos Inc.  </p>
<p>Also starting Thursday, the Pacific Stock Exchange plans to offer flex options on 10 companies including Compaq Computer Corp and Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>The CBOE plans to offer flex options on another six stocks on November 5. They include Citicorp, Ford Motor Co and Merck and Co Inc.</p>
<p>The Philadelphia Stock Exchange is waiting for approval from the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission to list flex options on individual shares.  </p>
<p>At the CBOE, flex options on the S&amp;P 100 and 500 stock indices were launched in February 1993 and flex options on the Russell 2000 index and Nasdaq 100 index have since been added.</p>
<p>The AMEX currently offers flex options on its major market index, its institutional index and the S&amp;P midcap index. Index flex options were launched in September 1993 at the AMEX.</p>
<p>--Derivatives desk, (312) 408-8750</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
