<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139194" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spyglass jumps into Internet device market.</title>
<headline>Spyglass jumps into Internet device market.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spyglass Inc said it is doubling its research and development efforts in its fiscal 1997 year to pursue aggressively an emerging market which allows users to access the Internet through everday products like cell phones, cars and televisions.</p>
<p>The device market, as it is called, integrates Internet access and technology into everyday uses, not necessarily via personal computers.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing information impacting people's lives in everything they do, and information is moving online,&quot; said Randy Littleson, Spyglass's vice president of marketing.</p>
<p>The goal is to create a software platform on which software applications are device-independent.  With this, a user could access an e-mail account via a cell phone from his car, for example, or determine why a copy machine in another building is not working.</p>
<p>Spyglass, which provides Internet-related software and services, said it has already licensed software to WorldGate Communications for its Internet access service via cable TV.  </p>
<p>With the software, for example, users will be able to connect directly to Web pages from a television.</p>
<p>&quot;If a user is interested in knowing more about a product advertised on TV, he could click a button on his remote and immediately launch to the advertiser's Web site to get more information,&quot; Spyglass said.</p>
<p>Only three percent of the world has a personal computer, the typical tool for going online, but many more use telephones, televisions, cars or manufacturing equipment. Spyglass plans to provide the software to &quot;Web-enable&quot; these devices, or connect them to the Internet and World Wide Web.  </p>
<p>&quot;Even if 10 to 20 percent of them become Web-enabled, it's a huge market,&quot; Littleson said in an interview.</p>
<p>Littleson said Spyglass will double the size of its research and development team and add staff to its customer services group.  He said the company is also focussing its marketing efforts on the Internet device market.</p>
<p>Spyglass said customer services could account for up to 20 percent of annual revenues as the device market takes hold.</p>
<p>In fiscal 1996, Spyglass spent $6.8 million or about 30 percent of revenues on R &amp; D.  Spyglass said R &amp; D spending is targetted at 40 percent for fiscal 1997.  </p>
<p>On Wednesday, Spyglass chief financial officer Gary Vilchick said the company expects overall revenues to grow &quot;in the 50 percent range&quot; for fiscal 1997.  Spyglass reported fiscal 1996 revenues of $22.3 million.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Spyglass reported earnings for its fiscal year ended September 30, 1996 of $0.27 a share versus $0.21, but Vilchick said the company could possibly report a loss in the first half of 1997 because of the increased investments and the uncertainty of when volume shipments to the device market will begin.</p>
<p>&quot;Potentially in the first half we could see us losing a few pennies per share,&quot; Vilchick said in a conference call with analysts. &quot;In the second half we could see profitability returning.&quot;</p>
<p>Doug Colbeth, chief executive of Spyglass, said the company will &quot;do what it takes&quot; to dominate this new market and will &quot;shape the company to meet the demands.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We see the potential for growth to be tremendous in late (fiscal) 1997 and '98,&quot; Colbeth said.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
