<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="141965" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Insouciant Europeans lag in high technology.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Insouciant Europeans lag in high technology.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>European indifference to high technology could permanently cede leadership to the U.S. in the world of computers.</p>
<p>Insipid economic performance in Europe, exacerbated by Maastricht treaty inspired efforts to slash budgets in the name of a single currency, has led to consumer cutbacks in spending on high technology.</p>
<p>But projected growth, although slowing, remains powerful compared with many other industries.</p>
<p>According to business information company Frost &amp; Sullivan, information technology revenues in Europe will slow to 7.1 percent this year to $190 billion compared with growth of 7.5 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>Between 1996 and 2002, compound annual growth will slide to about 5.7 percent.</p>
<p>Frost &amp; Sullivan say European information technology comprises computer hardware including mainframe and personal computers, software, services such as maintenance and training, and add-on equipment like printers, disk drives, modems and monitors.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, U.S. computer manufacturer Digital Equipment Corp reported much worse than expected losses for its latest quarter, with analysts saying a high proportion of its business was exposed to Europe's stagnant economies.</p>
<p>Nearly 43 percent of Digital's revenues come from Europe.</p>
<p>Analysts made a general warning about otherwise sound U.S. high-technology profit outlooks being held back by conditions in Europe.</p>
<p>COMPAQ Computer Corp, the world's biggest personal computer make and market leader in Europe, reported 43 percent higher third quarter profits last week. But margins are being shaved to the bone in Europe, analysts say.</p>
<p>Gartner Group's Eric Brethenoux doesn't expect any great long-term resurgence in markets, and says most Europeans will never embrace high technology with the enthusiasm of Americans.</p>
<p>&quot;Americans try new things right away; try to make the best out of it. Unlike the French and most Europeans they don't wait for theoretically elegant solutions,&quot; Brethenoux said by telephone from his Paris office.</p>
<p>He excluded the British from his cultural theory.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. is very pioneering in its mentality, and England too. This cultural difference is not going to go away. It is not just a question of waiting for prices to fall to rock-bottom, its more basic than that,&quot; Brethenoux said.</p>
<p>Jeremy Davies, senior partner at technology research company CONTEXT, shares this view of the different attitudes to technology between Americans and Europeans, but also points to consumer diffidence caused by shaky economies.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of economic malaise in Germany and France there's a lack of consumer confidence which knocked the bottom out of the consumer PC market,&quot; Davies said.</p>
<p>&quot;Look at the uptake of electronic devices like mobile phones and faxes. In the UK they are gizmo geeks (gadget enthusiasts), technology addicts. In certain areas of technology the UK is far more excited about picking up new technology than the French and Germans,&quot; Davies said.</p>
<p>Not everybody agrees.</p>
<p>Dean Bubley, analyst at Datamonitor, warns against generalisations on European technological attitudes and performance.</p>
<p>&quot;There's high market penetration by mobile phones in Scandinavia, and solid Internet use too. Smart cards are popular in France. It depends on how you define high technology. Certainly most major software houses and manufacturers are in the U.S. but there's SAP (AG ) in Germany, games software in the U.K.,&quot; Bubley said.</p>
<p>Brethenoux concedes that there are powerful high technology firms in Europe that can compete with the Americans.</p>
<p>&quot;(Franco-Italian semiconductor manufacturer) SGS-Thomson (Microelectronics NV ) is doing very good things. (Germany's) Siemens (AG ) is working on a lot of important things,&quot; Brethenoux said.</p>
<p>He says Britain's Amstrad Plc and Philips Electronics NV of the Netherlands are ideas powerhouses.</p>
<p>But while Europe looks to compete with American companies, there is a threat looming from the east.</p>
<p>&quot;Watch out for the Japanese,&quot; said CONTEXT's Davies.</p>
<p>&quot;They may finally be moving into high technology markets especially at the consumer level, and Sony (Corp ) and Toshiba (Corp ) have started selling personal computers in the U.S.&quot; Davies said.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry is looking nervously at how the Japanese are doing in the U.S. Will their expertise transfer from consumer electronics to PCs? Will it be Walkman, Trinitron, and PCs too?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
