<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146937" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft, Intel plan &quot;NetPC&quot;.</title>
<headline>Microsoft, Intel plan &quot;NetPC&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>REDMOND, Wash. 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp and Intel Corp on Monday announced a new computer reference platform called the NetPC, intended to reduce the costs of business computing.</p>
<p>Specifications for the platform will be finalized before the end of the year and will include an Intel Pentium processor rated at 100 MHz or higher, at least 16 MB of system memory and a lockable case to prevent user modification.  </p>
<p>The companies said major computer manufacturers that agreed to support the initiative included Compaq Computer Corp, Dell Computer Corp, Digital Equipment Corp, Gateway 2000 Inc, Hewlett-Packard Co, Packard Bell NEC and Texas Instruments Inc.</p>
<p>The move by Microsoft and Intel is a response to the drive for so-call network computers that are being positioned as Internet friendly devices that would cost less than $1,000 and be cheaper to operate than personal computers.</p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp, Sun Microsystems Inc and Oracle Corp are among the companies supporting the network computer effort.</p>
<p>A Hewlett-Packard official said in a statement that the manufacturer plans to have a NetPC available sometime in 1997 as part of its Vectra PC family.</p>
<p>&quot;By delivering an appropriate level of flexibility, the NetPC is the natural next step in further reducing total cost of ownership while maintaining the strategic value that PCs deliver to business,&quot; said Frank Gill, executive vice president at Intel.</p>
<p>-- Seattle bureau 206-386-4848</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="REDMOND, Wash."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
