<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149166" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: UAE takes copyright violator to court.</title>
<headline>UAE takes copyright violator to court.</headline>
<byline>Rana Sabbagh</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Arab Emirates has charged two men with violating copyright laws, the first such prosecution in the Gulf state which is trying to crack down on piracy, a local newspaper said on Monday.</p>
<p>The English-language Gulf News said the Dubai public prosecutor pressed charges against the sponsor of a computer shop, a UAE national, and his Tanzanian manager after police acting on a tip-off raided their computer shop in the city's commercial centre two months ago.</p>
<p>Police caught the manager selling a floppy disk of pirated software programmes and seized 12O discs and six catalogues containing a list of pirated programmes, it said.</p>
<p>The public prosecutor declined comment on the report.</p>
<p>A law firm representing the Washington-based Business Software Alliance (BSA) confirmed that legal action was being taken against the two men.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first criminal action on copyright piracy in the UAE. It was instigated by the software manufacturers themselves,&quot; said Hoda Barakat, head of the intellectual property department at Al-Tamimi and Co, the law firm representing BSA.</p>
<p>&quot;Definitely it is a very good sign that the country is dedicated and committed to fighting piracy,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Software manufacturers are going to feel much more comfortable without the fear of copied versions&quot; of their programmes sold for a fraction of their original cost, she said.</p>
<p>The first hearing in the case, set for October 23, was postponed to November 20 to prepare more documentation, Gulf News said.</p>
<p>If found guilty, both men could face a fine of 50,000 dirhams ($13,000) or more or between three months and three years in prison, the paper said.</p>
<p>Copyright laws were introduced in the UAE in 1992 as part of efforts to make the Gulf Arab state more attractive to foreign investors.</p>
<p>In recent years, authorities have stepped up the drive to enforce the law and regularly raided shops and companies suspected of selling pirated goods, a widespread practice in the oil-rich Gulf.</p>
<p>Authorities earlier this year destroyed thousands of pirated audio and video cassettes.</p>
<p>BSA, which groups leading U.S. software firms like Microsoft Corp, Novell Inc and Lotus, part of International Business Machines Corp, estimates software makers lost around $39 million to piracy in the UAE in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
