<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15933" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Quarterdeck's CEO Bastiaens resigns after tough tenure.</title>
<headline>Quarterdeck's CEO Bastiaens resigns after tough tenure.</headline>
<dateline>MARINA DEL REY, Calif 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Quarterdeck Corp, which recently launched a restructuring to restore profitability, said Tuesday that its chief executive, Gaston Bastiaens, was resigning to pursue other opportunities.</p>
<p>The announcement was not unexpected by analysts who said Quarterdeck, which recently reported a steep third quarter loss, is going through a difficult transition.</p>
<p>&quot;Quarterdeck is going through a very challenging period and one that may require a more operations-oriented, cost-cutter (CEO),&quot; said Chris Galvin, analyst with Hambrecht &amp; Quist.</p>
<p>Quarterdeck said it will be managed by a newly created temporary Office of the President consisting of King Lee and Anatoly Tikhman.</p>
<p>Lee, a member of the board and chief executive officer of Wynd Communications Corp., served as interim chief executive and chief operating officer at Quarterdeck from July 1994 to January 1995.</p>
<p>Tikhman, now a senior vice president of the company and head of its utilities business unit, was president and chief executive officer of Vertisoft before its recent acquisition by Quarterdeck.</p>
<p>The board has retained an executive search firm to seek a new permanent chief executive.</p>
<p>Quarterdeck has said it expects revenue growth to resume in its fiscal fourth quarter ending Sept. 30.</p>
<p>Revenues were down to $16 million in the third fiscal quarter ended June 30 from $28 million a year ago, resulting in a net loss of $22.9 million.</p>
<p>The Marina Del Rey, Calif.-based maker of Internet and utility software has said it plans to introduce several Windows products in the fourth quarter that should reverse the revenue slide.</p>
<p>As part of a recently announced restructuring, it has laid off about 100 people, or 10 percent of its work force. Analysts said that operations and results have been hindered by failure of its browser and Internet server products to take hold.</p>
<p>&quot;Bastiaens did a good job from turning the company from a one-product-oriented company to a multi-product company, but Quarterdeck must now focus on integrating its acquisitions, and reviving its stock and operations,&quot; said Galvin.</p>
<p>&quot;We appreciate the efforts of Gaston, who has grown the company from a $27 million one-product operation to a more than $140 million multifaceted utilities and Internet company,&quot; said Quarterdeck Chairman Frank LaHaye.</p>
<p>&quot;The challenge for the interim management is to effectively integrate and operate the companies we have acquired so that Quarterdeck can continue its growth and return to strong profitability,&quot; said King Lee.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARINA DEL REY, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
