<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161092" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Softbank, News Corp in talks with TV Asahi.</title>
<headline>Softbank, News Corp in talks with TV Asahi.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Softbank Corp said on Friday that it and News Corp were continuing discussions with TV Asahi, their affiliate broadcasting company in Japan, about placing members on the broadcaster's board.</p>
<p>&quot;We are carefully studying requests made by TV Asahi to see if we will accept them,&quot; said a Softbank spokesman. &quot;We have made clear from the start that we are not interested in taking over TV Asahi.&quot;</p>
<p>Asahi National Broadcasting Co, known as TV Asahi, said on Thursday that it would not accept board members from Softbank and News Corp unless they confirm in a written statement that they would refrain from purchasing further shares of TV Asahi.</p>
<p>TV Asahi, citing requests from other big shareholders, also asked Softbank and News Corp to confirm that they would not be involved in management of the company.</p>
<p>The two firms recently acquired a 21.4 percent stake in TV Asahi through their joint venture Softbank News Corp Media, becoming the third largest shareholder.</p>
<p>The announcement surprised other shareholders, including Japan's biggest newspaper company, as the purchases were made through another company.</p>
<p>TV Asahi originally planned to accept two part-time board members from the two firms at a shareholders' meeting on November 7.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
