<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162032" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Finding safe shades for surfing tikes. [CORRECTED 22:00 GMT 6/11]</title>
<headline>Finding safe shades for surfing tikes. [CORRECTED 22:00 GMT 6/11]</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Internet is a lot like life itself.</p>
<p>All it once it can be big, bold and beautiful. On the other hand, it can also be boring, forgettable and downright ugly.</p>
<p>As we do not let children run loose on the highways and byways of life, there have been efforts to restrict certain aspects of the Internet to youngsters.</p>
<p>Some cringe at any attempt to censor the Net, and the freedom of speech advocates have strongly fought the heavy handed and often futile attempts by governments to control what is published on the Net and the World Wide Web.</p>
<p>But it has been the dark side of the Web that has undoubtedly kept many people away from joining the digital revolution, especially schools. Many Internet advocates believe this has been a shame.</p>
<p>As the 1997 Canadian Internet Handbook points out, there are many fascinating and educating sites for children. As a good example of this, take a look at the SciEd:Science and Mathematics Education resources site (http://www-hpcc.astro.washington.edu/scied/science.html)  (Corrects spelling of washington in World Wide Web address).</p>
<p>where a student can soon begin studying the solar systems, black  holes and volcanoes.</p>
<p>So if the Internet has value for students, are there ways to allow them sufficient freedom to roam and learn on the Net?</p>
<p>In the June, 1996 U.S. court decision that blocked as unconstitutional the law prohibiting indecency on the Internet, Judge Stewart Dalzell strongly recommended parents take the initiative protecting children from pornography and the like by installing blocking software or not allowing access at all.</p>
<p>The idea of filtering the Net with strongly tinted censorship sunglasses to protect the surfing kiddie public has been gathering momentum.</p>
<p>A range of personal computer programmes has been released that put the responsibility on parents to decide what their children should see or not see.</p>
<p>The names of the programmes are almost as inventive as the software itself, with monikers such as, CyberPatrol, CYBERsitter, Internet Filter, NetNanny, NetShepherd, Surfwatch and Tattle-Tale.</p>
<p>One of the problems of filtering the Net is that with the Web comprising 57 million pages and counting, it is tough for any one group to rate Web sites and individual pages continually -- although most of the programmes do have ingenious techniques to do just that.</p>
<p>Some programmes let you automatically block newly created pages that have never been rated. Some have a password system that lets adults view new pages separately while others block any pages containing certain offensive words.</p>
<p>Last week, a Canadian entry, Net Shepherd Inc. of Calgary, Alberta, launched what it billed as the &quot;World's Largest Internet Rating Challenge&quot; at a Toronto area high school.</p>
<p>With high schools across Canada and one in New York City participating in the news conference via the Net, the company challenged teachers and librarians to spend a few minutes each week to help rate Web pages.</p>
<p>Qualified school personnel will be able to register and download special software from the StartSafe Challenge home site (http://www.startsafe.netshepherd.com). With the software, the educator would be directed to a list of Web pages, chosen randomly, to be studied and rated.</p>
<p>&quot;The StartSafe challenge chose to partner with teachers and librarians for this rating effort because teachers are bound by tradition and training to promote a balanced approach to acquiring knowledge,&quot; said David Beattie, a director of SchoolNet Canada, a government initiative.</p>
<p>Perhaps with efforts like this, a few more students will get to experience more of what life is all about on the Net.</p>
<p>-- To comment on this weekly column, send e-mail to russell.blinch(at)reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
