<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168828" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tech shares jump on Cisco profit, Prop 211 defeat.</title>
<headline>Tech shares jump on Cisco profit, Prop 211 defeat.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of high-tech companies surged Wednesday after news of strong earnings from Cisco Systems Inc and the defeat of a California measure that could have threatened technology profits.</p>
<p>After the market closed yesterday, Cisco, the world's biggest maker of computer networking equipment and a bellwhether technology stock, said its first-quarter earnings jumped 77 percent, better than Wall Street expected.  </p>
<p>California voters also rejected a ballot initiative that would have made it easier for investors to sue companies for stock drops. Technology companies with volatile stocks have been a favorite target of expensive class-action lawsuits.</p>
<p>&quot;We defeated the jackals of Proposition 211, the carrion feeders who would take away our profits,&quot; said James Cramer, principal of money management firm Cramer Partners in New York, which owns $225 million of stocks. In addition, recent worries about weak personal computer sales are &quot;premature,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>In early afternoon trading, Cisco shares, the most active in U.S. markets, were up 1/8 at 61-7/8. The stock had risen about seven percent in the past week in anticipation of strong earnings.</p>
<p>Compaq Computer Corp, the world's biggest PC maker, was up 1 1/2 at 71 7/8. And Intel Corp, the world's biggest maker of computer chips, rose 2-1/8 to 116-1/8.</p>
<p>The technology-laden Nasdaq market composite was up 10.63 at 1239.70.  </p>
<p>&quot;Cisco is notorious for saying they can't grow like this forever, yet they announced that their revenue grew 80 percent,&quot; said Kevin Baker, who manages $750 million of technology stocks for John Hancock Funds.</p>
<p>Baker also said President Bill Clinton's re-election reflects consumers' view that the economy was good.</p>
<p>&quot;For the big guys like Compaq and Intel, things will continue to be strong,&quot; Baker said.</p>
<p>Other technology shares posting big gains included database software developer Oracle Corp, up 1-1/8 at 45 1/4; Microsoft Corp, up 1 at 142-1/2; and Texas Instrument Inc, up 3-1/4 at 52-1/4.</p>
<p>Cramer said the gains were the start &quot;of a big run to the end of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Kourosh Karimkhany, Palo Alto newsroom, + 1 415 846 5401</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
