<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169759" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mixture of fact and fallacy in two FlagTower releases.</title>
<headline>Mixture of fact and fallacy in two FlagTower releases.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>The people behind &quot;The Unexplained&quot; have some explaining to do.</p>
<p>This CD-ROM (FlagTower, Windows, $30), a recent example of someone trying to make a buck off the pseudo-mysteries of the &quot;supernatural,&quot; invites you to &quot;examine the evidence&quot; and then neglects to provide key pieces of information to help you understand what's really going on.</p>
<p>It talks about spoons supposedly bent by mental energy and a photograph allegedly created with thought waves, never explaining how such tricks are done by sleight of hand.</p>
<p>One of my favourite supernatural topics is dowsing -- the alleged ability to find water, gold, missing persons, and just about anything using a forked stick, a couple of bent coat hangers, or a pendulum. The scientific research is overwhelming: it doesn't work. The psychology behind dowsing, particularly why people believe in it so fiercely, is fascinating.</p>
<p>&quot;The Unexplained&quot; makes the dowsing issue seem far more open to debate than it really is. On the one hand, &quot;The Unexplained&quot; treats dowsing as real, stating at one point that the U.S. Marine Corps is &quot;quite open about their use of the talent to detect dangerous sites,&quot; a highly questionable claim and one that the programme never bothers to document.</p>
<p>In some cases, the folks at FlagTower do something that the supernatural TV special and tabloid talk shows don't do -- offer at least a smidgen of scepticism. The dowsing section, for example, describes a test by the British military where dowsers failed miserably when they tried to located defused mines. It also states that false memories, suggestibility, and hoaxes may be responsible for some UFO reports.</p>
<p>There's a huge prize (currently over $740,000) for anyone who can demonstrate paranormal powers without using luck or fraud. (The challenge is outlined on the World Wide Web at www.randi.org/jr/chall.html.) A savvy consumer should question why none of the people on this CD-ROM who claim extraordinary powers have earned the money.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>From trepanation (the ancient practice of drilling holes in the head to cure headaches, epilepsy and mental illness) to organ transplants, FlagTower's &quot;A History of Medicine&quot; (Windows, $30) looks at the illnesses, discoveries and people who have shaped contemporary medicine.</p>
<p>The presentation is entertaining and interesting. It has a section on the Hammurabi Code, which was the first attempt to regulate doctors and ordered that a surgeon who saved the life of a lord must be handsomely rewarded, unless the lord died (in which case his hand would be cut).</p>
<p>This early form of managed care prevented a lot of unnecessary operations. Another section explains how the Hebrews pioneered the science of public health with their sanitation rules.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, &quot;A History of Medicine&quot; falls for much of the propaganda surrounding &quot;alternative&quot; medicine, stating that practitioners who use &quot;complementary&quot; therapies &quot;stress that disorders are not the product of a single cause but an accumulation of factors: inherited predispositions, diet, emotional state, an individual's way of life and abuses such as alcohol and cigarettes.&quot;</p>
<p>The truth is, that's the underlying philosophy of &quot;established&quot; medicine these days.</p>
<p>Yet though the programme seems unwilling to assess questionable medical claims, it offers a nice discussion of medical quackery.</p>
<p>&quot;A History of Medicine&quot; ends up being a mixed bag. If you're going to embrace its information in large doses, I prescribe a grain of salt.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Rama&quot; (Sierra, Windows95/DOS, $55) is based on the series of novels originated by science fiction author Arthur C. Clarke. Players on an alien spacecraft that has entered our solar system survive by interpreting languages and cultures.</p>
<p>&quot;The Polar Express&quot; (Houghton Mifflin Interactive, Windows/Macintosh, $20) -- Electronic edition of the award-winning Chris Van Allsburg book about a train trip to visit Santa Claus. Garrison Keillor narrates, for ages 3-8.</p>
<p>&quot;Algebra Smart&quot; (Princeton Review, Windows/Macintosh, $30) claims to make Algebra fun using a witty, irreverent approach. Over 130 videos to guide you through the step-by-step lessons.</p>
<p>&quot;Scrabble&quot; (Hasbro Interactive, Windows/Macintosh, $40) -- This easy-to-play CD-ROM version of the popular word game lets you compete against the computer, challenge other humans via a local computer network or the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;SimPark&quot; (Maxis, Windows, $40) -- A simulation where you become a park ranger with the responsibility for deciding where to build a wild game preserve and which animals to put there. It's for ages 8 and up.</p>
<p>&quot;Grandma Ollie's Morphabet Soup&quot; (KinderActive, Windows/Macintosh, $30) teaches reading skills to 4-to 7-year-olds with games like Heavenly Homonym Hominy and Multiple Meanings Moussaka. Actress Jean Stapleton hosts.</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
