<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175433" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SEC sues Systems of Excellence, chairman.</title>
<headline>SEC sues Systems of Excellence, chairman.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Commission said on Thursday it filed a lawsuit against Systems of Excellence Inc and its chairman, Charles Huttoe, for alleged massive market manipulation involving shares of the company.</p>
<p>In a civil complaint filed in Federal District Court here, the agency alleged that Huttoe, 49, a Miami resident, secretly distributed about 43 million company shares to his family members and corporations.</p>
<p>The SEC alleged he manipulated the market by issuing false, favorable information concerning the company using a stock promoter, and then selling his shares after the price had artificially risen, the SEC said.</p>
<p>The SEC also alleged that Huttoe had &quot;engaged in a massive coverup&quot; after the company's auditors found evidence of the unregistered distribution of the company's shares and raised questions about the matter in mid-September.</p>
<p>Systems of Excellence, a maker of video teleconferencing equipment, has offices in McLean, Va., and Coral Gables, Fla.</p>
<p>Also named in the civil complaint are six companies including stock promoter SGA Goldstar Research Inc, and relatives of Huttoe, including his wife Karen Purvis, his mother and a niece.  </p>
<p>The SEC's action came after it suspended trading of the company's stock for 10 days beginning October 7 because of questions about the accuracy of information given to the market.</p>
<p>The SEC is seeking to recover at least $10 million that investors lost because of Huttoe's and other defendants' alleged wrongdoing.</p>
<p>The SEC has sought a temporary restraining order, a preliminary injunction and other emergency relief, including the freezing of the company's bank accounts.</p>
<p>Cynthia Gramer, a company spokesperson, said from Boston that &quot;a group of people have taken the company in hand.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They are doing everything in their power to uncover what was wrong and make it right,&quot; she said, adding &quot;apparently there was a great deal that needs to be fixed.&quot;</p>
<p>Huttoe could not be reached for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
