<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176153" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: INTERVIEW-MasterCard sees rise in electronic trade.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-MasterCard sees rise in electronic trade.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senior executives from MasterCard International Inc said on Friday the company will seek to exploit expected sharp growth in world electronic commerce and computerised payments in the next few years.</p>
<p>Two MasterCard executives told Reuters in an interview that the Purchase, New York-based company sees 1997 as the year in which electronic commerce through the Internet will take off.</p>
<p>&quot;We see ourselves as a payment-service company, not just a credit-card firm,&quot; said James Cassin, Singapore-based president of MasterCard Asia and Pacific, referring to MasterCard's recent strong growth in debit-card business in the region.</p>
<p>Cassin said MasterCard's Maestro card, an on-line debit payment product, has posted triple-digit annual growth in cards issued in many Asian countries since its introduction three years ago.</p>
<p>Donald Van Stone, MasterCard's general manager for Southeast Asia, said 1997 will see major changes in electronic commercial and consumer transactions with chip cards being the next phase of growth in Asia.</p>
<p>Chip cards can be used to make payments of a few U.S. cents to large sums and can also serve as debit and credit cards.</p>
<p>&quot;Eighty percent of our business is cash-based transactions ...if you look at the future, debit and chip cards, electronic commerce, stored-value applications and things we don't even know about will be an increasingly big part of it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Stone said MasterCard and Visa International will soon announce the finishing touches to Secure Electronic Transactions (SET), a system for conducting secure bankcard transactions over the Internet and other open networks.</p>
<p>The two credit-card companies are developing SET jointly with GTE Corp, International Business Machines Corp, Microsoft Corp, and Netscape Communications Corp.</p>
<p>Stone said: &quot;1997 will be a major transitional year for the electronic-payment business. It will come in like a lamb and go out like a lion.&quot;</p>
<p>Cassin said slightly more than 10 percent of MasterCard's revenue comes from its electronic-commerce payment services.</p>
<p>He said MasterCard has issued 12 million credit, debit and payment cards in China, where it expected about 35 percent growth this year -- a moderate pace compared with the triple-digit annual increase between 1991 and 1994.</p>
<p>Cassin said the Agricultural Bank of Asia will launch the Maestro card in 12 Chinese cities in 1997.</p>
<p>He projected MasterCard will see the number of all its cards increase 25-30 percent in Asia this year with South Korea, Australia and India being its highest growth areas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150108">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
