<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177322" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Dassault sees 96 profit in line with H1.</title>
<headline>Dassault sees 96 profit in line with H1.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>French aircraft maker Dassault Aviation expects its pretax pre-exceptional profit for full-year 1996 to be in line with the trend seen in the first half, finance director Charles Edelstenne said on Friday.</p>
<p>Pretax pre-exceptional profit for 1996 &quot;will confirm&quot; the first-half trend, he told journalists.  </p>
<p>The pre-exceptional result will exclude the capital gain made from the flotation of a stake in Dassault Systemes in the first half, he said.</p>
<p>Dassault Aviation made a first-half pretax profit of 1.26 billion francs including the exceptional gain from Dassault Systemes, compared to a year ago profit of 277 million.</p>
<p>Dassault Aviation made a net attributable profit for the full-year 1995 of 401 million francs, up from 328 million in 1994.  </p>
<p>New orders this year would be lower than 1995 and would be inferior to 1996 turnover for the first time in a number of years as the government had not ordered any Rafale jets this year, Edelstenne said.</p>
<p>The French government has delayed 1996 orders for the Rafale combat jet and pushed back the production programme, he said.</p>
<p>But the government has budgeted four billion francs for the Rafale programme for 1997, and Dassault hoped there would be orders in that year, he said.</p>
<p>Dassault Aviation posted 1995 pretax pre-exceptional profit of 475 million francs versus 397 million in 1994.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
