<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185092" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Salomon Informix upgrade mixed with lower EPS view.</title>
<headline>Salomon Informix upgrade mixed with lower EPS view.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Salomon Brothers analyst Neil Herman upgraded Informix Corp Wednesday, but his reasoning sounded largely similar to that of other analysts who have issued downgrades on the stock in recent days.</p>
<p>While boosting his rating to buy from neutral, Herman said he lowered his earnings estimates for the company's current and upcoming years, in line with other analysts.</p>
<p>The main difference between the two camps of Wall Street analysts appears to be over Informix's valuation. &quot;If you look at the stock from a valuation basis, it looks pretty attractive&quot; at around 23 times earnings, Herman argued.  </p>
<p>Historically, the stock has traded at 26 times earnings, he noted.</p>
<p>Conversely, while Alex. Brown analyst Jim Moore cut his earnings view, Wednesday, citing near-term risks, he said he was confident of the stock's long-term prospects as Informix prepares to offer its next generation database system.</p>
<p>Herman estimated Informix will report $0.24 per share in the fourth quarter of 1996, versus his previous $0.28 per share estimate. Accordingly, he lowered his 1996 year estimate to $0.66 per share from $0.70 per share.</p>
<p>In addition, he projected the company would earn $0.95 per share in 1997, down from his prior view of $1.05 for the year. &quot;I think 1997 is going to be a good year,&quot; Herman said.</p>
<p>&quot;From a long-term perspective, the stock will do well,&quot; although he cautioned that, &quot;near-term, it's somewhat questionable,&quot; sounding a note similar to Informix doubters.</p>
<p>-- E. Auchard, Wall Street bureau, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
