<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186469" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Modern myths fuel three games on Ancient Egypt.</title>
<headline>Modern myths fuel three games on Ancient Egypt.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ancient Egypt has been an endless source of wonder, mysticism and silliness.</p>
<p>It has given us the legend that bad things happen to people who remove mummies from their final resting place. The folks who removed King Tut, for example, supposedly died early and mysterious deaths. (In truth, magician James Randi has found, the people intimately involved with digging T4ut up, unwrapping him and examining him had an average life span of about 73 years.)</p>
<p>It also sparked the now-tired theory -- developed by Eric von Daniken, passionately disputed by experts and promoted most recently by an ABC-TV special -- that Egyptians got special technology from space aliens. Variations on that theme speculate that the Egyptians mastered magic or developed scientific knowledge far superior to ours.</p>
<p>The ideas may be fanciful, but they've become popular myth. They show up in three recent CD-ROM games on Egypt. None is likely to go down in history as a new wonder of the (computer) world.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>&quot;Secrets of the Luxor&quot; (Mojave, Windows/Macintosh, $50) is short on story but long on puzzles. You play an archaeologist who has made an extraordinary discovery in a long-forgotten Egyptian pyramid. Your job is to find secret passages, restart ancient machinery and discover ways to avoid a series of booby traps.</p>
<p>Before I had managed to get halfway through the game, I'd been crushed to death, poisoned by a dart from a queen's statue, and gained several inches in height with the assistance of a very pointy stake.</p>
<p>I also had to deal with two sets of bad guys: the government agents trying to figure out how the ancient Egyptians made a scooter that levitates and a religious zealot attempting to claim an ancient obelisk that controls space and time.</p>
<p>Many of the puzzles will drive players crazy as they search for clues to the solutions amid all the inscriptions on the walls and floors.</p>
<p>The system for moving through the game isn't as easy as it could be. Adding to the difficulty is the fact that you cannot tell if an object is useful by putting the cursor on it. As a result, you're tempted to click on everything, wasting a lot of time.</p>
<p>By the way, you'll be interested to know that, according to &quot;Luxor,&quot; the ancient Egyptians not only had pipe organs and flying machines, they found a way to rid their buildings of pesky dustballs.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>&quot;Timelapse&quot; (GTE Entertainment, Windows95/Macintosh, $70) is the newest game of the three, and it doesn't restrict itself to ancient Egypt. After you discover a space/time transporter in an Easter Island cave, you can send yourself to the Mayan world, the cliff dwellings of the Anasazi Indians, or, ultimately, the underwater city of Atlantis. Like &quot;Luxor,&quot; it focuses on solving puzzles.</p>
<p>The game promises extraordinary graphics, then doesn't deliver. The full-screen images are colourful and richly detailed, but they're not significantly better than other games.</p>
<p>At the climactic moment when I found the transporter, the developers of &quot;Timelapse&quot; had a chance to flex their animation muscle. Instead, I got static images that were colourful, yet singularly underwhelming. Some of the animation is less than impressive, such as when the shadows don't change as the Nile boat turns.</p>
<p>&quot;Timelapse&quot; can be cumbersome to play. One of the first chores is finding a camera. I spotted something gleaming on the ground, but nothing happened when I clicked on it. Only much later did I discover that the only way to look down at that spot and be able to pick up the camera was to walk forward.</p>
<p>In another case, I spent so much time fruitlessly stabbing a crocodile with a spear that it became comical. The croc only reacted when I stabbed him in one specific place several times. It was unnecessarily exasperating.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>&quot;Mummy: Tomb of the Pharaoh&quot; (Interplay, DOS/Windows95, $48) has less mysticism, more intrigue, more people, fewer puzzles and it's easier to play.</p>
<p>You assume the role of Michael Cameron, who is sent to a mining site in Alexandria, Egypt, after workers discover a strange, ancient box with a curse written on it. The curse has spooked the natives, your ex-girlfriend is trying to figure out whether Egyptian authorities should be notified (which would shut down the mining operation) and the regional supervisor (played by actor Malcolm McDowell) keeps following you around like a bad reputation.</p>
<p>To make matters worse, the mining company's geologist, who has discovered some mysterious air pockets near the tunnels of the mining site, is murdered the first night you're there. You wake up the next morning to candles around your bed and a note warning that you, too, are in grave danger.</p>
<p>It's a wise warning. &quot;Mummy&quot; gives you several opportunities to be impaled, drowned, or otherwise turned into a candidate for mummydom.</p>
<p>Most of the puzzles aren't as difficult as &quot;Luxor&quot; and it can be fun snooping around.</p>
<p>The game has some oddities. It can only play one sound at a time, which gives it the appearance of being clunky. It was amazing how quickly Cameron learned to read a wall full of hieroglyphics. And when I stumbled out of a crevice to tell McDowell's character that I had found an ancient Egyptian tomb, he reacted with all the enthusiasm of a man being lectured about dustballs.</p>
<p>But if you prefer action and human interaction over puzzles, &quot;Mummy&quot; is the better choice.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
