<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186708" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Three firms fighting to be first on Easdaq.</title>
<headline>Three firms fighting to be first on Easdaq.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three firms from Britain, France and Belgium are racing to be first to float on Europe's new growth stocks market Easdaq, the exchange said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Easdaq spokesman Chris Pickles confirmed the identity of two candidates named in Britain's Financial Times newspaper on Wednesday as U.K.-based anti-virus software developer  Dr Solomon's Group, and French smartcard maker  ActivCard.</p>
<p>The third is biotechnology firm  Innogenetics NV which on Tuesday launched an initial public offering of 6,658,050 shares, or 32 percent of its share capital, at between $10 and $12 each.</p>
<p>Innogenetics's issue runs until November 25 and the company plans to quote its shares on November 28, though Easdaq officials have said another IPO might be possible before then.</p>
<p>&quot;It sounds like there's a race on between the three of them to come on the market first. All three have been approved by Easdaq for trading, though it is up to the issuer to decide exactly when they want to go public,&quot; Pickles told Reuters.</p>
<p>The pan-European exchange, which is modelled on New York's Nasdaq, became technically operational on September 30 and its rules were published in late October.</p>
<p>It expects to see between 12 and 15 stocks listed by year-end, building up to 50 in 12 months' time.</p>
<p>These would include some of the 80 or so European companies already listed on Nasdaq, which are seeking a dual listing.</p>
<p>Belgian-based software firm Artwork Systems plans an IPO later. Belgian Kredietbank unit KB-Securities is lead managing the Innogenetics and Artwork Systems flotations.</p>
<p>To be admitted, firms must be supported by at least two Easdaq-registered market makers. They must have total assets of 3.5 milliion Ecus and capital and reserves of two million Ecus.</p>
<p>So far 36 financial institutions have applied for membership as Easdaq dealers, market makers or sponsors.</p>
<p>The Easdaq project originated from contacts between the European Venture Capital Association, the European Commission and various market players.</p>
<p>Nasdaq is one of Easdaq's 91 shareholders which brought about 370 million Belgian francs together to finance its launch.</p>
<p>-- Lorrayne Smith, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6812, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
