<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186940" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BT, MCI and Microsoft in global intranet pact.</title>
<headline>BT, MCI and Microsoft in global intranet pact.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Telecommunications Plc, MCI Communications Corp  and U.S giant Microsoft Corp confirmed on Wednesday they plan to expand their alliances to develop a new range of global intranet services.  </p>
<p>The companies said they planned to target two types of customer demands, including one for a range of solutions for businesses that want to build and manage their own intranet, a customised internal computer network.</p>
<p>The second, to be rolled out in early 1997, is for a fully-managed, network-based intranet service for customers seeking a communications partner that can build and manage their intranet on a global basis.</p>
<p>The firms said analysts expected that by 1999, products and services associated with building corporate intranets to account for $28 billion -- more than half of the total Internet market. The new services will offer the full range of Microsoft's messaging and intranet platforms, the firms said in a joint statement released here.</p>
<p>BT and MCI, which plan to merge in a $20 billion deal, will market the new services worldwide.</p>
<p>The services will be offered by Concert, the two companies' existing telecommunications joint venture. Concert InternetPlus Service, a global Internet backbone that became operational this week between the United States and Europe, will support intranet transport for the new services.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
