<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188029" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: More Web sites let shoppers buy, download software.</title>
<headline>More Web sites let shoppers buy, download software.</headline>
<byline>Michelle V. Rafter</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Imagine ordering, receiving and installing new software in the space of a single coffee break -- without leaving your desk.</p>
<p>Sounds improbable but it is happening at a rapidly expanding band of Web sites that let shoppers buy, pay for and download programmes online.</p>
<p>The newest entry is retailer Egghead Software, which late last week opened a &quot;Try Before You Buy&quot; service on its Web site (http://www.egghead.com/) where shoppers download fully loaded programmes from Microsoft, SunSoft and Starfish Software for a free 15-day test drive before paying for unlimited use of the software.</p>
<p>Egghead joins virtual retailers such as Software.net, Stream, Internet Shopping Network and Cyberian Outpost that offer what the industry has dubbed electronic software distribution, or ESD.</p>
<p>Publishers such as Starfish Software and Qualcomm are using ESD to sell directly to consumers, in the process slashing packaging, marketing and distributing costs, reducing the time it takes to unveil new products and augmenting tough-to-get shelf space in retail computer stores.</p>
<p>Supporters see online software delivery as a signal of the coming Internet electronic-commerce boom, and picture a time when most software used at home and in business is distributed online.</p>
<p>But sceptics maintain that day may be long in coming, mainly, they believe, because consumers are used to buying software on a floppy disk or CD-ROM with a box and printed manual and don't easily change shopping habits. What's more, sceptics add, few established computer retailers have started selling online, and many software publishers can't or won't bypass established physical-world distribution channels to sell direct.</p>
<p>Technology researcher International Data Corp. expects sales of electronically delivered software to reach $4.6 billion by 2000 from next to nothing today. Even so, that will represent only 5 percent of all software sales.</p>
<p>Most of that will be sales to businesses because the limitations of current Internet technology make downloading software tedious, said Stephen Baker, an IDC senior analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;If you want a full copy of Doom, it would be faster to drive to CompUSA, buy it and come home because downloading thousands of megabytes of information and pictures and graphics on the 28.8 (kilobytes per second) modems most people use today would take a long time,&quot; Baker said.</p>
<p>Still, retailers and publishers that offer instant software delivery love it, and say their customers do too.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been absolutely phenomenal. It's changed our entire marketing strategy,&quot; said Beth Nagengast, Starfish's marketing director.</p>
<p>Half the people buying the company's new Starfish Internet Utilities programme are taking delivery online, and more than 20,000 downloaded free copies in a recent four-day promotion, Nagengast said.</p>
<p>Starfish, run by Borland founder Philippe Kahn, began distributing its popular Sidekick software and other programmes on CompuServe in February 1995, and today offers electronic delivery through nine Web sites, including its own.</p>
<p>&quot;The more places we can have our software, the more places we'll be,&quot; Nagengast said.</p>
<p>At Software.net, 60 percent of $7 million in software the company expects to sell this year will be delivered online, said Rob Lewis, marketing manager for CyberSource, the Web site's parent company.</p>
<p>CyberSource created Software.net two years ago to test electronic delivery and now is selling the service to other online merchants. One customer is virtual retailer Cyberian Outpost, which expected to begin offering instant downloads sometime this month.</p>
<p>For consumers, procedures for buying and downloading software vary from site to site, but all are fairly straightforward. In some cases, a shopper chooses a programme to buy, uses a credit card to pay for it and downloads an encrypted copy of the software. Once payment is approved, the retailer sends an electronic key that unlocks the software so it can be installed.</p>
<p>In the case of Egghead's &quot;Try Before You Buy&quot; programme, if a customer wants a programme after the trial period, they pay with a credit card and receive an electronic key that extends the life of the programme indefinitely.</p>
<p>Here are some Web sites that offer instant software delivery, and the type of programmes available:</p>
<p>- buydirect.com (http://buydirect.com) (eds: correct) -- cnet's soon-to-be-unveiled online software store.</p>
<p>- Cyberian Outpost (http://www.cybout.com)</p>
<p>- Egghead (http://www.egghead.com/) -- SunSoft JavaWorkshop 1.0, Microsoft Front Page and Starfish Internet Sidekick.</p>
<p>- Internet Shopping Network (http://www.internet.net/) -- Programmes from Microsoft, Day Timer, Starfish Software, Surfwatch, among others.</p>
<p>- Programmer's Paradise (http://www.pparadise.com/) -- Specialised programmes for software developers.</p>
<p>- Software.net (http://www.software.net) -- More than 1,500 ESD programmes, including software from Microsoft, Quarterdeck, Future Tense, and Tumbleweed.</p>
<p>- Software Spectrum (http://www.swspectrum.com/)</p>
<p>- Stream (http://www.stream.com/) -- More than 50 programmes available from Microsoft, Ulead, Netscene, among others.</p>
<p>(Michelle V. Rafter writes about cyberspace and technology from Los Angeles. Reach her at mvrafter(at)deltanet.com. Opinions expressed in this column are her own.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
