<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188427" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - What future for overcrowded British banking market?.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - What future for overcrowded British banking market?.</headline>
<byline>Joe Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britons can bank on the phone, bank on the internet, bank with a PC and bank while they shop but the proliferation of financial services only betrays serious doubts about what the future holds.</p>
<p>The crux of the matter is that Britain is over-banked and even more players are lining up to enter the fray.</p>
<p>The question for the industry is how to reduce expensive, routine banking operations and sell more &quot;product&quot;, like insurance or pensions, while not alienating the customers to an unacceptable degree.</p>
<p>The recent tie-up between supermarket chain J. Sainsbury and the Bank of Scotland is an illustration of the thinking going on in panelled boardrooms.</p>
<p>The bank, lightweight in its exposure outside its Scottish stronghold, needed to find a way of extending its customer base into England and Wales.</p>
<p>One obvious alternative, to buy customers from a bank or a building society, would have been expensive with no guarantee of success.</p>
<p>The food retailer needed to satisfy an apparent customer demand for banking services to be present &quot;in-store&quot;.</p>
<p>At a stroke, the demands of Sainsbury's customers will be met, at least partially, and Bank of Scotland will have a potential 12 million customers to sell things to. Profits will be shared.</p>
<p>Independent strategist Catherine Smith says retailers and possibly new intermediaries like Microsoft or BT are likely to take on more and more of the routine payments, cashing and deposit-taking business with their relatively sophisticated technology.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks might be better off in the long run because that side of the business is loss-making,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>But she also points out that for a long time, bankers have had an almost religious belief that, unless they provide the nitty-gritty, everyday services, then they cannot hope to sell money-making products like insurance and pensions.</p>
<p>&quot;The decisive factor will the ability of banks to walk away from loss-making business,&quot; said Smith. &quot;Strength of character to make fundamental decisions and a strong capital position to withstand a price war will also be important.&quot;</p>
<p>And banks have been walking away. From branches, for example.</p>
<p>National Westminster announced 300 closures earlier this year and the merger of Lloyds and TSB will likely lead to large scale closures, especially if their claims for cost savings are to be realised.</p>
<p>But closing branches and putting everyone on the telephone isn't always the best way. Some people still like to actually talk to their bank manager face to face (and vice versa, of course).</p>
<p>Barclays chief executive Martin Taylor is nervous of unthinking closure ideas.</p>
<p>&quot;Having high-cost branches is the disadvantage,&quot; Taylor told Reuters in an interview earlier this year. &quot;The marginal three or four hundred branches are not a big deal.&quot; The speed at which closures happen for Taylor is a function of what revenue they produce. Low cost branches can be kept open for longer but closing them will not save very much anyway.</p>
<p>&quot;If I heard that our competitors were closing down half their branches, I'd regard that as good news, as an opportunity,&quot; Taylor added.</p>
<p>In all of this, it's hard not to see internet banking and PC banking generally as rather a side-show.</p>
<p>No doubt they make it easier for the customer to keep a handle on account details, direct payments and other routine aspects, but its hard to see how any more complex financial product could be actually sold down these channels although they may help provide sales prospects.</p>
<p>Increasingly, the great British public are going to have to make personal provision for old-age as the State finds it more and more difficult to fund such massive programmes.</p>
<p>But even with that expansion, Smith says that the inescapable crunch will come because there is simply not enough business to go round.</p>
<p>Britain's traditional banks are now ranged against insurance companies, many of which have far better selling experience than the banks, and an increasing number of building societies who are converting to bank status and floating on the stock exchange.</p>
<p>Some of these are very big. Take the Halifax, Britain's largest home mortgage lender, for example. Add to these, the brand-based sellers of financial products such as Virgin and Marks &amp; Spencer, and you have a deregulated financial services sector where something will have to give.</p>
<p>Further mergers and takeovers seem inevitable, though the size of some of the present players makes this problematical, and even the prospect of cross-border mergers in Europe is thought a possibility by some who see these being facilitated by European monetary union, if that ever comes.</p>
<p>But many still feel that cultural barriers and brand loyalties make this a difficult nut to crack.</p>
<p>The Bank of Scotland/Sainsbury solution begins to look more and more logical and could be used on a larger scale.</p>
<p>Barclays is already co-operating with Microsoft on Microsoft's Money 97 software, a tie-up which allows Barclays customers to drop their financial details into a home finance software programme.</p>
<p>What price &quot;Barclays Microsoft Bank&quot;?</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
