<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198818" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Eicon Technology sees profit in Q2.</title>
<headline>Eicon Technology sees profit in Q2.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eicon Technology Corp said on Tuesday that it expects a return to profitability in its second quarter ended December and for all of fiscal 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We will probably make a small profit in this quarter,&quot; Eicon Chairman Peter Brojde told reporters after the company's annual meeting.</p>
<p>Brojde told the meeting that he expects the company will earn a profit in fiscal 1997, ending June 30, compared with a loss of C$2.8 million or C$0.08 a share in fiscal 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We will achieve a return to profitability this year,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>In its first quarter ended September 30, Eicon lost C$2.1 million or C$0.06 a share, compared with a profit of C$25,000 or nil a share in the year earlier period.</p>
<p>Describing fiscal 1997 as a &quot;transition year&quot; during which it will expand its product distribution network in the United States and Europe, Brojde said he expect &quot;moderate&quot; sales growth of 10-20 percent.</p>
<p>Despite the expansion, the company will try to maintain its fiscal 1997 sales and administration costs at the fiscal 1996 level, Brojde. But Eicon's sales in the latest second quarter will likely lag those of the year earlier period, he said.  </p>
<p>Brojde said that despite the loss in the first quarter, which is traditionally the company's slowest quarter, Eicon is in good shape for fiscal 1997. The company has no debt, cash and cash equivalents of C$40 million, and shareholders' equity of C$104 million, he said.</p>
<p>Eicon plans to focus more on the growing worldwide market for ISDN (integrated services digital network) connections for desktop computers. ISDN related products are expected to account for up to 40 percent of the company's revenues  within the next three years, Brojde said.</p>
<p>Eicon develops, markets and supports connectivity-related hardware and software products for computers, including wide area network access for personal computer-based servers, remote ISDN access for desktop and notebook personal computers and SNA host access to IBM mainframe and midrange computers.</p>
<p>The Montreal-based company said its EiconCard family of products has an installed base of more than 300,000 units, making it the world's leading intelligent WAN card.</p>
<p>--Reuters Montreal bureau (514) 985-2434</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
