<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203240" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Superhero series calculated to teach math.</title>
<headline>Superhero series calculated to teach math.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Today's Topic A: The secret lives of superheroes.</p>
<p>Most of us know about Batman's dark side and Superman's curious gaps in logic (does he REALLY think people can't recognise him when he puts on glasses?).</p>
<p>But some of the lesser-known superheroes have quirks as well.</p>
<p>Take Handsome Chance, who never met a mirror he didn't like. The guy is obsessed with producing action figures of himself in various combinations of colours and equipment. (His motto: &quot;If it says 'Handsome' on the box, I'm inside.&quot;)</p>
<p>There's Fraction Man, a closet pyromaniac obsessed with shooting off fireworks with different ratios of colours.</p>
<p>Finally, there's the guy who runs the Superhero Superstore, where you can't tell the robbers from the clerks or customers because EVERYONE wears a mask.</p>
<p>Kids can find these unconventional superheroes (plus a few more) in two titles from Edmark's &quot;Mighty Math&quot; series (Windows/Macintosh, $40). All are calculated to help children understand math fundamentals, from number lines and spatial learning to probability and geometry.</p>
<p>&quot;Number Heroes,&quot; ages 8 to 11, talks about fractions, basic geometry and probability. &quot;Calculating Crew,&quot; for ages 8 to 12, teaches buying skills, spatial reasoning and fundamentals such as addition, subtraction, multiplication and division.</p>
<p>Two other products in the series, both sans superheroes, are &quot;Zoo Zillions&quot; (for ages 5 to 8) and &quot;Cosmic Geometry&quot; (ages 12 to 14).</p>
<p>The games are easy to play, offer many levels of difficulty (and give you a simple system for adjusting the level), and they're playful enough to keep children interested, at least for a while.</p>
<p>Away from school, these types of games can be an effective supplement for classroom teaching. But children still need parental support and encouragement to stick with most educational products. In other words: If you want any of these products to work, be prepared to play with your child. You might learn something.</p>
<p>But you may also find yourself asking some nagging questions.</p>
<p>In the laboratory where Dr. Gee asks you to compare rotatable three-dimensional objects with flat patterns to see if each two-dimensional object can be folded into the 3-D form, why does Dr. Gee feel she needs to wear a mask? Is she ashamed of what she's doing? Does she have some kind of skin condition?</p>
<p>Why does Wanda Wavelet have one huge eye, and cover the other with her hair? Is she secretly battling a thyroid problem as she teaches unsuspecting youngsters?</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Topic B: Soccer and fashion rebels.</p>
<p>Here's the question: If RuPaul's soccer team took the field in green uniforms while she trotted out to her position as goalie in a pink uniform, would she get fined, disqualified, get a yellow card or get to keep wearing pink?</p>
<p>Sports trivia games will never be the same after &quot;You Don't Know Jack Sports&quot; (Berkeley Systems, Windows/Macintosh, $30), the sports version of the wonderfully irreverent &quot;You Don't Know Jack.&quot;</p>
<p>Constructed like a TV quiz show, it lets as many as three players tackle bizarre questions in categories such as &quot;Loudmouths and their teams,&quot; &quot;If the FDA says we can eat it, then it must be OK,&quot; and &quot;Beer.&quot;</p>
<p>Pick the &quot;Trash talk&quot; category and players are asked which celebrity's trash would contain a silver world championship medal, an empty box of Stayfree Maxi Pads, a press pass and a very small green elf outfit. Your choices: Mary Lou Retton, Bonnie Blair, Kathy Rigby and Nancy Kerrigan.</p>
<p>&quot;You Don't Know Jack Sports&quot; lacks some of the charm of the original, partly because host Andy Poland can't capture the Dennis Miller-esque style of ex-host Nate Shapiro, who was the real MVP of the first &quot;You Don't Know Jack.&quot; It also has a cheesey new feature in which people are supposedly called on the telephone and asked to propose questions for the game.</p>
<p>Fortunately, the bizarre questions remain. What other game would ask you to imagine that you're playing a lacrosse game against your facial features and want to know what would happen if you decided to &quot;pick&quot; your nose?</p>
<p>The choices are (a.) wear pink, (b.) Kathy Rigby and (c.) block your nose from guarding your teammate.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;The Ultimate James Bond: An Interactive Dossier&quot; from MGM Interactive (Windows, $40) -- A dual CD-ROM database that catalogues all the Bond films. It includes over 1,000 photos, 50 film clips, production notes, posters and a trivia game. It's being sold with a free copy of the &quot;Goldeneye&quot; home video.</p>
<p>&quot;The Universe According to Virgil Reality&quot; from 7th Level (Windows, $40) teaches science to children ages 8 and up. It features a peek inside atoms, talks about wacky inventions, and promises a look at &quot;cool disgusting stuff.&quot; &quot;Earth constantly spins,&quot; the package says, &quot;so why shouldn't your head?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;How to Catch a Wild Asparagus-Snatching Snagglysnort&quot; from DiAmar Interactive (Windows/Macintosh, $30) wins this week's award for the longest title. This cartoon storybook for ages 6 to 12 features the world-famous monsterologist Colonel Picklewart and his quest to capture the rare creature.</p>
<p>&quot;The Lords of Tantrazz&quot; from Atlantean Games (Windows/Macintosh, $30) wants you to help super-agent Veronica Callahan, her lone tragic flaw her inability to keep per blouse fully buttoned, save the world from a really, really toothy monster.</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
