<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="211039" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Ramos urges &quot;go, go go&quot; as APEC gropes for accord.</title>
<headline>Ramos urges &quot;go, go go&quot; as APEC gropes for accord.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asia-Pacific nations scrambled for agreement on Friday on a U.S. plan to scrap tariffs on computers and parts in a major test of APEC's credibility as a global trading force.</p>
<p>The issue overshadowed the opening day of an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation ministers' meeting and a related gathering of more than 400 businessmen in Manila.</p>
<p>Security was also very much on the minds of U.S. officials, who warned Americans gathering for the APEC meetings they may be under threat of terrorist attack. They said Philippine security forces had taken measures to protect Americans and others.</p>
<p>Philippine President Fidel Ramos called on some of the region's most powerful chief executives to &quot;Go, Go, Go&quot; for a free trade zone encircling the Pacific.</p>
<p>But it was not clear whether APEC governments were ready to fully liberalise trade in information technology, one of the most important areas of commerce in the region.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher urged an APEC summit due to be held at Subic Bay on Monday to endorse the plan to reduce to zero tariffs on computers, software, semiconductors and telecommunications equipment by 2000.</p>
<p>The United States wants APEC to press the World Trade Organisation (WTO) to endorse the Information Technology Agreement at its first ministerial meeting in Singapore next month.</p>
<p>&quot;We share a critical interest in reducing barriers to trade in the computer and telecommunications industries,&quot; Christopher said. &quot;The agreement will dramatically lower costs and raise productivity,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Japan has thrown its weight behind the agreement, but Malaysia was reported to be holding out.</p>
<p>On Thursday U.S. Undersecretary of State Joan Spero had indicated that accord on information technology was at hand. She said global trade in such goods was worth $1.8 trillion.</p>
<p>Ramos is enlisting the support of business executives to put into action APEC promises to create a borderless economy embracing half the world's people by 2020.</p>
<p>In messages to the Asia-Pacific Business Forum, and to APEC foreign and economic ministers at the start of a two-day meeting, Ramos said APEC's lofty goals must be backed by practical steps.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we move into the action phase,&quot; he told the ministerial meeting that began to the stirring strains of &quot;Land of Hope and Glory&quot;.</p>
<p>Outside the hall riot police scuffled with students demonstrating against APEC. The protesters waved banners saying &quot;No to APEC&quot; before being scattered by baton-wielding officers.</p>
<p>Hundreds of demonstrators have been marching in the Philippine capital to denounce APEC's pro-business vision of a single trading bloc for goods and services. They say it will benefit big business and rich nations at the expense of the poor.</p>
<p>They have promised more street action over the next two days leading to Monday's summit.</p>
<p>Security was tight ahead of the summit. U.S. State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said Washington had received unspecified information about possible threats to American diplomats during the conference.</p>
<p>Burns told reporters the Philippines had taken steps to assure the security of American and other delegates but the United States felt compelled to alert the public to the danger.</p>
<p>The ministers approved an action plan for open trade to be endorsed by leaders of 18 APEC economies, including U.S. President Bill Clinton, Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto and Chinese President Jiang Zemin.</p>
<p>The so-called Manila Action Plan for APEC stitches together free-market initiatives proposed by individual members.</p>
<p>It will determine whether APEC remains a loosely-organised talking shop or evolves into a cohesive force in global trade and investment, setting the pace in international forum such as the WTO.</p>
<p>Ramos, who is transforming the Philippines from sick man of Asia to an emerging tiger economy, has staked much of his personal credibility on the document that will emerge from the summit.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's go for it! Go Go Go!&quot; he told business leaders, including the heads of corporations such as Salomon Inc of the United States, Japan's Itochu Corp and Southeast Asian phone giant Singapore Telecom.</p>
<p>Two years ago APEC set a timetable of 2010 for developed nations to completely open their markets and 2020 for developing economies.</p>
<p>The Manila meeting is intended to work out ways to achieve that aim and develop closer cooperation in a broad range of areas, including worker education, capital markets, infrastructure, technology and the environment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
