<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215153" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian Artwork Systems to float on Easdaq.</title>
<headline>Belgian Artwork Systems to float on Easdaq.</headline>
<byline>Paul de Bendern</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian-based graphic software firm Artwork Systems Group NV said on Monday it would float its shares on Easdaq, Europe's newest growth-stock market, on December 11.</p>
<p>Artwork Systems, which specialises in producing software packages for the labelling and packaging sector, is offering up to 4,244,500 shares, at between $10 and $12 each, Johan Pede of lead manager KB-Securities NV said.</p>
<p>The subscription period will start on Tuesday November 26 and close at the latest on December 6. The firm has never before offered its shares for public sale.</p>
<p>Artwork Systems has produced a full range of software that runs on Apple Macintosh, the leader in the graphic arts industry.</p>
<p>&quot;The company's strategy is to extend its current leading position in its chosen niche market (packaging and labelling) and to become a market leader in the overall professional Pre-Press software market,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>Artwork Systems has two subsidiaries -- Artwork Systems NV, its Belgian subsidiary, and Artwork Systems North America Inc., its U.S. subsidiary.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that Artwork Systems has a lead of about three years on potential competitors...we do not expect increasing competition from existing players for the next two to three years,&quot; KB-Securities said.</p>
<p>Kredietbank unit KB-Securities is the lead manager of the flotation and forecast an average growth rate for the financial years 1997-2000 of 35.9 percent for sales and 32.9 percent for earnings.</p>
<p>Artwork Systems' net revenues increased by 283 percent from financial years 1994 to 1995 and by 194 percent from financial years 1995 to 1996.</p>
<p>Total assets rose to 329 million Belgian francs ($10.5 million) in 1996 from 89 million francs in 1995.</p>
<p>In financial year 1996, Artwork Systems' total revenue was 402.6 million Belgian francs, a rise from 128.3 million francs in 1995. Its net profit after-tax was 220.9 million francs in 1996 compared to 53.7 million in 1995.</p>
<p>The company forecast growth to come mainly from the U.S. and Asia.</p>
<p>ArtPro, Artwork Systems' flagship product, is aimed at the packaging and label market. ArtPro Repro is a programme for colour publishing and general commercial printing markets.</p>
<p>The group's Belgian subsidiary and its French distributor Elcede France S.A. are involved in a legal proceeding with Barco Graphics NV, a unit of electronics firm Barco.</p>
<p>Barco is seeking a permanent injunction from further commercialisation of the ArtPro software in France, claiming it infringes a Barco software programme.</p>
<p>Quotations and trading on Easdaq will start on November 27.</p>
<p>-- Brussels newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710 ($ = 31.19 Belgian Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
