<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220340" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Some wise software buys for the holidays.</title>
<headline>Some wise software buys for the holidays.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I. 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>'Tis the holiday season -- time for bright lights, the scent of pine needles and the sounds of children squealing for enough toys to land their parents in Bankruptcy Court.</p>
<p>If your gift list includes someone who wants computer software, here are some suggestions for CD-ROMs that won't wear out their welcome by the time you're ready to take down the ornaments.</p>
<p>FOR CHILDREN</p>
<p>&quot;Freddi Fish 2: The Case of the Haunted Schoolhouse&quot; from Humongous Entertainment (Windows/Macintosh, $40) -- Designed for ages 3 to 8, this is the wonderful animated tale of a fish and her pal who try to uncover the true identity of a ghost who is terrorising their school of guppies. Another puzzle-filled CD-ROM from Humongous that's equally entertaining is the just-released &quot;Pajama Sam -- No Need To Hide When It's Dark Outside.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Elroy Hits the Pavement&quot; from Headbone Interactive (800-267-4709, Macintosh/Windows, $30) is an offbeat strategy/role-playing game for children ages 8 and older involving a hyperenergetic boy trying to find his stolen dog, Blue, and keep his invention out of the hands of the crooks from MUCK (the Mysterious Underground Crime Korporation).</p>
<p>&quot;Muppet Treasure Island&quot; from Activision (Windows, $40) -- This adventure game based on the Disney movie has live-action sequences of Kermit, Miss Piggy and actor Tim Curry. The player assumes the role of a youngster who discovers a treasure map and must find the way to Treasure Island before Long John Silver and his co-conspirators make off with the booty.</p>
<p>FOR TEENS AND OLDER</p>
<p>&quot;The Pandora Directive&quot; from Access Software (DOS/Windows95, $50) -- In this the sequel to the futuristic detective game &quot;Under A Killing Moon&quot; (which was re-released this summer and is available for as little as $20), private eye Tex Murphy must solve a mystery that revolves around a mythical flying saucer crash in New Mexico in 1947.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dig&quot; from LucasArts Entertainment (DOS/Macintosh, $30) is the epic tale of a group of astronauts who find themselves whisked to a starkly beautiful alien world. A great musical score makes it a captivating experience.</p>
<p>&quot;Smart Games Challenge No.1&quot; from Random Soft (Windows, $30) is a collection of 20 types of puzzles and games, including cryptograms, anagrams and sliding tiles. But be warned: &quot;Smart Games&quot; doesn't provide any answers or clues to the puzzles you can't solve.</p>
<p>&quot;Star Trek: Klingon&quot; from Simon and Schuster Interactive (Windows, $40) -- Sold as a tutorial on speaking Klingon, the best part of this programme lets players assume the role of Pok, a young Klingon who is about to become a warrior when his father is murdered. The simulation uses real actors and sets from the Star Trek series, and was directed by Jonathan Frakes.</p>
<p>&quot;Duke Nukem 3D&quot; from 3D Realms (DOS, $50) -- It's violent. It's cheesy. It's got mostly naked women in distress. It's got LOTS of weaponry. It has no redeeming social value whatsoever. In short, this tale of heavily armed space aliens taking over Los Angeles will keep shoot-'em-up fans busy forever.</p>
<p>&quot;Zork Nemesis&quot; also from Activision (DOS/Windows95, $50) takes players to five worlds in an attempt to free four great alchemists trapped in perpetual hell. It's beautiful and addictive, with rich, entrancing music. It rates a 2 on the 4-point violence and nudity scales.</p>
<p>FOR ADULTS</p>
<p>&quot;You Don't Know Jack&quot; from Berkeley Systems (Windows/Macintosh, $40) is still one of the best computer games around, as long as you're not offended by its wildly irreverent trivia questions.</p>
<p>&quot;Ripper&quot; from Take 2 (DOS/Windows/Macintosh, $60) -- This futuristic update to the old Jack the Ripper saga definitely makes the cut. It has four different endings, stars Christopher Walken, Burgess Meredith and Karen Allen, and is for ages 17 and older because of the realistic blood and strong language.</p>
<p>EDUCATIONAL</p>
<p>&quot;The Logical Journey of the Zoombinis,&quot; from Broderbund (800-521-6263, Windows/Macintosh, $30) sharpens a child's ability to plan and think logically, and does it in a captivating way using creatures who are essentialy tiny blobs. It's for ages 8 to 12, and Broderbund has also packaged it with other educational products.</p>
<p>&quot;Life's Greatest Mysteries&quot; from A.D.A.M. Software (800-755-2326, Windows/Macintosh, $40) doesn't answer all of your questions, but it will explain what makes you sleepy, what makes a person's hair turn gray, and how memory comes in two varieties. There are 41 questions in all.</p>
<p>&quot;Volcanoes: Life on the Edge&quot; from Corbis (Windows/Macintosh, $50) provides everything you want to know about these fearsome mountains, the people who live in their shadow, and the scientists who study them. Roger Ressmeyer's photographs, taken in 1991 and 1992 on assignment for National Geographic, are spectacular.</p>
<p>&quot;Escher Interactive: Exploring the Art of the Infinite,&quot; from Byron Preiss (800-945-3155, Windows, $40) is a look at the work of Mauritis Corneille Escher, whose interlocking objects, patterns that morph from one figure to another, and his impossible structures provided the world with infinitely interesting art.</p>
<p>&quot;Masterpiece Mansion&quot; from Philips (800-883-3767, Windows/Macintosh, $40) is a CD-ROM game that teaches art appreciation by trapping the player in the hidden rooms of the Fouffenfester mansion, where the only way to escape is by solving art-related puzzles.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
