<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222057" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Traditional phone firms to facedown pretenders.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Traditional phone firms to facedown pretenders.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>Mobile phones, new multimedia markets across the Internet, and the lack of telephones in developing countries will provide a lucrative business in the next decade.</p>
<p>And establised telephone companies are preparing to fend off a tough challenge from upstart competitors.</p>
<p>Billions of dollars are being invested by high technology companies in satellite systems to cream off what they expect to be the hugely profitable new wave of mobile telephone services.</p>
<p>At the same time, traditional telephone companies are busily investing in high-capacity fibre-optic networks to serve whole continents. Some are quietly hedging their bets in both camps.</p>
<p>Huge new markets for data racing across the Internet, coupled with new markets in countries which have few telephones, will revitalise telecommunications markets in the next century.</p>
<p>U.S. high-tech research company Gartner Group says the world's telecommunications market will be worth more than $800 billion in 1996. It calls telecomms one of the few guaranteed long-term growth markets - &quot;for long term, read decades&quot;.</p>
<p>VOICE ALONE NOT ENOUGH</p>
<p>The days of POTs -- Plain Old Telephones -- are numbered. Voice alone is not enough. Telephone companies must be able to offer Internet connections for data transmission and multimedia services like home shopping and banking. Mobile phone services are becoming all pervasive.</p>
<p>Old acronyns like POTs are being replaced by LEOS -- low, earth-orbiting satellites. Over the next five years, up to five new consortia will be blasting satellites into space to provide world-wide telephone services.</p>
<p>But in spite of the flashy, headline-grabbing nature of these new schemes, regenerated POTs providers are likely to plod their way to victory, experts say.</p>
<p>Even the Teledesic partnership, combining the awesome power of AT&amp;T, software giant Microsoft Corp, 840 satellites and $9 billion, will not be enough to seriously dent the long-term dominance of traditional telephone companies.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole data side of the (telephone) business is seen as a huge opportunity. It's not the pipe, but the services around the pipe that are exciting. That will be the true differentiator,&quot; said Rana Mainee, director of consulting services at industry researcher IDC.</p>
<p>Big players are moving to improve capacity. Fibre links across the north Atlantic are established and are still growing. France's Alcatel and AT&amp;T plan to ring Africa with fibre and provide it with modern international links.</p>
<p>Fibre Link Around the Globe, otherwise know as FLAG and led by NYNEX Corp is being installed to improve links between Europe, north Africa, Asia and Japan.</p>
<p>LEOS, CHEAPEST AND QUICKEST WAY TO PENETRATE NEW MARKETS</p>
<p>Some companies reckon that the quickest and cheapest way to penetrate new markets is to launch a network of low-orbiting satellites. This avoids the time-consuming and expensive digging up of streets and building of infrastructure.</p>
<p>The Motorola led Iridium consortium expects to have its network up and running by the third quarter of 1998. Globalstar, founded by Loral Space &amp; Communications Ltd and Qaulcomm Inc, and including France Telecom, Hyundai Group, Alcatel Alsthom and Daimler-Benz Aerospace should start in 1999. ICO Global should be operational by 2000 and Odyssey by 2001, says Ovum consultant Alex Nourouzi.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of these systems will pick different markets. Iridium, for example, will be aiming at the international business traveller. Globalstar will go for providing national services. Others will hone in on countries where they see gaps in the mobile market,&quot; said Nourouzi.</p>
<p>&quot;They are all targetting slightly different needs and applications. But I can't see them all surviving, or even getting off the ground.&quot;</p>
<p>IDC's Mainee shares these doubts.</p>
<p>&quot;These little LEOS (larger LEOS are deeper in space and handle some traditional telephone and TV traffic) are likely to be successful at first with their ability to find niches, but when the big guys come in they are danger of being completely wiped out in the longer term,&quot; Mainee said.</p>
<p>Mainee said the traditional telephone companies will not hesitate to defend their territory.</p>
<p>&quot;They have long-term investments and are not going to let anyone share this revenue stream. Conservative and slow moving? No. Now they are dynamic and can move really quickly.&quot;.</p>
<p>LEOS can provide limited, mobile telephones, but cannot compete with the so-called high-band width services which allow Internet and multimedia services.</p>
<p>The Teledesic plan is aimed straight at this market, but even with the financial muscle on tap, analysts doubt its ability to make much of a mark.</p>
<p>&quot;Teledesic is completely revolutionary. As a concept it is very exciting. It can deliver two megabits or more to hand-held or remote terminals,&quot; said Michael Grant, principle consultant with telecommunications researcher Analysis.</p>
<p>&quot;But it is a major punt, a huge punt. Will the system work technically, will there be enough people to provide them with the market they need to make this system pay?&quot; said Grant.</p>
<p>TRADITIONAL TECHNOLOGY MAY KEEP PACE</p>
<p>Grant also points out that while high-technology projects progress, firms such as British Telecommunications and Deutsche Telekom are working quietly to improve their traditional technology. They are seeking to upgrade their copper networks so that they can deliver advanced digital services.</p>
<p>&quot;That would be a major threat if they could develop the copper wire,&quot; Grant said.</p>
<p>Yankee Group analyst Chris Champion believes it is not only the big telephone companies which can improve technology.</p>
<p>&quot;The same sort of development will happen with the satellite networks -- video, digital services on demand over satellites -- I don't see why this can't be developed as a competitor,&quot; Champion said.</p>
<p>But the consensus is that the traditional providers will win out in the long run.</p>
<p>&quot;The traditional operators like France Telecom and BT have a lot going for them. The risk is low -- look at Teledesic -- the technical risks are huge,&quot; said Grant.</p>
<p>&quot;They have to develop new technology, the frequencies are yet to be commercialised. And they have to launch 800 or so satellites and raise $9 billion. That's a lot of obstacles.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
