<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="22220" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Novell sees aggressive marketing as cure.</title>
<headline>Novell sees aggressive marketing as cure.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novell Inc's newly named president Joseph Marengi said he expects Novell to turn around its current problems through more aggressive marketing.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a very tough time for the last year and a half,&quot; Marengi told reporters on a conference call.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously we've had a lot of people that have been let go from the company. We sold off WordPerfect ... we have a real situation that we need to turn around and it can be turned around very quickly,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Marengi was named president on Wednesday after Chairman Robert Frankenberg resigned in part of a management reshuffle.  </p>
<p>He said a more aggressive approach to marketing was the key to future success. &quot;One of the things Novell has been remiss on in the past is agressiveness,&quot; he said. &quot;We've been relatively passive in the past few years and that's something that we're going to change over the next few months.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that once the new strategies are rolled out &quot;No longer will people be asking, 'Where is Novell?'&quot;</p>
<p>Novell's earnings and market share have dropped amid stiff competition from Microsoft Corp's Windows NT and due to ill-fated moves like its $1.4 billion buyout of WordPerfect Corp which it sold two years later for some $132 million.  </p>
<p>Newly appointed Chairman John Young was also upbeat on the firm's future.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe Novell is absolutely perfectly positioned ... where Novell is today is about the most attractive place in the market you could want to be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Young said a search was in place for a new chief executive oficer and that his role once the new CEO comes onboard was unsure. The company declined to give specific reasons for Frankenberg's departure and noted the changes are not expected to result in any lay-offs.</p>
<p>Shares of Novell were 17/32 at 10-15/32 in afternoon trading on Nasdaq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
