<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223474" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Innogenetics spawns trade on Easdaq.</title>
<headline>Innogenetics spawns trade on Easdaq.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Belgian biotechnology firm Innogenetics blossomed on their first day of trade in Europe's newest growth stocks market with volume exceeding 10 percent of the total stock offered to investors.</p>
<p>Innogenetics was the second issue to trade on the screen-based, pan-European exchange, which came to life only on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The opening stock had been Dr Solomon's Group Plc, a U.K.-based anti-virus software developer, but trade in its shares was relatively modest on their second day.</p>
<p>Innogenetics was the first Belgian stock to trade on the Brussels-based market, modelled on the Nasdaq in New York.</p>
<p>In contrast with other bourses in Europe, Easdaq -- the European Association of Securities Dealers Automated Quotations System -- uses a quote-driven system, common in Anglo-Saxon countries. The other exchanges use an order-driven set-up.</p>
<p>&quot;In a quote- or price-driven system there are always two prices -- a bid and an ask price,&quot; said Bruno Tuybens of stockbrokers KB Securities, one of the sponsors of the Innogenetics issue and a driving force behind Easdaq.</p>
<p>He expected Easdaq's backers and market makers trading in the exchange to have to make a notable effort to explain the Anglo-Saxon system to European investors.</p>
<p>The 'classic' order-driven system, in which a buyer's and a seller's orders are matched provided both are for the same price, knows only one price, he said.</p>
<p>In a quote-driven system a broker or market maker quotes two-way prices for a stock. He will execute a buy order provided it matches the bid price in the market and a sell order if its price is the same as that of the offer price.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, a market maker will adjust his prices in the direction of his order book,&quot; Tuybens said.</p>
<p>While in an order-driven system brokers charge a commission for executing a trade, large orders are net of fees in a quote-driven set-up and brokers earn their money on the spread, or difference, between the bid and the ask price.</p>
<p>As on Nasdaq, stocks on Easdaq are priced in U.S. dollars and quoted in segments of 1/8 of a dollar or multiples thereof.</p>
<p>&quot;Private investors will have to get used to that,&quot; Tuybens said, &quot;but for those who know Nasdaq, Easdaq will present no problem.&quot;</p>
<p>In Innogenetics' case Thursday's action, which involved a mix of private and institutional players, the dollar prices posed no obvious problem -- about 850,000 shares changed hands.</p>
<p>KB Securities estimates around 8,000 private Belgian investors had shares in Innogenetics following its initial public offer of about 7.6 million shares.</p>
<p>Initial trade was brisk with 130,000 shares, or more than $1.5 million worth, traded in the half hour after the market's 9.30 a.m. (0830 GMT) start. After 45 minutes a quarter of a million shares had changed hands.</p>
<p>At 4.30 p.m. Innogenetics closed at $12-7/8, above its $12 issue price.</p>
<p>Thursday's volume in Dr Solomon's was less than a third of the 17,775 total seen on Wednesday. Inauspiciously, the share slipped below its $17 issue price, closing at $16-5/8.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
