<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232545" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-Microsoft says Europe lags on Internet.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Microsoft says Europe lags on Internet.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Software group Microsoft Corp warned European businesses on Tuesday that they lagged behind the United States in tapping the power of the Internet and this could undermine their competitiveness.</p>
<p>&quot;We see a lot of short-sightedness in European businesses in their approach to the Internet,&quot; said Bernard Vergnes, president of Microsoft Europe. &quot;Unless we wake up, we may have a difficult time tomorrow,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Vergnes, a Frenchman who joined Microsoft in 1983 and  runs the group's European activities out of Paris, said a survey by consultants IDG showed that in the United States, about 65 percent of companies with more than 50 employees were using the Internet or planned to do so in the next 12 months.</p>
<p>In Britain, the proportion was 59 percent, in Germany, 45 percent, and in France, 28 percent.</p>
<p>Another series of statistics showed that in the United States, more than 90 percent of white collar workers use personal computers (PCs) while in western Europe the figure is 53 percent and in eastern Europe 35 percent.</p>
<p>More than 30 percent of U.S. homes have PCs, compared with less than 10 percent in Europe.</p>
<p>There are 24 PCs per U.S. school. Sweden does better with 25 per school, but the western European average is nine.</p>
<p>Vergnes said the gap between the United States and Europe helped the United States rise to become the most competitive country in 1995 from fifth place in 1991, according to the World Economic Forum.</p>
<p>Germany slipped from second to 10th while Britain and France ranked 19th and 20th, respectively, last year.</p>
<p>For Microsoft, the gap points to a big potential market. For Europe to match the PC penetration level of the United States, 48 million additional PCs must be sold, Vergnes said.</p>
<p>He said he expected PC shipments in Europe to total between 16.5 and 17 million this year and then rise a further 12 percent in 1997 to about 19 million.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, more than 70 percent of computers are being shipped in Europe with Windows 95 and (the percentage) is growing. But there is not much room to grow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Microsoft has launched a series of products for the Internet and Intranet market, competing head on with Netscape Communications Corp. They include the Explorer, Frontoffice and Internet Studio as well as server packages.</p>
<p>It recently added the Microsoft Commercial Internet System, code-named Normandy, which is being tested at 10 organisations in Europe for on-line commercial transactions.</p>
<p>Microsoft estimated the number of on-line consumers in Europe at 2.8 million in June 1996 and predicts it will grow to 4.2 million by June 1997, with some seven million business users.</p>
<p>A Microsoft official said the Explorer's share of the browser market was now around 25 percent. He did not give a breakdown for market leader Netscape Navigator and others.</p>
<p>Last year, Microsoft overhauled its MSN on-line information service and put it on the Internet instead of marketing it as a proprietary service for subscribers only. The new MSN will be rolled out in English, French and German in 1997 and partnership announcements could be made in the next few weeks, Vergnes said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
