<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="239278" id="root" date="1996-12-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Plugged in - Where are you taking us tomorrow Microsoft?.</title>
<headline>Plugged in - Where are you taking us tomorrow Microsoft?.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-12-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Perhaps it was the black formal gowns or the two transvestite platinum blonds impersonating Marilyn Monroe that greeted guests at the door.</p>
<p>But whatever was in the air last Tuesday night did not seem like a normal kickoff for a computer geek event.</p>
<p>Microsoft Corp was holding another gala event in its month-long, US$100 million re-launch of the MSN network, a television-like entertainment experience that resides on the Net.</p>
<p>The event attracted a glittering crowd from Canada's media and entertainment industries. A spokeswoman for the event said some 300 people attended the party at Toronto's Design Exchange, an art deco redo of an historic building that used to house the Toronto Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>She said Microsoft's Canadian public relations firm turned away 200 others who were late with their RSVPs for the event, which was a pastiche of jazz musicians, old-fashioned show biz and a standard computer demo.</p>
<p>It is doubtful that just a few years ago even the world's most important software company would have attracted such a crowd with nary a propeller beanie or breast pocket protector in sight.</p>
<p>But of course this is the new Microsoft, which after first dismissing it, has discovered the Internet with a vengeance.</p>
<p>MSN, a &quot;premium&quot; Internet service, has 1.8 million subscribers worldwide and reports say the company is looking to double that number within a year.</p>
<p>&quot;We're ahead of plan,&quot; allowed Jordan Chrysafidis, group product manager for MSN Canada. &quot;We're pleased with our growth rate.&quot;</p>
<p>Its content is a rather ingenious blend of entertainment. It has highbrow entries such as &quot;Slate,&quot; edited by Michael Kinsley, brain fluff type categories such as &quot;15 Seconds of Fame&quot; and more practical offerings such as Expedia, where you can make travel arrangments.</p>
<p>Chrysafidis said the content was designed to attract &quot;the second wave&quot; of computer users, the group that follows the early adopters of gee whiz technology. This group is less interested in technology than in being entertained and getting information in an entertaining way.</p>
<p>The evening was hosted by Martin Katz, MSN Canada's new executive producer, who looked every inch a new Internet producer type with his shirt and vest and flowing locks.</p>
<p>Katz made a blanket call to the high-powered audience for proposals to develop content for MSN. One party insider said Katz spent the rest of the evening being inundated with cards and on-the-spot proposals of new shows for the site.</p>
<p>Microsoft hopes that if movies and movie rentals lose their luster, the Web and places such as MSN will start attracting entertainment dollars and become a viable entertainment alternative.</p>
<p>But it is unclear how many people would pay the US$6.95 a month fee for the service (more if you do not have Internet access already) to watch Net-style TV in a lonely corner of their homes or offices.</p>
<p>With the onset of Web-ready television sets, it is easy to imagine this kind of service taking off. No doubt, this is where Microsoft would like to take us tomorrow.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question there is a lot of upside,&quot; said Chrysafidis.</p>
<p>-- To comment on this weekly column, send e-mail to russell.blinch(at)reuters.com (using the &quot;at&quot; key on your keyboard).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
