<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244806" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Softbank to take 35 pct stake in US software firm.</title>
<headline>Softbank to take 35 pct stake in US software firm.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Softbank Corp said on Monday it will take a 35 percent stake in the U.S. software venture TrendMicro for 3.5 billion yen ($30.9 million).</p>
<p>The company said payment to TrendMicro, which develops software to protect against computer viruses, would be made by December 27, 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to expand business, our group will strive to back up TrendMicro's Internet-related business,&quot; Masayoshi Son, SoftBank's president, told a news conference.</p>
<p>Softbank will try to persuade some 50 hardware makers worldwide to use TrendMicro's software in their systems and ask other makers to integrate the software in their memory boards, he said.</p>
<p>Son said his company would continue to actively invest in the Internet-related business but not necessarily with any large-scale purchases.</p>
<p>Softbank plans to use part of the money to be raised through a new share issue to finance its investment in TrendMicro. Softbank is traded in the over-the-counter market in Tokyo.</p>
<p>TrendMicro's parent sales in Japan are seen rising to 1.85 billion yen ($16.3 million) in 1996, up from 627 million yen ($5.54 million) last year.</p>
<p>A Softbank source said that TrendMicro has already moved its headquarters to Tokyo as part of its plan to list its shares on Japan's over-the-counter market as early as 1998.</p>
<p>Softbank has become the world's largest computer-related magazine and book publisher through a string of buyouts.</p>
<p>In the summer, it also launched a joint digital satellite television service, known as J-SkyB, with Australian media tycoon Rupert Murdoch's News Corp.</p>
<p>In June, the two bought 21.4 percent of national television network Asahi National Broadcasting of Japan.</p>
<p>($1=113 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
