<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246817" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Easdaq sees 5 stocks soon, liquidity &quot;no problem&quot;.</title>
<headline>Easdaq sees 5 stocks soon, liquidity &quot;no problem&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's new growth stocks market Easdaq, which went live on November 27 and now lists two stocks, hopes be to quoting five by the year-end, the European Asociation of Securities Dealers (EASD) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Nasdaq-quoted companies are still looking for (Easdaq- registered) market makers, but with five companies up in a month it's still pretty good going,&quot; EASD director Chris Pickles told Reuters, speaking on behalf of Easdaq.</p>
<p>As recently as mid-November Easdaq had forecast up to 15 stocks would be trading by end-December, some of which would simply be dual-listings of stocks quoted on Nasdaq -- a move designed to boost liquidity on the new European exchange.</p>
<p>But many of the latter which showed an interest have found a shortage of European market makers with knowledge of the 80 or so European companies listed on the U.S. growth stocks market.</p>
<p>Pickles said, however, liquidity was not proving a problem in terms of executing trades on Easdaq without causing price instability. It had seen &quot;tens of millions of dollars of trade so far, and hundreds of cross-border trades a day.&quot;</p>
<p>First to kick off on Easdaq was Dr Solomon's Group Plc, a U.K. based anti-virus software developer which launched on New York's Nasdaq the previous day. It was swiftly followed by Belgian biotechnology firm Innogenetics.</p>
<p>After two weeks, though, Dr Solomon's stock was unchanged from its listing price at $17, and Innogenetics stood around $11.75, just beneath its launch price of $12.</p>
<p>Undaunted by this low-key start, Belgian software company Artwork Systems Group NV launches on Wednesday. Its initial public share offer was more than twice oversubscribed and its shares are priced at $10.50 each.</p>
<p>French &quot;smart-card&quot; maker ActivCard SA has its sights on a launch around December 16. Another French firm -- low-cost flat screen technology company PixTech already traded on Nasdaq -- is aiming for around December 23.</p>
<p>Easdaq was still on target to have at least 50 companies listed by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>To be admitted, firms must be supported by at least two Easdaq-registered market makers. They must have total assets of 3.5 million Ecus($4.3 million) and capital and reserves of two million Ecus.</p>
<p>Pickles said more Nasdaq brokers were looking at setting up offices in Europe for the purpose of Easdaq market-making, or at going into joint ventures with European houses.</p>
<p>One such operation set up at the start of the year was Hambrecht &amp; Quist Saint Dominique in Paris -- one of Dr Solomon's Easdaq market-makers -- which is an investment services joint venture between U.S. bank  Hambrecht &amp; Quist and two units of France's  Credit National.</p>
<p>The Easdaq project, modelled on Nasdaq, originated from contacts between the European Venture Capital Association, the European Commission and various market players.</p>
<p>Nasdaq is one of Easdaq's 91 shareholders which brought about 370 million Belgian francs ($11.6 million) together to finance its launch.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
<p>($ = 0.805 European Currency Unit ECUs)</p>
<p>($ = 32.01 Belgian Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302017">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
