<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249691" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Artwork ends first day on Easdaq below list price.</title>
<headline>Artwork ends first day on Easdaq below list price.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Belgian software company Artwork Systems Group NV ended their first day on the new European growth stocks market Easdaq on Wednesday last traded at $9.75, below their listing price of $10.50.</p>
<p>Their price ranged between $11 and $9.375 during the session, with 851,690 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>Artwork's initial public share offer of 4,881,175 was more than two times oversubscribed. It raised about $44.5 million to reach a total market capitalisation of around $178 million.</p>
<p>The company is sponsored by KB Securities, and its market makers are  Aros Securities,  Beeson Gregory in London, France's  Hambrecht &amp; Quist Saint Dominique, Dutch ING Bank, and Belgium's KB-Securities and Puilaetco.</p>
<p>Artwork Systems is the third company to float on Easdaq, which went live on November 27 with the launch of Dr Solomon's Group Plc, followed swiftly by that of Belgian biotechnology firm Innogenetics.</p>
<p>Dr Solomon's ended at $17 on Wednesday in volume of 1,010 shares, matching its issue price. Innogenetics were at $11.625 in volume of over 33,000, below its $12 issue price.</p>
<p>Easdaq traders are linked by a computer system modelled on TRAX, the International Securities Markets Association communications system.</p>
<p>Deals are settled by Switzerland's INTERSETTLE which Easdaq said handled 571 Easdaq transactions during the first four days of trading.</p>
<p>&quot;All transactions which came directly from the EASDAQ trade reporting system settled at a rate of 100 percent,&quot; INTERSETTLE's chief executive officer Wolfgang Michaelis was quoted as saying in a statement from Easdaq.</p>
<p>&quot;The same was true of single-sided trades where one party entered the trade into the Easdaq system and the other instructed INTERSETTLE directly,&quot; Michaelis added. &quot;These first experiences are very encouraging.&quot;</p>
<p>Modelled on the successful U.S. Nasdaq growth stocks market, Easdaq originated from contacts between the European Venture Capital Association, the European Commission and various market players. Nasdaq is one of Easdaq's 91 shareholders.</p>
<p>-- Lorrayne Smith, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6812, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
