<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255002" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Investors bet on Oracle rebound.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Investors bet on Oracle rebound.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite a drop in shares of Oracle Corp, options investors appeared to be betting the stock would recover, traders said Friday.</p>
<p>In late trading, shares of the database software company were down 3-1/4 at 44 on very heavy volume of more than 24.2 million shares. It reached a session low of 42-15/16.</p>
<p>Analysts said the stock was hit after the company said weak European sales in its fiscal second quarter hurt profits and after more evidence showed cheaper software products from rival Microsoft Corp were cutting into its business.  </p>
<p>Late Thursday, Oracle reported fiscal second quarter earnings of $0.27 per share, up from $0.20 a share in the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>Among Oracle options, which trade on the Chicago Board Options Exchange, calls were the first pick of investors, with the January 45 call trading nearly 3,600 contracts, the December 45 call trading nearly 2,200 and the January 50 call trading more than 1,800.</p>
<p>But call buying was also strong in the March 45 and 50 and June 45 and 50 calls.  </p>
<p>The most active put was the December 45, which traded about 1,100 contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Oracle options investors) see a buying opportunity in the upside calls in case this stock runs back up in the next three to six months,&quot; said one trader at the CBOE.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically that's all we've seen today, but there have been premium sellers in the front two months because it's getting up a little high,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said institutions were the main call sellers and retail investors were the major buyers.</p>
<p>Volatilities held up at fairly high levels, he added.  </p>
<p>Volatilities in December and January slipped slightly as Oracle shares attempted to recover from early losses, but in general remained fairly high.</p>
<p>The trader said volatility in the January 45 call was around 47 while December call volatilities were around the 46 region.</p>
<p>In other trading, Intel Corp options remained the busiest on the American Stock Exchange even as the stock finally suffered a pullback after an amazing run.</p>
<p>Intel was off 4-1/4 at 132-5/8 in late trade on heavy volume. A week ago, the stock closed at 125-3/4.  </p>
<p>Also on the American Stock Exchange, several Philip Morris Cos Inc options were active as the shares declined amid profit-taking and talk of a shift in the tobacco industry's approach toward its foes.</p>
<p>Morris shares fell 2-1/4 to 111-1/2 on about 3.25 million shares. They hit a session low of 110-1/4.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Micron Technology had a few active options as investors set positions ahead of the company's fiscal first quarter earnings, scheduled for release December 16, traders said. ((--G.Crawford, 312 408 8750/E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
