<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257339" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Plugged In: Sign on, surf in and try not to drop out.</title>
<headline>Plugged In: Sign on, surf in and try not to drop out.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tune into the Internet next year and you might get a lot of static, bump into some angry surfers and land on &quot;channels&quot; rather than sites.</p>
<p>Making predictions about the Internet is not very smart, with many who previously dared to look into their digital crystal ball ending a little short of the mark.</p>
<p>The more common predictions have evolved around the theme, &quot;The Death of the Internet is Nigh.&quot; Some have projected that the Net was a fad that would go the way of CB radio, while others felt it would become so popular that it would collapse under its own weight.</p>
<p>The end of the Net may well come, but it is unlikely any time soon. Companies are throwing too much money at the new medium to let it fade away quickly.</p>
<p>Netizens will need to decide if it is a good thing, but watch for more sites having the look and feel of that old medium, television, albeit with a few amazing features.</p>
<p>Microsoft Corp.  blazed a new trail this year with the relaunch of MSN and its use of various &quot;channels&quot; to offer a variety of entertainment and functional services.</p>
<p>Watch for Sony Corp. (www.sony.com) to make a splashy announcement in conjunction with Visa for its new site, which has been given an appropriate TV-sounding name: The Sony Station.</p>
<p>A Sony spokeswoman said an announcement on the new site, or station, could come in the next few weeks. It is expected to include the latest technology, such as three-dimensional graphics and jazzy sounds and video.</p>
<p>Developers say Sony is investing heavily in the area to offer television-like entertainment such as soaps, children's shows and music.</p>
<p>With Visa's participation, however, there should be a major difference from TV. When viewers watch the Sony Station, they will likely be able to purchase goods online during a commercial break -- or so Sony and Visa hope.</p>
<p>If Microsoft and Sony are heading this way, then more are sure to follow. But more sites, and more sites bloated with information and other gadgets, add up to more trouble for the already overloaded Web.</p>
<p>A number of communication experts have backed away from dire predictions that the Internet faces outright collapse from this extra traffic.</p>
<p>Instead, they believe that with increased traffic, there will likely be more &quot;brownouts&quot; with periods of extremely slow surfing and more crashes of individual systems, such as the 19-hour failure experienced by users of America Online Inc. this year.</p>
<p>Communication problems will only add to the frustration of being on the Internet. Many Net &quot;newbies&quot; arrive eager, but leave less than fulfilled when they find the medium does not always deliver.</p>
<p>But newbies and old-timers alike must spend an extraordinary amount of money on their computer systems to enjoy all new aspects of the sites and channels on the Internet.</p>
<p>Many might get frustrated when their systems crash or slow down. They also might not be too happy when they are told they need another piece of software because the code they have comes from a competing company.</p>
<p>Louis Gerstner, the plain-talking chief executive of IBM Corp., predicted there would be a backlash if surfers kept coming away angry when reality did not reach the lofty levels of hype on the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;As an industry, we are not shy about telling people how beautiful our babies are, long before they are born,&quot; he said in a recent speech to Internet World in New York.</p>
<p>All told, it should be a fascinating but frustrating new year on the Net. So what else is new?</p>
<p>-- To comment on this weekly column contact: Russell Blinch at russell.blinch(at)reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
