<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261220" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: RTRS-Murdoch launches JSkyB, heralding TV battle.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Murdoch launches JSkyB, heralding TV battle.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Media tycoon Rupert Murdoch's News Corp and Japan's Softbank Corp formally announced on Tuesday they had set up a broadcasting company to offer multichannel satellite television in Japan.</p>
<p>The launch of Japan Sky Broadcasting Co (JSkyB) sets the stage for a battle for viewers between the Murdoch alliance and rivals including a digital satellite broadcaster owned by Hughes Electronics Corp., part of General Motors Corp.</p>
<p>Murdoch and Softbank President Masayoshi Son told a news conference that JSkyB, capitalised at 20 billion yen ($175 million) and officially set up on Monday, will launch a 12-channel service on a trial basis using the JSAT-3 satellite next April. The number of channels will rise to around 150 the following April.</p>
<p>Softbank, a software and publishing firm, has been aggressively expanding into computer-related and media fields, earning Son the nickname &quot;Asia's Bill Gates&quot;.</p>
<p>In a move which could help give JSkyB an edge in the Japanese satellite TV market, the companies also said they would work with a Japanese rival, PerfecTV, to develop a common receiver for both services.</p>
<p>&quot;Such a receiver will allow Japanese viewers to access about 260 channels provided jointly by JSkyB and PerfecTV by April 1998,&quot; Son said.</p>
<p>PerfecTV, which started pay services in October, will provide a 100-channel service by next spring. It is owned by a group of Japanese trading companies.</p>
<p>Another prospective rival is Hughes Corp's DirecTV, which plans a 100-channel service in Japan in the autumn of 1997.</p>
<p>Altogether, around 360 channels will be beamed into Japanese homes in early 1998.</p>
<p>The fresh competition from satellite packages offering a wide range of news and entertainment is also expected to energise Japan's terrestrial commercial broadcasters, who, some analysts say, have grown complacent about the standard fare of variety and gameshows.</p>
<p>Son said JSkyB will combine 50 to 60 major programmes including news, music and entertainment, in a low-cost package, while films and sports will be provided separately.</p>
<p>One big question, however, is whether the operators will be able to get terrestrial broadcasters, which feel under threat from satellite operators, to contribute quality programming.</p>
<p>Asked about the difficulty in acquiring such programmes, Murdoch said: &quot;We have received cooperation from Japanese software houses, production companies and some terrestrials. We don't see any difficulty at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Industry analysts said both News Corp and Hughes have sought the cooperation of Japan's upmarket public broadcaster NHK.</p>
<p>But NHK, which is sticking to its own analogue-based Muse satellite broadcasting technology, is said to have rejected the idea of cooperation with the newcomers.</p>
<p>($1=114 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
