<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261788" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP founder member quits supervisory board.</title>
<headline>SAP founder member quits supervisory board.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of the founders of fast-growing German business software company SAP AG said on Tuesday he was quitting his supervisory board post over differences with the company's chief executive.</p>
<p>Hans-Werner Hector, in a statement released by his lawyers, said the supervisory board was not able sufficiently to oversee the work of the management board, which he said was dominated by chief executive and co-founder Dietmar Hopp.</p>
<p>Hector alsi said his move earlier this year to transfer his SAP stake out of a shareholders agreement with the firm's other founders had resulted in &quot;unfavourable public statements&quot; by Hopp against him.</p>
<p>&quot;I am disappointed, but not surprised, that Mr Hopp has tried to stifle and deflect differing views of company business through personal attacks,&quot; Hector said.</p>
<p>An SAP spokesman had no immediate comment on the statement.</p>
<p>Hector had been responsible for worldwide training of SAP's staff, consultants and clients before he was elected to the supervisory board from July 1995.</p>
<p>But was called on to resign last May by Hopp after he transferred around 10.5 percent of the company's stock into a Channel Islands trust administered by Swiss bank UBS, possibly for sale later to stock-hungry investors.</p>
<p>That was seen at the time as threatening the grip of the four remaining founders of SAP by bringing joint ownership below a 74 percent floor specified in a consortial agreement in which their voting rights were pooled.</p>
<p>Hector's lawyer said he had no information on whether the stock held in the trust had been sold.</p>
<p>SAP shares had been a darling of the stock market, but lost a quarter of their value in a single day in October after the company warned that profits growth would not meet expectations.</p>
<p>The shares have not recovered since, and closed on Tuesday down 7.35 marks at 203.60 marks.</p>
<p>-- Douglas Busvine, Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
