<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264402" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fighting game packs unwanted surprise.</title>
<headline>Fighting game packs unwanted surprise.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>There's a disturbing little feature in &quot;FX Fighter Turbo,&quot; which is billed as &quot;The Ultimate PC Network Fighting Game&quot; by GTE Entertainment (Windows95, $30):</p>
<p>If you don't register the game during the installation process, the &quot;FX Fighter Turbo&quot; registration screen pops up uninvited, no matter what you're doing, 14 days later.</p>
<p>And 14 days after that.</p>
<p>And every 14 days thereafter until you either give up and register, locate and delete the registration programme, or uninstall the entire game.</p>
<p>Apparently this is the latest -- and most intrusive -- strategy to encourage customers to send companies their name, address, phone number and computer specifications.</p>
<p>This isn't encouragement, it's almost coercion, especially when you are told during the registration process that certain information is &quot;mandatory.&quot;</p>
<p>(There is, by the way, no legal requirement to register software, and certainly no law that says you must provide personal information to the manufacturer).</p>
<p>When consumers buy software, they do it with the expectation that the product will stay inactive until they want to activate it, and that it won't inconvenience them with unwanted surprises. Customers are not giving the manufacturer permission to interrupt their work with unsolicited reminders to register.</p>
<p>In the case of &quot;FX Fighter Turbo,&quot; I did not ask to be reminded to register, I did not want to be reminded to register, I certainly didn't appreciate having their registration form pop up from nowhere when I was trying to concentrate on my work, and when I elected to cancel the message I was told &quot;You will be reminded to register in 14 days,&quot; without the option of preventing future appearances of the registration form.</p>
<p>Even after I uninstalled the game, I kept getting an error message every time I turned on the computer telling me it was looking for the reminder file and couldn't find it. I was lucky enough to know how to find the source of that message and delete it. Other computer owners may not be so fortunate.</p>
<p>If the folks at GTE want to have a registration reminder pop up each time a consumer activates their game, that's their right.</p>
<p>But there's a name for a piece of software that performs unauthorised and unwanted activity on a person's computer. It's called a virus.</p>
<p>Consumers should treat &quot;FX Fighter Turbo&quot; and any product with similar behaviour accordingly.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>It's hard to pinpoint what finally convinced me that &quot;The Universe According to Virgil Reality&quot; (7th Level, Windows, $40) is the best general science CD-ROM I've ever seen.</p>
<p>Maybe it was when Dr. Reality, the cartoon host, turned out to be a male Dr. Ruth on speed.</p>
<p>Maybe it was the old movie of obscure inventions demonstrating the &quot;Police hooking car&quot; and the &quot;Overnight dimple machine.&quot;</p>
<p>Maybe it was the tribute to Jules Verne, who envisioned &quot;the ocean liner, the helicopter, the submarine and rockets. However, not even the great thinker Verne could have imagined the Garden Weasel.&quot;</p>
<p>Filled with action and peppered with humour, &quot;Virgil Reality&quot; is a delight.</p>
<p>Pop into his laboratory and players can get a fast-paced primer on a host of science topics, from space and dinosaurs, to time and magnetism.</p>
<p>If you click on the icon of a submarine, you get a two-minute overview of its development, beginning with the first 13-person model built of wood and leather in 1620. Then you can either click on the model of the aircraft carrier (which replaces the submarine icon) to learn about carriers, or you can go to another topic.</p>
<p>The hot air balloon icon takes you to information on balloons, then zeppelins (including a reference to Led Zeppelin), then to the Hindenburg.</p>
<p>Ask about the invention of the wheel (&quot;You can see how important it really is,&quot; says Dr. Reality in his German accent. &quot;It wheely, wheely, wheely is.&quot;) and you'll learn how the wheel was used to make pottery long before it became adapted for transportation. You also get to see Jimmy, the roller skating horse.</p>
<p>My two quibbles are minor. First, it sometimes takes many seconds for the individual sections to load, which is only noticeable because the pace of the rest of &quot;Virgil Reality&quot; is so fast. Second, Virgil doesn't mince words; he uses big ones -- perhaps too big for a game recommended for ages 8 and up.</p>
<p>But with experiments, an in-depth reference guide, great characters, wonderful animation and three catchy songs, &quot;The Universe According to Virgil Reality&quot; is the best thing to happen to science education for quite awhile.</p>
<p>If 7th Level could do a series of sequels, each giving some depth to individual scientific disciplines, perhaps we wouldn't have so many people wondering whether the Earth goes around the sun or vice versa.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
