<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267778" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - Salomon starts four Internet cos.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Salomon starts four Internet cos.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Salomon analyst Mark Usem said he initiated coverage of CompuServe Corp and America Online Inc as buys and Netscape Communications Corp and Netcom On-Line Communications Inc with hold ratings.  </p>
<p>-- In published comments, the analyst set a 12-month price target on America Online of $48.</p>
<p>-- Usem described America Online's management as &quot;visionary,&quot; with a &quot;50 percent&quot; market share that dwarfs its nearest competitor CompuServe at &quot;14 percent,&quot; an apparent reference to AOL's domination of the consumer Internet access market.</p>
<p>-- He said he expected AOL to produce four-year compound annual subscriber growth of 18 percent and revenue growth of 22 percent, resulting in earnings of $2.20 in the year 2000.</p>
<p>-- He set a target of $16 to 17 on CompuServe and earnings estimates of $0.68 a share for 1997 and $1.50 in 1998.  </p>
<p>-- Usem described Netcom as an attractive acquisition candidate as telecom companies face the &quot;make&quot; versus &quot;buy&quot; decision of whether to enter the Internet access business.</p>
<p>-- He projected a merger or joint venture could unlock additional value in Netcom of up to $26 per share, based on a sum-of-the parts valuation and recent industry deals, but said that that value will not be realized without a telcom or joint-venture partner.</p>
<p>-- The Salomon analyst said he belived the shares to be fully valued at $180 per subscriber and saw no near-term catalyst for further stock price appreciation.</p>
<p>-- Usem said he expected Netscape's revenue growth rate to slow during 1997 as Microsoft commoditizes the Internet browser and server software markets. He noted that Netscape's strategy had shifted to selling client/server software.</p>
<p>-- He set a 12-month price target of $45 on Netscape, based on a price earnings ratio of 50 times his 1998 earnings estimate of $0.90 per share. He estimated 1997 earnings of $0.55 per share.</p>
<p>-- By late morning on Thursday, Netscape had gained 2-1/4 to 54-3/4, Netcom added 1 to 15-3/8, AOL rose 3/8 to 36-3/4 and CompuServe was up 1/2 to 10-3/4.</p>
<p>((-- E. Auchard, Wall Street bureau, 212-859-1736))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
