<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267872" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Micro Warehouse sees disappointing Q4 EPS.</title>
<headline>Micro Warehouse sees disappointing Q4 EPS.</headline>
<dateline>NORWALK, Conn. 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Micro Warehouse Inc said it expects fourth quarter profits to fall sharply below analysts' estimates, citing a fall in gross margins and increased competition in the Macintosh business.</p>
<p>First Call puts analysts' consensus estimates for the quarter at $0.34 a share and for the full year at $1.37.  </p>
<p>Micro Warehouse said it expected fourth quarter revenues to be in line with estimates but said profits were likely to be &quot;significantly lower than expected.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Gross margins for the quarter have declined principally as a result of the continuing shift of product mix towards hardware,&quot; the company said.  It also cited tougher competition in the Macintosh business, the personal computers made by Apple Computer Inc, and higher operating costs.  </p>
<p>The higher operating costs are due to expenses stemming from the company's November decision to restate earnings to reflect a charge, which prompted the resignation of its chief financial officer, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1997, Micro Warehouse expects a continued shift in its product mix towards the Wintel platform,&quot; chief executive officer Linwood Lacy Jr, the former head of Ingram Micro Inc, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;We intend to expand our corporate selling activities, which will entail up front costs for additional sales personnel and some new selling vehicles.  We also intend to expand our investment in management information systems, with expenses being incurred before the hoped for benefits are achieved,&quot; Lacy said.</p>
<p>Shares of Micro Warehouse plunged after the news, falling over 30 percent, by 6-1/4 to 13-3/4. The stock was one of the top losers on the Nasdaq on a percentage basis.  </p>
<p>Lacy said Micro Warehouse is examining all of its costs and has begun renegotiating with some outside service suppliers as part of an effort to reduct operating costs as a percent of sales.</p>
<p>The company also said it expects to launch at least one new specialty catalog and expand its sales and customer communications efforts on the Internet in 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORWALK, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
