<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271795" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apple brings back Steve Jobs to get out of mire.</title>
<headline>Apple brings back Steve Jobs to get out of mire.</headline>
<byline>Kourosh Karimkhany</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>When Apple Computer Inc. fired co-founder Steven Jobs in 1985, Apple employees did not know whether to cry or to rejoice.</p>
<p>Through the early 1980s, Jobs had inspired Apple engineers to create a computer called the Macintosh which would change the world. At the same time, though, Jobs and his mercurial temper burned out many of the same engineers who adorded him.</p>
<p>On Friday, more than 11 years after Jobs was ousted in a stunning boardroom coup, Apple took a huge gamble by bringing him back.</p>
<p>His assignment is to help the Cupertinto, California-based computer company revamp the software behind the Macintosh, an effort that had been mired for three years.</p>
<p>The bet is that Jobs is the only person who can inspire Apple's demoralized programmers to create software that would leapfrog Microsoft Corp's competing Windows operating system.</p>
<p>&quot;He will help tremendously,&quot; said Randy Wigginton, a former Apple programmer who worked under Jobs to write the software of the original Mac. &quot;Steve is incredibly bright, talented, amusing.&quot;</p>
<p>On Friday, as word of Apple's decision to rehire Jobs spread, shares of the company rose $1.25 or 5.6 percent, to $23.50.</p>
<p>Job's new company, NeXT Software Inc., which Apple agreed to acquire on Friday for $400 million, offers a computer operating system that has many of the software bells and whistles Apple has been looking for to catch up with rival Microsoft.</p>
<p>Apple had tried to reach a deal with closely held software company Be Inc., founded by another former Apple executive, Jean-Louis Gassee, but the talks broke down and the company turned to Jobs for help.</p>
<p>With NeXT's existing technology, Apple hopes to finish the overhaul of its popular Macintosh operating system -- the type of program that controls the fundamental functions of a computer -- in late 1997.</p>
<p>But the key asset that Apple acquired is Jobs. He will serve part-time as a technology adviser and will report to Apple Chairman Gilbert Amelio.</p>
<p>Several Apple programmers working on the Mac overhaul said they have been frustrated for months with a string of weak managers who could not get the project past a rough sketch even after three years. With Jobs, the programmers said, they hope the project can finally move forward.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody is excited,&quot; said an Apple employee close to the project. &quot;I am very excited.&quot;</p>
<p>The risk of hiring Jobs is his volatility. People who have worked for him said Jobs has a knack for inspiring engineers to think that their work is a life-or-death project, a sentiment Apple now needs. But the same sentiment can burn engineers out.</p>
<p>&quot;In some ways he has mellowed, but he still has an incessant drive for perfection,&quot; said Joanna Hoffman, the Mac's first marketing manager.</p>
<p>Jobs could not be reached on Saturday for comment. On Friday he told reporters he was looking forward to rejoining the company he co-founded nearly 20 years ago out of his parent's garage.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel very lucky to be a part-time Apple employee and work for Gil and advise him on product strategy.&quot;</p>
<p>Jobs also will work with Apple Chief Technical Officer Ellen Hancock, a veteran International Business Machines Corp. software manager who has set specific goals for the operating system team.</p>
<p>Jobs' visionary role and Hancock's strict, no-nonsense management style balance nicely, said Tim Bajarin, analyst at market researcher Creative Strategies Research.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
