<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277601" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CA makes bumpy transition in Europe.</title>
<headline>CA makes bumpy transition in Europe.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Willens</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Weakness in Computer Associates International Inc's European sales is viewed by analysts as a temporary setback while the company moves into the higher-growth client/server business.</p>
<p>Investors reacted with disappointment to the company's warning on Friday that its third-quarter revenue would fall short of expectations. The stock was down 12-1/8 to 49-5/8 in early afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the revenue projection, issued late Thursday, raised concern that perhaps the company's solid growth during the last few years would not continue.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first time they missed a quarter for four or five years,&quot; said Andrew Brosseau, an analyst at Cowen &amp; Co. &quot;The question people are wondering is, what is the long-term growth here?&quot;</p>
<p>He said the softness in Europe market may be an anomaly or it may be a sign of a slowdown in the overall 20 percent growth in revenue that CA investors have come to expect.  </p>
<p>After the company's warning, Charles Phillips, an analyst at Morgan Stanley, downgraded the stock to outperform from a strong buy, though he said he considered the underlying CA franchise to be &quot;intact.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the company simply stubbed its toe in Europe during a transition to a higher-growth business,&quot; Phillips said in a research report.</p>
<p>The company, a leading supplier of corporate software, said it expected total revenue for the quarter ending December 31 to be in the range of $1.0 billion to $1.1 billion, lower than the consensus estimate of $1.2 billion.  </p>
<p>The forecast revenue compares with $1 billion posted in the same period last year.</p>
<p>To be sure, CA said it expected to reach the Wall Street consensus earnings estimate of $0.75 a share in the third quarter. That estimate excludes the previously announced charge of $598 million related to its acquisition of Cheyenne Software Inc.</p>
<p>Gibbs Moody, a UBS Securities analyst, said he was maintaining his buy rating. He said that recommendation had anticipated that the company's transition would lead to slower revenue growth.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are maintaining our buy rating on CA because we believe it should continue to be viewed as a core software holding,&quot; Moody said in a report.</p>
<p>CA's president and chief operating officer, Sanjay Kumar, said he was &quot;disappointed&quot; that European revenues were down but was encouraged by client interest in the company's products.</p>
<p>&quot;This transition has been going much smoother in North America than in the European marketplace,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley's Phillips said the company recently made management changes in Germany and France and replaced the head of its European division in an effort to turn around the business there.</p>
<p>The company announced in October it would increase its focus on its midrange, or client/server, software business and reduce its reliance on mainframe software sales. Client/server refers to the products to manage office computer systems that are based on networks of personal computers.</p>
<p>At the end of the company's second quarter, client/server business amounted to about 31 percent of the overall revenue and was the fastest-growing portion of the business. Mainframe software amounted to about 63 percent of CA's revenue in the September quarter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
