<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277940" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Computer Associates stock drops on forecast.</title>
<headline>Computer Associates stock drops on forecast.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Willens</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computer Associates Inc. stock tumbled Friday after the business software maker, citing weak sales in Europe, predicted lower-than-expected revenues for the current quarter.</p>
<p>Computer Associates stock fell $13.25 to $48.50, a loss of more than 21 percent that was the biggest of the day on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said weak sales in Europe were probably temporary as the company changes over from providing software for networks based on large mainframe computers to those running on personal computers, known as client-server networks.</p>
<p>The Islandia, N.Y.-based company, a leading supplier of business software, said late Thursday it expected revenues for its third quarter ending on Dec. 31 to be $1 billion to $1.1 billion, below analysts' average estimate of $1.2 billion.</p>
<p>Computer Associates also said it expected to reach the average earnings estimate of 75 cents a share for the quarter.</p>
<p>Still, the revenue projection raised concern that perhaps the company's solid growth in recent years would not continue, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first time they missed a quarter for four or five years,&quot; said Andrew Brosseau at Cowen &amp; Co. &quot;People are wondering, 'What is the long-term growth here.'&quot;</p>
<p>He said the softness in Europe may be an anomaly or may be a sign that the 20 percent revenue growth investors have come to expect from Computer Associates was slowing.</p>
<p>The company told analysts Friday that it expected revenues in the fourth quarter to hit $1.2 billion, according to an analyst who participated in a conference call. Computer Associates also said it could achieve earnings of 89 cents a share expected by analysts for the quarter.</p>
<p>Company President Sanjay Kumar said in Thursday's statement that he was disappointed that European revenues were down but was encouraged by general client interest in new products.</p>
<p>The transition to new client-server software would lessen dependence on the slower-growing mainframe software market. &quot;This transition has been going much smoother in North America than in the European marketplace,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Charles Phillips, an analyst at Morgan Stanley, said he downgraded the company to outperform from a strong buy Friday morning but considered its underlying franchise &quot;intact.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the company simply stubbed its toe in Europe during a transition to a higher-growth business,&quot; Phillips said in a research report.</p>
<p>Gibbs Moody at UBS Securities maintained his buy rating although the transition from mainframe to client-server business would temporarily mean slower revenue growth.</p>
<p>&quot;We are maintaining our buy rating on CA because we believe it should continue to be viewed as a core software holding,&quot; Moody said in a report.</p>
<p>Phillips said the company recently made management changes in Germany and France and replaced the head of its European division in an effort to address the problems in Europe.</p>
<p>The company said in October it would increase its focus on its mid-range, or client-server, software business and reduce its reliance on mainframe software sales.</p>
<p>In the company's second quarter ended Sept. 30, client-server software accounted for 31 percent of total revenue of $990 million and was the fastest-growing part of the business. Mainframe software was about 63 percent of the quarter's revenue.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
