<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278155" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Computer Assoc active on selloff.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Computer Assoc active on selloff.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A sharp drop in Computer Associates International Inc shares touched off moderately heavy options trading, traders said Friday.</p>
<p>Traders said that outside of the action in Computer Associates, equity options trading was quiet as the holiday period kept participation low.</p>
<p>By 1240 CST/1840 GMT, Computer Associates shares were down 12 at 49-3/4 on consolidated volume of about 13.1 million shares.</p>
<p>The busiest options were the at-the-money puts and calls, where traders said volume was heavy.  </p>
<p>The January 50 call traded about 2,775 contracts and fell 8-7/8 to 3-1/4. The January 50 put, which rose 2-1/8 to 2-1/4, traded about 1,320.</p>
<p>Among other Computer Associates options, the January 55 call had volume of 2,865 contracts, making it most active in the group.</p>
<p>The January 60 call traded about 870, the April 55 call traded 1,375 and the April 50 put traded more than 560.</p>
<p>Late Thursday, Computer Associates said its fiscal third quarter revenues would be below expectations.  </p>
<p>The stock's rating was lowered Friday morning by Morgan Stanley and Smith Barney.</p>
<p>Trading in Computer Associates was delayed for 45 minutes due to order imbalances, but even so, it was the most heavily traded issue on the New York Stock Exchange by afternoon.</p>
<p>Other than Computer Associates, traders said equity options trade was featureless, with investors still focused on some technology issues.  </p>
<p>&quot;There was a little flurry this morning, mostly in some techs like Motorola, Hewlett-Packard and IBM ,&quot; one broker in Chicago said. &quot;But it pretty much died after about 10:00 (1600 GMT).&quot;</p>
<p>On the American Stock Exchange, Motorola calls continued to see solid order flows even as the stock gave back some of its sharp recent gains</p>
<p>Motorola shares, which had rallied from around 54 about a week ago, were off 1-1/4 at 62-1/8 Friday afternoon.  </p>
<p>But the Motorola January 60, 65 and 70 calls continued to attract investors. The January 60 call traded 1,835 contracts, the January 65 traded about 2,280 and the January 70 call traded roughly 2,020.</p>
<p>The most active put was the April 60, which traded nearly 450 contracts.</p>
<p>((--Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>((E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
