<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278896" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FEATURE - Oracle says goodbye PC, hello network computer.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Oracle says goodbye PC, hello network computer.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Is the world at the brink of a new computing age? Are the days of the personal computer numbered, even before it has invaded every home? Will Bill Gates's dream of a personal computer on every desk never be realised?</p>
<p>According to Lawrence &quot;Larry&quot; Ellison the answer is yes.</p>
<p>Ellison, founder and chairman of Oracle Corp, believes that the future lies in a small, simple and cheap computing box -- the network computer.</p>
<p>It will be as small as a set-top box on a television, simple because it does not have a hard disk or lots of complicated software, and cheap because it will be free for almost everybody.</p>
<p>&quot;A year ago I said it would cost as little as $500. I was wrong,&quot; Ellison told the Oracle Developers Conference in Paris this month.</p>
<p>&quot;The only people who will pay are people who want to plug it into their own network. But I believe that phone companies and Internet access providers will make them available for free in exchange for a monthly subscription fee,&quot; said Ellison.</p>
<p>He anticipates a fee of about $20 a month with unlimited access to the Internet.</p>
<p>BATTLE OF THE TITANS</p>
<p>Ellison, a billionaire yachtsman who dreams of acquiring a MiG29 Russian fighter plane, is the network computer prophet.</p>
<p>He travels the world to extoll the virtues of what he believes will become the mass appliance that will really push the globe into the information age.</p>
<p>Cheap networking, with a set-top box you can plug into your television and which gives you electronic mail, Internet access and some productivity tools such as word processors and spreadsheet, are Ellison's holy grail.</p>
<p>His devil is Bill Gates and the Wintel monopoly of Microsoft software running on Intel powered personal computers.</p>
<p>&quot;Is the Microsoft PC the last computer to have been invented?&quot; asked Ellison.</p>
<p>His theory states that the computer industry has 15-year life cycles of which the mainframe, the personal computer and the network computer are stages, with that of the network computer starting this year.</p>
<p>Like Microsoft, Oracle is a sofware company. Microsoft is the world's biggest and Oracle comes second but has the lead in business applications. Gates's personal wealth is estimated at $18 billion; Ellison's &quot;only&quot; six.</p>
<p>Oracle specialises in applications for running networks and network servers -- the elements that would allow a network computer to operate.</p>
<p>A personal computer has a lot of autonomy with storage capacity and sofware applications. They can be linked to networks but they are generally over-equipped for average use, and rather expensive.</p>
<p>LITTLE BLACK BOX</p>
<p>The network computer is a little black box. Ellison demonstrated a prototype with a 200 Mhz Strongarm chip as well as one with an Intel 166 Mhz chip which should be commercially available shortly.</p>
<p>All the applications and data for the network computer are on the server, accessible over the Net -- Internet or private intranet -- at whatever location.</p>
<p>Ellison demonstrated smartcards with user identification which he expected people to have to tap into public network computers in hotels, airports or other places.</p>
<p>&quot;This year, 50 to 60 million PCs will be sold. With network computers the numbers will be a multiple of that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>During the demonstration, he surfed the Internet, viewed pictures and video images with cinema quality and played music that sounded a good as from a hi-fi system -- all directly from the server, with nothing downloaded onto the computer.</p>
<p>The only hitch is that the network computer, just like a PC, gets slowed down by jams on the Internet.</p>
<p>But to Ellison that is a passing problem. &quot;The telephone companies will take control of the Internet backbone, they will make the necessary investments so that it runs well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The actual machines, or rather family of machines, are not made by Oracle and Ellison has no intention of changing that.</p>
<p>Apple Computer Inc, WebTV and Thomson SA's RCA unit are working on network computers for the home while IBM and Sun are working for the business market.</p>
<p>For the business market, a network computer would need more frills such as a network printer.</p>
<p>POWER TO THE NETWORK</p>
<p>Ellison hopes the network computer will take over from the personal computer, just as personal computers took over from the big central mainframes.</p>
<p>The user remains, however, in charge of the data and applications stored under the user profile on the network.</p>
<p>Microsoft, meanwhile, is developing both a NetPC -- a cheaper terminal-like desktop computer that takes its data and applications from a network -- as well as the Window CE operating system which will support small applications such as personal assistants.</p>
<p>Bernard Vergnes, chairman of Microsoft in Europe, says the big theme for business clients would be the &quot;cost of ownership&quot; instead of just the price of a new computer.</p>
<p>This means that computers should be able to stay around for many years while software too should be easily upgradable.</p>
<p>For Microsoft, the answer is a netPC and Windows NT.</p>
<p>At IBM, where the personal computer was born, executives are embracing the network, but not necessarely the network computer.</p>
<p>Lucio Stanca, chairman of IBM Europe, said that &quot;intelligence&quot; would go to the network.</p>
<p>&quot;First we had big systems with large machines and dumb terminals. Then came the (smaller, smarter) personal computer. Now companies are becoming network centered,&quot; Stanca said, adding big computers are needed to run a network.</p>
<p>Whether Oracle or Microsoft will win the battle for dominance in the home will depend on the market and whether consumers want a cheap machine controlled by an anonymous system, or want to pay more to get computing autonomy.</p>
<p>Whatever the outcome, Ellison, who founded Oracle in 1977, expects the network computer to have a &quot;substantial impact&quot; on sales -- of Oracle network application software -- and results from 1998.</p>
<p>Oracle made a pre-tax profit of $919.5 million in the year to May 1996 on sales of $4.22 billion. &quot;We think that in the year 2000 the NC will outsell the PC,&quot; Ellison said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
