<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283144" id="root" date="1997-01-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Infosys races ahead on software boom.</title>
<headline>India's Infosys races ahead on software boom.</headline>
<byline>Anshuman Daga</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY, India</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Infosys Technologies Ltd. has come a long way from its humble beginnings in 1981 to spearhead the country's software export boom.</p>
<p>Set up by seven software professionals with an equity of 10,000 rupees ($280) in the southern city of Bangalore, India's Silicon Valley, the firm now ranks among the top software firms in the nation and boasts a client base of over 60 Fortune 500 companies.</p>
<p>These include Nestle SA, AT&amp;T Corp., Reebok International Ltd., Xerox Corp., Apple Computer Inc., J.P. Morgan &amp; Co. Inc., Nynex Corp. and Visa International.</p>
<p>A highly rated management, extensive human resources development, constant innovation and a network of global offices have put Infosys in the driving seat of India's software boom, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Infosys is our best bet in the sector because of its excellent management, accounting standards and a strong growth story,&quot; said analyst Niraj Somaiya at brokerage H.G. Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;The promoters' rich experience, Infosys's brand image and ability to adapt quickly to changing industry trends are the major plus points of the company,&quot; he said in an interview.</p>
<p>The firm's major markets are the United States, Canada, Europe, Japan, the Far East and India. Infosys derives 72 percent of its revenue from exports to the United States.</p>
<p>Infosys plans to boost revenues by increasing product sales and establishing centres in different parts of the world.</p>
<p>The company expects 1996/97 (April-March) revenues to jump 48 percent to 1.3 billion rupees ($36.3 million) this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We will establish more development centres in low-cost economies and sell more in premium markets and also move away from cost-based selling,&quot; N R Narayana Murthy, Infosys's chairman and managing director, said in an interview from Bangalore.</p>
<p>The company's main activities are the execution of fixed-price, turnkey software projects, maintenance and offshore development.</p>
<p>&quot;We will produce wherever it is cost-effective and sell where we'll derive maximum profits,&quot; Murthy said.</p>
<p>The company expects to operate two more sales offices in 1996/97 in the United States, in addition to its five existing offices there. It also plans to set up two offices for the first time in the Far East and add one more to its single operation in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;We are also focusing on products and productized services in niche areas to leverage our turnover to nearly 40 percent (from the current 19 percent) by the year 2000,&quot; Murthy said.</p>
<p>Software services make up about 75 percent of the firm's revenues currently, while online products developed for niche markets bring in about 19 percent.</p>
<p>At home, revenues from one such niche service, Banc 2000 -- a system for automation of banking operations -- jumped over 100 percent in 1995/96.</p>
<p>The online system has been installed in 13 banks with over 170 installations, analysts said. A first installation in Kenya has also opened up the export market for the product.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel that the company is making serious attempts to be a more product (-oriented) company,&quot; H.G. Asia's Somaiya said in a report.</p>
<p>India has been a favourite destination for global software companies willing to open shop because of cheap, skilled labour.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry is still in a nascent stage, but many top Indian software firms have reached a certain market maturity and are moving toward products from services,&quot; Murthy said.</p>
<p>The National Association of Software and Service Companies (NASSCOM) said India's software exports surged 61 percent to 18.7 billion rupees ($521 million) in the six months ended Sept. 30, 1996.</p>
<p>NASSCOM estimates Indian software revenue rose 62 percent to 30.9 billion rupees ($861 million) in the six months ended Sept. 30.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
