<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283231" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spyglass falls on earnings warning.</title>
<headline>Spyglass falls on earnings warning.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spyglass Inc. stock fell 10 percent Thursday after the Internet software company said it would report a fiscal first-quarter loss at least 10 times worse than analysts had expected.</p>
<p>Analysts blamed a software licensing agreement with giant Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>Spyglass slipped $1.25 to $11.25 on the Nasdaq market after saying it would report a loss of between 10 cents and 13 cents a share on revenues of $4 million.</p>
<p>Wall Street had been expecting a loss of just 1 cent per share on far greater revenues, according to First Call, which tracks analysts' estimates. In last year's fiscal first quarter, the Naperville, Ill.-based company reported a profit of $722,000, or 6 cents a share.</p>
<p>Spyglass said it did not expect revenues from Microsoft of more than $400,000 for the quarter, the minimum payment for the Internet software deal. The company's filtering software blocks access to objectionable material on the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;I was a little bit surprised -- not that they had a shortfall, because they are clearly going through a transition, but that the shortfall came from Microsoft,&quot; said Mark D'Annolfo, an analyst with Adams, Harkness &amp; Hill.</p>
<p>Spyglass recently entered the deal with Microsoft under which the software giant would use Spyglass SurfWatch software on its Microsoft Internet Explorer Web browser and therefore pay royalties.</p>
<p>Analysts said they had expected total fiscal first-quarter revenues of about $6 million to $6.7 million, and, of that, at least $1 million to $2 million was to come from Microsoft.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a $2 million shortfall ... by my model, $1 (million) to $1.5 million (of the shortfall in the quarter) is due to Microsoft,&quot; said Abhishek Gami, an analyst with brokerage Nesbitt Burns Securities Inc. &quot;Spyglass has not cut back on their spending, so it all hits their bottom line.&quot;</p>
<p>Spyglass also said in a news release it planned to exercise its contractual right to audit Microsoft's records.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a disagreement on what is owed to us, and that's why we're doing the audit,&quot; said Spyglass spokesman Randy Pitzer. He declined to comment further because the company is still in talks with Microsoft.</p>
<p>A Microsoft spokesman said it was ahead of schedule on royalty payments to Spyglass, but hoped to resolve the dispute amicably.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the review will show that we are actually ahead of our payments to Spyglass because we have prepaid several million dollars of royalties,&quot; Microsoft spokesman Mark Murray said.</p>
<p>Murray declined to comment on the specific provisons of the royalty agreement, saying details were confidential.</p>
<p>According to a source familiar with the agreement between the companies, the royalties apply only to versions of Microsoft's Internet Explorer for Windows 3.X and MacIntosh systems. Those systems account for a smaller part of Microsoft's Internet browser market. The royalty agreement does not apply to the successful Windows 95 browser versions, the source said.</p>
<p>Spyglass said the arrangement was a combination of fixed fees and royalties, but declined to provide the breakdown for various computer system products.</p>
<p>Nesbitt Burns' Gami said that, based on his reading of the contract between Spyglass and Microsoft, royalties apply to Windows 95 as well as other systems.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that's where the misunderstanding is,&quot; Gami said.</p>
<p>Microsoft's total share of the Internet browser market has been estimated as high as 25 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
