<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28711" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Online ads soar in quarter, survey reports.</title>
<headline>Online ads soar in quarter, survey reports.</headline>
<byline>Dick Satran</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>World Wide Web advertising revenue soared 83 percent in the first half of the year, and the Internet is on track to become a $5 billion-a-year commercial medium by the year 2000, research firm Jupiter Communications said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Ad spending totaled $71.7 million in the first half of the year, and it will balloon to $312 million for the year as a whole, Jupiter estimated, forecasting near-triple-digit annual growth for 1996.</p>
<p>But the survey showed that despite the optimistic growth in spending, a majority of advertisers were still high-tech companies advertising on each other's sites.</p>
<p>The consumer product companies that are the biggest advertisers for national magazines and broadcasters continued to tread cautiously on the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;When those companies get going, that will be the trumpet call that Internet advertising has really arrived,&quot; said Peter Storck, senior analyst for Jupiter. &quot;But that's only going to happen gradually.&quot;</p>
<p>The biggest advertiser on the Web right now is deep-pocketed Microsoft -- which shifted its corporate strategy heavily toward the Internet this year. It forked out $2.9 million in the first half as it promoted its Web browser, the software it hopes will become the standard for navigating throught the new medium.</p>
<p>Its archrival Netscape, whose browser software was virtually unchallenged before Microsoft's arrival, remained king of the hill in getting advertising revenue.</p>
<p>Its $9.7 million accounted for about 13 percent of the total, while search engines Infoseek ($5.8 million), Yahoo ($5.7 million), Lycos ($4.1 million) and Excite ($3.6 million) rounded out the top five.</p>
<p>The search engines, which flash advertising banners to users seeking information on the Internet, have dominated the medium since the beginning.</p>
<p>Traditional publishers -- those that create and sell content -- have been slower to find a place in the new order.</p>
<p>ESPN Sports Zone, a sports information service related to cable giant ESPN, and ZD Net, created from Ziff Davis's computer magazines, were the only traditional media to crack Jupiter's advertising top 10.</p>
<p>Publishers like Time Warner Pathfinder and the New York Times which have created Web products were lower on the list.</p>
<p>Jupiter expects the 80 percent plus growth to continue in the second half of the year, and, Storck said, consumer product companies could begin to take up a larger share of the advertising total from the high-tech companies.</p>
<p>The Jupiter survey, called Adspend, uses published rates and calculates the activity at each of the 100 sites it follows. The survey has been criticized by some, who say it fails to take into account the bartering and rate-cutting that are prevalent in the business, especially for Web-related advertising.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now you could say that the Internet companies are just taking money out of each other's pockets,&quot; said Storck. &quot;But as the pie grows you'll the Web-related companies taking a smaller share of the total.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I4752105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
