<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292901" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Zenith Internet product plans lift stock.</title>
<headline>Zenith Internet product plans lift stock.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zenith Electronics Corp's plans to introduce Internet television products through two new alliances gave its stock a boost Wednesday, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's favorable news ... and fits in with Zenith's production of settop (decoder) boxes,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Ahead of the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas, Zenith said it is teaming up with Network Computer Inc, a unit of Oracle Corp, and with Navio Communications Inc, an affiliate of Netscape Communications Corp.</p>
<p>Zenith, which makes television and video products, was trading at 11-7/8, up 3/4.  </p>
<p>George Podrasky of Duff and Phelps Credit Rating Co said while the new NetVision products, to be introduced later in 1997, are &quot;potentially positive, it remains to be seen what the consumer really wants.&quot;</p>
<p>Analyst Robert Gutenstein of Kalb, Voohris agrees.  &quot;If the consumer should choose to put Internet on his TV, Zenith will be in a good position.&quot;  He noted that competing consumer electronics companies have moved in a similar direction.</p>
<p>Gutenstein added that the latest alliances appear to be a replacement for Zenith's original plan announced last spring to produce an Internet-linked television product with Diba Inc of Menlo Park, Calif.  &quot;That has yet to be delivered,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((Thomas Witom - Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
