<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294679" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-Dassault, Aerospatiale merger seen by spring.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Dassault, Aerospatiale merger seen by spring.</headline>
<byline>Emmanuel Jarry</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's state-owned Aerospatiale and combat plane maker Dassault Aviation will merge this spring with privatisation of the new company to follow promptly, a defence ministry official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If we put everything together...at the end of the spring, the merger will be entirely complete,&quot; the offical said.</p>
<p>&quot;As for the privatisation of the new group, the government wants it to be done in the immediate aftermath and will ask the two company chairmen to think about it now and make proposals.&quot;</p>
<p>The finance ministry said on Tuesday that Aerospatiale and Dassault would be merged to form a company with a single supervisory board and one set of executive directors.</p>
<p>It called the merger the first stage of the privatisation of the new group but did not give a timetable for the operation.</p>
<p>The government said it would ask France's independent privatisation commission to fix the two firms' values and give its opinion on the merger terms.</p>
<p>Once the commission has given its views, the government will formally approve the final transaction terms, which will be carried out with approval of stock market authorities.</p>
<p>The government's decision to wait for commission approval before setting final terms of its plans is a sign the government is treading carefully in the Aerospatiale/Dassault matter and a recognition that it cannot afford another misstep after its bungling of the sale of Thomson SA last year.</p>
<p>The government abandoned its plan to sell Thomson to conglomerate Lagardere after the privatisation commission objected to the onward sale of the Thomson Multimedia unit to South Korean firm Daewoo Electronics.</p>
<p>The decision to freeze the sell-off, seen as inept at best and racist at worst, sparked an official protest from the South Korean government and scorn in financial and political circles.</p>
<p>The group formed from the merger of Dassault and Aerospatiale will pool much of their research and purchasing activities and create centralised departments to oversee finance, industrial strategy, quality, human resources, communications and legal affairs, the finance ministry said.</p>
<p>The group's industrial operations will be centred on units handling combat and business jets, passenger aircraft, space and defence, helicopters and maintenance, it said.</p>
<p>The official at the defence ministry said Dassault Systemes, which specialises in computer-assisted design manufacture (Cad/Cam) programmes, would not be part of the merged group.</p>
<p>Dassault Systemes &quot;is not intended to remain part of the merged group because of the nature of its business and its clients&quot;, the source said.</p>
<p>The official said a name for the merged company had not yet been chosen.</p>
<p>President Jacques Chirac announced the plan to create a single French aircraft manufacturer out of Aerospatiale and Dassault last February as part of a restructuring of France's defence industry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
