<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="296425" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Consumer electronics sales to grow 6 percent in '97.</title>
<headline>Consumer electronics sales to grow 6 percent in '97.</headline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. sales of consumer electronics equipment, including television sets, videocassette recorders and stereos, should reach $69.5 billion in 1997, a 6 percent increase over 1996's $65.7 billion, an industry trade group said Thursday.</p>
<p>The Consumer Electronics Manufacturing Association made the forecast at the opening of its giant Winter Consumer Electronics Show here. The show will highlight a host of new digital products like cameras, cellular phones and highly anticipated digital versatile disc players.</p>
<p>&quot;1997 will be a solid year for the consumer electronics industry,&quot; Gary Shapiro, president of the trade group, said in a statement. &quot;(It) will set the stage for two or more years of exceptional growth as more and more digital products enter the marketplace.&quot;</p>
<p>Shapiro said the combination of new products and falling prices for existing products like television sets should help boost sales in the year ahead.</p>
<p>The trade group said a total of 27.6 million television sets will be purchased in the United States in 1997, even though over 98 percent of U.S. households already own a set.</p>
<p>New digital products will be the focus of many of the trade show's participants as electronics giants like Philips Electronics NV and Sony Corp. introduce new digital versatile disc, or DVD, players.</p>
<p>DVD plays movies much like a VCR. But the technology is similar to an audio compact disc in size and shape, holds movies in several different languages, plays on TVs or computers and puts video in a digital format.</p>
<p>Though copyright issues pushed the introduction of DVD players into 1997 from a planned launch last fall, industry professionals believe those issues will be settled very soon.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Time Warner Inc.'s Warner Home Video unit said it would release 25 movies in DVD format this spring.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, Warner Home Video President Warren Lieberfarb said the company's intent is to take a leading role as movie studios enter this market.</p>
<p>He said Warner's new DVD titles would be released at the same time as they are on video cassette and would be comparably priced. Movies set for release in March or April of this year include &quot;Batman&quot;, &quot;Space Jam&quot; and a director's cut version of &quot;A Streetcar Named Desire&quot;.</p>
<p>In addition to DVD, many providers of satellite television prgramming, such as Hughes Electronics unit DirectTV, will be launching new products to deliver Internet service to subscriber homes.</p>
<p>Oracle Corp. will be showing off the newest version of its network computer, a low cost computer designed to connect users to the Internet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
