<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299435" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CIDCO, InfoGear plan Web access telephone.</title>
<headline>CIDCO, InfoGear plan Web access telephone.</headline>
<byline>Barbara Grady</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO, Calif. 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Responding to demand for easy Internet access, CIDCO Inc and Silicon Valley start-up InfoGear Technology Corp said they will unveil a telephone that doubles as an Internet surfer.</p>
<p>InfoGear Technology Corp said its &quot;iphone&quot; can be used to send and receive e-mail, visit the World Wide Web and perform some Web transactions, as well as act like a telephone.  </p>
<p>&quot;This product is not designed to replace the PC but to get on and off the Web quickly and allow consumers cheap, easy access,&quot; Robert Marshall, president of InfoGear said in an interview a day before the unveiling today in Las Vegas.</p>
<p>&quot;You can use it to order flowers, make travel arrangements, check stock quotes -- you know, on the way out the door you want to do something but don't want to spend three minutes booting up the PC,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>But the iphone will face lots of competition by the time it goes into the retail market in volume, which the companies expect by June.  The notion of supplying easy Internet access with simple appliances and telephones has become a calling among electronics manufacturers.</p>
<p>Since Oracle Corp released its &quot;network computer&quot; technology, several companies have said they are developing Internet telephones using that technology.  </p>
<p>The CIDCO-InfoGear team will also announce that several companies have decided to make products to work with the iphone, including VeriFone Inc, which is making a card-swipe secure payment system to attach to the iphone, and BigBook Inc, which will adapt a version of its Online yellow pages software for the iphone.</p>
<p>The iphone technology was developed by InfoGear, based on work started at National Semiconductor Corp, Marshall said, and uses a National chipset.  CIDCO developed the telephone hardware to package the iphone technology.  </p>
<p>CIDCO said in a press release that the iphone will be &quot;the first telephone to provide graphical, touchsceen Web access, e- mail and Internet directory services within a telephone.&quot; CIDCO manufactures telephone technologies such as smart phones and Caller ID systems.</p>
<p>Marshall said he expects the iphone will be priced at retail at about $500.   Initially, however, the CIDCO-InfoGear</p>
<p>team will market it to telephone carriers for the carriers to sell to their subscribers.</p>
<p>Sprint Corp will soon start a pilot program selling the iphone in a package with its Internet service. Medical Telecommunications Associates Inc has agreed to market iphones to its medical information consumers, InfoGear said.  </p>
<p>Acknowledging there are other Internet phones in the market or in development, Marshall said &quot;we have several differentiating features,&quot; chiefly that its iphone can display graphics and thus pages from the World Wide Web, the graphical portion of the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the Internet phone screens are text only - none of them can access the Web,&quot; Marshall said.  The iphone's screen is 7.4 inches diagonally and uses the the so-called VGA graphics standard.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
