<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299739" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Computervision sees 1996 EPS $0.62.</title>
<headline>Computervision sees 1996 EPS $0.62.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computervision Corp should post earnings of $0.62 per share for fiscal 1996 excluding charges, company officials said Friday.</p>
<p>Charges for the year will about $0.22 per share related to the acquisition of British technology company 3rd Angle Ltd, the company said.</p>
<p>Wall Street has been expecting full-year earnings of $0.71 per share, according to a consensus estimate by First Call.</p>
<p>Earlier Friday the company said it was expecting a fourth quarter net loss of $0.09 per share, compared to Wall Street earnings expectations of $0.23 per share.  </p>
<p>In a conference call afterwards, Chief Financial Officer Bill Foniri said Computervision should begin to see $20 million in annualized savings in the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>The savings will come from benefits achieved from the 3rd Angle acquisition and the sale of the company's Open Services Solutions business, Foniri said.</p>
<p>Foniri attributed the company's lower-than-expected 1996 results to a shortfall in revenues and profits from OSS, which amounted to about $0.12 per share in the third and fourth quarters.  </p>
<p>The results were also due to weakness in the company's software business in Asia/Pacific and Latin America, said Kathryn Cadigan, director of investor relations.</p>
<p>Foniri said with the sale of OSS and other changes, the company should ramp up into operating margins of close to 25 pct in the second half of 1997. The company's current operating margins are about 17 to 19 percent excluding OSS,  Foniri said.</p>
<p>Company officials also reiterated their intention to focus on Computervision's Electronic Product Definition business.  </p>
<p>They said their EPD business should grow in the double digits in 1997. &quot;It will be the solid core of our growth and the solid core of our focus,&quot; Cadigan said.</p>
<p>Computervision shares fell 1-5/8 in Friday morning trading to 7-1/8.</p>
<p>(Carol Huang, New York newsdesk, 212-859-1700)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
