<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300061" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Consumer electronics companies go digital.</title>
<headline>Consumer electronics companies go digital.</headline>
<byline>Bob Tourtellotte</byline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS</dateline>
<text>
<p>With interest in television sets and other electronic products waning, the giants of the consumer electronics industry are looking to the Internet and new digital technologies to boost sales in the years ahead.</p>
<p>The biggest push by companies at the Winter Consumer Electronics Show here is putting the Internet on TV sets.</p>
<p>In 1997's second quarter Thomson SA, maker of RCA brand TVs, will begin selling a TV set-top device to access the Net for around $300. Zenith Electronics Corp also plans a 1997 launch of a so-called &quot;Net on a Set&quot; set-top box.</p>
<p>Overseas manufacturers like Hitachi Ltd, Mitsubishi Electric Corp. and Sanyo Electric Co Ltd are planning their own products for the category. Satellite TV providers like DirectTV, in conjunction with Microsoft Corp, and EchoStar Communications Corp plan to give subscribers access to the Net by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Microsoft itself announced plans to adapt its Windows operating system for a new class of devices that are both computers and televisions, which it said would appear on store shelves in time for Christmas.</p>
<p>&quot;1996 was a rough year and I'm glad to see it gone,&quot; Jim Meyer, executive vice president at Thomson unit Thomson Consumer Electronics said at a press conference here.&quot;</p>
<p>He said sales of core television products fell five percent while the audio market saw sales drop 10 percent.</p>
<p>Overall 1996 sales of consumer electronics products, including phones, cameras and video equipment, rose only $2.6 billion to $65.7 billion, or about four percent over 1995's $63.1 billion, according to the Consumer Electronics Manufacturing Assocation (CEMA), an industry group.</p>
<p>That figure compares to a $3.9 billion sales increase from 1994 to 1995 and a $5.7 billion rise the year before.</p>
<p>Why should the electronics companies be enthusiastic about the future?</p>
<p>&quot;You can sum it up in one word,&quot; Gary Shapiro, CEMA president told Reuters, &quot;and that is 'digital'.&quot;</p>
<p>To meet what is believed to be a pent-up demand for digital products, television makers are scrambling to push out the new Internet TV devices.</p>
<p>Though a report from market researcher Dataquest Inc has questioned the viability of such products, WebTV, maker of one of three devices now on the market, said sales are good.</p>
<p>&quot;Audio compact disc (introduced in the mid-1970's) sold only 35,000 units in its first year, and we've blasted through that number in our first couple of months,&quot; Chief Executive Officer Steve Perlman told Reuters. WebTV was launched in October 1996 and backed by a multi-million marketing blitz.</p>
<p>Philips Electronics NV, one maker of WebTV set-top boxes, released a survey of all people who purchased the product. It showed 60 percent of them had not surfed the Net previously -- which exactly fits WebTV's target market. Also, 90 percent said they would recommend the device to others.</p>
<p>Robert Minkhorst, chief executive officer of unit Philips Consumer Electronics, called holiday sales &quot;very successful.&quot;</p>
<p>Other companies are launching products that give telepones Internet access and provide for videoconferencing via standard TV sets and the Net.</p>
<p>Beyond Internet-based consumer products, several industry giants will launch the long-anticipated digital versatile disc (DVD) players beginning in the second quarter of 1997. Philips will launch its DVD player in that time frame at about $600.</p>
<p>Like VCRs, DVD will play back movies. But one 5-1/2 inch disc can store movies in several different languages and formats for standard or wide-screen TVs. Also, the disc can be played on a player designed for TV sets as well as computers.</p>
<p>Several Hollywood studios such as Time Warner Inc.'s, Warner Bros., and Sony Corp.'s Columbia, will have DVD movies available at the launch.</p>
<p>Finally, the electronics manufacturers are looking to new digital HDTV television sets and flat panel television displays to increase consumer interest in 1998 and beyond.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
