<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="307710" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sun Q2 gross margin reaches 50.4 pct.</title>
<headline>Sun Q2 gross margin reaches 50.4 pct.</headline>
<dateline>MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif. 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sun Microsystems Inc on Wednesday said its gross margin rose to 50.4 percent in its second fiscal quarter ended December 29, up more than five percentage points from the comparable period the previous year.</p>
<p>Sun Microsystems Chief Executive Scott McNealy said the company next week would launch new high-end computer systems and storage products.</p>
<p>He said in a conference call with analysts it was difficult to say whether the strong gross margin was sustainable.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know,&quot; he said. &quot;We don't really manage for gross margin.&quot;  </p>
<p>McNealy later told Reuters in an interview that Sun has targeted its management incentives at revenue growth and earnings per share contribution, rather than gross margin. Still, the company's gross margin in the most recent quarter was the highest in at least a decade.</p>
<p>&quot;We do have some very strong incentives for revenue growth at the top line. We don't have any incentives for management compensation on gross margins,&quot; he said after the analyst call.</p>
<p>Sun's order backlog rose to $470 million from $407 million in its first quarter, but it was still much less than the $522 million backlog at the end of its 1996 fiscal year last June.  </p>
<p>Chief Financial Officer Mike Lehman told analysts that the company was experiencing strong growth in its entire line of servers, including the high-end Enterprise 6000s.</p>
<p>&quot;As in the past, we continue to monitor carefully the balance between short-term profits and long-term opportunities,&quot; Lehman said.</p>
<p>He also said Sun expected to have a more active product introduction cycle in the second half of the year than in the first six months.  </p>
<p>McNealy said the company planned to reveal plans for new high-end computers, codenamed Starfire, as part of an announcement next week highlighting the company's new data-storage systems.</p>
<p>Based on initial market data, the company appeared to be taking market share from its traditional rivals, he said, adding that Sun would continue making deep price cuts.</p>
<p>Lehman said its workforce rose by 1,100 in the quarter. More than half of the additional employees were in areas designed to create new business.  </p>
<p>Sun said its revenue in the first six months of fiscal 1997 rose 22 percent to $3.94 billion, despite some aggressive price cutting of up to 38 percent on some of models.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first half our revenue has grown quite nicely,&quot; McNealy said. &quot;We wouldn't mind seeing it grow higher.&quot;</p>
<p>The executives said the company was deriving increasing revenue from storage products, professional services and licensing of products based on its Java technology.  </p>
<p>McNealy also outlined how the company was positioning itself to face what he refered to as &quot;the Wintel juggernaut&quot; of powerful machines based on Intel Corp's microprocessors and Microsoft Corp's Windows and Windows NT systems.</p>
<p>The Sun chief executive said the company was working to build its strategy for users of both desktop computers and the powerful server machines used for intensive calculations such as databases and network management.  </p>
<p>Analysts said they were impressed by Sun's second-quarter performance. Many of them expect to boost earnings per share estimates for fiscal 1997 some $0.20 a share, though some still expressed reservations about Sun's longer-term strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's only a matter of time before the Wintel guys get him,&quot; one analyst said. &quot;He's got two or three years.&quot;</p>
<p>((--sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau +1 415 846 5400))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
