<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="307860" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clarify falls, drags down help-desk stocks.</title>
<headline>Clarify falls, drags down help-desk stocks.</headline>
<dateline>SAN JOSE, Calif. 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clarify Inc's share price plunged as much as 24 percent Wednesday after the help-desk software company reported earnings that disappointed some investors.</p>
<p>The news on Clarify also dragged down the stocks of other help-desk software companies.</p>
<p>Shares of Clarify, a San Jose, Calif., company, were off 9-1/4 to 36-3/4 in midafternoon Nasdaq trade. Earlier, the shares traded as low as 35.  </p>
<p>Clarify, which writes computer programs to let customer service departments keep track of telephone calls, reported Tuesday that its accounts receivable surged in the 1996 fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Some investors use rising receivables -- the amount of money owed by customers -- as an indicator of slowing business ahead.</p>
<p>The stocks of other help-desk software companies, a fast-growing but volatile group, declined in sympathy with Clarify.  </p>
<p>Closely watched Remedy Corp fell 4-7/8, or 9.6 percent, to 46. Vantive Corp slipped 3-5/8, or 12 percent, to 26. And Scopus Technology Inc slid 4-3/4, or 13 percent, to 32-1/4.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole group has been high flying,&quot; said Ed Bierdeman, analyst at Dakin Securities in San Francisco. &quot;When one breaks, people get real nervous about the other ones.&quot;</p>
<p>Charles Phillips, analyst at Morgan Stanley in New York, said, &quot;People's expectations are so high that any glitch brings the whole stock sector down. Their expectations get out of whack with reality.&quot;  </p>
<p>Expectations have been running high because the major help-desk software companies have reported a doubling of revenues, quarter after quarter, during the past year.</p>
<p>Clarify said its fourth-quarter earnings jumped almost five-fold to $2.89 million, or $0.13 a share, from $614,000, or $0.03 a share, a year earlier. Revenues more than doubled, to $19.2 million from $8.2 million.</p>
<p>However, the company also revealed that accounts receivable doubled to $18 million in the quarter.  </p>
<p>And analysts said fourth-quarter earnings would have been lower than the third quarter's had the company calculated its results with a higher tax rate.</p>
<p>&quot;The reported numbers look good, but they are not fully taxed,&quot; said Bierdeman.</p>
<p>In its earnings report, Clarify said its effective tax rate should rise to 37 percent in the first quarter from 20 percent in the fourth quarter because it had used up its federal and state operating loss carryforwards.</p>
<p>The loss carryforwards were used to reduce its 1996 taxes.</p>
<p>Clarify officials could not be reached for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN JOSE, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
