<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315755" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Malaysia wins support for multimedia zone.</title>
<headline>Malaysia wins support for multimedia zone.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, California 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad on Thursday met top high technology executives and received some initial commitments for his new Multimedia Super Corridor (MSC) zone.</p>
<p>Mahathir told a news conference at Stanford University he was encouraged by early support from the executives, several of whom voiced enthusiasm for the massive undertaking.</p>
<p>&quot;There's tremendous demand for Asia-sensitive new media content and the Multimedia Corridor promises to be a hub where a great amount of Asia-sensitive new media content will be developed,&quot; said Robert Bishop, chairman of Silicon Graphics Inc's Silicon Graphics World Trade.</p>
<p>&quot;No country has brought everything together as much as Malaysia has done,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The corridor, a nine-by-30 mile (15-by-50 km) zone extending south from Kuala Lumpur, is being designated as a location where Malaysia will provide a telecommunications and logistics infrastructure and new multimedia-friendly laws to promote development.</p>
<p>By adding incentives, such as tax-free operation for up to 10 years, the country hopes to spawn a new high-tech centre which, by the year 2000, will provide leading applications like telemedicine, smart schools and a national, multipurpose card which individuals can use for credit, banking, transport, government, telephones and other services.</p>
<p>Participants in the meeting said Malaysia aimed to use the major project to help raise per capita income to $16,000 in current currency terms by the year 2020, in addition to attracting fast-growing, high-tech companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Malaysia's very well-positioned strategically,&quot; said Madge chairman and chief executive Robert Madge, who was among the more than two dozen eminent business and academic leaders on the international advisory panel.</p>
<p>The panel, which includes chief executives such as Hewlett-Packard Co's Lewis Platt, Sun Microsystems Inc's Scott McNealy and Softbank Corp's Masayoshi Son, met for most of the day here behind closed doors.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very frank and open discussion of some of the things you might consider would worry foreign companies and individuals,&quot; one of the participants said after the talks.</p>
<p>&quot;There was nothing hidden or not discussed.&quot;</p>
<p>The Malaysian Prime Minister said participants had raised concerns about shortages of skilled knowledge workers, and about how to market products in neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>Malaysia's newly formed Multimedia Development Corp is preparing to take formal applications beginning in March from &quot;world-class companies&quot; wanting to set up operations in the Multimedia Super Corridor.</p>
<p>McNealy said Sun Microsystems was already planning to put a Java Software Development Competency Center in the new high tech zone, and a senior executive of NTT Corp said the Japanese telecommunications giant was also planning to locate a research and development centre in the multimedia corridor.</p>
<p>NTT also wants to join other participants in forming a Multimedia University which Malaysia envisions for the area.</p>
<p>Some of the executives said the project was ambitious, and would likely face many pressures for the plan to change as it progressed, despite its success in attracting initial support.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot command creation,&quot; said Bishop. &quot;We have an impeccable plan, but execution still has to happen. We know enough in this new digital world that there are a lot of unpredictable discontinuities that occur. No country has a monopoly on these things.&quot;</p>
<p>Mahathir said individual panel members would continue to meet over the next year, and that a further full meeting would be called in Malaysia a year from now to review progress.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
