<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317025" id="root" date="1997-01-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Microsoft CFO sees EPS growth.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Microsoft CFO sees EPS growth.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp Chief Financial Officer Mike Brown said he expected earnings and revenues to rise sequentially in the fiscal third and fourth quarters compared with the just-ended second quarter.</p>
<p>Brown said in an interview he expects the recent release of Office 97 to provide a &quot;nice step&quot; up in earnings in the third quarter from the $0.57 a share reported for the second quarter, and he sees a &quot;small sequential step up&quot; in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Brown also said he expected revenues and earnings growth in the 20 percent range for fiscal 1998 beginning July 1, 1997.  </p>
<p>&quot;It doesn't seem wise to get beyond that with data we have today,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brown said he was pleased with the record results of the just-ended second quarter, which he said was strong &quot;across the board.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said the company thought it was prudent to issue a warning about slower growth in fiscal 1998, when Microsoft will not enjoy the benefit of major revenue-enhancing upgrades such as Windows 95 last year and Office 97 this year.  </p>
<p>While the company does have an opportunity to boost its OEM revenue with the increasing penetration of the high-end Windows NT operating system, which generates more revenue per unit than Windows 95, Brown said he expected that to be more significant in fiscal 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just a good time to be a little bit realistic about '98,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brown said he expected research and development spending to continue to grow faster than revenues in fiscal 1998, although he declined to be specific. He noted that the company's R&amp;D spending now exceeds an annual rate of $2 billion, and he expected that to exceed $3 billion &quot;at some point&quot; in the future, putting pressure on profit margins.</p>
<p>He said while the company has reduced its cost of goods sold this year, it is unlikely to be able to reduce them much further next year.</p>
<p>But he said the company could continue to reduce its sales and marketing expenses as a percentage of revenues.</p>
<p>Brown also said the company's cash position spiked up in the second quarter, in part because of a hedging transaction connected with its stock option program. ((-- Reuters Seattle bureau 206-386-4848))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
