<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317915" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hewlett-Packard cutting workstation prices.</title>
<headline>Hewlett-Packard cutting workstation prices.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hewlett-Packard Co said it is launching an aggressive new pricing plan designed to create a price-performance lead for its workstations and 3-D graphics products and cutting prices by up to 41 percent.</p>
<p>The decision follows the company's consolidation of its workstation business at Fort Collins, Colo., and analysts said it is aimed at countering market share gains by its neighboring competitor, Sun Microsystems Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;This price cut is the opening salvo in determining how competitive they're going to be,&quot; said Joe Ferlazzo, analyst at Technology Business Research in Hampton, N.H..</p>
<p>The new pricing model also corresponds with Hewlett's strategic plan to implement a manufacturing cost structure more akin to personal computer makers by reducing expenses and passing economies-of-scale savings that result to customers. The strategy is aimed at rivals such as Digital Equipment Corp, Silicon Graphics Inc and especially Sun, widely regarded as the low cost producers of workstations used for number-crunching by engineers and technical workers.  </p>
<p>Sun Microsystems grew its market share to 41 percent in the workstation business in 1996, more than its next three nearest competitors combined, as the overall workstation market shrank by one percent to $15 billion, according to International Data Corp, a market research firm.</p>
<p>Managers at Hewlett's workstation operations said the new pricing strategy was aimed directly at its competition.</p>
<p>&quot;We're really focussing aggressively at the other Unix vendors and really hitting them at the price-performance level,&quot; Jan Silverman, director of business development at Hewlett's technical computing business unit, told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Barry Crume, project manager at Hewlett's Workstation Systems Division, said the new pricing was based on performance testing on applications in 21 core workloads used by customers and compared with competitors' machines.</p>
<p>In basing its testing on workstations that have been tuned for optimal performance -- its own and those of its competitors -- analysts said Hewlett-Packard has developed a method of benchmarking which may become a valuable industry measure.  </p>
<p>Andrew Allison, publisher of the Inside the New Computing Industry newsletter, said Hewlett's application benchmark could be adapted to help the workstation customers better gauge their actual performance using specific applications.</p>
<p>&quot;They need to get it adapted by other people,&quot; he said, but added that it would have to be demonstrated to be a strictly unbiased method.  &quot;Nobody's going to handicap themselves by using a benchmark that's loaded against them.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very significant change,&quot; Allison said of HP's pricing. &quot;HP has not heretofore been a price leader or expressed the intent to be a price-performance leader.&quot;  </p>
<p>The announced price cuts range from 27 percent to 41 percent, with the higher-end Model C180 equiped with HP VISUALIZE-48XP and a 20-inch color monitor slashed by 32 percent to $34,995 from $51,500.</p>
<p>At the lower end, HP VISUALIZE Model B132L which delivers 2-D and 3-D performance, is reduced in price by 41 percent -- the machine paired with HP VISUALIZE-EG 2-D graphics was cut in price to $6,795 from $11,500, HP said.</p>
<p>But Hewlett-Packard's pricing move is unlikely to go unnoticed by rivals in the fiercely-competitive sector.  </p>
<p>Executives at Sun Microsystems, which cut its prices in some cases steeply last quarter, told analysts last week it was prepared to make further aggressive price cuts in the power workstation market which it now dominates.</p>
<p>&quot;If anybody loses, it's not going to be Sparc-Solaris, I believe,&quot; Sun Chief Executive Scott McNealy told analysts in the company's quarterly conference call, referring to the Sun processor and Unix combination.</p>
<p>Sun can &quot;get aggressive on pricing wherever we need to,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Analysts noted Sun expanded revenues by 19 percent to a record $2.08 billion and net income surged 41 percent in Sun's December quarter despite the price cuts, boosted by substantial sales across Sun's server product line.</p>
<p>&quot;Sun is the low-cost producer,&quot; said Allison.  &quot;Sun is in the best position to deal with this issue and I would expect Sun to respond to HP's moves.&quot;</p>
<p>As distinct from Sun, Hewlett-Packard has taken a strategy of working with the dominant suppliers to the personal computer market, Intel Corp and Microsoft Corp, on developing its future workstation road map.  </p>
<p>HP is working with Intel, and major industry applications providers, to develop the IA-64 architecture for a new generation of high-end processors codenamed Merced.</p>
<p>The Merced processors are designed to run both HP's version of Unix and Microsoft's fast-growing Windows NT systems in a strategy aimed at containing costs and positioning HP as a vendor uniquely committed to both.</p>
<p>But Ferlazzo said they must still prove this strategy by effectively merging their operations, with the ability to transfer technologies from high-powered workstations down into PCs, which are eating into the workstation market.  </p>
<p>&quot;They have to quickly consolidate their Windows and NT business...which obviously eats away at their low end at the (Unix-based) RISC platform,&quot; he said.  &quot;You might see high-end technologies being transferred downstream very quickly.&quot;</p>
<p>Silverman said HP has been working in this area, but is not yet ready to disclose details.</p>
<p>Hewlett-Packard also said it has named Chris Christopher, a 28 year veteran who has been a key player in its development of the IA-64 architecture, to be general manager of the Workstation Systems Division.</p>
<p>Analysts said this was a further sign of HP's commitment to utilize its coming technical commitment to a multiple, Unix- Windows NT platform to its advantage as it prepares to launch the new Merced processor over the next two years.</p>
<p>&quot;Execution is the issue,&quot; said Allison. &quot;HP has matched Sun's prices and claims to have bettered price performance, but it's a question of how long it lasts.&quot;</p>
<p>--sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau +1 415 846 5400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
