<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318695" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Pirated software value in Malaysia rising - Microsoft.</title>
<headline>Pirated software value in Malaysia rising - Microsoft.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The use and resale of illegally-copied computer software in Malaysia is decreasing, although the value of pirated software is on the rise, senior Microsoft (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The percentage of illegally used software in Malaysia has decreased from 82 percent in 1994 to 77 percent in the calendar year of 1995,&quot; Benedict Lee, general manager of Microsoft's operations in Malaysia, told a news conference.</p>
<p>The Malaysian software industry lost a total of 201.25 million ringgit ($80.5 million) in 1995 against 165.61 million ringgit lost in 1994, said Microsoft's business development manager Andreas Lim.</p>
<p>The figures were derived from a report published earlier this month by the U.S.-based Business Software Alliance (BSA), which monitors software piracy globally.</p>
<p>&quot;The value of piracy has increased because the amount of software usage has increased, but the overall incidence of piracy has decreased,&quot; Lim said.</p>
<p>Lim attributed the overall decrease to government initiatives to legalise the software used in most of its departments.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a larger percentage of computers used in government departments than in the private sector, so such an initiative would have a very significant impact on the incidence of software piracy in the country,&quot; Lim said.</p>
<p>The government is trying to promote Malaysia as a hub for information technology companies, who require a high-degree of software protection, analysts said.</p>
<p>A more active BSA has also helped, Lim said.</p>
<p>In April the BSA, along with local authorities, raided a company in the southern Malaysian city of Johor Baru and uncovered what it believed to be a large-scale operation to counterfeit CD-ROM software.</p>
<p>Vietnam and China had the highest incidences of piracy at 99 percent and 96 percent respectively, Lim said.</p>
<p>($1 = 2.4838 ringgit)</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
