<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32072" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Major players race to erect regional Web sites.</title>
<headline>Major players race to erect regional Web sites.</headline>
<byline>Michelle V. Rafter</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forget the global electronic village. The latest World Wide Web mantra is local, local, local.</p>
<p>The race is on to build Web sites with strictly local or regional appeal, and some of the biggest names in the online industry are leading the charge.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of the year, America Online has launched the Digital City series of regional guides on its commercial online service, and Yahoo and Excite have created localised versions of their respective Web search engines. Microsoft is formulating city guides under the code name Cityscape, the first of which is expected in the first quarter of 1997. AT&amp;T and others have similar projects in the works.</p>
<p>The latest player in the regional content game is Pacific Telesis Interactive Media, which launched its At Hand (http://www.athand.com/) guide to California on Aug. 30 after close to a year of development and a month-long test.</p>
<p>The guide includes 1.2 million merchant listings in three categories -- home, entertainment and sports -- plus articles on related topics from 43 magazines and newspapers, and ads from 65 sponsors including Black &amp; Decker, Kodak, and IKEA. Another 10 categories should go online by mid-1997.</p>
<p>Major players join dozens, if not hundreds, of small enterprises that have built niches for themselves providing local business listings, events calendars, TV and movie guides, restaurant reviews, and other community information.</p>
<p>Joining them are newspapers that have begun publishing Web-based editions, some of which include local listings.</p>
<p>Everyone is after the same thing: ad revenues from local businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;People think that local content is a goldmine because it's an entry into local advertising dollars. That's what's driving all this interest,&quot; said Bill Bass, an analyst with Forrester Research in Cambridge, Mass.</p>
<p>Though the goal is the same, approaches are very different. For example, Yahoo and Excite provide directory style, hypertext listings of Web sites in a given city or region.</p>
<p>Among the services At Hand offers, is a &quot;proximity finder&quot; that lets registered users search for a plumber, florist or other business within approximately five miles of their home. Listings for 500,000 merchants on the Web site include hours a store is open, what credit cards they take and a brief description of their main business.</p>
<p>Visitors to the free Web site can read articles from American Express' Travel &amp; Leisure, People, Golf Digest or Windsurfing, then click on links to merchants that sell related items.</p>
<p>&quot;We're a telephone company. We're not known for being the place to find out the best jazz clubs, so we did content deals (with publishers) focused on brand names you would know as a consumer,&quot; said Carla McMorris, At Hand marketing and advertising director.</p>
<p>America Online has virtual communities for Washington D.C., Boston, Atlanta and San Francisco and is launching Digital Los Angeles today (Sept. 4) and Digital Philadelphia on Sept. 18.</p>
<p>The sites include information on local organisations, government, churches, entertainment, traffic, weather, people and shopping. Message boards and chat rooms are de rigeur. Digital City General Manager Bill Smith hopes eventually AOL subscribers will create a big chunk of what's online.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be about communications in the community, people talking to people,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>This summer, Tribune Co., publisher of the Chicago Tribune, paid $20 million for a 20 percent equity stake in Digital City Inc. and is creating sites for Chicago, Orlando and other cities where the company publishes daily newspapers.</p>
<p>Microsoft won't officially announce its string of local entertainment guides until later this month. Preliminary plans call for the guides, which are being renamed, to include movie listings and restaurant reviews, among other things.</p>
<p>Seattle will be among the first cities to be covered. Microsoft is hiring its own news staff -- and initially won't use resources from its MSNBC venture -- but could team up with publishers or others if it makes sense, a source close to the company said.</p>
<p>Analyst Bass predicts small players won't last much longer and will either work with the bigger companies, be acquired by them or go out of business.</p>
<p>One of those smaller players is Virtually Commerce Corp., a San Diego company which runs California Virtually (http://www.virtually.com/) and Virtually Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;The way we're going to beat them is join them,&quot; said Neil Greer, the company's president. &quot;We signed a license agreement with America Online to produce the surf reports for Digital City San Diego and they're interested in having us do more.&quot;</p>
<p>But Greer is covering his bases. Virtual Commerce will add a third regional site within 45 days, and hopes to raise $300,000 in an upcoming private stock offering.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't feel threatened because the market is so big,&quot; Greer said. &quot;It's like ice cream. There's 50 different kinds.&quot;</p>
<p>(Michelle V. Rafter writes about cyberspace and technology from Los Angeles. Reach her at mvrafter(at)deltanet.com. Opinions expressed in this column are her own).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
