<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="323792" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Q4 results so-far-so-good but Wall St wary.</title>
<headline>U.S. Q4 results so-far-so-good but Wall St wary.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. corporations have posted generally strong fourth quarter earnings thusfar that have given support to Wall Street stocks, despite Wednesday's IBM-led Dow downturn.</p>
<p>But as trading in International Business Machines Corp indicated, lofty stock prices are leading investors to look beyond the straight earnings per share numbers and sell stocks in companies that hint of potential troubles ahead, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In general, sentiment points toward fourth quarter earnings being viewed fairly positively,&quot; said Charlie Crane, director of research at Spears Benzak Salomon and Farrell. &quot;That has certainly helped lift the stock market in the face of rising interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Of 781 companies followed by I/B/E/S that had reported through Tuesday, 434, or 56 percent, beat Wall Street's consensus estimate with the fourth quarter results. Some 212, or 27 percent, had produced negative surprises, while 135, or 17 percent were on target.  </p>
<p>Large banks, including Citicorp and Chase Manhattan Corp, reported earnings close to forecasts.</p>
<p>Brokerages, including Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette and PaineWebber Group Inc, topped expectations with profits driven by Wall Street's record bull market.</p>
<p>Large pharmaceutical, regional Bell telephone, and oil companies have also reported solid profits, analysts said.</p>
<p>The numbers helped drive the Dow industrials to its 10th record close of the year on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But any companies indicating future problems have been punished, most notably so far high-profile technology stocks.  </p>
<p>Late Tuesday, IBM reported fourth quarter earnings of $3.93 a share, well ahead of the Wall Street consensus estimate of $3.88. But analysts said lower profit margins, disappointing hardware revenues and currency tainted the results.</p>
<p>IBM was down 9-1/8 to 158-7/8 accounting for almost half of the drop in the Dow, which tumbled 65 points to 6817 in mid-afternoon trading.</p>
<p>Investors &quot;are looking for reasons (to take profits) and rightly so,&quot; said John Wosczyna, market strategist at Roney &amp; Co. &quot;The (market) players themselves are very skittish.&quot;  </p>
<p>Last week microprocessor maker Intel Corp reported fourth quarter profits that beat the consensus expectations but was shy of some even higher estimates.</p>
<p>A projection from Intel that its first quarter revenues would be flat with 1996's fourth quarter hurt the stock initially, but it has bounced back. It was up 2-15/16 to 151 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Computer Associates International Inc sank 3-5/8 to 42-1/2 Wednesday. It reported earnings slightly above consenses expectations, but was hit by concerns over its mainframe business.  </p>
<p>But the downturn was not widespread in the technology group. Compaq Computer Corp shot up 5-1/4 to 83-5/8 after its earnings beat forecasts and the company said it expects to outpace industry growth rates this year.</p>
<p>The technology-studded Nasdaq composite was up six points, or 0.44 percent, to 1383.</p>
<p>The action in Compaq shares is an indication that investors will jump into stocks that make assurances of future growth in addition to showing strong quarterly numbers, analysts said. &quot;There's plenty of money sloshing around out there still looking for a place to live,&quot; Crane said.  </p>
<p>Given the strength in technology stocks in the face of IBM's disappointment, analysts said they did not foresee any one company yet to report that could send the market into a broad tumble with its fourth quarter results.</p>
<p>&quot;If IBM can't do it, than there's really no stock that can come in, disappoint and upset this market here,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd.</p>
<p>Key groups yet to report include the non-cyclical consumer products companies. Two bellwethers in that group, Coca-Cola Co and Procter &amp; Gamble Co, are expected to report next week.</p>
<p>((--Wall St Desk, 212-859-1721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
