<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32693" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Peoplesoft to acquire Co. in stock swap.</title>
<headline>Peoplesoft to acquire Co. in stock swap.</headline>
<dateline>PLEASANTON, Calif. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>PeopleSoft Inc said Wednesday it has agreed to acquire Red Pepper Software, a maker of manufacturing software based in San Mateo, Calif., for 2.975 million of its shares.</p>
<p>PeopleSoft, a developer of client/server software for business, saw its shares close off 1/2 at 75-3/4.</p>
<p>The deal will be accounted for as a pooling of interests and is expected to close by the end of 1996.  </p>
<p>&quot;Red Pepper has the best (manufacturing) planning and optimization technology on the market,&quot; Dave Duffield, chief executive of PeopleSoft, said in a statement.</p>
<p>In June 1995, PeopleSoft entered into a technology licensing and distribution agreement with Red Pepper, and earlier this year PeopleSoft launched a new line of software that embed Red Pepper's ResponseAgent technology.</p>
<p>The technology enables real-time planning and optimization of manufacturing operations, integrated supply chains, and customer orders, PeopleSoft said.</p>
<p>PeopleSoft will also benefit from the addition of significant Red Pepper's expertise in the areas of manufacturing and supply chain management.</p>
<p>&quot;After working together for more than a year, we know both companies share a common vision for the future of enterprise applications, and have similar corporate cultures and company values,&quot; Duffield said in a statement. &quot;This is a great company with great people.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PLEASANTON, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
