<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330719" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China Internet firm buys Microsoft platform.</title>
<headline>China Internet firm buys Microsoft platform.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. software giant Microsoft Corp on Friday signed a deal to supply an Internet platform to a Chinese on-line firm, with company officials predicting a rapid growth of Chinese Internet surfers in coming years.</p>
<p>China Infohighway Communications Co Ltd (IHW) had tested the Microsoft Commercial Internet Services (MCIS) platform for about three months before formally signing the deal, Infohighway president Zhang Shuxin said.</p>
<p>Officials declined to say how much the deal was worth.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is to generate an open, interactive Chinese cyberspace which the general public in China can enter for work, study, entertainment and shopping,&quot; Zhang said.</p>
<p>The deal was Microsoft's first sale of the MCIS platform in China and five or six other Chinese firms had inquired about purchasing the system, said Jia-bin Duh, president of Microsoft (China) Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Demand for Internet services in China would grow along with the rapidly swelling ranks of computer users, Duh said.</p>
<p>Sales of personal computers in China were about 2.5 million units in 1996 and that figure was expected to rise to more than three million in 1997, Duh said.</p>
<p>&quot;Wherever there is a telephone jack, there is a possibility that they will become an Internet user,&quot; he said. China says it has 100,000 Internet users.</p>
<p>Microsoft would also provide consulting and support services to IHW and copies of IHW's Internet start-up software would be included in Microsoft's Chinese-language version of Windows 95, Zhang said.</p>
<p>IHW had about 10,000 customers nationwide, about half of whom were individuals, Zhang said, adding that she expected that number to grow rapidly.</p>
<p>Set up in 1995, IWH had nodes in eight Chinese cities and was the first Internet provider to supply on-line services such as electronic mail, information retrieval and news in Chinese, Zhang said.</p>
<p>The firm, 74 percent state-owned, had a registered capital of 80 million yuan ($9.64 million). IHW's revenue was expected to hit about 100 million this year, Zhang said.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Beijing Newsroom (8610) 6532-1921</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
