<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="331620" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: DR SOLOMON'S OPER PROFIT UP FURTHER IN Q2.</title>
<headline>DR SOLOMON'S OPER PROFIT UP FURTHER IN Q2.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are key extracts from a statement on second-quarter results by Easdaq-listed anti-virus software company Dr Solomon's Group plc :</p>
<p>&quot;Dr Solomon's announced strong revenues and earnings for its second quarter ended November 30, 1996. Operating profit increased to GBP 1.9 million from GBP 1.5 million in the previous quarter and from GBP 0.4 million in the corresponding quarter last year. Bookings for the second quarter increased 76.8% year-on-year from GBP 5.7 million to GBP 10.1 million. Turnover (after allowing for deferral of bookings) increased by 89.5% year-on-year from GBP 4.6 million to GBP 8.7 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Cash inflow from operating activities for the first two quarters of the 1997 financial year was GBP 6.0 million compared to GBP 2.2 million for the same period last year. This, together with the GBP 36 million raised in the IPO in November, has enabled the company to redeem the preference shares and repay all the borrowings incurred at the time of the management buyout, leaving cash balances of GBP 20.2 million at November 30, 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Announcing the first set of results since the Company's IPO in November 1996, Geoff Leary, Dr Solomon's Chief Executive, said, &quot;While we are very pleased with the continuing overall strong growth and success of Dr Solomon's in our home U.K. market, we are particularly pleased with the contributions from our operations in the United States and Germany and the growth of our business from distributors and republishers in the rest of the world. Our investment in the United States market is already beginning to yield the results on which we can build our planned expansion in 1997 and beyond.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Dr Solomon's continues to invest in growth with marketing expenditure up by more than 100% and headcount by 50% compared to the same quarter last year. Headcount in the United States and German operations grew year-on-year from 24 to 56 as a result of the expansion of sales and marketing activities plus additional technical support in those markets.  The research and development and test teams have been further strengthened in pursuit of the Company's objective of maintaining and enhancing its technical leadership and product quality in the anti-virus market.</p>
<p>&quot;The increasing investment in development and marketing will continue with a number of new products scheduled for first customer shipment over the next few months:  - Dr Solomon's MailGuard, for protecting SMTP mail servers,  - Dr Solomon's GroupGuard for Lotus Notes, and  - Dr Solomon's Software Control System for the management of the Company's anti-virus solutions across enterprise networks utilizing Windows NT servers.</p>
<p>&quot;New retail products will be released in the U.S. and U.K. markets and the Company will provide automated online updating for its U.S. retail customers. Geoff Leary summed up by saying, &quot;Following Dr Solomon's successful IPO, I am pleased to report strong  results and progress on all fronts in achieving our vision of being 'first and best in the global anti-virus market.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
