<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="338302" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FBI makes nationwide searches in software probe.</title>
<headline>FBI makes nationwide searches in software probe.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The FBI said it carried out searches from coast to coast on Tuesday as part of an undercover investigation of computer software piracy codenamed &quot;Cyber Strike&quot;.</p>
<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation said its agents were interviewing people or searching homes and businesses in Atlanta, Miami, Oklahoma City and Pittsburgh. Searches or interviews were also under way in Columbus, Ohio; Des Moines, Iowa; and San Leandro and Cedar Ridge in California.</p>
<p>The search warrants allege violations of U.S. laws against copyright infringement and authorise agents to seize computer hardware, documents and records, the FBI said.</p>
<p>FBI spokesman George Grotz said he did not expect any arrests to be made on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The searches followed an eight-month undercover investigation of illegal duplication and distribution of computer software, a $1 billion a year crime, the FBI said.</p>
<p>The probe focused on people who have allegedly banded together to pass restricted information and copyrighted software through computer Bulletin Board Services, Internet File Transfer Protocol sites and Internet Relay Chat channels, the FBI said.</p>
<p>The investigation was led by the FBI's San Francisco-based International Computer Crime Squad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
