<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343092" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Vols on tech stock options rising.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Vols on tech stock options rising.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volatilities on leading technology stocks were rising as investors were busy buying puts and calls amid rallies in the underlying shares, traders said Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears to me they're buying volatility even at these levels, which are relatively high for the last few months,&quot; said Jesse Stamer, a designated primary market maker at the Chicago Board Options Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;They're buying both puts and calls, so volatility's increasing a bit here,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>At 1130 CST/1730 GMT, the technology-heavy Nasdaq composite index .IXIC was up 6.80 at 1,361.97, just shy of its session high.</p>
<p>A rally in semiconductor stocks led the broader group higher. The Philadelphia Stock Exchange's semiconductor index, was up 7.72 points, or 2.85 percent, at 279.02.</p>
<p>Options on the index were not particularly busy as investors centered on options on the individual stocks.</p>
<p>Matt Zahner, a lead market maker at the Pacific Stock Exchange, said investors were focused on the industry's leading stocks.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's happening selectively,&quot; he said. &quot;Basically the strong are getting stronger.</p>
<p>&quot;You have a lot of peripheral stocks that are more risky and I don't see a lot of people coming in to buy those,&quot; he said. &quot;People are looking to buy industry leaders like IBM, Intel and Applied Materials.&quot;</p>
<p>At the Pacific Stock Exchange, options volume was led by Micron Technology Inc, Microsoft Corp and 3Com Corp. All three underlying stocks were up solidly.  </p>
<p>Hank Nothnagel, senior vice president of options trading at EVEREN Securities in Chicago, said he had crossed some sizable orders in Micron, most of them buy orders.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a big drop-off after the main ones,&quot; Zahner said. &quot;As you look at them across the board, the ones that are trading are the industry leaders.&quot;</p>
<p>He agreed that volatilities on those options were on the rise.</p>
<p>Volatilities had spiked up on several of the technology company options ahead of quarterly earnings reports, only to collapse once the news was out.  </p>
<p>&quot;Now there's other, more fundamental things happening in the industry, and volatility in those bellwether stocks is picking up,&quot; Zahner said.</p>
<p>&quot;The scuttlebutt around the floor in general has been that volatility has been pretty low&quot; but is increasing, he added.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite has spent the last two trading sessions finding a bottom after correcting off its record close of 1,388.06 set on January 22.</p>
<p>((--Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>((E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
