<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349015" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP 96 net profit up 40 pct to 567 mln DM.</title>
<headline>SAP 96 net profit up 40 pct to 567 mln DM.</headline>
<dateline>WALLDORF, Germany 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software developer SAP AG said on Friday its 1996 net profit rose a higher-than-expected 40 percent to 567 million marks on a sales increase of 38 percent to 3.72 billion marks.</p>
<p>The results, which came amid analyst concern this week that growth was slowing, were boosted by a 43 percent jump in income from ordinary activities, the company said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The planned currency union and (adjustments that must be made to cope with) the turn of the century have increased interest in our products worldwide,&quot; said SAP chief Dietmar Hopp.</p>
<p>Sales of its R/3 product rose 44 percent to 2.37 billion marks, while consulting revenue increased 47 percent to 735 million marks.</p>
<p>Foreign sales contributed 75 percent of sales, up from 69 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>SAP also said sales could rise another 25 to 30 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>The 1996 results surpassed the forecast SAP gave in October, when it said sales would only rise to 3.5 billion marks because of a slow third quarter. It also warned that net profit would only increase 30 percent. </p>
<p>Fourth-quarter sales and profit rebounded beyond SAP forecasts because of robust international growth, the company said.</p>
<p>Asian sales rose 67 percent to 486 million marks and American sales were up 47 percent to 1.35 billion marks. European sales rose 27 percent to 1.81 billion marks.</p>
<p>Fourth-quarter pre-tax profit rose 58 percent to 457 million marks, SAP said. Earnings per share for 1996 rose to 5.48 marks from four marks in 1995.</p>
<p>Shares of SAP soared on the news, climbing 20 marks to 239 marks after 15 minutes of pre-bourse electronic trading.</p>
<p>SAP signed on 1,089 new R/3 customers in 1996, bringing worldwide installations of the &quot;client/server&quot; software to more than 9,000. In December it began shipping R/3 Version 3.1, which includes Internet capabilities.</p>
<p>At the end of 1996, SAP employed 9,196 workers, up 34 percent from a year ago.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WALLDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
