<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351161" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Strong quarterly results boost Creative.</title>
<headline>Strong quarterly results boost Creative.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Better-than-expected second quarter results gave sound card company Creative Technology's shares a boost on Monday.</p>
<p>Analysts said they were confident of a good set of numbers for the full year ending June 1997 and this should give more upside to its share price.</p>
<p>Creative's Singapore shares leapt more than 18 percent, or Singapore S$3.40, to a high of S$21.70 on Monday. It closed at S$21, up S$2.70.</p>
<p>&quot;The results were way above expectations,&quot; said Timothy Wong, research manager at Vickers Ballas.</p>
<p>The company said second quarter net profit surged 111 percent to US$56.93 million.</p>
<p>Analysts told Reuters they had doubled their forecasts for Creative's full-year net profit to between US$116 million and US$123 million for the 1997 financial year.</p>
<p>Wong said Creative's shares could go as high as S$23 to $25 based on a price-earnings ratio of about 12-15 times for the current financial year.  </p>
<p>Analysts said Creative's impressive performance started from its first quarter results that reversed losses in the two previous quarters.</p>
<p>They said Creative's results had been improving after it instituted expense-control measures and concentrated on higher-end products. Better gross margins at 28 percent gave its second quarter results a big boost.</p>
<p>But analysts said margins might ease in coming quarters.</p>
<p>&quot;Margins may not be sustainable and may dip back to 20-22 percent in the next two quarters,&quot; said Patrick Yau, an analyst at Schroders Securities.</p>
<p>Also, the 1998 financial year might pose some challenges, analysts said.</p>
<p>Yau said Creative had benefitted from falling semiconductor prices in 1996 that lifted its margins. This might not happen again in 1998, he said.</p>
<p>As a technology company it might not be able to continue to keep down future expenses, especially for research and development, he said.</p>
<p>Analysts had mixed views on whether competition from Intel's recently launched MMX chip, which has sound capability without the use of a sound card, would dent Creative's market share.  </p>
<p>An analyst from a local broking house said Creative's move into digital video disc, a multimedia storage system for computers, TV video and audio systems, augured well for its future earnings, especially its tie-up with Korea's Samsung.</p>
<p>&quot;Creative has realised it can't be a leader in markets dominated by the Japanese and has tied up with Samsung, who will make the DVD drives and Creative will produce the software,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>($1 = S$1.41)</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
