<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351134" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore piracy watchdogs eye corporate offenders.</title>
<headline>Singapore piracy watchdogs eye corporate offenders.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Wong</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading software piracy watchdog plans to fight rising CD-ROM piracy in Singapore by targeting end-users and pushing companies to join a new corporate programme to guard against huge losses in revenue.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to shift the focus, win the mindset, by giving companies the message that if you are in business, you have to pay for it,&quot; Stuart Ong, vice-president of the Business Software Alliance (BSA) told Reuters in an interview on Monday.</p>
<p>Rising software piracy prompted the BSA to approve plans for a corporate recognition programme in March, where companies sign a code of ethics to comply with the use of legal business software.</p>
<p>Members of the BSA would then audit the company's software, which would grant them immunity from a lawsuit if illegal software was later found to be circulating on the premises.</p>
<p>Formed in 1988, the BSA represents leading software publishers such as Microsoft, Apple and Lotus Development.</p>
<p>According to the latest available figures, about 58 percent of software used in Singapore was pirated in 1994.</p>
<p>Vietnam has one of the worst rates of piracy, with more than 90 percent of software being fake.</p>
<p>Overall, software theft in Asia exceeded US$4.3 billion in 1994, some 29 percent of the US$15.2 billion lost worldwide.</p>
<p>Ong said raids on software retailers at shopping complexes around Singapore only affected suppliers and not users.</p>
<p>CD-ROMs are becoming the most common method of data storage for sophisticated computers and multimedia equipment.</p>
<p>&quot;With the advent of CD-ROM's and availability of compilation CD-ROM's, software piracy has taken a huge jump,&quot; Ong said.</p>
<p>Consumers had to be dissuaded from buying and using pirated software, which involved vigilance at the corporate level, he said.</p>
<p>In addition to the corporate recognition programme, the BSA has established a hotline to alert against software piracy that has provided useful tip-offs and led to the successful prosecution of numerous retailers and one well-known engineering firm so far, Ong said.</p>
<p>The caller was rewarded with Singapore $5,000 (US$3,570) for the tip that led to a successful prosecution of the firm. The firm settled the case by paying S$42,000 in damages and costs and had to purchase original copies of the pirated software to legitimise its operations.</p>
<p>&quot;If any of your employees call this hotline (for sabotage), and you have joined this programme, I will call you and say this has happened,&quot; Ong said.</p>
<p>He noted that efforts by the company to audit its internal software circulation would give it a first round of defence.</p>
<p>Ong said intensifying publicity against offenders should slow the rate of CD-ROM piracy, which has worsened since early 1996 and now exceeds US$45 million in lost revenue for Singapore.</p>
<p>CD-ROM compilations include a series of programmes on one disc and are relatively easy to duplicate. Word-processing programmes, spreadsheets and games are commonly pirated, officials said.</p>
<p>The influx of CD-ROMS and increased information technology business in Singapore is expected to worsen its piracy rate in the short-term.</p>
<p>Singapore has adopted stiff penalties for piracy -- jail terms of up to 36 months and S$180,000 in fines for distributors, but Ong said more had to be done to educate end-users.</p>
<p>&quot;We need a stick as well as a carrot,&quot; he said, noting that no reputable government office, bank or listed company would want to be subject to raids and bad publicity.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
