<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353197" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Computron responding to SEC/Nasdaq queries.</title>
<headline>Computron responding to SEC/Nasdaq queries.</headline>
<byline>Hugh Bronstein</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The new chief executive of Computron Software Inc said Tuesday the company is cooperating with Nasdaq and Securities and Exchange Commission inquiries about some of its financial statements.</p>
<p>&quot;We are re-evaluating some of our financial statements,&quot; new CEO John Rade said in an interview.  </p>
<p>Computron's stock was halted January 27 when the company said information had come to its attention that may impact previously reported financial results, and its independent auditors would withdraw their reports on the company's previously reported financial statements.</p>
<p>&quot;The SEC and Nasdaq asked what periods we're talking about and they asked us to quantify this,&quot; Rade said. &quot;We gave them additional backup on any potential adjustments that we are evaluating.&quot;</p>
<p>Rade said he did not want to disclose specific information before Nasdaq and the SEC are satisfied.  </p>
<p>&quot;I expect there will be another press release today or tomorrow, clearly putting that situation to rest,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Computron on Monday announced Rade's appointment as director, president and chief executive and the company said it is &quot;actively recruiting&quot; a new chief financial officer.  </p>
<p>Computron said the new executives will replace Adrian Peters, formerly director, president and chief executive and Alex Comandini, formerly chief financial officer, who have left the company.</p>
<p>Rade declined to comment on the reason for the management changes, but said, &quot;It would be unwise to infer there is a connection between the accounting changes and the departure of Mr. Peters and Mr. Comandini. We are addressing the accounting concerns as a totally separate issue.&quot;</p>
<p>Neither Peters nor Comandini could be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Rade joined Computron from S-Cubed International, a company he founded in the client server system development and consulting market. Prior to launching S-Cubed, Rade was President and CEO of Information Science Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the last 15 years, all of my activities have been in restructuring and turnaround,&quot; Rade said.</p>
<p>In November, Computron reported a third quarter loss of $0.39 a share compared to a profit of $0.07 per share in the 1995 period.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
