<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357441" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hasbro Sinks This 'Battleship'.</title>
<headline>Hasbro Sinks This 'Battleship'.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prayer has always been an important element in the classic board game Battleship.</p>
<p>My friends and I would put our little plastic ships in the plastic grid, then silently plead with the Almighty to make our opponents call out an empty spot on the grid. This allowed us to shout &quot;Miss!&quot;, breathe a sign of relief, and then plead for divine guidance so, when we announced a spot on the grid, they would have to grudgingly announce &quot;Hit!&quot;</p>
<p>Foxholes aren't the only places where there are no atheists.</p>
<p>Now Hasbro Interactive, which did a good job of adapting Scrabble to the computer and also offers CD-ROM versions of Monopoly, Clue, and Risk, has come up with a souped-up version of Battleship.</p>
<p>&quot;Battleship,&quot; the CD-ROM game (Windows 95, $40), tries to offer the same suspense, plus lots of other fancy features to give this computerized version an extra dimension you could never find in the classic board game.</p>
<p>For me, that extra dimension was frustration.</p>
<p>At first, &quot;Battleship&quot; seemed promising. I began with a practice game, which plays like the board game. It worked just fine. The computer showed the hits and misses. The animation in the background was colourful (if not always an accurate reflection of what was occurring on the game grid).</p>
<p>I won the first game and decided to play a second.</p>
<p>No way.</p>
<p>&quot;Battleship&quot; wouldn't let me replay the basic game. I was required to move on to the higher-tech version, complete with oil rigs, islands, jet fighters, helicopters, satellites and every element of modern warfare except $20,000 toilet seats.</p>
<p>So I succumbed to the game's wishes and began to learn the tasks of moving convoys, selecting weaponry and mastering the intricacies of satellite telemetry.</p>
<p>Good games are intuitively easy to play, with few directions necessary. &quot;Battleship&quot; is not. Instead of using on-screen prompts to walk you through the various techniques you'll need to practice to win your battles, you find yourself stumbling around the screen, forced to consult the all-text 24-page reference book that isn't always clear.</p>
<p>For example, the booklet advised that &quot;In the top (left) corner of the battle map you will see your fleet, awaiting orders. You will notice a yellow square around the fleet representing the maximum range of your fleet's currently selected weapon.&quot;</p>
<p>Wrong. The top left corner apparently does nothing but show videos, which I discovered only after endlessly clicking the pointer over every imaginable spot. The yellow square, showing the maximum range of your weaponry, turned out to be located on the main grid in the centre of the screen.</p>
<p>The radar screen in the top right corner was equally useless (the controls on the radar are never explained) and the constant full-screen background animation showing a passing satellite overhead quickly became annoying and hindered the ability to play the game.</p>
<p>I found other reasons to lose faith.</p>
<p>When you start firing at enemy ships, the game doesn't mark your misses, so you may waste shots firing at the same spot. At one point, the game said my frigate was at 100 percent, yet the game grid showed that one third of it had been destroyed in battle.</p>
<p>Perhaps I'm just bitter because the game made it obvious that the only country likely to give me a naval commission is Switzerland.</p>
<p>Perhaps people who thrive on computerized battle simulations will be willing to take all of this in stride.</p>
<p>But for anyone else looking for a game that's as easy to play and just as much fun as the original, don't pick up &quot;Battleship.&quot; You won't have a prayer.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;American Heritage: The History of the United States for Young People&quot; (Byron Preiss Multimedia, Windows, $30) boasts that it's &quot;the only software your kids will ever need to study American history.&quot; It's based on the Prentice Hall textbook &quot;The American Nation,&quot; but it has multimedia biographies of all 42 presidents and 50 influential Americans, plus a searchable library and a Report Maker.</p>
<p>&quot;Cooking Light 4.0&quot; and &quot;MasterCook Deluxe 4.0&quot; (Sierra, Windows/Macintosh, $35 and $40 respectively) -- The first has over 1,250 recipies that are low in fat. &quot;MasterCook Deluxe&quot; has over 2,000 recipes. Both products will analyse any recipe for fat, calories, vitamins and other nutrients, and help you find recipes based on ingredients and cooking times.</p>
<p>&quot;Flying Corps&quot; (Empire, Windows/DOS, $50) -- A World War I dogfight simulator from an era when the air battles were up close and personal. You can fly a Sopwith Camel, Nieuport Scout and other planes and battle the likes of Baron Manfred Von Richthofen, also known as The Red Baron.</p>
<p>&quot;The Great Reading Adventure&quot; (Kids' World, Windows, $30) stars the voice of comic Howie Mandel and is the fourth title in the &quot;Great Adventure&quot; series. This one covers phonics, comprehension and word families. It's for grades Kindergarten through 3.</p>
<p>&quot;The Roberta Williams Anthology&quot; (Sierra, Windows/DOS, $49) -- A collection of 14 computer games developed over 17 years by the prolific game designer Roberta Williams, ranging from &quot;Mystery House&quot; (1980) to the first chapter of &quot;Phantasmagoria&quot; (1995). It's rated for ages 13 and older.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
