<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363752" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: FEATURE - IT firms spot gold in electronic commerce.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - IT firms spot gold in electronic commerce.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Internet boom in the last two to three years has sent information technology (IT) companies tripping over each other to spot the next money-making trend.</p>
<p>And they seem to have zeroed in on the same idea -- business transactions over the Net.</p>
<p>&quot;Electronic commerce&quot; and &quot;e-business&quot; are the latest buzzwords at leading IT companies including IBM Corp and Digital Equipment Corp, where engineers are trying to come up with an array of choices for people and companies to buy and sell in cyberspace.</p>
<p>At the Internet World International Conference held in Singapore in late January, speeches, workshops, exhibitions and meetings with the media centred on the promise of electronic commerce. </p>
<p>THE PUSH FACTORS</p>
<p>While the debate rages on over just how useful and profitable electronic commerce can be, IT companies are not waiting for the dust to settle.</p>
<p>&quot;The technology isn't perfect, but the business incentive is so compelling it's worth the risk. The biggest risk is to do nothing,&quot; Rose Ann Giordano, Digital's vice president, Internet business group, said in her keynote address.</p>
<p>The expectation that a huge number of people will be surfing the Net is pushing companies in that direction.</p>
<p>&quot;Close to 40 million people are expected on-line by year's end,&quot; said John Patrick, IBM's vice president of Internet technology.</p>
<p>&quot;How will businesses take advantage of the ability to reach an increasing number of people around the world via the Internet and intranets?</p>
<p>&quot;E-business is what will change the economies of the world. It will allow businesses to reach out to touch constituencies they couldn't before,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>IBM has identified three areas in e-business -- ways to conduct commerce, business collaboration and managing content on the Internet.</p>
<p>QUESTION ON PROFIT AND USEFULNESS</p>
<p>Analysts say the stage is set for electronic commerce but it may not prove to be immediately profitable for businesses operating in cyberspace.</p>
<p>&quot;I see the basic infrastructure for this business is already there but I don't see it being profitable so soon,&quot; said Patrick Yau, technology analyst at Schroders Securities.</p>
<p>IBM launched its virtual shopping mall, called World Avenue, in the last quarter of 1996 and now has about 15 merchants signed on. It gets a start-up fee from the vendors, a five percent commission on sales and a monthly maintenance charge.</p>
<p>Some critics say such a retailing concept does not add much value other than the convenience of shopping from home.</p>
<p>&quot;Malls on the Internet are not what people want,&quot; said Stan Dolberg, a Forrester Research analyst, in a Reuter report.</p>
<p>&quot;If they want a mall, they want products grouped together by categories, say like shoes, so they can comparison shop...The Internet itself is like a whole mall, where a lot of different things are already grouped together,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other recent Internet shopping mall efforts have also failed, like MCI Communications Corp 's MCI Marketplace.</p>
<p>While IBM conceded it was too early to tell if its virtual mall would succeed, it said one advantage was that people would be able to shop as and when they liked, even when shops were closed.</p>
<p>&quot;We are thinking of doing a poll at one of the large malls to ask if people really enjoy shopping at the mall itself,&quot; said Patrick.</p>
<p>TECHNOLOGIES IN THE PIPELINE</p>
<p>IBM hopes to license a project called Panoramix, currently being tested, which gives a three-dimensional experience, be it in a shop or a museum. The consumer can view products close up and effect a purchase through a simple point and click.</p>
<p>Digital is demonstrating Millicent, a technology that allows low-value transactions credit card companies normally would not accept.</p>
<p>And the network computer, which the industry is banking on to help boost electronic commerce, will be rolled out from the first half of this year.</p>
<p>Software company Oracle Corp champions the network computer -- a simple and cheap device that pulls data from a network -- as the way to get computer-shy people onto the Net as it would look and work like a consumer device, for instance, a television set.</p>
<p>SECURITY AND COST</p>
<p>Companies say hurdles like security, bandwidth and regulation have already been crossed or would soon be resolved. The major barrier is gaining people's trust that it is safe to do business over the Net.</p>
<p>IBM and Digital say that with techniques such as encryption now available it is as safe if not safer to transact over the Net than over the telephone.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, the lure of electronic commerce is that it provides new ways of doing business at a lower cost.</p>
<p>&quot;Small businesses will have a global reach which they couldn't have before. Vendors can go directly to customers and cut out the middlemen,&quot; said Giordano.</p>
<p>Businesses can exist without buildings and with fewer staff, resulting in lower overheads. Inventory levels can be cut.</p>
<p>Yau of Schroders said banks would probably be the first to adopt electronic commerce in a big way as they were the ones who had the financial resources to invest in the technology.</p>
<p>Analysts say electronic commerce will only really take off when people find the Net as comfortable as using the telephone.</p>
<p>Will a parallel economy emerge in cyberspace? The debate goes on.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
