<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365363" id="root" date="1997-02-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: CD-ROM media market slow in catching on.</title>
<headline>CD-ROM media market slow in catching on.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>CANNES, France 1997-02-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The market for CD-ROM titles, games or reference works on compact discs, is slow in catching on and will remain largely unprofitable for some years, experts told the MILIA multimedia trade show on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;The number of CD titles published is still totally out of line with the size of the market,&quot; said Ben Keen of Screen Digest, showing that a best-selling title in Europe has difficulty reaching the 10,000 units mark.</p>
<p>Keen made the comment during a series of opening speeches at the MILIA show which is being held here until Wednesday with some 1,170 companies showing off their wares.</p>
<p>While the internet and digital television are clamouring for attention with announcements about new developments over the coming days, the &quot;old&quot; medium of compact-discs for computers claimed the opening day.</p>
<p>Keen said that in 1996, 43 million CD-ROM's were sold in Europe for a value of $2.3 billion while this was 56 million in the U.S.</p>
<p>In Europe, the biggest market for CD-ROM's is Germany, followed by France and Italy while Britain comes fourth.</p>
<p>Games make up about 70 percent of sales in Germany, Spain, the U.K. and U.S., while it is closer to 50 percent in France, Italy and Japan.</p>
<p>Julie Schwerin, chairman of data researchers InfoTech, said that the world wide CD-ROM market exceeded $30 billion in 1996 and is expected to grow by over 30 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>The installed base of CD-ROM players passed the 100 million level in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumer titles contributed 31.4 percent of total worldwide CD-ROM title revenue in 1996. Yet the worldwide consumer multimedia publishing industry as a whole operated at a net loss,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>To add insult to injury, the top selling CD-ROM publishing companies are Walt Disney and Microsoft, for which the business is a secondary line of activity.</p>
<p>Schwerin said that technological issues threw up big obstacles for CD-ROM publishers. In 1997 alone, they have to adapt to an update of the Windows 95 operating system, the new MMX multimedia chip from Intel and the arrival of Digital Video Disc (DVD) which will succeed the CD-ROM.</p>
<p>InfoTech expects that just over four CD-ROM titels will be sold per driver in 1997.</p>
<p>A move to the internet is for publishers &quot;going from the frying pan to the fire&quot; because internet advertising revenues are forecast to contribute just one percent of the multimedia industry revenue in 1997.</p>
<p>A possible solution is to bring out hybrid products which combine discs with the internet or digital television.</p>
<p>Benedict Tompkins, of mergers and acquisitions advisors Broadview Associates, said he expected an increasing number of deals combining content, technology and communications.</p>
<p>Last week's French alliance of publisher Havas, the Cegetel telecoms unit of Generale des Eaux and pay television group Canal Plus is an illustration of this trend.</p>
<p>Another, smaller, example is NetGem. This French firm will sell a set-top box to turn a digital television into an internet terminal from April at 2,000 francs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANNES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
