<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368640" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Technology stocks may drop more.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Technology stocks may drop more.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>As U.S. technology stocks attempted to halt their recent correction, investors continued to trade both put and call options, particularly on industry bellwethers and volume leaders, traders said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Jesse Stamer, a designated primary market maker at the Chicago Board Options Exchange, said technology stocks appear to have further downside to go before recovering.</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect a little more downside,&quot; he said. &quot;It appears every morning they try to firm up and by mid-morning they're in full retreat.&quot;  </p>
<p>In late trading, the technology heavy Nasdaq composite index .IXIC was down 13.82 points at about 1,322. It had reached a session high of 1,345 in early trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a trend market,&quot; Stamer said. &quot;The sellers step away in the morning and they start to come in in mid-morning and the trend continues.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said options investors appeared to be both buying and selling throughout the sessions.</p>
<p>Put and call options on technology stocks were the most active issues on all five options exchanges.  </p>
<p>Intel Corp options led the pack, with the February 155 call trading 6,400 contracts.</p>
<p>Intel shares were down 3-3/4 at 147-7/8, off their 146-1/2 session low, on more than 16.6 million shares. The stock had risen to 154-3/4 in early trading before sliding.</p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp shares edged 1/8 higher to 142-7/8 after dropping about six points Monday.</p>
<p>At the CBOE, the IBM February 150 call was most active, with volume of about 3,750 contracts.</p>
<p>The February 145 call traded about 2,600. The February 140 and 145 puts also were busy.  </p>
<p>Options on shares of 3Com Corp remained heavily traded at the Pacific Stock Exchange, where a few Microsoft Corp options also were busy.</p>
<p>Stamer said he has seen more trading from firms rather than from retail customers and that the firms appear to be expecting more volatility in the group.</p>
<p>&quot;What's interesting is that the earnings cycle is over and they (the firms) are looking to buy February, March, April, July, all the way out,&quot; he said. &quot;So it appears the firms are expecting more volatility in the future rather than less.&quot;  </p>
<p>One leading technology company that still has quarterly earnings due is Hewlett-Packard Co, which recovered 1-1/8 to 50-1/4 after dropping 2-3/4 Monday.</p>
<p>John Streibich, in the Hewlett trading crowd at the CBOE, said volatilities in the near term options on Hewlett had climbed to the mid-50 area from around 35.</p>
<p>&quot;They're anticipating a big move,&quot; he said. &quot;The question is which way. The stock could go to 60 or it could drop back down to the 40s. It's anybody's guess.&quot;</p>
<p>He noted that other technology stocks, like IBM and Cisco Systems Inc, had big moves after reporting earnings. ((--G.Crawford, 312 408 8750/Email: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
