<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377340" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Mitsubishi says no plan to quit pinball business.</title>
<headline>Mitsubishi says no plan to quit pinball business.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mitsubishi Corp said on Thursday that it had no plan to withdraw from the business of prepaid cards for &quot;pachinko&quot; pinball machines.  </p>
<p>A Mitsubishi spokesman said the trading house had no plan to sell its stake in Japan Leisure Card System Co, which issues prepaid cards for pachinko pinball machines.</p>
<p>The card company is 18.85 percent owned by Mitsubishi and 10.05 percent owned by NTT Data Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no plan to withdraw from the business. We will support the card company with NTT Data,&quot; the Mitsubishi spokesman said.</p>
<p>The spokesman also said, however, that it was unclear whether the unit, which is saddled with debts and accumulated losses, could post profits in the year to March 31, 1997.  </p>
<p>The Mitsubishi spokesman said the card unit&quot;s liabilities exceeded its assets by 46 billion yen at the end of September 1996.</p>
<p>He said the unit has been facing difficulties due to widespread card forgery but the financial impact from the forged cards was now sharply decreasing.</p>
<p>&quot;We hear that losses from forged cards are dramatically decreasing but we don&quot;t know if the unit can post profits in this fiscal year because it has accumulated losses,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Japanese business daily Nihon Keizai Shinbun said on Thursday that the unit was expected to post a net loss in 1996/97, despite an estimated record nine trillion yen or more in sales. The paper did not specify the amount of the estimated net loss.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
