<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393743" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: INTERVIEW-Microsoft exec has advice for rivals.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Microsoft exec has advice for rivals.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp vice president Steve Ballmer had some pointed advice Thursday for competitors.</p>
<p>&quot;Netscape, Oracle and IBM are fine, smart companies. That's good, it keeps us running,&quot; said Ballmer, in charge of sales and support, at a news conference in Bogota to launch the Spanish-language version of Office 97.</p>
<p>He was referring to Netscape Communications Corp, Oracle Corp and International Business Machines Corp, the leading makers of Internet navigation, database management and computer hardware, respectively.  </p>
<p>But he also had some terse messages for the competition. Microsoft has of late been going head-to-head with Netscape, which he described as &quot;small and agile,&quot; for dominance in the Internet browser market.</p>
<p>Ballmer predicted Microsoft, based in Redmond, Wash., would edge ahead when it released its Internet Explorer 4, scheduled for June, adding the new package would &quot;integrate the desktop with the Internet&quot; in a way that Netscape cannot.  </p>
<p>He was referring to Microsoft's plans to merge Internet browsing functions directly into its Windows operating system, which is used by more than 90 percent of the world's personal computers, minimizing the need for a separate browser.</p>
<p>In a brash attempt to minimize the challenge posed by Netscape, he advised it to move into the Internet commerce and business applications or merge with Oracle if it was to mount a serious challenge.  </p>
<p>&quot;If I were Netscape, I would probably try to merge with Oracle...that would give them a far stronger base for business applications automation. I would also focus on Internet commerce. That would mean it may not grow as quickly as the stock market wanted it to, but it would mean it wasn't setting off on a crazy tangent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ballmer was also straightforward on IBM, recognizing IBM as still being the No. 1 competitor, but warned the computer giant may be heading down a &quot;bad path&quot; by turning its back on Microsoft Windows operating system in favor of Java software, which operates independently of such systems.  </p>
<p>Java is a programming language for Internet applications, and many companies are hoping that Java-based applications will displace the dominance of Windows/Intel-based PC-based software.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a smart strategy and will lead IBM further down a bad path,&quot; said Ballmer, an apparent reference to IBM's history of attempting to develop software operating systems independent of Microsoft's Windows.  </p>
<p>Ballmer was described by Forbes magazine in its January edition as Microsoft's &quot;chief coach, cheerleader and hatchet man.&quot; He is said to own $5 billion in stock of the $100 billion company.</p>
<p>On the Latin American market, he expressed optimism. He predicted company sales in Latin America would top $300 million this year and said the rate of growth was outstripping the corporation's global rise in revenues, which he put at between 25 percent and 30 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a great sophistication in the information technology community in Latin America even if the personal computer market isn't that great. We've got a good business growing quickly and the key will be to forge a greater acceptance of PCs as a fundamental tool for productivity. We're starting to see that happening,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((-- Karl Penhaul, Bogot newsroom, 571 610 7944))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
