<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400370" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Compuware CEO mulls adding jobs in Conneticut. - paper.</title>
<headline>Compuware CEO mulls adding jobs in Conneticut. - paper.</headline>
<dateline>HARTFORD 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Compuware Corp chairman and chief executive Peter Karmanos, may bring up to 1,500 high-technology jobs to the Hartford area, the Hartford Courant reported on Monday.</p>
<p>The paper quoted Karmanos, who also owns the National Hockey League Hartford Whalers, denying any link between the possible new jobs and Karmanos' efforts to get Connecticut to finance a new sports arena for the team.</p>
<p>The Whalers have said they will leave Connecticut unless the state helps build a new arena that could cost around $160 million.</p>
<p>Connecticut Governor John Rowland, a Republican, is expected to announce soon whether he will support a state-financed arena.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether the Whalers stay or not, I view the Hartford area as a prime spot for one of our development labs,&quot; Karmanos said.</p>
<p>&quot;We'd like to pursue that independently of what goes on with the Whalers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Compuware, based in Farmington Hills, Michigan, has about 5,000 employees.</p>
<p>Since its founding in 1973, it has been the dominant supplier of software for testing, debugging and maintaining large mainframe computer systems.</p>
<p>More recently, the company has grown in professional services, including helping corporations deal with updating computer systems to deal with the year 2000, or fighting the so-called millenium bug.</p>
<p>((-- Hartford newsroom 860 727-0224))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
