<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403468" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Infoseek says ads on 45-50 pct of pages.</title>
<headline>Infoseek says ads on 45-50 pct of pages.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO, Calif. 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Infoseek Corp executives said the company is currently selling advertising on 45 to 50 percent of the available page views, slightly below its 60 percent earlier levels.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first time we've been able to see some headroom,&quot; in terms of potential advertising space which could be sold, Leonard LeBlane, Infoseek chief financial officer, told Reuters at a Robertson Stephens conference.</p>
<p>Earlier, LeBlane said traffic on the Web search and information company's site is currently running at a rate of 6 million page views a day.</p>
<p>Earlier, Infoseek President and CEO Robin Johnson said the company's site ranks third on the Web in terms of advertising volume, adding that clickthrough of Infoseek ads - the number of advertising banners on which viewers actually click - is several times the industry average.</p>
<p>Clickthrough for Infoseek was around four percent, versus an average of around 1.6 percent for the industry as a whole. Infoseek is using a new capability named Ultramatch to increase the correlation between an individual user's interests and advertisers, he said.  </p>
<p>Infoseek currently has indexed approximately 75 million separate unique resource locators, or URLs, the basic addresses for finding sites on the Internet.</p>
<p>Rival search engine and Internet media company Yahoo! Inc told analysts at the conference on Monday that although only about 25 percent of its available inventory had carried ads in the last quarter, its capacity was not limited at that level.</p>
<p>Yahoo! Chief Financial Officer Gary Valenzuela said 100 percent utilization would not be realistic, but it was not inconceivable it could reach 90 percent at some point in the future.</p>
<p>Industry executives have noted that the first quarter of the calendar year tends to be a quieter period for advertising in traditional media, and this may also be the case for the fledgling Internet search firms.</p>
<p>Four search firms went public last year - Infoseek, Yahoo!, Lycos Inc and Excite Inc.</p>
<p>Lycos President and CEO Robert Dravis said his company also sold just under half, or around 45-50 percent, of the available advertising inventory in the quarter just completed to January 31.  </p>
<p>Dravis said Lycos recorded 17 percent traffic growth and said the company's licensing model assures it of more steady and predictable revenue streams on a major portion of its total revenues. ((sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau 415 846 5400))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
