<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="407435" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China to mark Hong Kong's return with video game.</title>
<headline>China to mark Hong Kong's return with video game.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>China is calling for more home-grown computer games to inspire patriotism among the young and counter a flood of politically incorrect foreign video games, the Xinhua news agency said on Thursday.</p>
<p>One game about the 1839-42 Opium War, which saw British forces humiliate a backward imperial China by wresting away the territory of Hong Kong, would be released when Beijing resumes control over the colony on July 1 this year, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Though China lost the war in history, players of the games can... gain a better understanding of... the impact of the war on the development of modern China, thereby inspiring patriotism for modern-day China,&quot; Xinhua said.</p>
<p>Foreign video games had captured 98 percent of the Chinese market and 70 percent of such imported games &quot;advocate violence, terrorism or greed&quot;, Xinhua said, quoting a survey conducted by Qinghua University.</p>
<p>&quot;Around five percent contain pornographic material, and three percent promote Nazism and militarism,&quot; the agency quoted the survey as saying.</p>
<p>Qinghua invested 2.0 million yuan ($240,000) in the first half of 1996 in developing video games that could instill patriotism in their young players, the agency said.</p>
<p>Another game was based on the experiences of Chinese pilots who shot down more than 300 U.S. fighter planes in the 1951-53 Korean War, Xinhua said.</p>
<p>&quot;Such games have long been overlooked as an educational tool that could promote cultural and ethical progress,&quot; Xinhua quoted Tian Yong, president of a Beijing secondary school, as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;It is impossible to prevent them (students) from playing video games,&quot; Tian said. &quot;The best thing we can do is provide them with good games.&quot;</p>
<p>China's communist rulers have increasingly sought to use patriotism to replace fading Marxist values that have been eroded by nearly two decades of market-oriented economic reforms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
