<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410962" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: FEATURE - India software firms see billions in a bug.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - India software firms see billions in a bug.</headline>
<byline>Hanif Arafat</byline>
<dateline>BANGALORE, India 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Y2K sounds like the name of a character from a science-fiction movie.</p>
<p>In this south Indian city, hundreds of software experts are working hard to turn it into a multi-billion dollar reality.</p>
<p>Indian software companies are racing against time to grab business from a huge market emerging from computers that were not tuned to account for the end of a millennium, called the Y2K (Year 2000) problem by industry professionals.</p>
<p>Companies in Bangalore, called India's Silicon Valley because of its low-cost, high-skill software writers, are pitching for deals to set right the internal time mechanism of computers that need correction.</p>
<p>&quot;India is an automatic choice. I would imagine that India should rake in at least 10 percent of the global market share,&quot; said S.K. Mitra, chief executive of BAeHAL, a venture formed by British Aerospace and state-run Hindustan Aeronautics Ltd (HAL).</p>
<p>&quot;India can boast of technology as well as skills at 40 percent less than the rate in the West,&quot; Mitra told Reuters.</p>
<p>HUGE MARKET POTENTIAL</p>
<p>According to one U.S. estimate, the global market in Y2K solutions is estimated anywhere between $300 and $600 billion. But leading Indian officials say this is not realistic.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that the international market for this is anywhere between $60 and 100 billion,&quot; Dewang Mehta, executive director of India's National Association of Software and Service Companies (Nasscom), told Reuters in New Delhi.</p>
<p>Software corrections are needed to save the data and functioning of thousands of computers built at a time when the &quot;Millenium Bug&quot; was not anticipated.</p>
<p>Mehta said Nasscom formed a task force called SIG-Y2K (special interest group-Y2K), which held a seminar in Luxembourg last October, in which 48 international banks took part and listened to officials from 17 Indian companies.</p>
<p>Fourteen of the 17 came back with orders, Mehta said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are doing a second series of seminars in May in the United States and in June in Britain,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;With all these efforts we might be able to get $2-5 billion in the next three years.&quot;</p>
<p>The government of the state of Karnataka some years ago set up an &quot;Electronics City,&quot; which offered facilities with high-speed satellite communication links that helped firms talk round the clock with customers in far corners of the globe.</p>
<p>The offshore software business, as it is now called, has become a favourite theme for many other state governments, which are racing to set up &quot;information technology parks.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;More and more companies in the United States, Japan and Europe are looking towards India to overcome the Millenium Bug problem,&quot; said Ajit Chakravarti, executive vice-president of Mindware, the export division of Pertech Computers Ltd (PCL).</p>
<p>PCL recently tied up with Japan's NEC Corp, which also has a partnership for Y2K work with Madras-based Square D Software Ltd</p>
<p>THE JAPANESE ARE COMING</p>
<p>&quot;We are NEC's major partner here and and the contract is quite substantial,&quot; Chakravarti said, adding that his engineers were being taught Japanese to help them an advantage.</p>
<p>&quot;All our contracts with the U.S. and Japanese companies are in the region of $25 million,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>PCL was eyeing a $50 million business in Calcutta and might turn down new clients by 1998, he said.</p>
<p>Infosys Technologies, often cited as the biggest Indian software success, offers Japanese courses to its 1,000-odd employees to help offshore solutions in Y2K.</p>
<p>Infosys is one of the five Indian companies that formed a consortium called Jasdic Park with five Japanese firms including Hitachi Ltd and Fuji Data Control.</p>
<p>Around 15-20 percent of the consortium's business will come from Y2K, said N.R. Narayana Murthy, Infosys' chairman.</p>
<p>Infosys also has a partnership with U.S.-based Platinum Technology, a leading tool vendor on the IBM mainframe computer platforms which need Y2K solutions.</p>
<p>BIG-TICKET CUSTOMERS</p>
<p>BAeHAL's Mitra said his firm had been awarded Millennium-related contracts by a major international airline and a leading U.S.-based group, but declined to give more details.</p>
<p>Satish Bangalore, chief executive of Command International Software, a subsidiary of the U.S. insurance firm Phoenix Home Life Insurance, said his company was targeting the insurance industry for high-growth business.</p>
<p>While many firms see a fast buck in the Y2K bug, Pradeep Kar, chairman of Microland Ltd sounded a note of caution.</p>
<p>&quot;It is indeed an opportunity, but there must be an optimum mix,&quot; Kar said. &quot;We need to invest in leading edge technologies. Y2K will only solve the problems of old technology.&quot;</p>
<p>India's software industry is expected to close the current 1996/97 (April-March) fiscal year with a growth rate of 50 percent, Mehta said.</p>
<p>Exports are expected to fetch 39 billion rupees and internal sales 25 billion, accounting for a total of $1.8 billion worth of business. In 1995/96, India exported 25.2 billion rupees of software and sold 16.7 billion rupees worth at home, accounting for $1.2 billion in all. ($1=35.8 rupees)  </p>
<p>INFRASTRUCTURE:</p>
<p>* The Infrastructure Development Finance Company has been incorporated. Section 80IA of the Income Tax Act grants a five year tax holiday for certain infrastructure projects. Last month, I announced that telecommunication will qualify as infrastructure. I now propose to add Oil Exploration and Industrial Parks to this category.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>* I am also glad to announce that the vexed question of assignability of telecom licences has been resolved and that tripartite agreements are proposed to be entered into among the Department of Telecommunications, the licencee and the lenders.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>* As Commerce Minister, I proposed in the Exim Policy that supply of goods to oil, gas and power projects, if the supplies are made under the procedure of international competitive bidding, should be given the benefits of 'deemed exports'. As Finance Minister, I am glad to accept this wholesome proposal. Details are being notified separately.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>* The National Highway Authority of India (NHAI) is now geared to implement the new policy on roads and highways. I propose to enhance budget support for NHAI to Rs.500 crore which is a significant step up from Rs.200 crore provided in the current year.</p>
<p>FOREIGN INVESTMENT:</p>
<p>* Foreign Institutional investors (FIIs) continue to repose great confidence in India. Net FII investment in India is now over U$$ 7 billion. During the course of this year I have expanded the opportunities for such investments. I propose to take one more step at the instance of Indian companies. The limit of aggregate investment in a company by FIIs, NRIs and NRI-OCBs is now 24%. I propose to allow companies to raise this limit to 30%, subject to the condition that the Board Directors of the company approves the limit and the general body of the company passes a special resolution in this behalf.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>* Venture capital funds are important vehicles for stimulating investments in new ventures. Under the present guidelines they can invest upto 5% of their corpus in the equity of any single company. This is unduly restrictive. The limit is being increased to 20%.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CAPITAL MARKET</p>
<p>* Over 20 million Indians have invested their savings in the capital market. The establishment of the first Depository was an important step taken to bring the Indian capital market upto world standards and to protect the interests of the investors. SEBI was asked to suggest more measures. The committee appointed by me to draft a new Companies Bill has also made valuable suggestions. After considering these suggestions, I propose to accept five recommendations.</p>
<p>+ The principle of buy-back of shares by companies subject to certain conditions will be introduced in the Companies Act;</p>
<p>+ The provision of Sections 370 and 372 of the Companies Act will be merged and an overall ceiling of 60 percent will be kept for intercorporate investment and loans;</p>
<p>+ The Companies Act will be amended to provide for nomination facilities for holders of securities;</p>
<p>+ Companies raising funds from the capital market will be required to give an annual statement disclosing the end-use of such funds; and</p>
<p>+ One time permission will be given to stockbrokers to corporatise their businesses without attracting tax on capital gains, which will be exempted.</p>
<p>I am of the firm view that markets will prosper when economic growth continues to be strong, the fiscal deficit is reduced, interest rates decline and investors are reassured that their interests are secure.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>FERA AND MONEY LAUNDERING:</p>
<p>* As we progress towards a more open economy with greater trade and investment linkages with the rest of the world, the regulations governing foreign exchange transactions also need to be modernised. It is generally acknowledged that the Foreign Exchange Regulation Act, 1973 needs to be replaced by a new law consistent with full current account convertibility and our objective of progressively liberalising capital account transactions. Hence, I propose to introduce, later this year a Bill titled 'The Foreign Exchange Management Act'. An RBI appointed group is expected to complete the drafting of the Bill shortly.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>* While FERA is being replaced, we will not let up in our effort to curb the laundering of ill-gotten money. A Bill dealing with money laundering is under preparation and I propose to introduce it during this session of Parliament.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CAPITAL ACCOUNT CONVERTIBILITY:</p>
<p>* A little while ago I made a reference to capital account convertibility. We are proud of our foreign exchange earners. They have been given the facility of the Export Earners Foreign Currency (EEFC) Account. At present, the total amount in these accounts is a modest Rs.2000 crore, I propose to expand the scope of the account by allowing the following facilities:</p>
<p>+ To open offices abroad and to meet the expenses thereof; and</p>
<p>+ To make investments from the balance in the account in overseas joint ventures upto the limit of U$$ 15 million, without reference to the RBI.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>* I also believe that the time has come for preparatory work towards capital account convertibility. This is a cherished goal. It is also a matter of great sensitivity. Hence, I shall not make any commitment. For the present, I am asking RBI to appoint a group of experts to lay out the road map towards capital account convertibility, prescribe the economic parameters which have to be achieved at each milestone and work out a detailed time table for achieving the goal. I believe the appointment of such a group will send a powerful signal to the world about our determination to join the ranks of front-line nations.</p>
<p>SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY:</p>
<p>* My last budget was viewed in certain quarters as science and technology-friendly. Flattery has its rewards, and I intend to strengthen my friendship with the scientific community. I propose to take the following initiatives;</p>
<p>+ The scheme to match every additional commercial rupee earned by CSIR and ICAR laboratories, as well as the IITs, will continue on a permanent basis.</p>
<p>+ The Technology Development Board, established to accelerate the commercialisation of indigenous technology has identified 16 projects that are commercially viable in the fields of agriculture, health, chemicals and pharmaceuticals. In 1996-97, I provided Rs.30 crore to the Technology Development Fund. I propose to increase the allocation in 1997-98 to Rs.70 crore.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>* Tomorrow's technology is based on today's science. I am concerned that there is declining interest in the learning of sciences in schools and colleges. I hold the view that an MBA - even if he is from Harvard - is not a patch on a scientist. On the occasion of the 50th anniversary of our Independence, we will launch the &quot;Swarnajayanti&quot; fellowships. Outstanding scientists below the age of 45 will be assisted to attain and sustain world class levels in science. A sum of 500 million rupees in the Department of Education's budget will be used to create a corpus. The Minister of State for Science and Technology will announce the details of the science.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>* Closer linkages have to be developed between Indian industry and publicly-funded research laboratories. Hence, I propose to allow government-promoted societies recognised by the Department of Scientific and Industrial Research and notified under the Income Tax Act to invest in the equity of private sector companies. These institutions will invest not money but their knowledge and know-how as their equity.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY:</p>
<p>* If there is one science that will dominate the 21st century, it is information technology. If there is one industry in which India can emerge as a world leader, it is information technology. However, for this potential to be realised, we need a completely new policy for manufacturing and marketing IT products. The Electonic Hardware Technology Park (EHTP) Scheme, presently in force, gives limited flexibility. There is an imperative need to increase production volumes and attract foreign direct investment. Accordingly, it has been decided that EHTP/EOU/EPZ units in electronic hardware may be permitted to sell one half of the value of their products, during any 12 month period, in the domestic market will be on payment of excise duty equivalent to full customs duty, including the additional duty of customs. Details of the new unified manufacturing scheme will be incorporated in the new EXIM policy that will be effective from April 1, 1997.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>COMPANIES ACT AND DIRECT TAXES ACT:</p>
<p>* Hon'ble Members will recall that  I had set up an expert group to draft a new Companies Bill and another expert committee to prepare a new Direct Taxes Bill. Both groups have done splendid work and have submitted their reports. Copies of the reports will be placed in the Parliament Library next week. They will also be distributed widely. A working draft of each Bill will also be circulated as soon as it is ready. It is my hope that there will be wide and informed debate on this bill. It is my intention to bring the new Companies Bill before this House in the monsoon session and the New Direct Taxes Bill in the winter session.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGALORE, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
