<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="411697" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German software upstart finalizing listing plans.</title>
<headline>German software upstart finalizing listing plans.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software maker Star Division GmbH had its best year ever in 1996 and said it was winding down preparations for its planned listing on the Nasdaq stock exchange in the United States.</p>
<p>Star Division is one of the few software companies in Germany that appear to be having any success in muscling into the core market for desktop software controlled by U.S. software giant Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>On the back of its recent successes at home, the company has embarked on a course of European expansion and with its listing it hopes to find strategic partners to help it carve out a stake on the fiercely competitive U.S. software market.</p>
<p>The flotation would take place in two steps and could begin with a private placement of around 10 percent of its equity with a strategic partner in the U.S. by the end of June.</p>
<p>A public placement of 15 percent of its shares would follow in the fourth quarter with a listing on the Nasdaq computer index. Another 15 percent would be offered to employees.</p>
<p>&quot;We are finalizing plans to form a holding company in the U.S.,&quot; Star Division founder Marco Boerries told Reuters in an interview this week.</p>
<p>&quot;We are talking with prospective partners about the private placement, which could be done by the end of June. I would prefer to complete the public placement in the fourth quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>Boerries will keep control of over 50 percent of the firm.</p>
<p>Star Division is a rare breed of enterprise in Germany, resembling the youthful dynamism found at a Silicon Valley start-up in sharp contrast to the staid button-down image of Germany's blue-chips or the plodding Mittelstand.</p>
<p>Besides SAP AG, the hugely successful business software maker, no German software group has achieved international success that parallels the likes of U.S. firms such as Microsoft, Lotus Development or Netscape Communications.</p>
<p>While Microsoft's latest products will only run on its newest operating systemes -- Windows 95 and Windows NT -- Star Division creates its programmes for all operating systems, including the older Windows 3.1, IBM's OS/2, Unix, which is popular at universities, and the Unix offshoot Linux.</p>
<p>&quot;When we entered the market in 1986 Microsoft already had over 50 percent market share,&quot; said Boerries.</p>
<p>&quot;There have always been companies like Borland or Lotus that had 60 percent or more in markets where Microsoft was not active. But then enters Microsoft and wham.&quot;</p>
<p>Last year marked a turning point for Star Division.</p>
<p>While the software industry whirled with visions of the Internet and it looked like Microsoft was losing ground to an upstart called Netscape, Star Division introduced the first office &quot;suite&quot; that was fully integrated with the Internet.</p>
<p>So-called suites are typically a bundle of programmes that allow office workers to perform all daily tasks and organize their work. Microsoft owns about 80 percent of the world suite market with its Microsoft Office.</p>
<p>But Star Office version 3.1 was the first of the suites to allow users to view, edit and publish documents on the World Wide Web, nearly a year before Microsoft added this function.</p>
<p>Sales have soared. After shipping just 200,000 copies of Star Office in Germany in 1995, the number jumped to over 860,000 last year and it added versions in Dutch, Italian, French, Spanish and English, selling more than one million copies in total.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in a new phase. We are encountering demand that we cannot even fulfill. The big challenge facing us now is not the technology, but rather managing our expansion,&quot; said Boerries.</p>
<p>Boerries said he believed the company's German market share rose significantly in 1996 from industry estimates of a 22 percent share in 1995, but he gave no figures.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
