<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41348" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gates, not Murdoch, tops media heap - Vanity Fair.</title>
<headline>Gates, not Murdoch, tops media heap - Vanity Fair.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft wizard Bill Gates has bumped Rupert Murdoch from the top spot in the information age's &quot;New Establishment,&quot; according to Vanity Fair's annual list of 50 media leaders.</p>
<p>Gates won, the magazine said on Monday, because he overhauled his company to meet a challenge from upstart Netscape and raised the stock value of Microsoft to $18 billion from $13 billion.</p>
<p>He also got into television with all-news MSNBC; started an on-line magazine, &quot;Slate&quot;; and published the bestselling &quot;The Road Ahead&quot; -- all while celebrating his 40th birthday.</p>
<p>Vanity Fair also said Gates, No. 2 on its list last year behind Murdoch, &quot;retained the title of 'scariest man' too, by throwing money at every opportunity and obstacle in Microsoft's path.&quot;</p>
<p>Murdoch did not have a bad year either, the magazine said. It said the Australian-born media baron's $20 billion empire got bigger when he bought New World Communications' U.S. TV stations, putting him in 35 percent of American homes while he made the deals allowing him to set up an all-news cable station to compete with CNN.</p>
<p>Listed as No. 3 was Walt Disney Co. head Michael Eisner, the same as last year. No. 4 was Time Warner Inc. chairman Gerald Levin, who moved up two notches, even though his company's stock price hit its year's low recently.</p>
<p>Vanity Fair asked: &quot;What do you do if you're the lackluster chairman of a vast media conglomerate burdened by enormous debt and irritated shareholders? ... Here's an idea -- buy Turner Broadcasting System. If nothing else, the $6.5 billion merger will ensure that your empire remains the biggest in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Rounding out the top 10 were Intel Corp. president Andrew Grove, Allen Co. chief  Herbert Allen, Tele-Communications Inc. president John Malone, Viacom Inc. chairman Sumner Redstone, IBM head Louis Gerstner and DreamWorks SKG co-founder David Geffen.</p>
<p>The biggest jump on the list was made by Gordon Crawford, No. 44 last year and 19 this, thanks to his control of large chunks of America Online, Time Warner and Turner Broadcasting.</p>
<p>Director Steven Spielberg, No. 8 on the list last year, was at No. 17, while &quot;Star Wars&quot; creator George Lucas, No. 40 last year, rose 12 places after his special-effects house, Industrial Light &amp; Magic, contributed to a string of Hollywood hits, including &quot;Twister&quot; and &quot;Mission Impossible.&quot;</p>
<p>Once-imprisoned junk bond king Michael Milken made No. 12, thanks to his behind-the-scenes work on several major media mergers, including helping Ted Turner sell his empire to Time Warner.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
