<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414684" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: News Corp sells Japan TV shares for JSkyB support.</title>
<headline>News Corp sells Japan TV shares for JSkyB support.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian media giant News Corp and Japan's Softbank Corp, which shocked Japan last year by quietly taking a stake in a national TV network, said on Monday they were giving up their stake to one of the network's Japanese parents.</p>
<p>But they said that in return they had secured the cooperation of a major Japanese media conglomerate for their Japan Sky Broadcasting Co, or JSkyB, a digital satellite TV project with Sony Corp which will start beaming digital channels in Japan in April.</p>
<p>News Corp and Softbank, Japan's biggest software distributor, said that they decided to sell their shares in Asahi National Broadcasting Co (TV Asahi) because of strong requests from other shareholders, most notably the mass-circulation daily Asahi Shimbun, the biggest shareholder.</p>
<p>&quot;We decided to respond to the strong request from the Asahi Shimbun because in return, we were given assurance that we will get further support (from Asahi) for the launch of JSkyB,&quot; Softbank's president Masayoshi Son told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;News Corp has had friendly relationships with Asahi Shimbun going back to some years ago,&quot; News Corp chairman Rupert Murdoch, who made a surprise, unannounced appearance at the Tokyo news conference, said.</p>
<p>&quot;(Today's agreement) will become a new chapter in our relationship. We wish to work together for our mutual benefit,&quot; Murdoch added.</p>
<p>He said there were four reasons why the sale would lead to friendlier relations. First, News Corp was in the same position as Asahi in wanting to strengthen its terrestrial broadcasting networks.</p>
<p>Second, News Corp would not be investing in any other existing Japanese networks, and third, it was his &quot;dream&quot; to provide Japanese television viewers with a range of choices by successfully launching JSkyB.</p>
<p>The final reason, Murdoch said, was that Asahi Shimbun had agreed to give its blessing to JSkyB itself.</p>
<p>Contractual relationships did not last long, he said, but &quot;what we really need for the successful launch of JSkyB is to build a true relationship of trust.&quot;</p>
<p>The sale to Asahi Shimbun of 5,136 shares will be made at 41.75 billion yen ($345 million), the same amount paid by News Corp and Softbank in June 1996.</p>
<p>The acquisition last year of TV Asahi stakes came as a surprise to TV Asahi shareholders as Softbank had quietly arranged the purchase through another Japanese company called Obunsha Media.</p>
<p>&quot;The aquisition of stakes in TV Asahi was made in a unique way...But we would like to cooperate as much as possible now that they have kindly agreed to our requests,&quot; Asahi Shimbun president Muneyuki Matsushita told the news conference.</p>
<p>Analysts at that time of sale said News Corp's entry into the cozy industry, normally immune to realignments, could force more competition into terrestrial broadcasting at a time when Asian TV services and satellite broadcasters were stepping up their offensives.</p>
<p>Broadcasters, now enjoying large income from advertisers under a strict licensing system, said the News Corp move was one they had never expected.</p>
<p>TV Asahi's shareholders declared to Softbank that they would not accept board members from Softbank or News Corp unless they confirmed in a written statement that they would refrain from purchasing any more shares of TV Asahi.</p>
<p>TV Asahi, citing requests from other big shareholders, also asked Softbank and News Corp for written confirmation that they would not be involved in the management of the company.</p>
<p>TV Asahi plans to list its shares on the Japanese stock market within a few years.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the aggressively expanding Softbank, which late last year tapped deeply into Japan's financial markets to fund a string of bold buy-outs, said the reason behind its planned sale was not financial.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no reason for us to sell the (TV Asahi) shares from a financial viewpoint,&quot; Son said.</p>
<p>On JSKyB, Son said the three partners were negotiating as &quot;equals&quot; over how to launch the project.</p>
<p>&quot;We're working very closely with Sony,&quot; Murdoch said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
