<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415533" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Summit Medical to restate revenues downward.</title>
<headline>Summit Medical to restate revenues downward.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Summit Medical Systems Inc. said Monday it expects to revise downward its reported revenues for at least last year and announced that its new chief financial officer, who had discovered accounting discrepancies, had resigned after less than a week on the job.</p>
<p>Summit said its 1996 revenues will be &quot;substantially less&quot; than the $19.5 million it previously reported, and added that it probably will also revise downward its revenues for 1995 and 1994.</p>
<p>Summit's stock plunged $1.50, or almost 70 percent, to $3.25 in early trading on the Nasdaq market.</p>
<p>The Minneapolis-based company also announced that it planned to eliminate an unspecified number of jobs and establish a cost reduction programme to reduce annual expenses by 20 percent.</p>
<p>Summit said a preliminary review of its books indicated that revenues for the past three years had been overstated by between $4 million and $6 million -- or between 8 percent and 12 percent of the total.</p>
<p>Last Wednesday Summit, which provides information services and systems for the healthcare industry, reported 1996 revenues of $19.5 million, up from $17.7 million in 1995.</p>
<p>The exact size of the adjustments to revenue and the years in which they apply will not be determined until an extensive audit is completed, the company said Monday.</p>
<p>Summit also said that Donald Haas, who joined the company as chief financial officer last Monday, resigned Saturday -- after informing management that some 1996 revenue had been incorrectly recognised.</p>
<p>The company said that Haas told management on Thursday -- a day after the company reported its 1996 results -- that it had incorrectly recognised revenue during 1996 in some circumstances. Management immediately began a review of these issues, it added.</p>
<p>&quot;The company's auditors, Ernst &amp; Young LLP, have expanded the scope of their audit and are performing additional audit procedures based in part on the questions raised by Mr. Haas,&quot; Summit said in its statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The incorrect recognition of revenue resulted from the erroneous application of its revenue recognition accounting policies to sales of software and related services,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Summit added that it had retained the law firm Dorsey &amp; Whitney LLP to initiate an investigation of the matter with the assistance of independent accounting advice from Arthur Andersen LLP.</p>
<p>The company said it expected to announce corrected financial information by the end of March.</p>
<p>&quot;Summit Medical is extremely concerned by the discovery of accounting errors and is working vigorously to correct past mistakes and to establish stricter management controls and policies,&quot; Chief Executive Kevin Green said.</p>
<p>The company also said that the cost-reduction programme announced Monday will result in an unspecified charge in the current quarter for employee severance and other costs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
