<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416304" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: FORECAST-Singapore IT firms '96 profits seen flat.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Singapore IT firms '96 profits seen flat.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most of Singapore's electronic firms are expected to report flat earnings growth for the 1996 financial year, hit by a global slump in the industry, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Few companies are expected to buck the trend with double-digit growth, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The results we are waiting for are likely to be flat at zero to 5.0 percent in earnings growth,&quot; said Patrick Yau, analyst at Schroders Securities.</p>
<p>Ng Eng Hou at Keppel Securities said he expected most companies to post single digit net profit growth.</p>
<p>Most Singapore electronics firms are scheduled to report their earnings for the financial year ended December 1996 this month.</p>
<p>The global electronics industry suffered from excess inventories and sluggish demand last year.</p>
<p>Contract manufacturers, which make up the bulk of Singapore electronic firms, were likely to turn in dull results, the analysts said.</p>
<p>Earnings for end-product companies, like personal computer distributors and multimedia firms, were likely to be mixed, they said.</p>
<p>But the analysts singled out Venture Manufacturing as one of the few exceptions, a contract manufacturer expected to report double-digit growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Venture makes high-value modules and intermediate components and is likely to escape the trend,&quot; said Yau.</p>
<p>He said Venture's net profits were likely to be 39 percent higher at Singapore S$30.46 million (US$21.45 million).</p>
<p>&quot;They managed to hold their costs down and it has a diversified customer base and so would not be as badly hit as the others,&quot; said another analyst of Venture.</p>
<p>Views on PC manufacturers and distributors varied.</p>
<p>Some analysts projected flat results from Acer Computer International (ACI) while others were optimistic it would still turn in growth in the mid teens.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Acer will be disappointing with zero to five percent growth,&quot; said an analyst at a foreign broking house.</p>
<p>Ng at Keppel Securities thought ACI, a unit of Taiwan's Acer Inc, could manage a 15 percent rise in net profit to S$35.7 million. But this was unspectacular compared to 1995's growth of 21.5 percent, he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said ACI, which distributes PCs in the Asia- Pacific region, saw its sales hurt by labour unrest in South Korea.</p>
<p>Its low-priced, stripped-down PCs did not have a flying start in 1996 but should do better in 1997, they said.</p>
<p>The analysts said IPC Corp was a wild card because of financial problems at its South Korean subsidiary.</p>
<p>&quot;They may write off their Korean losses in 1996 to start 1997 on a clean slate, said Ng at Keppel.</p>
<p>He said if IPC managed to report profits, it would likely be S$1.0 to S$2.0 million. But it could lose around S$20 million.</p>
<p>Korea First Bank said in January that IPC Corporation (Korea) Ltd defaulted on repaying 570 billion won (US$657,000) worth of promissory notes.</p>
<p>IPC said in February it estimated its Korean exposure to be S$45.5 million.</p>
<p>Expectations for multimedia company Aztech, which had been hit by a copyright dispute with rival Creative Technology Ltd, were also mixed.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people expect a loss for Aztech but I am projecting negative 37 percent growth at S$16 million,&quot; said Ng.</p>
<p>US$1.00 = S$1.42 = 867 won</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
