<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418405" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Gates to help India bid to become software major.</title>
<headline>Gates to help India bid to become software major.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp chairman Bill Gates said on Tuesday that India had the potential to become a computer software superpower and promised help to New Delhi in building its vital communications infrastructure.</p>
<p>&quot;To be a leader in the digital economy of the 21st century, India must invest in basic infrastructure, education and information technology,&quot; Gates, who arrived in India on Monday on a four-day visit, said in a speech on information technology.</p>
<p>&quot;These are the tools which will drive the country into the future and make India an economic and software superpower.&quot;</p>
<p>Gates, whose visit was celebrated with lead stories in newspapers, said he discussed India's need for an information infrastructure, especially in telecommunications, with Prime Minister H. D.Deve Gowda over breakfast on Tuesday.</p>
<p>On Monday, he met with Finance Minister P. Chidambaram.</p>
<p>&quot;The key things they are talking about are opportunities for India and for investment,&quot; Gates told a news conference.</p>
<p>Gates was described as the &quot;Wizard of Windows,&quot; &quot;Sultan of Software&quot; and &quot;Infotech czar&quot; by newspapers in India, where thousands of software engineers see him as a success story to emulate in a high-growth industry.</p>
<p>India's software industry, which reported sales worth $1.2 billion in 1995/96 (April-March), expects to grow by 50 percent to $1.8 billion in the 1996/97 fiscal that ends this month.</p>
<p>The 41-year-old Gates, one of the richest men in the world, owns 25 percent of Microsoft, and his personal stake was estimated at $23 billion last December.</p>
<p>Microsoft was committed to establishing India as a global pool of talent and resources in computer software and to build in the country a national infrastructure to help computer connections and communications facilities, Gates said.</p>
<p>&quot;India has a great reputation for having world-class universities, particularly the IITs (Indian Institute of Technology) for companies like Microsoft which has sourced a lot of our really great engineers (from there),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gates launched the University Advanced Technology Labs (UATL) Programme in five Indian universities, where Microsoft would invest nearly $1 million to help set up research laboratories that will teach Microsoft software skills.</p>
<p>&quot;This is something we can build on as the years go on,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Education is going to be the engine of growth for the Indian information technology industry and for all industries in the 21st century,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Microsoft would also provide access to its Windows NT networking software codes to computer programmers in these institutions, Gates said.</p>
<p>Asked whether he was in India to sell software or to boost India's software writers, Gates replied that the two issues were linked. As software developers use Microsoft tools, both would gain, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
