<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421197" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 'Golden Gate' CD-ROM Lacks Real Riches.</title>
<headline>'Golden Gate' CD-ROM Lacks Real Riches.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here's a nice premise for an adventure story: An ancient treasure protected by an evil spirit has been hidden somewhere in San Francisco. You have to find it, and hope you don't go mad (as previous treasure hunters have) if you mess up.</p>
<p>Which brings us to &quot;Golden Gate&quot; (Panasonic Interactive, Windows95/Macintosh, $45), a CD-ROM game where the premise may be creative, but the execution leaves plenty to be desired.</p>
<p>&quot;Golden Gate&quot; offers virtual tours -- in the form of images from several vantage points -- of landmarks like Chinatown, Golden Gate Park, Lombard Street and Fisherman's Wharf, complete with pleasant New Age-style music for each location.</p>
<p>Instead of conventional computer graphics, all of the scenery is depicted in watercolors. The game boasts of more than 2,000 hand-painted images, which give &quot;Golden Gate&quot; a distinctive look. The scenery sometimes seems so real, one might suspect the developers used photographs that had been painted over.</p>
<p>The controls for &quot;Golden Gate&quot; are delightfully simple.</p>
<p>The shape of the cursor shows if there is something on the screen that needs to opened, moved or examined. Experienced gamers will find it too easy, but less serious players will be glad to avoid the annoyance of having to use the mouse to click on virtually every item on the screen. It lets players focus on the nine puzzles that must be solved to get through about 10 percent of the game.</p>
<p>But although &quot;Golden Gate&quot; is set in a real city, it never seems to get a firm grip on reality.</p>
<p>Players are supposed to be looking for the lost treasure of King William. It's not clear why, or why anyone would go looking for clues at the various landmarks. Some old film clips of San Francisco are thrown in for no apparent reason. After a video shows a woman burying a diary in the sand, the pages are inexplicably found in a broken bottle next to the water.</p>
<p>&quot;Golden Gate&quot; boasts of an &quot;insane mode&quot; that begins if you make a major miscalculation and incite the wrath of the enigmatic &quot;beast&quot; that guards the treasure map. Yet the demonic beast isn't particularly scary, and the insane mode isn't particularly weird. The colours simply go out of whack and you occasionally hear a deep voice talking to you.</p>
<p>Actually, I thought I was in the insane mode when I was playing the regular portion of the game. When I went to the old mission and looked up, there were places where images of a monk and a Joan of Arc-type figure swept across the screen. Both were cut off at the knees like cheap cardboard cutouts. And every time I stopped in a spot at the Cliffhouse, I heard a disembodied voice saying &quot;Hey, you followin' me?&quot; when there was nobody around.</p>
<p>In fact, aside from an occasional video with human characters, there's NOBODY in this game. Although it's broad daylight, there's no traffic and there are no pedestrians in one of America's liveliest cities. The only movement or sign of life comes from the occasional flapping flag, or an animated bug or rat. That's okay for other computer games, where the developers have used locations where they don't have to create and animate lots of human figures, but it's downright spooky here.</p>
<p>Perhaps the game should have been named after the atomic weapon that wipes out living creatures, but keeps structures intact. So call it &quot;Neutron Bomb.&quot; It's appropriate in more ways than one.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>My review of &quot;Discworld II: Mortality Bytes!&quot; two weeks ago produced a spurt of e-mail chastising me for neglecting to mention that the CD-ROM is based on the series of &quot;Discworld&quot; books by Terry Pratchett.</p>
<p>Although his work is especially popular in Britain, he's got plenty of fans in the United States, including one acquaintance who was scandalised that I was unfamilar with Pratchett's work.</p>
<p>Several correspondents suggested that Pratchett's books are funnier than the CD-ROM, and one helpful writer reports that Pratchett has three Usenet groups on the Internet dedicated to him: alt.books.pratchett, alt.fan.pratchett and alt.fan.pratchett.announce.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Freddi Fish and Luther's Water Worries&quot; and &quot;Freddi Fish and Luther's Maze Madness&quot; (Humongous Entertainment, Windows/Macintosh, $15 each) -- Two arcade games based on the popular animated fish. In the first, the duo have to pop air bubbles to keep the ocean from draining. In the second, they have to manoeuvre through more than 50 maze-like underwater caves. Both are for ages 3 to 8.</p>
<p>&quot;MasterClips 101,000 Premium Image Collection&quot; (IMSI, Macintosh, $60) -- Let's figure this out. If you used four of these drawing or photographic files per day every year, you wouldn't run out of images for another 70 years. You get 17 images per penny. The three volumes showing which images are on the nine disks measures 2-1/2 inches thick. There's almost too much here to comprehend. The Windows version came out last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Print Shop Press Writer&quot; (Broderbund, Windows95, $40) -- This newest addition to the popular Print Shop series helps people do text-oriented projects such as newsletters, resumes, booklets and brochures.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
