<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424421" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: DUTCH CAP GEMINI 96 PROFIT JUMPS 25 PCT.</title>
<headline>DUTCH CAP GEMINI 96 PROFIT JUMPS 25 PCT.</headline>
<byline>Wendy Braanker</byline>
<dateline>UTRECHT, Netherlands 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Software firm Cap Gemini NV said on Thursday 1996 net profits jumped 25.3 percent to 90.2 million guilders on the back of healthy sales growth across all its divisions.</p>
<p>The company, 58 percent-owned by France's Cap Gemini SA said it expected further market growth in 1997, but that it was too early to give a firm forecast of full-year earnings.</p>
<p>It said it would hike its 1996 dividend to 1.75 guilders per share, a rise of 30 percent on the 1.35 guilders of 1995.</p>
<p>Net profit margins rose to 9.1 percent in 1996 from 8.5 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the highest profit margin among Dutch software firms,&quot; co-chairman Berend Brix told a results news conference.</p>
<p>Brix said Cap Gemini's net margins were some 30 to 50 percent higher than the overall market.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot improve our net profit margin relative to the overall market as it is already extremely high,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the market declines, so will our margins, but if the market shows a healthy increase we will also benefit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cap Gemini said it was keen to boost turnover from Information System Management, which currently accounts for some 6.2 percent of group turnover, to around 20 percent.</p>
<p>It said it expected no major sales boost from computer systems updates to cope with the millennium and the advent of a single European currency, despite some upbeat remarks from competitors earlier.</p>
<p>Dutch electronics firm Getronics said last week systems and programme updates would generate some 10 billion guilders in additional turnover on the Dutch market.</p>
<p>Getronics said then it expected to capture around five percent of the market growth.</p>
<p>But Cap Gemini's Brix said he did not believe the market would grow as a result.</p>
<p>&quot;Our clients are making the changes to their systems themselves or reducing other information technology spending so as not to increase their budget,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cap Gemini shares rose 2.20 guilders to 70.00  at 1300 GMT on Thursday after briefly touching a high of 70.40 earlier. REUTER/WGB lvl</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UTRECHT, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
