<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424921" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Bill Gates predicts on-line future for Africa.</title>
<headline>Bill Gates predicts on-line future for Africa.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bill Gates, computer guru and chief executive of U.S. software giant Microsoft, said Thursday the Internet was poised to open up Africa to the world.</p>
<p>The continent's image as technologically backward was unfounded, and the Internet was enormously important for economic development, Gates told a news conference at the start of a business visit to South Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;The Internet is the single most important tool that will open Africa up to the rest of the world. It is the future of communication worldwide and Africa is not as far behind as some people believe,&quot; Gates said.</p>
<p>Microsoft is expanding in Africa using South Africa as a base. Last month the software giant opened offices in Kenya and Ivory Coast and it plans to open 10 more in the next three years.</p>
<p>&quot;Africa is changing rapidly and for the better...the infrastructures are being improved to sustain these developments and Microsoft is in a position to drive this forward from South Africa,&quot; said Rob Katz, Microsoft South Africa general manager.</p>
<p>However, Africa does lag behind the developed world in its use of computers and the Internet. In the United States there are 300 personal computers for every 1,000 people. In South Africa - by far Africa's most on-line country - the figure is just 34 per 1,000.</p>
<p>Undaunted by this, Gates said the use of computers and the Internet would trickle down inevitably throughout Africa's emerging markets as first government departments and then larger businesses started to use the technology.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
