<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427934" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sulcus Computer names CEO, acting chairman.</title>
<headline>Sulcus Computer names CEO, acting chairman.</headline>
<dateline>GREENSBURG, Pa. 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sulcus Computer Corp said Friday it has named Leon Harris chief executive officer and  Robert Gries acting chairman.</p>
<p>Harris, who joined the board of directors in November, 1996, will continue as a member of the board.  Both he and Gries will assume their new duties immediately.</p>
<p>Most recently, Harris was chairman and chief executive of Physalia Corp, a company he founded in 1994 to gather, organize, and apply diverse expertise in the computer systems/technology market.  </p>
<p>The company said that Gries, who has been a director of Sulcus since 1983, will serve as acting chairman until a permanent chairman is appointed. The former chairman, Jeffrey Ratner, resigned last month. Ratner remains a director.</p>
<p>Gries is president of the Gries Cos and has been engaged in venture capital financing.</p>
<p>It was not immediately known who Harris was replacing as chief executive.  </p>
<p>Last May, the Securities and Exchange Commission sanctioned the company and two former executives, including Ratner, for allegedly using improper accounting methods and issuing false financial statements.</p>
<p>Ratner and former Chief Financial Officer John Picardi, without admitting or denying the SEC's allegations, agreed to a &quot;cease and desist&quot; order requiring them not to violate those regulations in the future.</p>
<p>In addition, Picardi, who is a certified public accountant, was barred from appearing or practicing before the SEC for 1-1/2 years.</p>
<p>In an administrative proceeding, the SEC alleged that Sulcus used improper accounting in connection with the acquisitions of four unprofitable domestic and foreign corporations in 1991 and 1992.</p>
<p>As a result, it filed false financial statements for those years, the SEC alleged.  </p>
<p>Ratner gave up his chief executive title in September 1995, but remained chairman until his resignation from that post last month, said William McLay, managing director of the company.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GREENSBURG, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
