<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428359" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW-BMC zooms in on partners and products.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-BMC zooms in on partners and products.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. database management products company BMC Software's partnerships with key technology players and a focus on core products will keep its growth brisk, chairman and president Max Watson said on Friday.</p>
<p>Watson said BMC expected its revenues for the fiscal year ending March 31, 1997 to rise more than 25 percent and top US$550 million. Next year's revenue and profit growth should be at least as much, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Largely, ours has been organic growth. We think long-term that's the way to go to sustain growth. We have a very long history of extremely good product development,&quot; Watson told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been able to grow and expand by doing what we do better than anyone else, by staying very focused like a laser beam but regularly opening that aperture to expand our reach,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>About 25 percent of BMC's revenue was spent on research and development and its product developers get a commission on successful developement as an incentive, he said.</p>
<p>Product focus &quot;has permitted us to partner with key technology players in the industry and not compete with them&quot;, Watson said.</p>
<p>BMC's partners include software group Oracle Corp, chip giant Intel Corp and hardware firm Hewlett Packard.</p>
<p>Its dual strategy had given BMC an enormous competitive advantage, said Watson.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain one of the most profitable software companies with 40 percent pretax margins,&quot; he said. Watson said he expected BMC to maintain its pretax profit margin in the coming years.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at revenue and profits growing in tandem,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>BMC would be meeting with Wall Street analysts in April on its 1998 forecasts, he added.</p>
<p>Traditionally operating in the mainframe environment, BMC has expanded into all other platforms used by its customers.</p>
<p>Watson said BMC should chalk up some US$100-120 million in licensing sales from non-mainframe business in fiscal 1997, up from US$45 million previously. He saw non-mainframe revenue doubling in fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>In the coming years, the faster growing non-mainframe sales would match mainframe revenue. Currently 75 percent of BMC's turnover comes from mainframes, he said.</p>
<p>Watson said BMC would consider acquiring small companies with good technology that can be integrated with BMC's products. But it &quot;would not buy revenue&quot; through acquisitions, he said. BMC was extending its core products into the Internet area with the use of Web technology.</p>
<p>The company is looking at its relationship with Intel to take it further into the network computing area.</p>
<p>&quot;They want to make sure the network moves ahead faster than it currently is ... so that you can can move more to the desktop therefore creating requirement for faster processors on the desktop,&quot; he said of Intel.</p>
<p>BMC was developing an input-output standard called I20, which would be appropriate with network technology, Watson said.</p>
<p>--Singapore newsroom (65-8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
