<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428568" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Verity sees rev growth from new products.</title>
<headline>Verity sees rev growth from new products.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO, Calif. 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Verity Inc expects to start showing revenue growth after completing a period of heavy investment in its Internet search platform, the company's chief executive said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's happening as we speak,&quot; Philippe Courtot told Reuters, referring to the pickup in revenues. Courtot is Verity's president as well as its CEO.  </p>
<p>At a presentation to a Hambrecht &amp; Quist Internet technology conference in San Francisco, Courtot said during the past three and a half years the company invested 35 percent of its revenues in engineering aimed at updating its products.</p>
<p>He said Verity was now focusing on marketing its SEARCH '97 product family, which adds intelligent search components to its indexing engine.  </p>
<p>The company is prepared to announce the shipment next week of its client search product, he said. In his presentation, he said the company was close to an agreement with Chinese officials on deploying its products throughout China's educational system.</p>
<p>He did not elaborate on those developments or on how much he expected revenues to increase.</p>
<p>&quot;Our growth strategy now is increasing operating profits,&quot; Courtot said in the presentation. &quot;We're focusing on leveraging now on what we have done.&quot;</p>
<p>In answer to an investor's question, Courtot said the company planned to add 20 to 25 more employees.</p>
<p>A Hambrecht &amp; Quist analyst said the thrust of Verity's SEARCH '97 product strategy was to generate more sales among the company's existing installed base of about 15 million seats. ((sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau 415 846 5400))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
