<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429307" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UUNET expands Web hosting services abroad.</title>
<headline>UUNET expands Web hosting services abroad.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Willens</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>UUNET Technologies Inc. plans to launch on Monday its Web hosting services in Britain and Germany and will expand soon throughout Europe, Canada, Australia, Japan and Taiwan.</p>
<p>Web hosting services provide companies with all the services and network facilities necessary to create and manage a Web site.</p>
<p>Paul Hoffmann, UUNET's manager of business development, said the company, a unit of WorldCom Inc., has purchased or bought a stake in several service providers in a race to stay ahead in the fast-growing Web hosting market.</p>
<p>Localized Web hosting speeds Internet service internationally because it eliminates the delay associated with having to update Web sites via crowded overseas network connections to the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;We really think big companies, small companies, medium companies are going to be looking for a Web service provider. There is just going to be no other choice,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>UUNET currently provides Web hosting for customers like True North Communications Inc., the SciFi Channel of USA Networks and  The Motley Fool.</p>
<p>Hoffmann said he was expecting to get global business from between about 10 percent and 20 percent of UUNET's existing domestic customers as well as from new clients.</p>
<p>Analysts said UUNET, a leading Internet service provider (ISP), is indeed ahead of the curve in its expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;This will be a fairly critical step for the major ISPs. There is going to be some consolidation and they are going to need some differentiation to stay alive,&quot; said Matt Nerney, a senior research analyst at Aberdeen Group Inc.</p>
<p>A report by Forrester Research said Web hosting companies are expected to post revenues of about $170 million this year, up from $60 million in 1996. David Goodtree, a Forrester analyst, said he saw the business growing to $5.3 billion by 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;The hosting market came out of nowhere and now is zooming like no tomorrow,&quot; he said. &quot;(Companies) can save money, increase reliability and get to market faster.&quot;</p>
<p>UUNET's Hoffmann said that businesses are looking for outside Web hosts to manage their Web pages because multimedia technology is increasingly perplexing and the need for secure and fast transactions is on the rise.</p>
<p>&quot;You need somebody who can provide that bandwidth,&quot; to handle excessive traffic, he said. &quot;You need to make sure that support is available.&quot;</p>
<p>Forrester's Goodtree said Web hosting costs less than for companies to go it alone. The first-year costs for a fully interactive Web site would be about $42,000 using a Web host compared with about $221,000, including labor, for a company to do on its own, he said.</p>
<p>Nipping at UUNET's heels are Performance Systems International Inc., popularly known as PSINet, BBN Corp.'s BBN Planet and MCI Communications Corp., analysts said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
