<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430995" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ValueVision agrees to buy NetRadio stake.</title>
<headline>ValueVision agrees to buy NetRadio stake.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>ValueVision International Inc said Monday it agreed to acquire a 15-percent interest in NetRadio Network, a subsidiary of Navarre Corp, a national distributor of music, computer software and interactive CD ROM products.</p>
<p>ValueVision operates the nation's third-largest television home-shopping network.</p>
<p>Following the acquisition, ValueVision's 24-hour a day shopping program audio feed will be carried by NetRadio, a music and entertainment site on the Internet.  </p>
<p>The $3 million acquisition price will be comprised of $1 million cash and an additional $2 million in advertising time to increase NetRadio's visibility among cable subscribers.</p>
<p>ValueVision will also be granted exclusive rights for most merchandise categories to be made available in NetRadio's programming.</p>
<p>&quot;This joint investment with Navarre represents an opportunity for ValueVision to participate in the Internet marketplace that is expected to grow significantly in the foreseeable future,&quot; said Robert Johander, chairman and chief executive officer of ValueVision, in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;This arrangement will allow both Navarre and ValueVision to capitalize on the future expected growth in direct-to-consumer selling on the Internet,&quot; said Eric Paulson, Navarre's chairman and chief executive officer.</p>
<p>NetRadio Network, www.netradio.net, uses streaming technology that allows a computer user to listen to music and news, and access the Internet or work on PC desktop applications, such as word processing.</p>
<p>		 ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
