<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44754" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Time Warner says to unveil online service.</title>
<headline>Time Warner says to unveil online service.</headline>
<dateline>AKRON, Ohio 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Time Warner Inc planned to introduce on Tuesday a high-speed online service called Road Runner that will operate over a cable network and through a cable modem, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Road Runner (will begin) delivering a wide range of exclusive content to Akron and Canton (Ohio) area customers via their personal computers at unparalleled speeds,&quot; Time Warner said. &quot;We expect Road Runner to become a significant new business for Time Warner Cable.&quot;</p>
<p>It will carry &quot;compelling&quot; proprietary national and local content and will be launched elsewhere soon, Time Warner said.</p>
<p>Road Runner will connect users to the Internet, e-mail and other online services via Time Warner Cable's upgraded 3,000-mile fiber optic/coaxial cable network here, it said. Traditional modems use local telephone lines.</p>
<p>Hewlett-Packard Co built Road Runner's computer servers and routers, Time Warner said, and Motorola Inc built the cable modems that connect the fiber optic/coaxial network with customers' personal computers.</p>
<p>MCI Communications Corp is providing Internet connectivity and customer care, and customers will navigate the service using a customized version of Microsoft Corp's Explorer 3.0 Internet browser, Time Warner said.</p>
<p>Time Warner Cable said its chairman and chief executive officer, Joseph Collins, planned to unveil the service on Tuesday at Inventure Place, a hands-on science learning center and museum that houses the National Inventors Hall of Fame.</p>
<p>&quot;Road Runner ... represents a creative combination of the sophisticated technological part of Time Warner Cable and the vast journalistic resources of Time Inc with the unrivaled entertainment talent of Warner Bros,&quot; he said in the statement. Time and Warner are Time Warner units, and the service is named after a Warner Bros. cartoon bird.</p>
<p>The Akron Beacon Journal and the Canton Repository newspapers and Time Inc's Time, People, Money and Sports Illustrated magazines will provide electronic news.</p>
<p>Independent content suppliers will offer a Medical Advisor Online, Home Improvement Encyclopedia and other features.</p>
<p>Local net sites will feature libraries and public schools, art museums, Akron and Canton city halls, Inventure Place and sports entities such as a minor-league baseball team here and the Pro Football Hall of Fame, which is in Canton.</p>
<p>&quot;I am really excited about what this service will mean for our school children,&quot; Stephen Fry, president of Time Warner Cable in Northeast Ohio, said in the statement.</p>
<p>Time Warner Cable, the second largest U.S. cable television operator with 1.8 million customers, said it plans to supply the service and modems free to local schools.</p>
<p>Time Warner said it had more than 400 customers online before the service was formally launched and had more than 1,000 on a waiting list.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AKRON, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
