<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448098" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP expected to raise 1996 dividend.</title>
<headline>SAP expected to raise 1996 dividend.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>German business software group SAP AG is likely to announce an increase in dividends when it presents consolidated 1996 results next week, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Pointing to a surprisingly robust fourth quarter, analysts contacted by Reuters said they expected SAP to propose a dividend of 1.65 to 1.80 marks per common share, up from the 1995 dividned of 1.30 marks.</p>
<p>The analysts forecast preferred share dividends of 1.70  to 1.85 marks, up from 1.35 in 1995.</p>
<p>Heinz Steffen of Dresdner Kleinwort Benson Resesarch expected SAP to propose a common share dividend of 1.65 marks and to award one bonus share for every five shares to celebrate the company's 25th anniversary year.</p>
<p>Others, like Heinz Weyerhauser at DG Bank  DGBG.g.F saw an anniversary bonus combined into higher dividends. Weyerhaeser predicted a common share dividend of 1.70 marks.</p>
<p>SAP shares were up four marks in floor trading at 279.50 marks, helped by reports that U.S. auto maker General Motors Corp was considering a &quot;billion dollar&quot; implementation of SAP's R/3 software, which businesses use to monitor manufacturing, purchasing, payroll and acounting data.</p>
<p>Sales for 1996 rose 38 percent to 3.7 billion marks, with net income climbing 40 percent to 567 million marks, after a strong finish more than offset a weak third quarter.</p>
<p>SAP last week told Reuters sales in the first quarter of 1997 were running according to expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;We have said we expect sales to grow 25 to 30 percent and pretax profit to increase at a slightly faster rate, by a few percentage points,&quot; management board member Henning Kagermann said.</p>
<p>But he also said that most of the quarter's sales would be booked in March. &quot;The last month of the quarter always has the most business,&quot; he said. The next weeks will tell.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Neal Boudette, Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
