<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453301" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Two games offer fun ways to fly.</title>
<headline>Two games offer fun ways to fly.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>For philosophers who have long pondered the question, &quot;What is one life worth?&quot; I now have an answer: 40 points.</p>
<p>I learned this important factoid while playing &quot;SimCopter&quot; (Windows95, $40) a flight simulation game by the folks at Maxis, the people behind the popular &quot;SimCity&quot; series.</p>
<p>I also learned (and you might want to pass this on to local aviation authorities) that you don't want me in a pilot's seat. Ever.</p>
<p>While flying around in the simulated cities trying to break up simulated traffic jams, put out simulated fires, and transport simulated human beings to simulated hospitals for their simulated injuries, I managed to (a.) crash into a satellite antenna (b.) fly low enough to clip the hairs of a gopher and (c.) race right at a skyscraper to see whether I could pull up in time to avoid a collision. I couldn't.</p>
<p>Actually, I destroyed the chopper because the people at Maxis encouraged me to. Page 18 of the instruction booklet tells you to &quot;Aim for a building, close your eyes, and fly into it. Repeat as necessary until the helicopter is destroyed. That was fun, wasn't it?&quot;</p>
<p>Sure was.</p>
<p>Actually, you don't have to be suicidal to play &quot;SimCopter.&quot; Most of your time is devoted to doing good deeds. In addition to traffic control, transporting people and fighting fires, you can track down criminals, chase speeders and pluck people from disaster sites.</p>
<p>It's a lot of fun. Unlike a real helicopter, this chopper is easy to manipulate. Although there are about 50 keyboard commands, most are for non-flight tasks such as manipulating fog levels, lowering rescue equipment, changing day to night, selecting a camera angle from which to view the action, and summoning police, fire and rescue equipment.</p>
<p>There are 30 cities to fly through and above, or you can use ones you've created if you have a copy of &quot;SimCity 2000.&quot;</p>
<p>The fact that a life is only worth 40 points isn't the only weird thing about &quot;SimCopter.&quot; Some examples:</p>
<p>-- If you walk into the road, an oncoming car will pass right through you.</p>
<p>-- You, your dispatcher, and the people on the radio seem to be the only ones who speak English. When you're on the ground, everyone mumbles like Bob Dylan with a mouthful of peanut butter.</p>
<p>-- When I transported an injured man on a hospital helipad, the paramedic who came to the roof to treat him dropped the poor guy on the ground, then he decided (without an invitation, I might add) to join me on board the chopper. (Maybe the SimVictim didn't have SimMedicalInsurance.)</p>
<p>-- When I called a policeman to the scene of a traffic tieup, the officer only made the situation worse. (Ooops. Sorry. That DOES happen in real life.)</p>
<p>-- If you kill someone, it costs you 40 points. If you injure them, it costs you 100 points. Maybe it's because the dead ones can't hire SimLawyers to sue you.</p>
<p>But overall, SimCopter is SimPly a lot of fun.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>&quot;Banzai Bug&quot; (Grolier Interactive, Windows95, $45) is not your typical flight simulator. You play a bug with human-like eyes and teeth. You fall in love with Gnatasha, a brilliant spider who has some of same attributes that made Anna Nicole Smith famous.</p>
<p>In this game, you're trapped in the worst of all possible locations: the home of a high-tech exterminator, a guy who proclaims &quot;I love the smell of DDT in the morning.&quot;</p>
<p>Your first job is to find a half-dozen crumbs scattered around the garage while avoiding the flying bug-killing robots the exterminator has designed.</p>
<p>Then, it's into the air ducts, where you have to manoeuvre to the basement to meet with Sluggo, a slug who wants to wrest control of the house from its human occupants using the Stink-u-lator, a stink bomb made from human foot excretions.</p>
<p>But achieving that goal requires avoiding or eliminating even more bug killers, dive-bombing Mom's hair, and saving Albert Fleinstein, the buggy equivalent of a scientific genius, from the clutches of the exterminator's son, Bobby.</p>
<p>Stripped to its essentials, &quot;Banzai Bug&quot; is an arcade game with some clever animated introductory sequences. It unfolds as a story, told by a now elderly Banzai. If you lose all of your lives, the elder Banzai appears and says something like, &quot;And then (pause) I died. (pause) Just kidding!&quot; and you get to go back to the beginning of that level to try again.</p>
<p>And if you're really in the mood for a challenge, this is one flight simulation that lets you spend most of the game flying upside down.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
