<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45565" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spacetec sees small Q2 loss, higher revs.</title>
<headline>Spacetec sees small Q2 loss, higher revs.</headline>
<dateline>LOWELL, Mass. 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spacetec IMC Corp said Wednesday it expects &quot;a modest loss&quot; for the quarter ending September 30 but a rise in revenues of 23 percent from a year earlier, to about $2.5 million.</p>
<p>Spacetec said the quarter will include the first shipments of the new SpaceOrb 360 RealLife 3D game controller for the consumer electronics market and the release of SpaceWare AniMotion, the company's first software and hardware solution for the multimedia professional 3D animation market.  </p>
<p>The company said efforts to accelerate manufacturing and delivery operations to meet stronger-than-expected demand for SpaceOrb 360 resulted in higher product costs.</p>
<p>It predicted a &quot;modest loss&quot; for the quarter, partly resulting from the &quot;high up-front costs of starting a retail launch program.&quot; The three months ending September 30 constitute the company's fiscal second quarter.</p>
<p>Company spokesmen were not available to quantify the expected loss.</p>
<p>Spacetec said it had reached an agreement with D&amp;H Distributing to distribute the SpaceOrb 360 to such stores as Computer City, Incredible Universe, Electronics Boutique, Hammacher Schlemmer, and numerous smaller retail outlets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOWELL, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
