<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46506" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: A Good, But Not 'Ultimate,' Encyclopedia For Kids.</title>
<headline>A Good, But Not 'Ultimate,' Encyclopedia For Kids.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Do you know that the name &quot;porpoise&quot; means &quot;pig fish,&quot; or that the silhouette got its name from a tightwad French politician reputed to have only hung the outlines of drawings in his home to save money?</p>
<p>Your kids will if know it if they spend some time browsing through &quot;The Ultimate Children's Encyclopaedia&quot; (from The Learning Company, Windows, $45). Based on the Kingfisher collection of reference books for children, this CD-ROM for ages 7 to 12 also includes a thesaurus, atlas, dictionary and profiles of the famous and infamous.</p>
<p>It features bouncy music, colourful artwork, and a cartoon host named Zak who guides youngsters through the product and whose enthusiasm is likely to keep elementary school students poking around for a while, just to see what will pop up next.</p>
<p>The developers of children's encyclopaedias always have to walk a fine line between overwhelming a youngster with information and being superficial. Let's just say the folks behind this encyclopaedia didn't err on the side of depth.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, the quality of the information is pretty good -- if you know to look for it.</p>
<p>For example, in the listing on the reputed prophet Nostradamus, it makes the usual wishy-washy claim that &quot;even today people claim to see his predictions fulfilled in events around the world.&quot;</p>
<p>The youngster must click on the tiny &quot;picture facts&quot; icon to uncover the secret to Nostradamus' success: That he &quot;wrote his predictions in verse, often so obscurely that readers can put different interpretations upon them.&quot;</p>
<p>You have to wonder whether a typical 8-year-old will know what &quot;obscurely&quot; means, but clicking on the word brings up a dictionary item that explains it.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ultimate Children's Encyclopaedia&quot; also provides background on common phrases and expression, wise sayings and the elements that make up a word.</p>
<p>Its biggest flaw is the lack of good system for searching the CD-ROM for words. The item on &quot;baseball&quot; says it evolved from a game called &quot;rounders.&quot; But if a child looks for a reference to &quot;rounders,&quot; the closest it will get is painter Henri Rousseau.</p>
<p>Multimedia products such as this one have the ability to use animated diagrams to explain how things works. On that level, this encyclopaedia is disappointing because its illustrations are so limited.</p>
<p>For example, the diagram of a copying machine gives names to some of the parts, yet doesn't explain how it works. The animation showing the principles behind an elevator mentions a counterweight, but doesn't show viewers where it is.</p>
<p>The Learning Company has come up with a good product, but calling it &quot;Ultimate&quot; is ultimately pretentious.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Of the many CD-ROM encyclopaedias available for older children and grownups, Grolier never seems to be the name that comes to mind.</p>
<p>&quot;Grolier's&quot; problem has been its lack of pizzazz. It hasn't had the flashy graphics and displays of colour that have enlivened &quot;Encarta&quot; and &quot;Compton's.&quot;</p>
<p>That's been unfortunate. In some areas I've found the quality of the Grolier articles to be far better and more authoritative than the other big-name encyclopaedias, including the &quot;Britannica.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Grolier&quot; doesn't lack pizzazz anymore.</p>
<p>The just-released &quot;1997 Grolier Multimedia Encyclopaedia&quot; (Windows/Macintosh $50) has put the same high-quality database into a livelier-looking package, and given customers a choice of four &quot;looks&quot; from which to choose.</p>
<p>It also has an atlas and (for some people with access to the Internet) World Wide Web sites to provide updated articles and lists of authoritative Web pages.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the &quot;Grolier&quot; system for connecting to the Internet doesn't support some systems. For example, I couldn't get it to work through Prodigy's Internet system.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, it's a bargain at $50. And with its new look, maybe &quot;Grolier's&quot; will get the respect it deserves.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in stores:</p>
<p>&quot;Independence Day&quot; (Fox Interactive, Windows/Macintosh, $20) is for the folks who can't get enough of the hit movie about alien invaders with emminently hackable computers. It includes over 500 photos from the productions, film clips and more than 750 electronic storyboard illustrations.</p>
<p>&quot;Invention Studio&quot; (Discovery Channel Multimedia, Windows, $35) -- Inspired by the TV series &quot;Invention,&quot; this game gives players information about inventors and lets them build their own simulated inventions in the Gadgetorium. It's geared to youngsters ages 9 to 14.</p>
<p>&quot;Voyeur II&quot; (Phillips, DOS/Windows, $40) lets you sneak a peek through some unshaded windows and try to stop a murder. This dual CD-ROM game stars Jennifer O'Neil and is rated for ages 17 and older because of its nudity and adult subject matter.</p>
<p>&quot;Adventures of the Smart Patrol&quot; (Inscape, Windows/Macintosh, $40) features the musical group Devo and bills itself as &quot;'Blade Runner' on steroids.&quot; Players must prevent deadly bacteria from escaping in a world filled with &quot;mega-corporate villainy, rabid technscience, come-hither erotic naughtiness and dangerously mutated humour.&quot; It also is for ages 17 and over.</p>
<p>&quot;Nine Worlds&quot; (Palladium, Windows/Macintosh, $40) -- This look at the solar system, hosted by Star Trek's Patrick Stewart, has original animations, interviews with astronomers, and over 500 photographs.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
