<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="465281" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Phamis to merge with IDX Systems.</title>
<headline>Phamis to merge with IDX Systems.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-03-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>PHAMIS Inc Tuesday said it agreed to merge with IDX Systems Corp, an industry provider of healthcare information systems.</p>
<p>Under terms of the agreement, Phamis shareholders will receive 0.73 shares of IDX common stock for each share of PHAMIS common stock, subject to adjustment within a range of 0.6811 to 0.80 shares of IDX common stock, based on the average market price per share of IDX.</p>
<p>Phamis last traded up 3-3/8 to 22-1/4. IDX last traded at 31-3/4, up one.  </p>
<p>At of the end of last year, PHAMIS had 6.35 million shares outstanding, giving the deal a value of about $147 million.</p>
<p>In a statement, the company said the merger is scheduled to close in early July pending regulatory and shareholder approval.</p>
<p>The combined company is estimated to be the third largest healthcare information systems vendor in the industry. PHAMIS said its offices will remain in Seattle, giving IDX a stronger West Coast presence. The combined workforce will include approximately 1,600 people.</p>
<p>Richard Tarrant, president and chief executive officer of IDX, will continue as chief executive of the new organization and Frank Sample, president and chief executive officer of PHAMIS will become an executive vice president.</p>
<p>The transaction terms call for a tax-free exchange of shares which will be accounted for on a pooling of interest basis.  </p>
<p>Separately, IDX said the transaction is expected to be slightly accretive to earnings in 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
