<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="466937" id="root" date="1997-03-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Electronic Arts to develop more games for Nintendo.</title>
<headline>Electronic Arts to develop more games for Nintendo.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Electronic Arts Inc. has agreed to develop its popular line of sports video games for the Nintendo 64 platform, the two companies said Monday in a deal providing badly needed support for the device.</p>
<p>Larry Probst, chairman of Electronic Arts, said the first title to be shipped under the five-year, worldwide agreement would be available sometime in mid-1998, with an several more titles to be released later in the year.</p>
<p>Electronic Arts' first title for Nintendo 64, FIFA Soccer 64, is shipping to stores this week.</p>
<p>But executives of the San Mateo, Calif.-based Electronic Arts have been reluctant to devote resources to the new Nintendo Co. Ltd platform, citing the high costs and relatively low profit margins of game cartridges compared with the compact disks used by rival video game machines.</p>
<p>That kind of reluctance has contributed to a paucity of game titles available for the Nintendo 64, which had only eight titles available at the end of 1996, compared with hundreds for the rival Sony Corp. PlayStation.</p>
<p>Nevertheless Nintendo executives say the game device has surpassed all sales projections, achieving 2 million unit sales in the United States alone its first five months of availability.</p>
<p>Nintendo projects sales of 12 million units worldwide in the fiscal year that begins next week, with sales being driven in part by a recent price cut to about $150.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly it has launched very successfully in North America,&quot; Probst said in an interview, when asked about the company's apparent change of heart.</p>
<p>&quot;Our sense is that success is going to be replicated in Europe as well,&quot; he said. &quot;Having seen that it makes more sense with us now to be more aggressive with our support.&quot;</p>
<p>Neither he nor Nintendo of America Chairman Howard Lincoln would comment on terms of the agreement, although analysts said they assumed Electronic Arts had negotiated a favorable arrangement on royalties.</p>
<p>&quot;This agreement represents something that is very much in Nintendo's interest and very much in EA's interest,&quot; Lincoln said.</p>
<p>Mike Wallace, an analyst at UBS Securities, said the deal should give Nintendo a boost, although he noted it would be more than a year before the agreement begins to bear fruit.</p>
<p>&quot;Sports is obviously a big category for video games and EA has 40 percent of the sports category,&quot; Wallace said. &quot;This lets them compete with Sony.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
