<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="472495" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oracle's Ellison mulling Apple takeover - report.</title>
<headline>Oracle's Ellison mulling Apple takeover - report.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>An investor group led by Oracle Corp. Chairman Larry Ellison is mulling a bid of more than $1 billion to take control of Apple Computer Inc., the San Jose Mercury reported Thursday.</p>
<p>According to the Thursday edition of the newspaper, Ellison is floating the possible bid as a trial-ballon to gauge investor reaction in the coming days, especially among major stakeholders, before he decides to go ahead with a bid.</p>
<p>Ellison and Apple officials could not be reached for comment on the report. The possible bid for control of Apple was mentioned in a Business Week report several weeks ago.</p>
<p>The latest report said that if Ellison's group were to take control of Apple, it would remove Apple's board of directors and top managers, including Chairman and Chief Executive Gilbert Amelio.</p>
<p>The Mercury report said Ellison and Apple co-founder Steve Jobs would be likely candidates for a new board of directors.</p>
<p>The story quoted Ellison making highly critical comments of Apple management, including co-founder and long-time board member A.C. &quot;Mike&quot; Markkula.</p>
<p>&quot;Markkula has taken 10 years to destroy what Steve Jobs created,&quot; Ellison was quoted as saying in the Mercury report.</p>
<p>Ellison said a bid, if he makes one, would give current shareholders &quot;60 percent in cash and 40 percent in equity in the newly run Apple,&quot; but only if shareholders are willing to sell at the current share price.</p>
<p>Apple's stock rose 75 cents to $17.50, while Oracle fell 25 cents to $40.25 on Nasdaq, where they were among the most active issues at mid-morning.</p>
<p>The Oracle chief executive said at a conference early last year that he had considered making a takeover bid for Apple in 1995 with a group that included Jobs.</p>
<p>Jobs recently became a member of the Apple board following Apple's $400 million acquisition of his NeXT Software Inc.</p>
<p>Apple has suffered declining market share for its famous brand of easy-to-use computers and endured several rounds of restructuring in recent years. The stock has languished in the mid-teens since early January and is at a 10-year low.</p>
<p>In mid-March, the company said it planned to discontinue several product lines and lay off 4,000 employees, or one-third of its staff, in its latest bid to slash costs and turn the company around.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
