<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="477980" id="root" date="1997-04-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Cisco busy as stock whips around.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Cisco busy as stock whips around.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Options on shares of Cisco Systems Inc were busy as the stock bounced in a wide range on heavy volume, traders said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cisco shares ended up 1/4 at 48-3/8 on heavy turnover of nearly 12.6 million shares.</p>
<p>The stock fell off the open to 46-3/8 before recovering to climb as high as 49-1/8.</p>
<p>Patrick Hamilton at LETCO said early options activity was from shorts but that the main action was from investors doing the April 45 and May 45 time spread.  </p>
<p>He said one investor was a particularly big seller of that time spread.</p>
<p>&quot;May is earnings month, so I'm assuming they were trying to position themselves a little bit for the May earnings,&quot; Hamilton said.</p>
<p>The Cisco April 45 put traded 5,535 contracts and the May 45 put traded about 3,725.</p>
<p>Other busy Cisco options included the April 50 call which traded nearly 4,000 contracts, the April 50 put which traded about 2,210, and the April 60 call which traded 1,395.  </p>
<p>Hamilton said volatility in Cisco options rose a few points early on as the stock declined, but came in later in the session as the stock settled into a range.</p>
<p>He said that over the last few days, volatility has climbed three to four points to the mid-50 region.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, big volume was seen in the RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp June 40 call, where 7,255 contracts changed hands. The option, which was unchanged at 3/8, had open interest of 12,188.</p>
<p>RJR shares eased 3/8 to 31-7/8.  </p>
<p>Several Informix Corp options saw solid volume as the stock slumped 5-7/32 to 9-29/32 on turnover of more than 24 million shares.</p>
<p>The stock fell after the company said it expected to report a &quot;substantial&quot; first quarter loss on far weaker than expected sales. It hit a session low of 8-3/4.</p>
<p>The most active Informix option was the May 12-1/2 call, with total volume of about 1,170 contracts. The option, which lost 2-11/16 to 9/16, had open interest of 136 contracts.</p>
<p>Several hundred contracts traded in the April 10 puts and calls, the April 12-1/2 calls and the April 15 puts.  </p>
<p>Trading was also fairly brisk in several May and August calls, particularly the 12-1/2 and 20 strikes.</p>
<p>Most of the volume crossed on the Chicago Board Options Exchange. The options also trade on the American Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>((Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
