<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484584" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apple stock rises amid renewed takeover speculation.</title>
<headline>Apple stock rises amid renewed takeover speculation.</headline>
<byline>Kourosh Karimkhany</byline>
<dateline>CUPERTINO, Calif. 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Apple Computer Inc. stock rose Thursday on renewed speculation that the troubled computer maker was trying to sell itself to a bigger company.</p>
<p>The stock of the Cupertino, Calif., company gained 87.5 cents to $18.875 on trading of 4.9 million shares, making it one of the most active issues on the Nasdaq. Earlier, the stock traded as high as $19.125.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Saudi billionaire Prince al-Waleed bin Talal revealed he bought a 5 percent stake in Apple for $115 million because he expects the company to turn itself around.</p>
<p>Last week, software billionaire Larry Ellison, chairman of Oracle Corp., said he intended to form an investor group to try to buy a majority stake in Apple, take control of the company and revamp it with a new management team.</p>
<p>The New York Times, citing unnamed Apple sources, also reported Thursday that Apple was actively seeking to sell itself and has approached high-performance computer maker Sun Microsystems Inc. again. Sun tried to buy Apple in late 1995, but negotiations fell apart over price.</p>
<p>An Apple spokeswomen declined to comment about the speculation. Sun Chief Executive Scott McNealy also declined to comment about the rumours, &quot;no matter how accurate or silly they may be.&quot;</p>
<p>Mulling takeover bids is nothing new at Apple. In addition to Sun, Apple negotiated with International Business Machines Corp. about a merger two years ago. IBM also demurred over price.</p>
<p>Former high-level Apple executives who keep close contact with the company said Thursday they have not heard of any recent moves by Apple to approach suitors.</p>
<p>One former executive said, however, that increasing pressure from investors -- who hold stock near a 10-year low -- may make Chairman Gilbert Amelio more receptive to any takeover proposal that might come along.</p>
<p>Trouble is, none might come along, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's always possible, but we're not putting a lot of weight into it,&quot; said Peter Andrews, analyst at brokerage AG Edwards &amp; Sons Inc. in St. Louis.</p>
<p>Even though Apple still has a huge following of Macintosh users, the company will not be able to stop its sales from falling for at least another year, making it an unattractive buyout, analysts said.</p>
<p>In the past five quarters, Apple has reported financial losses of close to $1 billion and has had two rounds of job cuts totalling 5,400. Despite the massive expense reductions, the company does not expect to report a profit until the September quarter.</p>
<p>Company executives have told investors they expect revenue for the year to fall about 20 percent to $8 billion.</p>
<p>The most likely suitor for now is Ellison, the flamboyant head of Oracle who has publicly criticised Amelio for failing to turn the company around.</p>
<p>Ellison set up a World Wide Web site last week to solicit e-mail from investors to gauge support (http://www.us.oracle.com/corporate/press/html/apple.html). Depending on the response, he would launch a bid.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Ellison said it was too early for him to comment on the results. Ellison could not be reached immediately for comment.</p>
<p>Some investors said they were not impressed by Ellison's offer.</p>
<p>Richard Ash, a private investor who owns 3,000 Apple shares, said he would not sell his stock to Ellison because he was not offering a premium over the current stock price.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CUPERTINO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
