<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="484966" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: FEATURE - India software firms milk Y2K cash cow.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - India software firms milk Y2K cash cow.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's amazing what just one number can do.</p>
<p>India's computer whiz-kids, who were until not so long ago considered a bunch of eccentrics with strange tastes, are earning millions by trying to prevent computers from crashes linked to the Year 2000, known as Y2K in industry jargon.</p>
<p>&quot;Just about every Indian software company and its uncle is into this job. The business potential is enormous,&quot; D.N. Prahlad, senior vice-president in charge of Y2K projects in software leader Infosys Technologies, said in Bangalore, India's Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>Infosys' sprawling software facility, equipped with a satellite earth station, is located at the end of a pot-holed highway, from which one can see mud huts that show India is still far from the 21st century.</p>
<p>But there's money pouring from the sky as software solutions are beamed up and down the stratosphere to distant clients.</p>
<p>Analysts say Indian software experts, who cost 40 percent less than their counterparts elsewhere, are well-positioned to grab a market in correcting computers that were not tuned to account for the end of a millennium in their internal time mechanisms.</p>
<p>Many key technology-driven service industries such as banking and insurance need their expertise to save their computers from collapse caused by the &quot;millennium bug&quot; that could make data vanish when the clock strikes midnight on December 31, 1999.</p>
<p>MARKET IN Y2K SOLUTIONS COULD BE AS MUCH AS $100 BILLION</p>
<p>Dewang Mehta, executive director of India's National Association of Software and Service Companies (Nasscom), said the international market in Y2K solutions was estimated anywhere between $60 and $100 billion.</p>
<p>Nasscom expects India to easily get $2-5 billion worth of business in the next three years, which are considered crucial.</p>
<p>Madras-based Square D Software Ltd, which has a collaboration for Y2K business with Japan's NEC Corp, is a key player.</p>
<p>&quot;Square D has the full range of Y2K services. Its methodology 'Update 2000' addresses all the concerns of the client. Cost effectiveness, timely delivery and quality are the key factors,&quot; M. Selvapandian, principal consultant at Square D, told Reuters in an electronic mail response to questions.</p>
<p>&quot;Square D has very large contracts of Y2K work from the United Kingdom, the United States, Japan, Switzerland and Saudi Arabia. It is planning to execute $24 million of Y2K work during the financial year 1997-1998 (April-March),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Infosys expects 25 percent of its revenues coming from Y2K solutions linked to insurance, retail and banking industries. Its revenue in 1995/96 (April-March) stood at 885 million rupees ($24.7 million).</p>
<p>Last year, it entered into a partnership with U.S. firm Platinum Technology Inc to execute Year 2000 projects.</p>
<p>Infosys has been offering Japanese courses to its 1,000-odd employees to help offshore solutions in Y2K.</p>
<p>NIIT Ltd, India's leading computer education company, and other similar firms have launched special programmes to teach Y2K solutions and help young professionals make a fast buck.</p>
<p>MILLENNIUM A REAL OPPORTUNITY FOR INDIAN SOFTWARE FIRMS</p>
<p>&quot;Y2K opportunity is a real boon to our Indian software companies. Most of the major contracts will be signed by end of 1997. Indian companies that have demonstrated (skills) by the middle of 1997 have a very large role to play,&quot; Selvapandian said.</p>
<p>&quot;It (Y2K) is a great door-opener,&quot; said Satish Bangalore, chief executive of Bangalore-based Command International Software, an affiliate of the U.S.-based insurance firm Phoenix Home Life.</p>
<p>His software export company, only six months old, is projecting a revenue of $8 million in the first year of operations.</p>
<p>&quot;Our focus is on the insurance industry in the United States. We plan to cater to Europe and the Indian market later,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Square D is offering &quot;millennium bug&quot; solutions in banking and finance, tourism, manufacturing and telecommunications, Selvapandian said.</p>
<p>But Indian software companies have to cope with the problem of high staff turnover in an industry where skilled professionals are restless and demand is booming.</p>
<p>&quot;Rewarding and retaining the senior technical staff is a very important factor for success,&quot; Selvapandian said.</p>
<p>Infosys is one of the five Indian companies that formed a consortium called Jasdic Park with five Japanese firms including Hitachi Ltd and Fuji Data Control.</p>
<p>Around 15-20 percent of its business is expected from Y2K solutions.</p>
<p>India's software industry is expected to close the 1996/97 (April-March) fiscal year with a growth rate of 50 percent.</p>
<p>Exports are expected to fetch 39 billion rupees and internal sales 25 billion, accounting for a total of $1.8 billion worth business. In 1995/96, total business was worth $1.2 billion. ($1=35.8 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
