<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48542" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FULL TEXT - Oracle reports Q1 results.</title>
<headline>FULL TEXT - Oracle reports Q1 results.</headline>
<dateline>REDWOOD SHORES, Calif. 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oracle Corp Thursday reported first quarter results. The following is a copy of the company's news release.</p>
<p>---------------------- PRESS RELEASE -------------------</p>
<p>REDWOOD SHORES, Calif., Sept. 12 /PRNewswire/ -- Oracle Corporation (Nasdaq: ORCL) today announced record first quarter results for the quarter ended August 31, 1996. Revenues increased 36 percent to $1.052 billion from $772 million in the same period last year.  Net income for the period increased 110 percent to $113 million, or $0.17 per share, compared to net income of $54 million, or $0.08 per share, in the first quarter of fiscal 1996, which included the $34 million after-tax charge for the purchase of in-process research and development from Information Resources, Inc. in the same period last year.</p>
<p>First quarter license sales grew by 27 percent year-to-year (26 percent when combined with other revenues). Database license revenue led overall license growth at 41%, confirming the continued strong demand for Oracle(R) Universal Server(R), Oracle's core technology.  Oracle Services (Support, Consulting and Education) grew 45%.</p>
<p>Geographically, Oracle reported solid performance worldwide, despite a 3 percentage point negative currency translation during the first quarter, with Asia/Pacific heavily impacted by a weaker yen.  Oracle Americas reported the strongest revenue growth geographically at 43% versus the same period last year.</p>
<p>Oracle made a number of significant announcements during the first fiscal quarter of 1997:</p>
<p>* Oracle outlined its intranet strategy to deliver the industry's first comprehensive product line that enables full-service intranets.  This platform enables the full-service intranet for the first time by helping corporations build real applications, conduct Web transactions, easily manage corporate Web information, and minimize information overload.  Products include:</p>
<p>-- Oracle7.3, the world's most popular database,</p>
<p>-- Oracle Web Server 2.0, the first Web server to support next generation intranet applications,</p>
<p>-- Designer/2000, Developer/2000 and Oracle Power Objects, for client server application development and HTML application deployment,</p>
<p>-- Oracle InterOffice, the only fully scalable, web-based collaboration software,</p>
<p>-- Oracle Applications for the Web, version 2.0, a new family of self-service applications providing extensive new functionality targeted for enterprise intranets.</p>
<p>* Oracle announced the successful rollout of Oracle(R) Universal Server(R) with Oracle7 Release 7.3 which began shipping in March of this year and has been adopted by hundreds of companies, government organizations and leading institutions worldwide.  Preparing for the next major step with Oracle(R) Universal Server(R), Oracle has achieved its first key milestone for Oracle8, which entered beta testing in August.  Over 300 partners and representatives have been trained on the beta product, which will undergo intensive testing before moving into general availability.</p>
<p>* Oracle's Developer/2000 and Designer/2000 continue to win top honors in key product surveys.  The June InfoWorld review found that Developer/2000 delivered the most robust performance and features for mission-critical applications. Also, in Computerworld's 1996 Application Development Tool Brand Preference Survey, Developer/2000 won for &quot;best technology,&quot; &quot;best service and support,&quot; &quot;best documentation,&quot; and the &quot;preferred company to do business with,&quot; while Designer/2000, Oracle's generation and modeling tool, swept all seven CASE categories.</p>
<p>* Oracle's database and warehousing solutions beat Informix and Sybase as its flagship Oracle7 relational database was honored with awards for &quot;Best Database Server Software&quot; and &quot;Best Data Warehousing Product&quot; in Databased Advisor Magazine's annual Readers' Choice Awards.  Polling over 125,000 readers, Databased Advisor asked them to choose the products that provided the best tools for building powerful business solutions.</p>
<p>* Oracle announced their roadmap for delivering its core products on the Microsoft Windows NT 4.0 operating system including Oracle7, Oracle WebServer, application development tools, collaboration products, packaged applications, OLAP products and middleware.  These announcements extended Oracle's commitment to the Windows NT platform, which started two years ago when Oracle became the first major information management company to make its database available on Windows NT.  </p>
<p>&quot;The continued strength in our server performance affirms the need for powerful technology in the new market of network computing,&quot; said Raymond J. Lane, Oracle's President and Chief Operating Officer.  &quot;As the world expands its need for client server computing, Oracle is providing a stack of technology, applications and services capable of responding to these requirements.&quot;</p>
<p>Oracle Corp. is the world's second largest software company, and the largest supplier of software for information management.  With annual revenues of more than $4.5 billion, the company offers its database, tools and application products, along with related consulting, education, and support services, in more than 90 countries around the world.</p>
<p>For more information about Oracle, please call Oracle Investor Relations at 415-506-4073 or see Oracle's World Wide Web page: (URL) http://www.oracle.com/.</p>
<p>&quot;Safe Harbor&quot; Statement Under the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act 1995:</p>
<p>Information in this release relating to Oracle's future prospects which are &quot;forward-looking statements&quot; are subject to certain risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially, including, but not necessarily limited to the following: (1) The market for Oracle's products is intensely competitive and is characterized by rapid technological advances, and frequent new product introductions.  There can be no assurances that Oracle will continue to introduce new products and new versions of existing products that keep pace with technological developments, satisfy increasingly sophisticated customer requirements and achieve market acceptance.  (2) Intense competition in the various markets in which Oracle competes may put pressure on Oracle to reduce prices on certain products, particularly in the enterprise and departmental database marketplace.  (3) Management's ability to manage growth, continuously hire significant numbers of qualified employees, forecast revenues and control expenses continues to be a challenge.  An unexpected decline in the growth rate of revenues without a corresponding and timely slowdown in expense growth could have a material adverse effect on results of operations.  (4) Delays in product delivery or closing of sales can cause quarterly revenues and income to fall significantly short of anticipated levels.  (5) Oracle is introducing new products for the Internet, online services, electronic commerce, interactive media and data warehousing; the market acceptance and contribution to Oracle's revenues cannot be assured.  Oracle undertakes no obligation to update information contained in this release.  For further information regarding risks and uncertainties associated with Oracle's business, please refer to the &quot;Risk Factors&quot; section of Oracle Corporation's SEC filings, including, but not limited to, its annual report on Form 10-K for the year ended May 31, 1996, copies of which may be obtained by contacting Oracle Corporation's Investor Relations Department at 415-506-4073 or Oracle's Fax-on-Demand service 800-ORCL-NOW (672-5669).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="REDWOOD SHORES, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
