<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="48550" id="root" date="1996-09-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Call buying in U.S. Robotics.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Call buying in U.S. Robotics.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Options on shares of U.S. Robotics Corp continued active on Thursday as the shares extended Wednesday's rally.</p>
<p>By 1420 CDT (1920 GMT), U.S. Robotics was up 4-3/4 at 61-5/8 on turnover of more than eight million shares. The stock hit 62-1/2 intraday.</p>
<p>Analysts said the stock continued to rally on expectations it would have a faster modem on the market by the end of the year.</p>
<p>In the options, call buying was the strategy of the day, traders said, as investors tried to catch the stock rally.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are more call buyers today than there were yesterday,&quot; a trader on the floor of the Chicago Board Options Echange said. &quot;Yesterday there were lots of call sellers on the way up.</p>
<p>&quot;But today there are a lot of call buyers.&quot;</p>
<p>On Wednesday, U.S. Robotics shares surged 4-3/8 to 56-7/8, closing at its high for the day.</p>
<p>He explained that selling calls on Thursday was difficult because the stock was climbing steadily. Volatilities remained fairly constant, he added.  </p>
<p>Among the calls, the September 55 was most active, with about 1,500 contracts changing hands.</p>
<p>The option, which had open interest of 7,065 through Wednesday, was up four at seven.</p>
<p>Other active calls included the September 50 and 60.</p>
<p>In addition, calls at the 55, 60 and 65 strikes were active in the October series as were the 60, 62-1/2, 65 and 70 strikes in November.</p>
<p>Small call buying was also seen in some February 1997 calls as well.  </p>
<p>Options on several other technology stocks were active as the group, led by Microsoft Corp, rallied sharply.</p>
<p>Microsoft shares were ahead 3-1/2 at 128-3/4 in late trading after outlining an aggressive rollout of several new Internet-based products and services.</p>
<p>Among the options, which trade on the Pacific Stock Exchange, the Microsoft September 130 call traded more than 3,5000 contracts, the October 130 call traded 2,120 and the October 135 call traded nearly 1,800.</p>
<p>Few Microsoft puts were active.  </p>
<p>Also, options on shares of Micron Technology Inc, Oracle Corp, Sun Microsystems Inc and Dell Computer Corp were active.</p>
<p>In other activity, long-term options, or LEAPS, on shares of AT&amp;T Corp were active for the third day in a row.</p>
<p>The AT&amp;T January 1998 60 call traded 3,296 contracts and the corresponding put traded 3,300. Traders said the trades could have been an investor selling the January 60 straddle.</p>
<p>A spread was spotted in the Unocal Corp September and October 35 calls.</p>
<p>--G.Crawford, (312) 408-8750/E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
