<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="488705" id="root" date="1997-04-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Sony, Sony Music disagree on JSkyB stake - sources.</title>
<headline>Sony, Sony Music disagree on JSkyB stake - sources.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sony Corp as a group plans to take a one-third stake in Japan Sky Broadcasting Co, but wrangling continues within the group over which units will hold how much of the stake, industry sources said on Friday.</p>
<p>They added that disagreement between Sony and its content production unit Sony Music Entertainment (Japan) Inc is to blame for a delay in the official announcement of Sony's stake in the satellite broadcasting venture.</p>
<p>&quot;Sony wants Sony Music Entertainment to own at least half the stake in JSkyB, but Sony Music is shunning the investment,&quot; one industry source close to the companies said.</p>
<p>Sony Music, despite its abundant funds and expertise in deals with content producers, fears that participation in JSkyB could interfere with its software sales channels to other broadcasters, he said.</p>
<p>Although Sony's ally Softbank Corp has been saying since early March that Sony, Softbank and News Corp of Australia would each own an equal stake in JSkyB, Sony has refused to comment.</p>
<p>Industry sources said the Sony group is likely to invest a total of 10 billion yen in JSkyB, but Sony has not confirmed this.</p>
<p>Analysts say Sony's participation in JSkyB has boosted its credibility and financial standing, and has made it easier for the satellite broadcaster to strike distribution deals with other content providers.</p>
<p>&quot;Japanese broadcasters (who own broadcasting content) were unwilling to cooperate with Murdoch, a foreigner, and Son, an outsider, until Sony decided to join JSkyB,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Rupert Murdoch, chairman of News Corp, and Masayoshi Son, president of Softbank, reportedly had difficulties convincing Japanese broadcasters to supply content for JSkyB.</p>
<p>News Corp and Softbank jointly acquired a stake in nationwide Japanese broadcaster TV Asahi, but later sold the stake to Asahi Shimbun, TV Asahi's largest shareholder, in return for the two companies' support for the JSkyB project.</p>
<p>Sony president Nobuyuki Idei is said to have worked as a go-between for Murdoch and Asahi Shimbun president Muneyuki Matsushita in the deal.</p>
<p>JSkyB was originally scheduled to start beaming 12 satellite channels from April, but analysts said the launch was likely to be delayed and would start with only nine channels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
