<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489689" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft to buy WebTV for $425 million.</title>
<headline>Microsoft to buy WebTV for $425 million.</headline>
<byline>Mark Egan</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Software giant Microsoft Corp. said Sunday it has agreed to acquire privately-held WebTV Networks Inc. for cash and stock valued at about $425 million in a move aimed at bringing the personal computer and the television closer together.</p>
<p>Microsoft said it hopes the move will help it become a leader in the new frontier of digital television where consumers can enjoy better pictures, enhanced programming, Internet access and video and data feeds on their televisions.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to take the personal computer and its progeny ... quickly into the home,&quot; Microsoft Senior Vice President Craig Mundie told reporters on a conference call.</p>
<p>Founded in 1995, WebTV Networks has developed a set of technologies and guidelines for manufacturers to make set-top boxes that allow consumers to use their televisions to surf the Internet and send and receive electronic mail.</p>
<p>WebTV, which includes Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen among its investors, licenses its design for set-top boxes to Philips Consumer Electronics Co. and Sony Corp.</p>
<p>The consumer-friendly set-top box, about the same size as a cable box, hooks up to the Internet via a regular telephone line and is easy to use. The system also features a credit card reader that allows users to shop on the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition is the cornerstone of our long-term effort to combine the best of the Internet and the best of digital television technology,&quot; Mundie said.</p>
<p>While about 98 percent of homes in the United States have televisions, even more than have telephones, only about a third of homes have computers and only about one third of those with computers have Internet access.</p>
<p>While services such as WebTV are undoubtedly in their infancy industry experts have predicted explosive growth for the sector. Microsoft's acquisition of WebTV is its attempt to win the battle to take the Internet into every home.</p>
<p>Microsoft said that while numbers were still being finalized it expects to take a charge of between 50 percent and 60 percent of the purchase price, or between $212.5 million and $255 million.</p>
<p>The charge will be taken in either Microsoft's fourth fiscal quarter of 1997 or the first fiscal quarter of 1998, depending on when the deal closes. The rest of the goodwill for WebTV will be written-off shortly after that.</p>
<p>Microsoft said the $425 million comprised mainly of Microsoft shares given to the management of WebTV and its employees but declined to specify how much of the acquisition price was cash.</p>
<p>Seatle-based Microsoft made an equity infusuion into WebTV in September of last year. Since then the two firms have been negotiating to cross-license each others technology.</p>
<p>The acquisition, the biggest for Microsoft so far in the Internet sector, will bring Microsoft's Internet Explorer browser and Window CE, a scaled down version of the Window 95 operating system made for pocket computers, to WebTV which will lead to a more sophisticated product, Mundie said.</p>
<p>WebTV, based in Palo Alto, Calif., will operate as a unit of Microsoft and will continue to be managed by President and Chief Executive Officer Steve Perlman.</p>
<p>Microsoft also said future versions of its Windows operating system will allow personal computer users to view traditional television programs, enhanced television programs and Internet broadcasts, and access innovative new services such as personalized news delivery on their PCs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
