<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="493975" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS-Dow Jones in Microsoft deal.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Dow Jones in Microsoft deal.</headline>
<byline>Nick Louth</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dow Jones &amp; Co Inc on Tuesday announced an alliance with Microsoft Corp designed to edge the embattled media group into faster growing markets, revamp its dusty image and help appease disgruntled shareholders.</p>
<p>The two companies will work together on building a package of services compatible with standard computer software and the Internet to bring financial information and electronic trading out of specialist environments and into new markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Its a typical (Bill) Gates deal,&quot; said analyst Ed Atorino of Oppenheimer and Co.  </p>
<p>&quot;He puts up his expertise and systems and Dow Jones puts up the content,&quot; Atorino said.</p>
<p>No financial details were given, but Dow Jones said the initiative is part of plans to spend $650 million over four years revamping its financial information services unit Dow Jones Markets unit, which used to be called Telerate.</p>
<p>Dow Jones, whose flagship is the Wall Street Journal, has been attacked by shareholders for its pedestrian stock market performance and failure to grow as fast as arch-rival Reuters Holdings Plc and aggressive newcomer Bloomberg LP.  </p>
<p>Some major shareholders say it should sell Dow Jones Markets instead of spending hundreds of millions of dollars on it after letting rivals get ahead in past years.</p>
<p>Analysts say that, if Microsoft really puts its weight behind the alliance, it could be a potent deal that competitors would have to take seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;Once you put Microsoft in the equation it becomes a serious threat to its competitors,&quot; Atorino said.</p>
<p>&quot;If Microsoft is serious about it, it could help close the gap to Reuters. It also gives management something to show shareholders.&quot;  </p>
<p>Dow Jones closed 5/8 lower at $40-3/4 on the New York Stock Exchange, while Reuters' American Depositary Receipts ended 1/2 weaker at $58-1/8 on Nasdaq. Bloomberg is privately owned, although some investors expect an IPO eventually.</p>
<p>Geoffrey Moore, senior vice president of strategic communications at Dow Jones Markets, forecast the global market for financial information services would grow to $8.5 billion by the end of 1999 from $6.5 billion in 1997.</p>
<p>He told Reuters that Dow Jones was planning to get 17.5 percent of that market by 1999, up from 14.5 percent now.  </p>
<p>Moore said Dow Jones will build services that offer electronic transaction services in stock, bond, commodity, energy and foreign exchange with Internet-based standards of news and information presentation, historical databases, risk management and advanced analytical tools.</p>
<p>He acknowledged that both Reuters and Bloomberg were ahead in key areas, but said Dow Jones Markets had worked hard to listen to customers and change its culture.  </p>
<p>Moore said the buy side -- fund managers and wealthy individuals -- was a relatively untapped market for Dow Jones Markets, but was growing faster than the sell-side of big trading rooms, which account for most revenues now.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to expand into the buy side, which we think will grow faster and where Bloomberg has done well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Transactions is a business that Reuters has been a major player in and it is a $1 billion a year revenue business for them.&quot;</p>
<p>Microsoft will not be putting up any money for the venture, but will help distribute the products through its sales force whose coverage overlaps that of Dow Jones.</p>
<p>&quot;For Microsoft it is going to be a great way to sell Windows NT and Internet technology into new market places,&quot; Matthew Conners, Microsoft marketing manager for financial services told Reuters. &quot;This does not preclude Microsoft from working with other vendors.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts say Dow Jones's plans are ambitious.</p>
<p>&quot;Dow Jones is giving itself four years. This is not a tune up, its an engine overhaul,&quot; Atorino said.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsrom 212 859 1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
