<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494186" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBC signs affiliates to Internet package.</title>
<headline>NBC signs affiliates to Internet package.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Electric Co's NBC said Tuesday it has signed up its 11 owned and operated stations, as well as four affilates owned by LIN Television Corp, to join its NBC-Interactive Neighborhood, a local Internet content package.</p>
<p>Scheduled to launch by the end of the year, NBC-Interactive Neighborhood said the first signed partners came after the company presented the package yesterday to all of its 204 affiliates and 11 owned and operated stations.  </p>
<p>Marty Yudkovitz, the president of NBC Interactive, said the package offers the local station's Web pages a range of local content, such as Microsoft Corp's Sidewalk for entertainment listings, NYNEX Corp's Big Yellow, an online yellow pages, as well as apartment and job listings.</p>
<p>The company said its chosen search engine for NBC Interactive is Infoseek Corp.</p>
<p>The Internet package is designed to offer &quot;the most useful real value to normal people in their normal daily lives,&quot; Yudkovitz said, backed by the national brand name and resources of NBC.  </p>
<p>&quot;The concept here is to combine some real horsepower with sensibility in how it is branded and how it is promoted,&quot; he said. &quot;Having it customized to the local affiliate is crucial.&quot;</p>
<p>NBC Interactive Neighborhood faces stiff competition in the market to provide local Internet content and get some of the estimated $72 billion market in local advertising.</p>
<p>Besides the local niche players and start-ups, the competition includes  CitySearch and Warner Brothers CityWeb. Yudkovitz said he welcomed the competition.  </p>
<p>&quot;The CityWeb of Warner Brothers has been very very aggressive. Having that competition out there helped focus people's attention on this,&quot; he said. &quot;It just made people that much more receptive to the interactive neighborhood.&quot;</p>
<p>Yudkovitz said the Internet package is offered free of charge to the local affiliates in exchange for promotion of the service on the local television station. The package is designed to help the stations build their Internet businesses without incurring financial risk.</p>
<p>The affiliates will get 100 percent of the local ad inventory and a fraction of the ad revenues stemming from the local section of the content provider's pages, Yudkovitz said.</p>
<p>&quot;The more traffic they drive, the more cash they get,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The NBC stations signed on include: WNBC New York; KNBC Los Angeles; WMAQ Chicago; WCAU Philadelphia; WRC Washington; WTVJ Miami; NBC 7/39 San Diego; WCMH Columbus, Ohio; WNCN Raleigh, N.C.; WJAR Providence, R.I.; and WVTM, Birmingham, Ala.</p>
<p>The LIN affiliates are: KXAS Dallas; KXAN Austin; WAVY Norfolk; and WOOD Grand Rapids, Mich.</p>
<p>The other content providers included so far in the package are TMP Worldwide Inc's Monster Board job list, CUC International Inc's RentNet, HOT Coupons, Happy Puppy games site, and Auto-By-Tel, a car-buying service.</p>
<p>-- Patricia Willens, 212-859-1727</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
