<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="494667" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oxford Molecular launch OMIGA drug software.</title>
<headline>Oxford Molecular launch OMIGA drug software.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oxford Molecular Group Plc said on Wednesday it had launched its latest software package for use in drug discovery.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement that the OMIGA system would help scientists to search for new biological targets by analysing DNA and protein sequences.</p>
<p>Shares in Oxford Molecular, which specialises in creating software that allows scientists to model molecules and design drugs, were up 18 1/2 pence at 420 pence in early afternoon trading.</p>
<p>Oxford Molecular said OMIGA was the first in a planned family of integrated software tools. It added that OMIGA was also the first sequence analysis software to be available in both the Windows 95 and Windows NT 4 formats, which are the most widely-used by pharmaceutical companies and academic researchers.</p>
<p>The new software will allow scientists to identify contrasting gene sequences. Gene-cloning experiments can also be simulated on screen to test for possible results.</p>
<p>Oxford Molecular already has alliances with major drug companies, including Japan's Yamanouchi Pharmaceutical Co. It also has a contract with Glaxo Wellcome Plc to install special software in 3000 computers which allows different computer programmes used by its researchers to be integrated.</p>
<p>Shares in Oxford Molecular have risen by 18 percent since the start of 1997, although they are below the February 24 high of 475 pence, which followed the release of a new version of its MacVector sequence analysis software.</p>
<p>According to Reuters 3000 data the shares have outperformed the FT-SE all-share index by around 10 percent since the start of the year after outperforming it by up to 26 percent at their February peak.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
