<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497454" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Computer executives earn big bucks.</title>
<headline>Computer executives earn big bucks.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-04-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Carnegies and Rockefellers of the information age gathered here on Wednesday at a computer conference that showed off the commercial might of technology as much as its computing power.</p>
<p>Where once the titans of industry made steel and railroads or searched for oil in Texas, the industry leaders at the Compaq Computer Corp. event here make chips, assemble PCs and write software.</p>
<p>On the bill Wednesday was Intel Corp. Chief Executive Officer Andy Grove, who, according to a company filing, made $95 million in stock options in 1996.</p>
<p>He was hosted by Compaq President Eckhard Pfeiffer, who pulled in $23.5 million in stock options last year, Compaq said.</p>
<p>Scheduled to close out the two-day Innovate Forum was Microsoft Corp. Chairman Bill Gates, the richest man in the United States with $26 billion in Microsoft stock holdings.</p>
<p>Gates is a perennial bargain as far as salary goes. He made $562,000 in the latest fiscal year including bonuses and is not eligible for stock options. Several Microsoft executives made more than he did.</p>
<p>The three men, however, have not just enriched themselves, they have helped fire a bull market in stocks that is only now beginning to flag.</p>
<p>Grove's Intel, for example, has gone from a 12-month low of $58.25 before hitting a high of $165. It slipped more than $4 Wednesday to $142.25 as the general market sagged.</p>
<p>Intel spokesman Howard High said that in 1996 Grove exercised options to buy 1.04 million Intel shares. The difference between what he paid for the stock and its market value gave him a paper profit of $95 million, he said.</p>
<p>In addition, Grove got salary and bonuses totalling about $3.4 million, High said.</p>
<p>Compaq spokeswoman Nora Hahn said Pfeiffer had a gain of $23.5 million on Compaq stock options. His total compensation for the year, including the options, was $27 million, she said.</p>
<p>In both cases, the executives exercised options that were about to expire. High and Hahn said company pay plans were based on longevity and excellent performance.</p>
<p>&quot;Intel has performed very well over the years and Andy has certainly been a big reason for that. His growth in net worth mirrors the company's success,&quot; said High.</p>
<p>Analyst John MacGilvary of Datapro Information Services Group said the salaries could be justified.</p>
<p>&quot;It may seem excessive to the average person, but they're (the executives) the ones taking all the risk and setting all the directions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Peter Lowber, also a Datapro analyst, disagreed.</p>
<p>&quot;From a common person like myself, it's so way out of sight and out of line with other people's needs around the world,&quot; he said. &quot;But that's the way our society is set up. Is that the way to set up a society?</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
