<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499382" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: McDonnell Douglas seal first Hungary offset.</title>
<headline>McDonnell Douglas seal first Hungary offset.</headline>
<byline>Duncan Shiels</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>McDonnell Douglas announced on Thursday it had set up the first business deal which may count towards the recent offset agreement it signed with Hungary in its bid to sell fighters to the country.</p>
<p>The deal, worth 90 million forints ($500,000), is for architectural software to be delivered by Hungarian software company Graphisoft to Finnish wooden home constructor Honkarakenne Oy.</p>
<p>McDonnell Douglas (MD) vice-president Bud Mitchell told reporters MD was looking to have at least some of the value of the deal offset against an eventual purchase by Hungary of F/A 18 Hornets if the U.S. firm wins a future tender for around 30 fighter planes expected to be published late in 1997.</p>
<p>The company signed a protocol industrial cooperation agreement with Hungary's Ministry of Industry and Trade in December.</p>
<p>&quot;We have at the current time not established a credit from the ministry -- we will be preparing a submittal under the guidelines of the protocol agreement we signed in December,&quot; Mitchell told reporters. &quot;We expect to be treated very fairly by the offset committee.&quot;</p>
<p>Honkarakenne Oy is one of the companies involved in MD's offset programme with the Finnish governent which forms part of a deal signed in 1992 to sell Hornets to the Finnish air force.</p>
<p>Finland selected the Hornet after intense competition between Lockheed Martin's F-16, the Dassault's Mirage 2000-5 and the Saab 's JAS-39 Gripen.</p>
<p>All four firms have expressed their intention to bid for the $1 billion tender to supply Hungary and all but Dassault have signed offset deals, although the French company is also expected to conclude an industrial package under the expected terms of the tender.</p>
<p>Mitchell said deals set up between small and medium companies were seen by the Hungarian and Finnish governments as an important component of the offset arrangements. He added that MD has examined over 100 companies in Hungary.</p>
<p>&quot;We have plenty more in the pipeline,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;In the aggregate, (small and medium companies) will probably end up representing up to 15 percent of the total.&quot;</p>
<p>Mitchell said MD's joint bid submitted last month with Boeing Co and Czech airlines Ceske Aerolinie (CSA) for a 34-40 percent stake in Czech jet maker Aero Vodochody could be part of an offset agreement with the Czech government once it launches a tender of its own for new fighter planes.</p>
<p>&quot;We have responded to guidelines in the Czech government's tender request and we are awaiting their evaluation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The consortium has offered to use Aero facilities to make spare parts for Boeing civilian planes and in assembling components for the Hornet.</p>
<p>Finland is among eight countries that either fly the Hornet or have ordered it. A total of 1,290 of the aircraft have been delivered worldwide.</p>
<p>The U.S. Navy and Marine Corps have taken delivery of 960, Canada 138, Australia 75, Spain 72 and Kuwait 40. Switzerland has ordered 34 F/A-18s, Malaysia eight, and Spain has signed an agreement to purchase 24 additional F/A-18A model Hornets from the U.S. Navy's inventory.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom +361 327 4048</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I46000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
