<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="499898" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CEO pay far outstrips economy, stocks - Business Week.</title>
<headline>CEO pay far outstrips economy, stocks - Business Week.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chief executives' pay far outstripped the roaring economy or the increases racked up by shareholders last year, with the average big-company CEO's annual compensation hitting $5.78 million, Business Week magazine reported Thursday.</p>
<p>The average total CEO pay soared 54 percent in 1996 and came on top of a 30 percent increase in 1995, the weekly magazine said in its April 21 issue out Thursday.</p>
<p>That compared with a 3 percent raise in the average annual pay of factory workers, who made 209 times less, Business Week said.</p>
<p>The magazine said the highest-paid boss in its 47th annual survey, with $102,449,000 in salary and bonus, was little-known Lawrence Coss, chairman and CEO of Green Tree Financial Corp., a St. Paul, Minn.-based company that makes loans for mobile homes.</p>
<p>The magazine pointed to a five-year deal set in 1991 that pays Coss the equivalent of 2.5 percent of pretax income.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed, it is a high number,&quot; Coss told Business Week, &quot;but I'd rather talk about the success of the company.</p>
<p>Between 1991 and 1996, the company had compounded annual returns of 53 percent as it became the largest lender in its sector, according to the magazine.</p>
<p>Experts argue that as long as CEOs continue turning in strong results for their shareholders, the absolute level of executive pay is irrelevant, Business Week said. But unions and shareholder activist groups say CEOs are making too much.</p>
<p>The average CEO pay, counting salary, retirement benefits, incentive plans and -- most importantly, Business Week said -- gains from stock options, was $5,781,300. The magazine examined the pay of top two highest-paid executives at 365 companies.</p>
<p>The magazine also identified Microsoft Corp. Chairman Bill Gates and Avon Products Inc. CEO James Preston as the best-performing executives over a three-year period.</p>
<p>Gates, who made $1.436 million in total pay from 1994 to 1996, got top honours for giving shareholders the most bang for their bucks.</p>
<p>Microsoft shareholders saw a 310 percent return for the period, calculated by taking the stock price at the end of 1996 plus dividends reinvested for three years and dividing it by the stock price at the end of 1993, the magazine said.</p>
<p>Business Week pointed out that Gates also has a 23.7 percent stake in Microsoft worth $27.7 billion.</p>
<p>Preston, whose three-year total pay was $7.907 million, was the leader among executives whose companies did the best, the magazine said. He racked up the highest return on equity -- a 141 percent three-year average -- relative to his pay.</p>
<p>Business Week also singled out &quot;underperformers.&quot; Conseco Inc.'s Stephen Hilbert gave shareholders the lowest return -- 133 percent -- from 1994 to 1996 relative to the $165 million he's collected since 1994, the magazine said.</p>
<p>America Online Inc. CEO Steve Case took &quot;honors&quot; for the worst corporate performance relative to salary, earning $33.5 million over three years while the online service's return on equity was a negative 413 percent, Business Week said.</p>
<p>Coming in second after Coss in the list of top-paid executives was Intel Corp. President and CEO Andrew Grove, who made $3.003 million in salary and bonus and $94.587 million in long-term compensation for a total $97.59 million.</p>
<p>No. 3 was Travelers Group Inc. Chairman and CEO Sanford Weill, with $6.33 million in salary and pay and $87.828 million in long-term compensation.</p>
<p>Other well-known names on the Top 10 list included H.J. Heinz Co. Chairman and CEO Anthony O'Reilly, No. 5 with $64.236 million in total pay, and Citicorp Chairman and CEO John Reed, seventh with $43.61 million.</p>
<p>--------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Here is a list of the Top 10 highest-paid executives, with name, company and total pay, in millions:</p>
<p>Lawrence Coss     Green Tree Financial Corp. $102.449</p>
<p>Andrew Grove	Intel Corp.		     $97.590</p>
<p>Sanford Weill     Travelers Group Inc.	  $94.157</p>
<p>Theodore Waitt    Gateway 2000 Inc.	     $81.326</p>
<p>Anthony O'Reilly  H.J. Heinz			$64.236</p>
<p>Sterling Williams Sterling Software	     $58.249</p>
<p>John Reed	   Citicorp			  $43.610</p>
<p>Stephen Hilbert   Conseco			   $37.412</p>
<p>Casey Cowell	U.S. Robotics		   $33.952</p>
<p>James Moffett     Freeport-McMoran C&amp;G	  $33.732</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
