<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="513680" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CD-ROM brings pirates' lives to life.</title>
<headline>CD-ROM brings pirates' lives to life.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ah, the life of a pirate! There's salt in the air, adventure in the wind, sword fights at every turn! Of course, there's also disease, rats scurrying around the deck and crewmates who haven't bathed for weeks.</p>
<p>When you think about it, be glad you don't get the full sensory experience when you play &quot;Pirates: Captain's Quest&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $30). In the days of the pirate, pain and bloodshed abounded and death was around every corner, or, as I was told when I was killed in a sword fight, &quot;The worms await you.&quot;</p>
<p>Nonetheless, this new educational game from Discovery Channel Multimedia offers an entertaining look at what it was like to be a Caribbean buccaneer in the 18th century, where success was measured by how much you could steal by raiding a town or capturing a merchant ship.</p>
<p>&quot;Pirates&quot; is partly a game and partly a learning experience. It lets you easily control the speed and direction of your ship, climb to the crow's nest to check out a distant island, engage in battle to replenish your provisions, pick up some gold for trade, or board a ship to cross swords with its captain.</p>
<p>These are the elements that are most likely to appeal to children 9 and older, the target audience for &quot;Pirates.&quot; Unfortunately, this is the area where the developers tried to save too many doubloons.</p>
<p>The ports I visited all looked essentially the same, with the same tavern, governor's quarters, jail, and trading post. Often the same people showed up in different ports hundreds of miles apart, such as the robed fortune teller with the blue lipstick who spouted bad poetry.</p>
<p>The animation won't win any awards. In a tavern, you may hear a huge crowd of people raucously celebrating; but when you look around, the entire place is empty except for a bartender and a waitress. In the sailing simulation, there were times when the distant ship seemed to sail just above the waves like an 18th century Flying Dutchman.</p>
<p>The character's words didn't always match the movement of their mouths.</p>
<p>But the game is so easy to use, most pre-teens will probably forgive the shortcomings.</p>
<p>The real strength of &quot;Pirates&quot; lies in its information about the politics and culture that shaped the age of the pirates.</p>
<p>&quot;Pirates&quot; gives players 47 missions, each designed to reveal new tales of the profession.</p>
<p>A pirate crew, for example, was often a democracy. Captains were elected into the job by the crew, and all members had a equal say in the key decisions, including whether to give the captain's job to someone else and what type of discipline to mete out for a serious charge.</p>
<p>Although women were seldom allowed aboard pirate ships, some notable pirates were women.</p>
<p>Ann Bonny was an Irish girl who became part of a pirate band by posing as a man. When her group captured a Dutch merchant ship, a handsome young sailor who joined the crew also turned out to be a woman. Her name was Mary Read.</p>
<p>Mary and Ann became friends and eventually revealed their gender to the other pirates, who accepted them. From that point, they dressed as women, except when attacking other ships.</p>
<p>It's stories like these that offer the real treasure in &quot;Pirates.&quot; And with plenty of tales to unearth during visits to 34 Caribbean ports -- and lots of ships to attack along the way -- would-be swashbucklers should stay busy for quite a while.</p>
<p>By the way, &quot;Pirates&quot; was officially released April 15 -- the day income tax returns were due. The folks at Discovery Channel Multimedia say it's just a coincidence.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Interstate '76&quot; (Activision, Windows95, $50) lets you drive a car with as much firepower as horsepower as you try to defend America's largest oil reserve from auto terrorists in the racing/battle simulation set in the 1970s. There are 17 missions in all.</p>
<p>&quot;Screamer 2&quot; (Virgin Interactive, DOS/Windows95, $30) may sound like a horror game, but it's actually the sequel to an arcade-style car racing game. It lets you race on tracks through the Austrian mountains and between the pyramids of Egypt. The game also promises that &quot;realistic car physics mean you feel every inch of road, every ounce of centrifugal force.&quot; Yeah, right.</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
