<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="518248" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.S. stocks in London steady, tobaccos active.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks in London steady, tobaccos active.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. shares were steady to firmer on Thursday following Wall Street's third straight winning session on Wednesday but trading activity, with the exception of red-hot tobaccos, was light as investors remained wary about the Dow's rally.</p>
<p>&quot;This market looks like it's building up for a sucker punch. I think it will suck in a few more people before a big fall,&quot; one market maker said. The Dow, which jumped nearly 93 points on Wednesday has gained 288 points over the past three trading days but is still over 400 points below its all-time closing high of 7,085.16 reached on March 11.  </p>
<p>But dealers said Wall Street's recovery was not broad based, noting that second-line stocks continued to underperform blue chips.</p>
<p>The broader-based Nasdaq Composite, closed lower for the second straight session on Wednesday and U.S. treasuries also lost ground, with the yield on the benchmark 30-year long bond rising to 7.10 percent from 7.08 the previous session.</p>
<p>&quot;The tobaccos and some fairly good earnings news is keeping the Dow afloat at the moment but I still think it will only delay another push down,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>Chris Chaitow, technical analyst at Robert Fleming believes the Dow is staging a technical bounce from an oversold position but is still destined to drop as low as 5,500 by the end of the summer.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dow could rally quite easily up to the 6,800 level but by the last two weeks of May I would expect the sellers to be back on top,&quot; Chaitow said.</p>
<p>Chaitow said a 20 percent Dow correction to around 5,500 should be expected considering U.S. blue chips had jumped over 70 percent in the past two years alone.</p>
<p>&quot;The real question is when we reach the 5,500 area whether or not the selling will continue. If it does, then we have a real problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Fired-up tobaccos continued to burn bright in active European trade as investors hoped the industry may finally see the light at the end of a long U.S. litigation tunnel.</p>
<p>Philip Morris Cos. Inc, which jumped $4-3/8 on Wednesday, accounting for 15 percent or 14 points of the Dow's gains, was up $1/4 to $43-1/2, while RJR Nabisco Holdings added $1/8 to $33-5/8 after a $3-1/4 spurt in New York.</p>
<p>Cyrix Corp was up $2-1/2 to $20-1/4 in Europe after hitting a high of $21 in U.S. after-hours in reaction to the company's strong first-quarter earnings report.</p>
<p>The personal computer chip maker said Q1 profit rose $0.33 from $0.10 in the same period the previous year, attributing the increase to strong customer acceptance of its microprocessors, higher gross margins and improved manufacturing efficiencies.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Microsoft Corp was up $1/2 to $97-3/4 ahead of its third-quarter figures due later on Thursday.</p>
<p>Analysts expect the software group to post earnings of $0.64 a share in Q3 compared with $0.44 a year ago, according to First Call.</p>
<p>Shares in Gillette Co were shaved $3/8 lower to $81-1/2 after soaring over five percent in New York on Wednesday in anticipation of strong first-quarter figures later today.</p>
<p>The June S&amp;P 500 futures contract was down 0.60 to 767.70 by 1100 GMT, while the June T-bond rose 8/32 to 107-23/32.</p>
<p>--Dale Faulken, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
