<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52123" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Technology shares in US up on improving sentiment.</title>
<headline>Technology shares in US up on improving sentiment.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Technology stocks rallied on Friday on signs Wall Street's outlook on the sector is improving after months of disfavor.</p>
<p>One standout Friday was International Business Machines Corp, which jumped 4-1/4 to 121-1/2 after Merrill Lynch raised its near-term rating to a strong buy from accumulate.</p>
<p>SoundView Financial Group President and Market Strategist James Townsend said technology stocks as a group are poised to outperform the broad market once again.  </p>
<p>Since the marketwide sell-off in July, tech stocks have lagged the broad market and the tech-laden Nasdaq Composite remains well below its peak even as the resurgent Dow has rebounded, setting an intraday record early today.</p>
<p>Townsend, who raised his near-term weighting on the sector to overweight from average, said he expects the group as measured by the firm's SoundView index to rally by 30-40 percent over the next four to five months.  </p>
<p>&quot;Generally speaking, technology as a group has underperformed not only for the last few months, but actually from September 13, 1995, so one can argue there's been a long-term period of relative underperformance,&quot; Townsend said.</p>
<p>The upgrade does not just reflect the underperformance, he said, because &quot;as we look at the group today, it's with a focus on whether the fundamentals are in place (for a rally).&quot;</p>
<p>Townsend declined to make a prediction about the broader market, but said &quot;it's hard to be too optimistic in technology if the broader market seems vulnerable to a correction.&quot;  </p>
<p>The American Stock Exchange's computer technology index rose seven points, or 2.5 percent, to 279.29. On a percentage basis, the index's gains were triple the Dow's 48 point, 0.83 percent, rise to 5819.</p>
<p>Townsend's technology call brings his short-term rating in line with his long-term weighting, which has remained at overweight for some time, he said.</p>
<p>Technology stocks topped the actives lists on both the NSYE and Nasdaq, where Oracle Corp was most active, rising 3-3/8 to 40-7/8 after Alex Brown upgraded the shares to buy and Cowen &amp; Co reiterated its strong buy rating.  </p>
<p>Intel Corp rose 2-3/8 to 87-3/4 and modem maker U.S. Robotics Corp rose 4-1/4 to 66. Cisco Systems gained 1-9/16 to 57-3/4 and Microsoft Corp rose 1-1/4 to 129-7/8.</p>
<p>IBM was the NSYE's most active issue, with Micron Technology Inc also busy, rising 1/4 to 23-3/4.</p>
<p>The optimism was not enough for some individual stocks to shake off their troubles. One example was Novell Inc, which fell 1/8 to 10-3/8, after touching a year-low 10-1/8 early in the session.</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
