<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="523670" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Waiting for IBM earnings.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Waiting for IBM earnings.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Business Machines Corp options drew a great deal of interest ahead of the computer giant's quarterly earnings due out on Wednesday, traders said.</p>
<p>IBM options volume on the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE) was spread out relatively evenly among at-the-money strike and three or four strikes out in both puts and calls, reflecting the stock's wild gyrations in recent weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect them (IBM shares) to continue to trade nervously ahead of those numbers,&quot; said Jon Najarian, president of Mercury Trading.  </p>
<p>&quot;They had a big run up in just the last week and a half, where they came up from the 20s (April 3 low of 128-7/8) up here, and then had this selloff (today),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The stock was at 137, down 2-5/8 on the day, in late trade.</p>
<p>Traders implied volatilities for May options in the 135 and 140 strikes stood at around 35 percent and would probably get richer in the next one or two days.</p>
<p>&quot;Normally, we would expect them to peak at something in the mid- to low-40 percent number right around the earnings, so they've probably got a little more to go,&quot; Najarian said.  </p>
<p>Todd Salamone, a senior research analyst at Cincinnati-based Investment Research Institute, agreed.</p>
<p>He said compared with the stock's actual historical volatility of around 30 percent, the May pricing was not too high, only days before an earnings report.</p>
<p>May 140 and 150 calls were among the busiest calls on CBOE with turnover of about 1,500 to 2,400 each by late afternoon while May puts with strikes from 125 to 140 traded 1,400 to 2,800 lots. Although the volume was not too impressive, overall options market activity was slow today after Friday's April option expirations.  </p>
<p>One brokerage trader said some investors who had not rolled over their April positions to May last week were re-opening positions today.</p>
<p>Salamone noted that the highest open interest concentration was in the 130 puts, with 11,322 contracts outstanding as of end-Friday. The 130 puts were also the busiest IBM option today with volume of 2,809 contracts.</p>
<p>That, combined with the fact that the 130-area coincided with the early 1996 highs and the lows earlier this month, could provide some cushion to the downside in the event of a negative earnings report, he said.  </p>
<p>According to First Call, analysts expect IBM's first quarter earnings to be around $2.28 per share against $2.21 a year earlier.</p>
<p>Najarian warned that the Street's expectation had probably become higher in recent days after a number of good earnings reports, notably Microsoft Corp's stratospheric results last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's almost like a beauty contest ...&quot; he said. He added, though, that IBM in recent years had not disappointed investors with earnings.</p>
<p>Shin Kishima/Chicago Derivatives Desk ((312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
