<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="52381" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Video game industry faces challenge from Internet.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Video game industry faces challenge from Internet.</headline>
<byline>Robert Woodward</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Heaven may be just around the corner for video &quot;gamers&quot; hooked on the likes of Nights, Mortal Kombat and Monster Truck Madness as Europe's soft- and hardware companies turn their attention to the challenge of the Internet.</p>
<p>The main battle in Europe's $2.8 billion electronic games market is being fought between manufacturers of dedicated consoles and software, and those who believe personal computers and CD ROM software are the future of video games.</p>
<p>But talk at this week's European Electronic Games Industry fair increasingly turned to the threat and opportunities provided by the World Wide Web and online platforms.</p>
<p>At present online commands only two percent of the market but by the turn of the century this could rise to 20 percent, according to research by Datamonitor released at the fair.</p>
<p>The fair featured only a sprinkling of online companies among huge stands manned by Sega, Sony and Microsoft which all predicted a bumper Christmas for the video games industry.</p>
<p>But visionaries talk of online platforms allowing 150 players to fight for supremacy inside an electronic universe. Players could log on 24 hours a day and chart their kill ratio against other players around the world in a league table.</p>
<p>&quot;The vision is there to create this market. There's not a truly multi-player game out there at the moment,&quot; said Robert Smith, of British Telecom's personal communications division.</p>
<p>Gamers in Europe can currently take part in a multi-player game on a Local Area Network -- linked personal computers normally in the same building.</p>
<p>Until recently, the Internet allowed gamers in Europe to play against each other on games -- like bridge and chess -- not relying on speed or large amounts of information.</p>
<p>Now 3-D action games are beginning to appear on the Internet with real time and real audio, allowing players to ride a roller coaster or battle through a multi-user dungeon (MUD).</p>
<p>Two products showcased at the London industry fair showed the possible shape of the future. BT, Britain's largest telecommunications company, has dipped its toe in the online pond by launching &quot;Wireplay&quot;, an interactive games network.</p>
<p>Players can choose opponents, monitor skill levels, set up leagues, and discuss tactics and rules in an electronic &quot;locker room&quot;. BT set up its &quot;Wireplay&quot; pilot in April with 2,000 gamers and hopes 100,000 will sign up within a year of its start-up.</p>
<p>It has just introduced a special edition of flight combat game EF2000 which, like all its software, is available free. Wireplay does not charge a subscription but makes its money from gamers' telephone usage.</p>
<p>Players, whom BT reckon spend an average of 30 minutes online, pay a special low rate at weekends and in the evenings.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been lots of multi-player games on the market for a long time but you could not use them properly until now,&quot; Smith said. &quot;Wireplay is a lot smoother, faster and easier than the Internet and you play real people, not just a computer.&quot;</p>
<p>Wireplay works off one dedicated central server but E-On, launched by British-based Entertainment Online, plans to have a different language server for all the main countries in Europe for its online games network.</p>
<p>Entertainment Online, based in Leicester, central England, claims to be the world's first dedicated online games channel. For six pounds ($9.33) a month, the company's web site allows access to hundreds of games.</p>
<p>E-On aims to involve the whole family -- the web site contains a magazine, a digital shop and educational material.</p>
<p>Chief operating officer Mark Bernstein does not expect E-On to take off until mid-1997 because of the immaturity of the European market. But &quot;there is little doubt online will become a major distribution mechanism over the next 15 years&quot;, he says.</p>
<p>Datamonitor estimates the online games market could be worth $900 million by 2000 compared with around $65 million this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The development of the market will allow new revenue streams to be extracted by network operators, including telecommunications and cable companies,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Service provision will be the second important revenue stream, and the role of the service provider could well be filled by network operators and software publishers alike.&quot;</p>
<p>Software companies welcome the Internet, seeing online platforms as offering new markets and marginal profits for mature games. New games are increasingly being made Internet-compatible and multi-player software specifically designed for use on the Internet is in the pipeline.</p>
<p>They believe the web will help accelerate the move away from dedicated consoles to personal computers.</p>
<p>&quot;The expanding market is the casual gamer who has bought his PC for educational and other reasons and wants to have a go at games,&quot; says Microsoft's Stephen McGill. &quot;We estimate one in three homes will have a PC in Britain next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Those in the dedicated console market, the area most likely to be affected by increased online use, are sanguine about the threat. Datamonitor sees the console hardware market peaking in 1999 under pressure from PC's and online providers.</p>
<p>In an industry which craves new technology, hard-core gamers are bound to give the Internet a try, says Andy Mee, European market director for Sega.</p>
<p>Sega has launched &quot;Net-link&quot; which allows point to point gaming between Sega consoles. Mee sees no reason why, in the future, Sega Saturns could not &quot;game&quot; with PCs across the web.</p>
<p>Quite how influential Internet gaming becomes appears to depend on how &quot;personal&quot; addicts like to get in a hobby which until recently has been a largely solitary one.</p>
<p>Mee believes the &quot;faceless society&quot; of online will not interest gamers but McGill maintains they just want to play as many people as possible, whatever the medium.</p>
<p>&quot;Online is initially an add-on,&quot; Mee said. &quot;It has its place in the market but it is not going to be the be-all and end-all.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
