<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="525942" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Iona Technologies Q1 revenue up 145 pct to $9 mln.</title>
<headline>Iona Technologies Q1 revenue up 145 pct to $9 mln.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iona Technologies Plc, an Irish company quoted on NASDAQ, on Monday reported a 145 percent increase in total revenues to $9.1 million for the first quarter to March 30.</p>
<p>The company reported an increase of 31 percent in net income to $1.4 million, or $0.08 per share, up from $1.1 million or $0.07 per share in the corresponding period in 1996.</p>
<p>Chairman and chief executive Chris Horn said it has been an historic three months for Iona.</p>
<p>&quot;Our first quarter on NASDAQ, along with the release of a number of notable new products and initiatives has marked a busy period in our history,&quot; Horn said.</p>
<p>He said the group was continuing to work hard to maintain its leadership in the object technology market.</p>
<p>Iona, formed in 1991, creates systems to integrate multiple, diverse software applications.</p>
<p>Its flagship product Orbix, allows organisations to build software components with open standard interfaces so that they can communicate with any other software conforming to the same standard.</p>
<p>&quot;The company has performed well in the first quarter of this year with good growth in all our business areas,&quot; Mick Prokopis, chief financial officer said in a results statement.</p>
<p>He said Iona plans to continue to grow its business with aggressive spending on sales, marketing and research and development.</p>
<p>Iona reported total first quarter operating expenses of $5.6 million versus $1.8 million in the first quarter of 1996 and gross profit of $6.97 million up from $2.95 million.</p>
<p>-- Dublin newsroom +353 1 676 9775</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
