<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="526698" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: FEATURE -  Ireland lures the cream of the high tech industry.</title>
<headline>FEATURE -  Ireland lures the cream of the high tech industry.</headline>
<byline>Carmel Linnane</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silicone Valley is not just unique to California. The tiny Republic of Ireland, with its 3.6 million population, has attracted a list of major international names which reads like a who's who in the high technology arena.</p>
<p>&quot;In the last 10 years, Ireland has established itself as the software capital of Europe,&quot; said Kieran McGowan, chief executive of IDA Ireland, the state body whose task it is to attract overseas investment.</p>
<p>&quot;Since Lotus established here in 1984, a list of overseas software companies have followed their example, including five of the world's top 10 independent software houses,&quot; McGowan said.</p>
<p>Ireland now treats as household names international conglomerates such as Intel Corp, Microsoft Corp, Hewlett-Packard Co Novell Inc, Electronic Data Systems Corp and International Business Machines Corp, all of whom have invested large amounts of funds in facilities in Ireland.</p>
<p>&quot;Ireland has become the market leader for U.S. companies undertaking greenfield investment into Europe,&quot; McGowan said, noting that 30 percent of all such projects now come to Ireland.</p>
<p>ECONOMIC BENEFITS</p>
<p>Such is Ireland's success that income from multinationals now supports one in three people in the country's manufacturing labour force.</p>
<p>The exchequer is reaping billions of pounds in corporation tax from overseas companies, who account for threequarters of manufacturing exports and half of total exports out of Ireland.</p>
<p>&quot;The impact of overseas companies in the economy has increased substantially, with exports of 12.6 billion Irish pounds ($19.8 billion) and the Irish economy expenditures of 4.4 billion Irish pounds generating very significant downstream employment,&quot; McGowan said.</p>
<p>He said there were many spinoffs as well, including the growth in linkages between overseas companies and indigenous firms.</p>
<p>&quot;Purchasing of Irish-made components and raw materials has reached 1.3 billion Irish pounds per annum, nearly 90 percent growth over six years and spending on Irish services is 1.4 billion Irish pounds, which means 60 percent growth over six years,&quot; the IDA said.</p>
<p>McGowan said both of these give rise to substantial employment growth in Irish service and supplier companies and multinationals now employ in excess of 97,000 workers.</p>
<p>FOUR PILLARS OF STRENGTH</p>
<p>The IDA said Ireland's success in the highly competitive area of attracting inward investment was based on four pillars of strength.</p>
<p>First, the high level of qualifications and skills in the workforce, second, the existence of a special 10 percent rate of corporation tax, third, the flexibility and adaptability of the workforce and finally, the pulling power of the existing 'blue chip' companies already operating successfully in Ireland.</p>
<p>Ulster Bank economist Eoin Fahy agrees, but emphasised the importance of the 10 percent special tax rate.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a combination of the availability of an English-speaking workforce which is well educated and of course the 10 percent tax rate is hugely important,&quot; Fahy told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said although the capital grants given by Ireland were not always as large as those offered by some other countries such as Britain, the overall package, including the special tax rate, was very favourable.</p>
<p>INTEL</p>
<p>One of Ireland's biggest investors Intel Corporation, located in California's Silicone Valley, has committed a total of $2.5 billion to its Irish division's development, Intel Ireland Ltd, and is now the biggest supplier of semi-conductors to Europe from its Irish base.</p>
<p>General manager Intel Ireland Frank McCabe told Reuters the firm chose Ireland primarily because of its close proximity to Europe. He said other key factors were being able to hire the &quot;best and the brightest&quot; of Ireland's highly educated graduates in an environment conducive to agility, speed and flexibility.</p>
<p>McCabe said the special tax rate was of course relevant, but would not be drawn on what the company would do if Ireland's low tax incentive, which is due to be reviewed in 2010, ceased.</p>
<p>He pointed out that the Irish exchequer received large sums in tax revenue from multinationals like Intel Ireland despite the low rate of tax.</p>
<p>EXODUS FEARED IF TAX INCENTIVE SCRAPPED</p>
<p>Many people fear a mass exodus out of Ireland by multinationals or at least a vastly reduced success rate if Ireland loses its special tax incentive.</p>
<p>Ulster Bank's Fahy argues that while many countries have higher corporation tax rates they can end up with lower real rates due to special conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;While other European countries do not declare that they have a 10 percent tax rate, it is quite possible to negotiate such a rate or even lower if one is looking at a special areas,&quot; Fahy said.</p>
<p>He said countries such as Belgium and the Netherlands, while having a high nominal rate of corporation tax, have a system where people can claim deductions several times over and end up with a tax rate even below the 10 percent level.</p>
<p>Fahy pointed out that there is nothing illegal about having a 10 percent tax rate. The European Union merely requires that each country has one and only one corporation tax rate across the board.</p>
<p>Ireland reduced its 38 percent general corporation tax rate to 36 percent in its 1997 annual budget and Fahy said he could see the government eventually reducing that general rate to as low as 15 percent across the board in the future.</p>
<p>Fahy said that the cost to the government of such a reduction was more 'apparent than real'.</p>
<p>&quot;It doesn't cost you all that much to cut the tax rate because while you are reducing your revenue from the top rate, you are also reducing a lot of the tax avoidance schemes. So the exchequer would not lose out all that much,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In any case, Fahy said, Ireland had more to offer than tax rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Ireland also has a relatively good telecommunications system and low labour costs relative to core Europe and the U.S., and a very favourable quality of life.&quot;</p>
<p>($ = 0.635 Irish Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
