<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="529397" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - Netscape rated underperform.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Netscape rated underperform.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO, Calif. 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volpe Brown Whelan &amp; Co. analysts initiated coverage of Netscape Communications Corp with an &quot;underperform&quot; recommendation, the brokerages most unfavourable stock rating.</p>
<p>Based on comparative valuations with other fast growing technology companies, including Microsoft, Oracle and Cisco Systems, the analysts said Netscape is trading at a 50 percent premium to the group despite its limited operating history.</p>
<p>Based on a scaled back 30 times earnings model, they set a 12-month price target of $21, down 20 percent from current prices. Netscape, which will report first quarter earnings on Wednesday, fell 1-1/8 to 26-3/4 on Monday.</p>
<p>One of the analysts, Charles Finnie, said the study also took into account surveys of Netscape users and potential customers.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not saying that Netscape's going out of business,&quot; said Finnie. &quot;We're just saying the stock does not come close to reflecting the risks in their business, which are growing more substantial every day.&quot;  </p>
<p>Finnie and colleague David Locke said in their report on Netscape that it no longer enjoyed the luxury of sneaking up on potential rivals, as it had when it began offering browser software to help popularize the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, it is attacking many well-entrenched, well- respected and well-financed gorillas with its new products,&quot; said Finnie, citing Microsoft Corp and International Business Machine Corp's Lotus.</p>
<p>Risks outlined by the analysts include the challenge of building complicated messaging systems, the potential competition of small, privately held startups, and the expected stretching out of its sales cycle. --sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau 415 846 5400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
