<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="529433" id="root" date="1997-04-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP surges as dollar boosts Q1 profit.</title>
<headline>SAP surges as dollar boosts Q1 profit.</headline>
<dateline>WALLDORF, Germany 1997-04-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in German business software group SAP AG jumped on Tuesday after it said the strength of the dollar and a number of large new contracts led to sharp increases in its first quarter sales and earnings.</p>
<p>The company said in a regulatory statement that sales in the first quarter surged 49 percent to 1.032 billion marks and pre-tax profits jumped 54 percent to 181 million marks.</p>
<p>Currency movements, notably the recent rise of the dollar to 37-month highs against the mark, added 55 million marks to revenues, it later calculated.</p>
<p>SAP's DAX-30-quoted preference stock jumped to a new high of 303.50 marks after the figures, later settling back to 300 marks, still 7.10 marks or 2.5 percent up on the day.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market had been expecting pre-tax profit in the region of 155 million marks on sales of 920 million. &quot;SAP was a complete surprise,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>SAP nonetheless stuck to its earlier forecast that sales would rise in the full year by some 25-30 percent. chairman Dietmar Hopp warned that sales growth could slow somewhat from the first quarter's pace.</p>
<p>&quot;Due to the high comparison figures from last year, especially in the fourth quarter, we expect for the year as a whole a flattening of sales growth,&quot; Hopp said.</p>
<p>Strong orders from customers in the U.S., South Africa, India and France were largely behind the first quarter revenue gain, SAP noted.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom + 49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WALLDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
