<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="535550" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Softbank profit grows as U.S. units shine.</title>
<headline>Softbank profit grows as U.S. units shine.</headline>
<byline>Yuzo Saeki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Softbank Corp, an aggressively expanding software and publishing house, showed strong growth in its group results in the last business year thanks to healthly earnings at its U.S. subsidiaries.</p>
<p>The good news was expected to continue in the current year as well, with U.S. acquisitions again putting in a robust performance.</p>
<p>Softbank, led by one of Japan's most charismatic entrepreneurs, on Thursday announced group sales of 359.74 billion yen ($2.85 billion) in the year ended on March 31, more than double the previous year's sales.</p>
<p>Group current profit was up 94 percent to 27.88 billion yen ($221 million) in 1996/97. Current profit is pre-tax and includes losses or gains on investments.</p>
<p>&quot;In short, we can call this fabulous,&quot; Softbank president Masayoshi Son told a news conference on Thursday. &quot;We are seeing increasing contribution from our overseas operations.&quot;</p>
<p>Son said operating profits at Softbank's subsidiaries outside Japan accounted for 75 percent of total group profit. The ratio was up from 48.9 percent the previous year.</p>
<p>The weak yen also aided the company's earnings, as it raised the value of dollar-based U.S. assets, he said.</p>
<p>Since September 1994, Softbank has invested nearly 500 billion yen ($3.96 billion) in information-related U.S. businesses such as the Comdex industry trade show and Ziff-Davis Publishing. Son said the value of these investments had risen 20 percent in yen terms as of March.</p>
<p>On a parent basis, the company's sales grew 40 percent to 196.83 billion yen ($1.56 billion) and its current profit rose 79 percent to 23.41 billion yen ($185 million) in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Softbank also expects handsome growth in its earnings in the current business year, which began on April 1, as the U.S. units contribute more to group profits. It forecast a group profit of 35 billion yen ($277 million) for 1997/98.</p>
<p>Son said Softbank aims to register the shares of some of its U.S. subsidiaries on the Nasdaq market in New York in the next few years.</p>
<p>It also plans to take another two of its Japanese subsidiaries public in 1998, in addition to Yahoo! Japan and other units it has already said it will list this year and next.</p>
<p>Despite the strong growth forecast, however, analysts are mixed on whether Softbank, burdened with 250 billion yen ($1.98 billion) in debt accumulated through aggressive acquisitions, is an attractive investment target.</p>
<p>Softbank's share prices dipped as low as 4,544 yen on the over-the-counter market in December, from a high of 12,087 yen in April 1996, after adjustments for stock splits, as investors focused on its massive debts following the acquisition of U.S. memory-board maker Kingston Technology last August.</p>
<p>But share prices rebounded earlier this year and on Thursday closed at 8,120 yen.</p>
<p>Analysts were also concerned about uncertainties over Softbank's digital satellite broadcasting venture with Sony Corp and News Corp, led by media tycoon Rupert Murdoch.</p>
<p>Some analysts said Softbank does not have much influence in the project because of the expected strong leadership by the other two companies. Others warned that the firm could post a special loss of up to 4 billion yen ($31.7 million) related to the project, which is to be launched this year. (1$=126 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
