<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="537754" id="root" date="1997-04-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW - Saville targets Asian growth.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Saville targets Asian growth.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. accounting software firm Saville Systems said on Thursday liberalisation of Asian telecommunications should allow its revenue and profits to continue to grow by about 50 percent a year.</p>
<p>Saville's senior vice president John Kiley told Reuters the company expected its turnover in the Asia Pacific region to grow quickly over the next two or three years.  </p>
<p>&quot;By 2000, we see (US) $50 million to $100 million worth of revenue from the Asia Pacific region, or around 30 percent of forecast global turnover. Now it is negligible,&quot; Kiley said in an interview.</p>
<p>The company's global revenue in 1996 was US$54 million. It is due to announce its first quarter 1997 results on April 28.</p>
<p>&quot;We are growing in excess of 50 percent a year in revenue and income with 30 percent pre-tax profit margin and now have a $700 million market capitalisation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked if he expected this rate of expansion to continue for the foreseeable future, Kiley replied:  </p>
<p>&quot;Yes, we do.&quot;</p>
<p>Saville sells and installs accounting computer programs that allow telecommunications companies to send out integrated bills to customers covering all the various services they use.</p>
<p>Mark Perry, Saville's vice president for Asia Pacific sales, said the company's software made billing faster and more efficient and helped speed up delivery of new services by companies to their target markets.  </p>
<p>He said customers gained by only having to pay one bill a month and dealing with one company official when arranging to pay bills. Companies saved money and could use the billing system to sell new products to customers and target advertising more efficiently using the databases.</p>
<p>Kiley said up to six percent of a bill for many telecommunications companies was attributable to the cost of the billing system itself. If these costs were reduced, they could boost profits and reduce customers' bills, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Billing systems are fundamental to a business. You can have all the traffic that you like and if it can't be billed it's useless,&quot; Kiley said.</p>
<p>He said Saville saw huge potential demand for its billing systems in the Asia Pacific.</p>
<p>&quot;There are in excess of one billion potential customers in Asia who are ready, willing and able to pay for telecommunications services and don't have them today,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Every one of those billion people will require a bill and all of the businesses which they work for will also require billing services. It provides an opportunity which is staggering,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kiley said Saville aimed to sell its billing system to established companies such as Singapore Telecomunications and its new competitors, as the Singapore market was deregulated.</p>
<p>&quot;We want existing companies as well as companies you've not even heard of today which will be emerging. India, China, Indonesia and Japan will also offer tremendous upside,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703199)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
