<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539322" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Westinghouse's CBS-TV seen needing Internet.</title>
<headline>Westinghouse's CBS-TV seen needing Internet.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Westinghouse Electric Corp's CBS television network, saddled with lower than expected revenues, will need to invest in new distribution technology to deliver earnings growth, analysts said Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The technology for the distribution of electronic media content today is changing rapidly; it requires more investment if you're going to be a preeminent network,&quot; said Nick Heymann at NatWest Securities. &quot;You've got to have that Internet connection.&quot;  </p>
<p>Analysts said to make CBS more profitable via advertising revenues, Westinghouse should find a partner to distribute content over the Internet, as rival network NBC, a General Electric Co subsidiary, did with Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;You find a younger audience on the Internet,&quot; Heymann said. &quot;Advertisers are willing to pay more for a younger audience who spends more. CBS doesn't have an engine to get content out...when we turn on our Internet connection.&quot;</p>
<p>Westinghouse Friday reported a first-quarter loss of $0.23 per share, compared with a loss of $0.26 per share last year.  </p>
<p>Wall Street's consensus estimate for the quarter was a loss of $0.10, with a range of a loss of $0.05 to a loss of $0.22, according to First Call.</p>
<p>Analysts said the CBS radio group posted an impressive first-quarter performance. Radio sales increased 18 percent and earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization increased 38 percent on a proforma basis.</p>
<p>Earnings at the CBS TV network, however, fell. Westinghouse blamed the decrease on lower audience levels in key demographic areas as well as higher costs associated with sports and special events broadcasts.  </p>
<p>&quot;Radio was spectacular and I think that reflects strong management and superb assets,&quot; said John Reidy at Smith Barney.  &quot;They significantly outperformed the industry by three or four percentage points in terms of revenues.</p>
<p>&quot;But I think it will take a while longer before we see a turn at the network.  The revenues haven't crept up as much as the costs.  I think in the fourth quarter we'll see a positive number.&quot;</p>
<p>Westinghouse has been targeting an audience aged 25-54 with CBS television programming.  </p>
<p>While analysts said that age group is a growing market that eventually will be the largest, CBS needs to reach a younger audience that uses the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;CBS could end up as number one in prime time and not the most profitable network,&quot; Heymann said. &quot;For the 25-54 audience, advertisers pay 30 to 60 percent of what they pay for the 18-49 crowd.  The Internet is an advertiser-based model that requires more investment.&quot;  </p>
<p>On the industrial side, analysts said Thermo King, a refrigerated transport unit that has been consistently profitable, will provide capital for the company's other industrial segments when Westinghouse splits its media and industrial operations into separate companies this summer.</p>
<p>Westinghouse plans to sell up to 20 percent of its equity in Thermo King via an initial public offering later this year.</p>
<p>Thermo King's operating profit grew four percent and orders increased five percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Thermo King is a recognized winner, no question about it,&quot; said Bob Kanters at Legg Mason. &quot;They'll use that to provide capital for the others.&quot;</p>
<p>Westinghouse's other industrial segments include Government and Environmental Services, Power Generation and Energy Systems, all of which have been posting sluggish results.</p>
<p>Shares of Westinghouse were down 1/2 to 17-3/8 in afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>((Kerri Selland))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
