<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="539371" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Forte Software shares plunge on expense outlook.</title>
<headline>Forte Software shares plunge on expense outlook.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forte Software Inc.'s stock lost nearly half its value Friday after the software company told investors it will have to spend more money in coming quarters to beef up its sales team, hurting profits.</p>
<p>Shares of Forte, based in Oakland, Calif., plunged $8.25 to $8.375 in afternoon Nasdaq trading of 6.2 million shares. The stock was the biggest decliners in U.S. markets.</p>
<p>After the market closed Thursday, Forte said income for the quarter ended March 31 tripled to $3.0 million, or 14 cents a share -- better than the 11 cents Wall Street was expecting, according to a recent analyst survey by Zacks Investment Research.</p>
<p>But Forte told analysts that it plans to hire more sales managers in coming quarters to replace people who left the company earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Spending will be up next year in sales and marketing,&quot; said Jim Pickrel, analyst at investment bank Hambrecht &amp; Quist in San Francisco. &quot;A lot of earnings estimates went down&quot; on Wall Street after the call.</p>
<p>Forte sells software that helps corporate programmers write other software for managing information in big databases. The company's stock has traded as high as $81.75 in the past 12 months because of the growth prospects of this hot software niche.</p>
<p>But Forte has had some problems keeping experienced sales managers, analysts said.</p>
<p>Forte executives could not be reached for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
