<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541082" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Wall Data sees 20 pct of sales from Asia Pacific.</title>
<headline>Wall Data sees 20 pct of sales from Asia Pacific.</headline>
<byline>Doreen Siow</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. software firm Wall Data Incorporated hopes to see Asia Pacific sales rise to about 20 percent of group revenues over the next three or four years from four to five percent now, president John Wall said on Friday.</p>
<p>Speaking to reporters on the group's Asian plans, Wall, who is also the company's founder and chief technology officer, said the U.S. market now accounts for about 70-75 percent of group revenues with much of the rest coming from Europe.</p>
<p>He said he hoped the Asia Pacific region would contribute at least 20 percent in revenues over the next three to four years.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect revenues from the Americas and Europe to be 35-40 percent and the remaining will come from Asia (over that period,&quot; Wall said.</p>
<p>Wall Data makes a range of software that help businesses use their computers more effectively. Its connectivity software lets users access information located anywhere on a computer network.</p>
<p>The group's highly successful RUMBA products, which account for the bulk of sales, take advantage of Microsoft' Windows 95 and Windows NT 32-bit technology.</p>
<p>Wall said that while the outlook for the traditional connectivity market was expected to be flat this year, the group had managed to chalk up a 24 percent growth for the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>The company's revenues were US$29.9 million for the three months ended March 31 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect Asia Pacific to see growth in excess of 24 percent (this year). The Japan market is rather large and we have just released our 32-bit technology there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wall said the group had a close relationship with Microsoft Corp on the technology front and on a marketing basis.</p>
<p>He said the group planned to use Singapore as a base to expand in the region and was looking at opportunities in Thailand.</p>
<p>With a cash hoard of $75.6 million at the end of the last quarter, the group planned to invest some of that in the Asian region to increase distribution and revenue, he said.</p>
<p>Another possible avenue of investment would be in companies which had compatible technologies which the group could leverage on, he said.</p>
<p>Cavin Choo, territory manager of Asia, said the group was currently working with its Taiwanese partners to produce a simplified Chinese language version of the group's products.</p>
<p>He said this was expected to be ready in about three to four months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
