<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="541335" id="root" date="1997-04-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: GROWING RISKS IN SPACE CHALLENGE INSURERS.</title>
<headline>GROWING RISKS IN SPACE CHALLENGE INSURERS.</headline>
<byline>Gordon Mackenzie</byline>
<dateline>VENICE, Italy 1997-04-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>On May 1, the first of 66 Iridium satellites will be launched into orbit, carrying with it the hopes of a group of investors for high returns.</p>
<p>If successful, it will be the first of around 1,700 commercial launches in the next 10 years which aim to milk rising demand for telecommunications.</p>
<p>But although the potential gains are high, these multi-million dollar investments are under threat from space junk, meteor storms and a host of other risks which are causing concern to those who pick up the bill if things go wrong.</p>
<p>Satellite launch figures dwindled after the collapse of the Soviet Union and the easing of military tension. Nearly 120 a year were launched each year in the 1980s but only 70 went up in 1996.</p>
<p>But the plans of telecommunications companies around the world mean the number of commercial launches is set to soar.</p>
<p>Corporations such as Motorola Inc, Microsoft Corp and News International Plc aim to spend more than $50 billion to fill the sky with satellites over the next few years to transform the transmission of telephone calls and television pictures.</p>
<p>The rush has been fuelled by leaps in technology and manufacturing efficiency and guaranteed levels of access from the World Trade Organisation to telecommunications systems in 60 countries.</p>
<p>IRIDIUM PROJECT</p>
<p>The $5.0 billion Iridium project, backed by Motorola, will provide global telephone, paging and data services aimed at well-heeled business travellers.</p>
<p>The biggest project is the $9.0 billion Teledesic project backed by Microsoft's Bill Gates, which plans broadband Internet access by way of a system of 924 satellites.</p>
<p>Most of these projects seek protection through insurance. A few years ago it was unthinkable that space insurance premiums would be on a par with those for airlines, but they were in 1996 when gross written premiums for launch and in-orbit exposures exceeded $1500 million.</p>
<p>There are now 150 insured satellites in space, insured for a total of $16 billion.</p>
<p>However, when space insurers met for their biennial conference hosted by the Italian insurance giant Generali in Venice, there was clear concern about the growing risks to their claims experience.</p>
<p>SPACE JUNK</p>
<p>Hundreds of tonnes of orbiting 'space junk', ranging from parts of discarded rockets to paint fragments from other satellites, are threatening the safety of spacecraft and could present a real problem to insurers.</p>
<p>Generali, the market leader in space insurance, says more than two million kg (2.2 million lbs) of debris have accumulated within 2,000 km (1,240 miles) of the Earth's surface since the Soviet Union launched the first 'Sputnik' probe in the late 1950s.</p>
<p>Around 9,500 objects are large enough to be tracked and avoided on space missions, while other fragments are small enough for shields to offer protection.</p>
<p>The high risk comes from thousands of objects too small to track but too large to protect against.</p>
<p>Designers of the space shuttle counted on collisions with occasional small meteorites, but did not expect flight paths to be paved with human litter. Now their windows are regularly replaced after being hit by space junk -- at a cost of $40,000 a time.</p>
<p>&quot;There are mounting fears about space debris, both in terms of its number and its volume,&quot; said Generali deputy general manager Benito Pagnanelli as he drove the message home to the Venice conference.</p>
<p>CLEANING UP SPACE</p>
<p>Cleaning up space would be costly and dangerous, but stricter rules or economic incentives could be used to alleviate the situation.</p>
<p>One idea at NASA -- not yet approved -- is to zap junk out of orbit. An ultra-sensitive radar would detect the fragment and a laser gun would blast a corner of it, creating an exhaust effect which would jet the object into the atmosphere to burn up.</p>
<p>But some space junk does not burn up as it is supposed to, and that is another concern for insurers. Pagnanelli warned of the dangers of third party liabilities stemming from space junk re-entering the atmosphere and crashing to Earth in populated areas.</p>
<p>&quot;The conventional wisdom was that these things are supposed to burn up on re-entry, but more than 10,000 objects have re-entered the atmosphere in the last decade,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The change is in part due to technical advances. Tougher components are increasingly able to survive impact with the atmosphere.</p>
<p>Last year a 225 kg (495 lb) part from a Delta rocket crashed in Georgetown, Texas, only 45 metres (yards) from a private home. Insurers are now wondering if they may have to pay up for damages caused on Earth.</p>
<p>METEOR STORMS</p>
<p>Man-made debris is not the only threat. Astronomers predict a high intensity meteor storm, nicknamed Leonid, in November 1998. The last one to pass near Earth was in 1966, making Leonid the first such storm of the modern satellite age.</p>
<p>Scientists calculate that a satellite with a surface area of 10 square metres (110 square feet), the equivalent of a small car, stands a 0.1 percent chance of being struck and short-circuited by a tiny particle.</p>
<p>Insurers will have to consider whether current policies cover this, or if the clauses in their policies will protect them from extra payouts.</p>
<p>TECHNOLOGICAL FAILURES</p>
<p>As satellites and rockets get more complicated, there is more to go wrong. In May 1996, television viewers around the world watched in horror as the new European rocket Ariane 5 exploded 40 seconds after its launch from French Guiana after a defect in its positioning system.</p>
<p>Flights of McDonnell Douglas Delta 2 rockets were postponed after problems with the thermal protection were discovered in January, holding up the first Iridium launch.</p>
<p>And the crash of China's Long March rocket last year, killing six people and destroying 80 homes, throws up the question of whether current launch insurance policies give sufficient cover from personal and property injury claims sustained in such a disaster. Imagine if it had happened over Florida.</p>
<p>INSURANCE INDUSTRY RESPONSES</p>
<p>Insurers have so much to lose they are now asking questions such as -- Do manufacturers cut corners to keep costs down? Are mergers among manufacturers affecting the workforce? Can quality control be maintained when cutting production time from three to two years?</p>
<p>Even within the industry some say fierce competition is undermining the decisions of underwriters.</p>
<p>Capacity in the space insurance market soared to $850 million in 1996 from $550 million in 1995 as new players rushed in. Pagnanelli is one of several established space insurance experts who fear new entrants lack expertise.</p>
<p>&quot;We are dealing with operators who are sustained by large capital and who enter the market with considerable capacity. They have the typical characteristics of those insurers who offer but an opportunistic presence, based more on fortune and gambling than on a will to remain in the market,&quot; Pagnanelli said.</p>
<p>&quot;Often they charge inadequate premiums and expose themselves to high participation shares, thereby reducing the negotiating power of the more experienced companies.&quot;</p>
<p>Since 1984 space insurers have earned $4.8 billion in premiums and paid out around $900 million in claims.</p>
<p>However, as satellites become more expensive, the cost of debris wrecking just one could be $350 million, and a rocket exploding with two satellites on board could cost $700 million.</p>
<p>On risks like this, the margin between profit and loss for insurers could be very fine indeed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640045">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VENICE, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
