<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546587" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: INTERVIEW - SAP says LatAm growth fastest.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - SAP says LatAm growth fastest.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software company SAP AG sees Latin America as its fastest-growing market and forecasts a 150-percent hike in annual revenues from the region by 2000, a top company official said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is our fastest growing region,&quot; Paul Wahl, SAP board member and chief executive officer for the Americas, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe this market will be at a $250-million level in a couple of years, possibly by 1999 or 2000,&quot; Wahl said in a telephone interview.  </p>
<p>SAP, which has operations in Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Mexico and Venezuela, expects to rake in $100 million in revenue from the region this year, up from $83 million in 1996, he said.</p>
<p>First-quarter revenues in the Americas rose 91 percent over last year's January-March period while, worldwide, SAP posted a a 49-percent hike in revenues in the period, he added.</p>
<p>SAP is a world leader in client/server applications software with a customer base of some 6,000 companies.  </p>
<p>Wahl attributed its growth in Latin America in the last two years to the opening of the region's markets and the growing reliance on information systems.</p>
<p>&quot;People recognize, with the opening of the market, that they need a better information system to replace existing software,&quot; said Wahl, adding demand the firm has a roughly 30-percent market share in the region.</p>
<p>The company, he said, has invested some $30 million in Brazil in the last two years, mostly in infrastructure and product extension, and plans to invest $4-5 million more this year.  </p>
<p>Investment will continue as long as the company continues to feel it is profitable, he added.</p>
<p>SAP began operating in Latin America mostly serving to multinational clients who moved to the region but its penetration of the market means it now serves a growing number of local firms, including small and mid-sized companies.</p>
<p>The firm plans to double its workforce in Brazil this year to about 200 employees, bringing to 400 the number of people who work for the company in the region, Wahl said.</p>
<p>Although the company so far has offices in a handful of the region's largest countries, it plans to serve clients in others, including Paraguay and Bolivia, he said.</p>
<p>((-- Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 2485413))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
