<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="547194" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Big growth seen for Internet in financial services.</title>
<headline>Big growth seen for Internet in financial services.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Consumers' use of the Internet to carry out financial service transactions is expected to grow dramatically, executives of brokerage, information and technology firms said at a panel discussion Tuesday.</p>
<p>David Weisman, director for money and technology strategies at Forrester Research Inc, said a recent study by his firm projected more than 10 million online brokerage accounts by the year 2001, up from 1.5 million at the end of 1966 and a projected 2.77 million by the end of 1997.  </p>
<p>Weisman was one of several speakers debating how Internet technology could bridge the gap between Wall Street and Main Street. The discussion was among a week-long series of events here sponsored by Reuters Holdings Plc.</p>
<p>Donald Marron, chairman and chief executive of PaineWebber Group Inc, said the financial services business in the U.S. had been transformed by the trend toward giving individuals the responsibility of managing their own retirement funds.</p>
<p>&quot;We're building a nation of professional money managers,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Marron said the role of PaineWebber, a full service brokerage, would be to provide advice that customers would value more as their retirement assets grew.</p>
<p>Peter Job, chief executive of Reuters, said Reuters is making a profit in the Internet area.</p>
<p>After the formal discussion, asked by a reporter for details, Job said that &quot;a modest income flow&quot; covers the cost of adapting the company's product for display on the Internet. He said there was &quot;a little margin on top&quot; but he did not have an exact figure available.  </p>
<p>Peter Quick, president of discount broker Quick &amp; Reilly Group Inc, said the Internet is attracting a new type of client who gravitates to the technology. But he added, &quot;I wouldn't preclude the older client.&quot;</p>
<p>Quick compared the opportunity offered by the Internet to the one that came about in May 1975 when fixed commissions on Wall Street were ended.</p>
<p>Phillip White, chairman, president and chief executive of Informix Corp, said the growth of the Internet had come about because it is easy to use and because the cost to the user is low.  </p>
<p>White said companies that want to participate must invest today in order to be competitive because the technology is moving so fast.</p>
<p>Edward Kozel, chief technical officer and senior vice president of business development at Cisco Systems Inc, said the Internet is moving rapidly toward a &quot;multi-tiered&quot; structure where users pay for what they get, with fees varying according to the level of service.</p>
<p>((--Cal Mankowski, New York Newsdesk 212 859 1732))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
