<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="552142" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Worldwide Advertising &amp; Media Digest - April 30.</title>
<headline>Worldwide Advertising &amp; Media Digest - April 30.</headline>
<text>
<p>------------------------- WAM ------------------------</p>
<p>....REUTERS WORLDWIDE ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST.....</p>
<p>-------------------April 30, 1997----</p>
<p>Reuters news from around the world on Advertising, Marketing, Media, the Internet, Brand-name Products and Consumer Trends</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>LONDON - Cordiant Plc is considering a public offering of its U.S. Siegel &amp; Gale unit, but this is only one of several options being considered, a company spokesman says. Cordiant, which last week announced plans to split its Saatchi &amp; Saatchi and Bates advertising agencies and Zenith media planning and buying operation into three independently managed businesses, has been studying a range of options to boost Siegel &amp; Gale. *********</p>
<p>NEW YORK - The New York City Council, one of the first to restrict smoking in restaurants and workplaces, plans to unveil a bill to curb tobacco advertising near schools. The measure would restrict advertising and promotion of tobacco products within 1,000 feet of schools and other places where children gather.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>HAMBURG - German advertising agency Baader, Lang, Behnken says it plans to demerge from the German unit of ad group Ammirati Puris Lintas after nine years and buy back its majority shares.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - German leaders in politics, the media, industry and associations put little faith in advertising as a source of information, an industry survey shows.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>LONDON - British Digital Broadcasting (BDB), a consortium of UK television giants, has begun talks about an alliance with British Telecommunications, the Times newspaper says. The newspaper says BDB, formed to bid for licences to broadcast digital terrestrial television in the UK, has asked BT to devise interactive set-top boxes that could also be used for home banking and shopping.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - English premier league soccer clubs could soon earn an average of 30 million pounds ($48.7 million) per year from the sale of television rights on a pay-per-view basis, Robin Welch of European broadcast group Canal Plus tells the Soccerex 97 conference.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Telecommunications companies must adapt or die in the face of the competitive threat from Internet telephone services that could offer land-line quality calls within two years, Jeff Hurmuses, Asia Pacific managing director of Polycom Inc, says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>NEW YORK - U.S. television threw its biggest coming out party ever this week when the leading character in comedy show &quot;Ellen&quot; announced &quot;I'm gay.&quot; It's the first time a central character in a U.S. comedy show is openly gay.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>AUCKLAND - New Zealand's Canadian-owned TV3 network says its net earnings totalled C$23.15 ($16.57) million in the year to June, 1996, up sharply from C$9.65 million a year earlier. TV3 managing director Graeme Hunter says it is the channel's most profitable year to date.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>NEW YORK - NBC led prime time television viewer ratings for the week April 21 to April 27, with six of its shows, led by hospital drama series E.R., crowding the top 10 spots, Nielsen Media Research says.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>PURCHASE, New York - PepsiCo Inc gives more details of its plan to divest its restaurant operations, including selling some chains and taking its New Zealand restaurants public in an initial public offering. &quot;We refranchised 94 stores this quarter, and for the full year expect to sell as many or more than we did last year,&quot; a spokesman says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>OAK BROOK, Illinois - McDonald's Corp says it expects by the end of 1998 to open restaurants in Karachi and Lahore, Pakistan, a new market for the company.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>INGOLSTADT, Germany - German carmaker Audi AG says it has won an international marketing industry award for 1997 for its success in creating a distinctive corporate image. Audi says the Marketing Society of Great Britain recognised its worldwide boost in sales in the last two years as a marketing coup.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>ZAGREB - Cosmetics-to-detergents firm Unilever says it has established a full subsidiary to take care of its operations in Croatia.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SAN DIEGO - Apple Computer Inc. demonstrates a preliminary version of its new operating system for the Macintosh personal computer, which it claims is easier to use and has more Internet capabilities.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - Tobacco to insurance group B.A.T Industries Plc reports 10 percent growth in sales of its international filter brands, selling more than 40 billion cigarettes in the first quarter.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PURCHASE, New York - PepsiCo Inc says its first-quarter earnings per share, which exceeded analysts' estimates, were helped by double-digit domestic volume growth for its Mountain Dew brand.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - European appliance makers face an onslaught of competition from U.S. and Asian manufacturers attracted by the size of the European market and high disposable income, France's Industry Ministry says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Swedish telecommunications group Ericsson expects good growth of its phone systems and mobile handphones in Asia over the next few years, senior vice president for Asia Pacific Bo Landin says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SAN FRANCISCO - Microsoft Corp plans to put software in personal computers to enable them to get television broadcasting, a senior vice president for Microsoft says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>JAKARTA - Leading cigarette company PT BAT Indonesia envisages tougher rules on smoking, but even well-regulated markets offer an enormous playground for tobacco firms, BAT president-director Johannes Priem says.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>CONSUMER TRENDS:</p>
<p>SHANGHAI - Chinese consumers are discovering the delights of eating beef, even as consumers in the developed world are starting to avoid red meat for the sake of their health and girths, a U.S. marketing executive says. &quot;When we see the growth in income in China, and the number of people, we can't help but believe there has got to be quite a bright future here for U.S. meat products,&quot; says Bryant Wadsworth, of the U.S. Meat Export Federation.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - Music companies are waiting for the world to rock to a new sound that will entice consumers back into record shops and drive up sluggish global sales, analysts say. Without new global best sellers, few analysts expect the global market to bask in the double digit growth seen from 1984 to 1994 when queues eager for records such as pop group R.E.M.'s &quot;Monster&quot; stretched from music shops.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SANTIAGO - Chilean supermarket sales rose 9.1 percent in real terms in March over the same month last year and were up 17.6 percent in nominal terms, the National Statistics Institute says.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>See full stories on Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. And why not visit our Internet site at http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com?</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>($ = 1.396 Canadian Dollars)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
