<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="553085" id="root" date="1997-05-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Broad technology rally extends to even small caps.</title>
<headline>Broad technology rally extends to even small caps.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A continued rally in technology stocks on Thursday extended to small capitalization stocks, which have been overlooked during the recent market recovery, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The high techs are very, very strong across the board. And it's spilling over into smaller stocks for the first time in months,&quot; said Nicholas Karos, senior over-the-counter trader with Piper Jaffray.</p>
<p>&quot;All of a sudden, there's this spill into small stocks that have really missed out on any positive movement lately,&quot; Karos said.  </p>
<p>Traders cited stocks such as Cylink Corp, Secure Computing Corp, and Discreet Logic Inc as smaller capitalization stocks that have benefitted from this new resurgence.</p>
<p>Cylink gained one to 10-1/4, Secure Computing added 5/8 to 7-7/8 and Discreet Logic jumped 1-1/4 to 9-3/8.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Nasdaq shares outpaced gains in the Dow industrials, on a percentage basis.  That strength continued on Thursday, with the Nasdaq composite index up 9.69 points or 0.78 percent to 1270.45.  The Dow industrials lagged again, down about 32 points or 0.45 percent to 6977.  </p>
<p>On the Nasdaq, advancing issues led declining issues 2,070 to 1,485 on total volume of 302 million shares at midday.</p>
<p>The rally reached a broad range of technology sectors, from networking stocks to semiconductor stocks to Internet stocks, traders said.</p>
<p>Networking stocks such as Ascend Communications Inc and Cisco Systems Inc have jumped in the past few sessions on expectations of positive news coming out of a major industry trade show next week, traders said.  </p>
<p>Ascend gained 1-1/4 to 47, while Cisco added 1-1/8 to 53-1/2.  3Com Corp increased 2-1/4 to 31-1/4. The American Stock Exchange's networking index jumped 3.29 percent or 7.27 points to 236.76.</p>
<p>Technology stocks have largely missed out on the recent resurgence in the broader markets.  Investors shifted their focus to large-capitalization, Blue Chip stocks with stable earnings, turning away from smaller or less predictable issues, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;They've been beaten up. They got so low that there had to be some buyers, especially when a lot of tech earnings and industry data have been strong lately.  People aren't so afraid to buy techs at these prices,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Compaq Computer Corp jumped to 87-3/8, up two, and Dell Computer Corp traded at 85-7/16, up 1-11/16.</p>
<p>Adobe Systems Inc also jumped 2-7/8 to 42 on news it will be added to the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
