<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560022" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP backs staff in insider probe.</title>
<headline>SAP backs staff in insider probe.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>German business software group SAP AG on Monday said it was cooperating fully with a probe by authorities into possible insider trading in its shares and that it had no reason to doubt the integrity of its employees.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still no reason to doubt the reliability and confidentialty of SAP employees that have access to insider information and who have signed an insider statement,&quot; the company said in a statement from its Walldorf headquarters.  </p>
<p>SAP  SAPG.G backs staff in insider probe</p>
<p>The statement added that chief executive Dietmar Hopp would make a &quot;comprehensive statement&quot; at the company's annual general meeting on Wednesday in which he &quot;would make clear that should the accusations prove true the company itself would, of course, draw consequences.&quot;</p>
<p>The BAWe securities trading watchdog said it had launched a probe into over 100 &quot;primary and secondary insiders&quot; in connection with share movements shortly before a key announcement last year that drove the company's share price sharply down.</p>
<p>The first category of &quot;primary insiders&quot; implies staff at SAP and banks and &quot;secondary insiders&quot; refer to their relatives or friends. It is one of the largest insider cases the BAWe has handled since insider trading was outlawed in 1994.</p>
<p>The maximum punishment for insider trading here is five years in jail, but so far authorities have stuck to fines.</p>
<p>SAP said it had cooperated in the investigation from the beginning, providing prosecutors with files and the names of all employees who had access to insider information.</p>
<p>Based on information from the prosecutors, SAP said the investigation involves a routine examination of all employees and divisions that have access to relevant information.</p>
<p>&quot;That means there are currently no investigations targetting particular people,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;The managment and workforce of SAP are very interested that these accusations are cleared up as soon as possible so they can devote their entire attention to the development and distribution of SAP software,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>-- William Boston, Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097 150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
