<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560990" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Old habits die hard as Germany hunts down insiders.</title>
<headline>Old habits die hard as Germany hunts down insiders.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A major insider trading investigation revealed in Frankfurt on Monday suggests that old habits die hard in the once lax financial centre but also proves regulators are determined to clean up Germany's act.</p>
<p>Alerted by the stock market watchdog, the BAWe, and armed with a list of suspects, Frankfurt prosecutors are investigating a potentially huge case of alleged insider dealing in shares of software maker SAP AG.</p>
<p>The BAWe said over 100 &quot;primary and secondary insiders&quot; were named in the initial probe -- the first category implies staff at SAP and banks and the second their relatives or friends -- making it one of the largest since Germany criminalised insider trading in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;But we expect that this number will fall as time goes by,&quot; said BAWe spokesman Juergen Oberfrank.</p>
<p>Investors showed their disapproval by sending SAP's shares plummeting in early electronic trade by as much as five percent on Monday, although they stabilised in the bourse trading session and closed at 324.50 marks, up 3.10 marks.</p>
<p>Some dealers said incidents like this could have a bad effect abroad. SAP stock could face more pressure once the London market reopened on Tuesday after a public holiday, despite Germany's assiduous and mainly successful efforts to shed its image as an insider dealing haven, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;This does have an impact on sentiment, at least in the short term. After all people don't like to think of prosecutors in the boardroom,&quot; said Josh Waiblinger, assistant vice president of equities at Frankfurt's BHF Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;But things are improving here. People are very alert to any really big moves in the market and I think people do see that there is a diligent team on the watch. I don't think anyone really believes there are a lot more skeletons hanging around,&quot; Waiblinger added.</p>
<p>The BAWe, the linchpin of Germany's crackdown on market irregularities over the past three years, says the SAP case could be one of its most serious yet.</p>
<p>The maximum punishment for insider trading is five years in jail, but so far authorities have used only fines.</p>
<p>This year Germany imposed its toughest penalty yet for insider trading, with a single fine of 3.6 million marks ($2.1 million) in total, of which one million marks had to be paid immediately and the rest is suspended pending a probation period.</p>
<p>The individual involved was connected with the windows and doors manufacturer Weru AG and has not been named.</p>
<p>The BAWe has been stepping up its fight against insider activity since it began operations with just three staff in 1995. Now with about 100 employees and an electronic system which allows it to monitor around 400,000 trades in Germany daily, it believes its teething problems are over.</p>
<p>The BAWe passed on 11 cases to prosecutors in the first quarter of 1997, compared with seven for the whole of 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not that there are more black sheep out there, it is more a question of our technical capacity,&quot; said BAWe spokesman Juergen Oberfrank.</p>
<p>The initial probe into SAP could be completed in a month, according to public prosecutors but the case is likely to drag on for considerably longer should it go to court.</p>
<p>The probe concerns trades carried out immediately before a company announcement on October 23, 1996. Within minutes of the announcement that SAP's nine-month profit was below expectations SAP shares plunged 23.6 percent.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.726 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
