<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="560934" id="root" date="1997-05-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP targeted for insider trading probe.</title>
<headline>SAP targeted for insider trading probe.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-05-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software manufacturer SAP AG said on Monday that it was the target of a probe into suspected insider trading which a market watchdog official said could become one of the most serious such cases in Germany.</p>
<p>A company spokesman told Reuters that SAP was aware of the investigation and said the company had discussed the case with Germany's two-year-old stock market watchdog, the BAWe, last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We provided documents for the BAWe back in October,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Alerted by the BAWe to the case and armed with a list of names, Frankfurt prosecutors are currently trying to find out whether there is evidence of large-scale insider trading in SAP shares in October last year.</p>
<p>More than 100 people were targeted in the probe initially, the BAWe said, but that number was expected to fall as the investigation proceeds.</p>
<p>Job Tilmann, spokesman for the prosecutors' office, said the probe concerned trading by SAP employees and their relatives and friends immediately before a company announcement on October 23, 1996.</p>
<p>Within minutes of that announcement -- that SAP's nine-month profit was below expectations -- SAP shares had plunged 23.6 percent to 212 marks on the Frankfurt Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Tilmann declined to give more than sketchy details, saying it was too early to predict the scale of the incident. The initial investigation could be finished in about a month.</p>
<p>&quot;This is probably the most serious case we have seen here,&quot; said BAWe spokesman Juergen Oberfrank, who said his authority had passed on lists of names to prosecutors.</p>
<p>Insider dealing was outlawed in Germany in 1994 as part of a drive to clean up the financial markets and make them more attractive to international investors.</p>
<p>The BAWe watchdog, which started operations in 1995, is the linchpin of insider investigations and passes on cases to public prosecutors once it itself is satisfied there is evidence of irregularity.</p>
<p>The maximum punishment for insider trading is five years in jail, but so far German authorities have resorted to fines.</p>
<p>Among the highest fines so far was imposed on an owner of drinks manufacturer Krones, who had to pay 600,000 marks ($347,000) in 1995 and was given a two-year suspended sentence.</p>
<p>The BAWe also said earlier this year that an unnamed person was fined one million marks immediately and set a total fine of 3.6 million marks, with due payment suspended pending a probationary year.</p>
<p>News of the probe pushed SAP's shares sharply lower in early trade on Monday.</p>
<p>The firm's DAX-listed preferred shares then recouped most of their losses to trade steady in the bourse session, but underperformed an otherwise firmly upbeat market. At 0946 GMT, SAP stock was at 322 marks, up 60 pfennigs.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.726 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
