<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56498" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intuit swaps ISC unit for CheckFree stake.</title>
<headline>Intuit swaps ISC unit for CheckFree stake.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intuit Inc and CheckFree Corp said they agreed to a deal in which Intuit will swap Intuit Services Corp, its back-end bill payment processing unit, in exchange for a stake of about 23 percent in CheckFree.  </p>
<p>The transactions will allow Intuit to decouple sales of its core, front-end software products, such as Quicken personal finance software, from its private back-end processing network.</p>
<p>The move could alleviate widespread concerns among bankers that Intuit's control over both elements of the emerging electronic banking system gave Intuit direct access to a bank's customer base.</p>
<p>Critics of Intuit have charged that over time, Intuit could use this power to cut traditional banking institutions out of the electronic banking equation.  </p>
<p>&quot;It signals a major shift in strategy,&quot; said Gary Craft, an analyst with Friedman, Billings who covers online financial services firms like Intuit and CheckFree. &quot;Intuit is no longer talking about being a full service provider,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would appear that they are moving out of the back-end processing system businees,&quot; Craft said, noting the move was at least partly due to the resistance Intuit had encountered within the banking industry to its efforts in this area.</p>
<p>The analyst said Intuit's exit from the transaction business also reflected difficulties it had in trying to manage both consumer software and electronic commerce businesses.  </p>
<p>&quot;The skills required for sucess in both are different,&quot; Craft said, noting that the quality of customer service demanded in the transaction end of the business was far higher than in the consumer software business.</p>
<p>Intuit was alone in trying to offer consumer software, transaction processing and systems integration, Craft said.</p>
<p>He noted how even rival Microsoft Corp has hewed to the software business and left the transactions end to third parties.</p>
<p>&quot;It was too much to handle both,&quot; he said of Intuit.  </p>
<p>Terms of the Intuit-CheckFree deal call for Intuit to receive 12.6 million shares of CheckFree common stock -- about 23 percent of the resulting 54 million outstanding shares -- in exchange for its ISC subsidiary.</p>
<p>Based on Friday's closing price of 18-1/16 for CheckFree stock, the transaction is valued at $227.6 million.</p>
<p>In a statement, Intuit said the ISC unit, which it had acquired in July 1994, had played a key role in igniting consumer usage of online banking and bill payment services.  </p>
<p>The company said its decision to swap its payment processing unit for an equity position in CheckFree is designed to give banks and other financial services firms using its software products such as Quicken a choice of financial processing options, including the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;Our decisions to open our products to direct Internet links and to sell ISC in exchange for an equity stake in CheckFree creates more opportunity for Intuit as well,&quot; said Intuit Chairman Scott Cook.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are now free to pursue new software and Internet businesses while continuing to participate in the bill payment processing business, creating benefit to both Intuit and our full range of customers.&quot;</p>
<p>Subject to regulatory and shareholder approval, the CheckFree deal is expected to close by the end of calendar year 1997. Intuit said it intends to account for its investment in CheckFree using the cost method of accounting. Accordingly, Intuit intends to sell about 2 million shares of CheckFree acquired in the transaction.</p>
<p>ISC's revenues accounted for less than three percent of Intuit's revenues in fiscal 1996.</p>
<p>The company also disclosed that, in anticipation of the completion of the CheckFree transaction, the August 1996 acquisition of GALT Technologies, which was originally intended to be accounted for as a pooling of interests, will now be accounted for as a purchase transaction.</p>
<p>It plans to amortize about $9 million of intangibles from the GALT deal over a three-year period beginning this month.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
