<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56510" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CheckFree to acquire Intuit unit. [CORRECTED 13:55 GMT]</title>
<headline>CheckFree to acquire Intuit unit. [CORRECTED 13:55 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>COLUMBUS, Ohio 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>CheckFree Corp said Monday it agreed to acquire Intuit Services Corp, the electronic bill payment and bank services unit of Intuit Corp, for 12.6 million shares of common stock in CheckFree Corp.</p>
<p>Based on the September 13 closing price of 18-1/16 for CheckFree stock, the indicated price CheckFree is paying for the unit is $227 million.</p>
<p>Intuit Inc has guaranteed to pay CheckFree, under the purchase agreement, the dollar amount of any shortfall below $46 million in its unit's revenues for the twelve months ending July 31, 1997, CheckFree said.</p>
<p>The transaction is expected to close before December 31, and is subject to regulatory and stockholder approval.</p>
<p>After the acquisition is complete, CheckFree will provide home banking and bill payment services for over 180 financial institutions and bring CheckFree's base of home banking and bill payment users to over one million.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition makes us the go-to service company for electronic commerce, and with the shift from paper to electronic commerce clearly underway, that's a good position to be in,&quot; said Pete Kight, Chairman and CEO of CheckFree.</p>
<p>CheckFree said it will merge the unit's operations into its existing processing systems.</p>
<p>&quot;There are parts of the (unit's) operation that are best of breed, including the telecommunications architecture and the security systems, which we will maintain as part of the merged system,&quot; said Peter Kight (Corrects from Knight), chairman, in a statement accompanying the announcement.</p>
<p>He added that the overall acceleration of growth at CheckFree resulting from the acquisition of ISC would result in increased staffing, including staffing at the ISC facilities.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk  (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBUS, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
