<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567128" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall Street cautious on Bay plans.</title>
<headline>Wall Street cautious on Bay plans.</headline>
<byline>Eric Auchard</byline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1997-05-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bay Networks Inc released a detailed road map of its future product plans Tuesday, giving the company a solid groundwork for its ongoing turnaround, Wall Street analysts who attended a two-hour briefing here with company executives said.</p>
<p>But analysts leaving the meeting said they still were waiting for further evidence that Bay is ready to execute its new strategies -- including several quarters of healthy results -- before they consider it back on track.</p>
<p>&quot;This is all marketing stuff right now,&quot; A.G. Edwards analyst T. Peter Andrew said of Bay's product plans. &quot;This is not a revenue generator that's going to affect the next quarter or two,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Time will tell,&quot; Bear Stearns analyst Eric Blachno said. &quot;We think the company in general is making progress, but we will have to wait and see results,&quot; Blachno said.</p>
<p>Both analysts maintain neutral ratings on Bay. But Andrew said he may be re-evaluating his view of the stock in light of recent positive developments at Bay, but that he had not decided to alter his position yet.</p>
<p>Wall Street has shied away from the one-time networking powerhouse after repeated management miscues and product delays caused it to lose market share, leading to poor financial reports in the last three quarters that left brokers in doubt about Bay's future.</p>
<p>But, beginning six months ago, Bay began making dramatic changes, starting with the hiring of ex-Intel Corp executive David House as its new chairman and chief executive. Under his guidance, Bay has carried out a management house-cleaning and internal restructuring.</p>
<p>Earlier Tuesday, Bay revealed a new transitional product strategy it calls &quot;Adaptive Networking&quot; -- that is designed to make the plumbing of Internet-based networks easier to upgrade to the higher-speed networks.</p>
<p>The briefing took place in the midst of Networld+Interop, the network industry trade show taking place here this week.</p>
<p>Furman Selz analyst Martin Pyykkonen, who also attended the Bay meeting, said he came away convinced the company has a defensible strategy that will permit it to see healthy growth in coming years, although at rates that are somewhat slower than key rivals.</p>
<p>He projected the company will see revenue growth during fiscal 1998 in the range of 15 to 16 percent and around 20 percent in fiscal 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a bolt of lightning or a reinvention of the industry,&quot; he said of the new product strategy.</p>
<p>By contrast, industry giant Cisco Systems Inc has for several years managed to terrify its competitors by reporting revenue growth of faster than 50 percent year-over-year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
