<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567553" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP tries to limit insider probe damage.</title>
<headline>SAP tries to limit insider probe damage.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>MANNHEIM, Germany 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software developer SAP AG, trying to halt the damage from an insider trading probe, asserted on Wednesday that its top managers had engaged in no illegal dealings.</p>
<p>SAP issued a declaration in which executives and supervisory board members swore that they had not used inside information in trading SAP shares and stock options, the focus of a probe by Frankfurt prosecutors.</p>
<p>At the same time, the company set a goal of raising revenue by one billion marks ($580 million) this year, although it admitted that the insider probe had already hurt the company.</p>
<p>&quot;The unbelievable uproar over this process is likely to have caused major financial damage,&quot; chief executive Dietmar Hopp told SAP's annual general meeting.</p>
<p>Hopp and other top officers have signed documents asserting they &quot;at no time dealt in SAP shares or derivatives in violation of insider trading rules&quot;, supervisory board chairman Bernd Thiemann said.</p>
<p>In addition, Thiemann told SAP shareholders that managers had not passed on any relevant information to third parties where this was not necessary.</p>
<p>Prosecutors have launched an investigation into trades by over 100 people in both SAP shares and financial derivatives after sharp price movements around October 23 last year.</p>
<p>SAP stock plunged by a quarter in value after the release of weaker than expected third quarter profits, prompting an investigation by the Frankfurt bourse's supervisory watchdog.</p>
<p>Hopp said the crash in the stock price came after a 10-week, 75-mark rise which occurred without apparent reason or positive news from the company.</p>
<p>The combination of rising expectations and the unforeseeable weakening of third quarter growth resulted in the crash in the stock price, Hopp said.</p>
<p>Since last autumn SAP shares climbed to near 320 marks and were at 314.90 on Wednesday afternoon, down 2.10.</p>
<p>Hopp said the outlook for 1997 was good. Strong first quarter earnings should not encourage the view that the company's business forecast was too cautious. But he added that if the mark remained weak this year, earnings could exceed management expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is a revenue increase of one billion marks,&quot; from last year's 3.722 billion marks, he said, &quot;with a cost increase of less than that&quot;.</p>
<p>SAP sought to land 300 new customers in Germany this year, and he forecast a boom in 1998 when companies accelerated upgrades to SAP R/3 software modified to accommodate the change to dates in the year 2000.</p>
<p>Hopp reiterated that management would help investigators to bring the affair to a speedy end and that any employees found to have engaged in insider trading would face &quot;appropriate consequences&quot;.</p>
<p>But Hopp also repeated assertions that he saw no reason to doubt the dependability and discretion of workers with access to sensitive figures who had signed written pledges to abide by Germany's 1994 insider trading law.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to downplay the whole thing,&quot; Hopp told shareholders. &quot;But every insider trading investigation naturally begins with the primary insiders, and that is the supervisory and management boards.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150 ($ = 1.723 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANNHEIM, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
