<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="569356" id="root" date="1997-05-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: FEATURE - Japan hastens plan to join digital TV rush.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Japan hastens plan to join digital TV rush.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aggressive U.S. moves to enter the digital TV market have alarmed Japan into rushing ahead with its own plans, which it hopes will make up for lost time and create opportunities for Japanese manufacturers.</p>
<p>But while official policy is to forge ahead, Japan's TV networks -- wary of change and competition -- have fiercely opposed the government plans, particularly the launch of terrestrial digital broadcasting in 2000, five years ahead of the original programme.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no need, no incentive, for launching terrestrial digital broadcasting services so soon,&quot; said a senior executive at a key TV station in Tokyo, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;Many complex issues remain unresolved, such as the preparation of content libraries, the distribution systems and whether or not to introduce paid service. We can't accept such a schedule,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>RESISTANCE TO CHANGE</p>
<p>Broadcasters also say the large financial burden -- about six billion yen ($47.6 million) to 20 billion yen ($158 million) for a big key TV station -- of refurbishing facilities and switching to digital equipment is another reason to resist the new timetable.</p>
<p>But analysts say the point behind their opposition is that broadcasters, now enjoying large advertising income under the strict licensing system, are stung by the prospect that the new digital era would bring about incalculable change to the industry structure.</p>
<p>Japanese television is dominated by five key Tokyo-based stations, including Tokyo Broadcasting System (TBS), Nippon Television Network (NTV) and Fuji Television Network, which will go public on the Tokyo Stock Exchange this autumn.</p>
<p>&quot;Digital TV technology will increase the number of TV channels, encourage new entries and put an end to an era where broadcasting belongs to big key TV stations,&quot; said Tadashi Nishi, analyst at Sakura Institute of Research.</p>
<p>NEED TO STAY COMPETITIVE</p>
<p>Despite the protests and grumblings from the industry, the Ministry of Posts and Telecommunications, armed with the powerful authority to grant TV licences, is determined to launch terrestrial digital broadcasting in Japan in 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;New hybrid PC/TVs, such as PCs that can receive digital TV signals, will hit the U.S. market next autumn. Such products would soon spread around the world,&quot; said Noboru Yoshida, an official at the ministry's broadcasting bureau.</p>
<p>&quot;A delay (in Japan) could undermine opportunities for Japanese electronics makers and communications companies, hindering Japanese TV viewers from receiving the benefits of multimedia services,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Electronic giants such as Matsushita Electric Industrial Co Ltd and Sony Corp are already keen to tap into the lucrative industry, with both said to be planning a stake in a digital broadcasting ventures led by British Sky Broadcasting Group Plc (BSkyB) ). Sony has joined the Japan Sky Broadcasting (JSkyB) project with News Corp Ltd and Softbank Corp , which plans to start broadcasting in Japan next year using a smaller communications satellite (CS).</p>
<p>EYE ON AGGRESSIVE U.S. MOVES</p>
<p>In comparison, U.S. broadcasting and computer companies have already moved decisively towards digital TV.</p>
<p>Early last month, COMPAQ Computer Corp, Microsoft Corp and Intel Corp said they would work cooperatively with the broadcasting and entertainment industries to develop new PCs with interactive TV functions.</p>
<p>The three companies also said they would produce millions of new PCs that can receive digital video and data as early as the second half of 1998.</p>
<p>The initiative follows Washington's decision last year to launch terrestrial digital TV services in the U.S. by May 1999. Britain plans a similar move in the first half of 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope and expect Japanese broadcasters will start terrestrial digital broadcasting in 2000, not after that,&quot; Yoshida said.</p>
<p>MORE CHANGES AHEAD</p>
<p>Analysts say the new digital TV era will dramatically change the pyramid-like structure of Japan's broadcasting industry, where big Tokyo stations place small content producers and regional TV stations under their wing.</p>
<p>&quot;Small producers that can supply high-quality, popular content or companies with large content libraries will gain strength as demand for quality content will surge in the multi-channel era,&quot; said Nishi at Sakura Research.</p>
<p>But Nanako Sakaguchi, an analyst at Dresdner Kleinwort Benson, said dominant stations would also boost their presence helped by their content libraries, high production capability and financial strengh.</p>
<p>Sakaguchi in particular rates highly the value of TBS's and Fuji's content libraries.</p>
<p>The big five stations in general enjoy extremely sound financial standing and high internal reserves. The five companies account for half of the total two trillion yen ($15.8 billion) revenues for Japan's 123 TV stations.</p>
<p>Besides terrestrial broadcasting, the industry is also closely watching the launch of Japan's new broadcasting satellite (BS), scheduled for around 2000, for which Japan recently chose to use digital rather than analog technology.</p>
<p>Analysts say BS broadcasting promises rosy business prospects because the cost of broadcasting, at about 2 billion yen ($15.8 million) is much cheaper than for terrestrial services, and in the meanwhile it can take over the 10 million subscribers of analog BS channels.</p>
<p>The government is expected to issue six licences for digital BS channels, in which five channels are expected to go to the five terrestrial networks.</p>
<p>Industry watchers agree that Sony will be a definite bidder for the one remaining channel when the ministry comes up with the licencing rule in the summer of next year. ($1=126 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
