<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="570591" id="root" date="1997-05-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Seek 'quality' in picking tech stocks - Merrill.</title>
<headline>Seek 'quality' in picking tech stocks - Merrill.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seeing more room for a rally in the technology sector in the next several quarters, Merrill Lynch chief investment strategist Charles Clough recommended that investors &quot;stay with quality,&quot; especially companies with proprietary technologies.</p>
<p>&quot;There's still money to be made&quot; in technology stocks, Clough said in a telephone conference call to clients on Wednesday. He warned of &quot;disappointments&quot; in secondary software companies.  </p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite, which suffered a sharp decline from January through April, began moving up on April 28. The index closed down 0.41 to 1322.91 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Six Merrill technology analysts, joining Clough in the late-morning conference call, cited their top stock picks:</p>
<p>Among technology blue chips: Compaq Computer Corp, Microsoft Corp, Xerox Corp, and International Business Machines Corp.</p>
<p>In semiconductors: Intel Corp, Micron Technology Inc, and Texas Instruments Inc.  </p>
<p>Among telecommunications equipment: Lucent Technologies Inc and Tellabs Inc.</p>
<p>In the computer services sector: Computer Sciences Corp and First Data Corp.</p>
<p>Analyst Tom Kurlak said the semiconductor industry is &quot;quite strong&quot; with pricing of semiconductors &quot;firming&quot; and low inventories.</p>
<p>Kurlak said he sees 15-18 percent growth in worldwide shipments this year.</p>
<p>Kurlak said he expects Intel's new Pentium II computer chip to be &quot;the biggest product ever produced by the company.&quot;  </p>
<p>Lucianne Painter, the personal computer analyst, said she expected the commercial market to continue to be the &quot;bread and butter&quot; of sales.</p>
<p>She said Compaq was &quot;still the best value in the group,&quot; and set a price target of $100-$105. Shares rose 2-3/8 to 92-1/2 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>She described Microsoft as the &quot;undisputed leader&quot; in PC software, and set a short-term price target of $130 and long-term at $150.</p>
<p>Analyst Dan Mandresh said he seeks IBM selling for $195 in 1998. Shares closed down 2-7/8 to 162-1/8 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He said IBM &quot;defies easy categorization (because) it has almost one dozen major businesses.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he sees annual revenue growth of eight to nine percent, &quot;at the expense of gross margins.&quot;</p>
<p>He said IBM &quot;has more than adequate resources for another acquisition.&quot;</p>
<p>On Xerox, Mandresh sees the stock selling at $80. Shares closed up 1/8 to 64-5/8.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
