<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572848" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gates outlines technology views at CEO gathering.</title>
<headline>Gates outlines technology views at CEO gathering.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-05-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. Chairman Bill Gates called on some of the world's leading executives to develop a &quot;digital nervous system&quot; that would increase business productivity.</p>
<p>The billionaire software magnate, speaking to 103 chief executive officers from 25 countries at his two-day &quot;CEO Summit,&quot; said businesses needed to invest in a single infrastructure to connect employees and customers.</p>
<p>&quot;The excellence of that nervous system will define your competitiveness,&quot; he told the CEOs. &quot;To put this basic infrastructure together is a very serious investment. ... It requires leadership from the top of the company.&quot;</p>
<p>Executives at the summit also heard views on the future of technology from Vice President Al Gore, former Repoublican presidential candidate Steve Forbes and Federal Communications Commission Chairman Reed Hundt.</p>
<p>&quot;It's fair to say there were probably a hell of a lot more issues raised and vetted than answers,&quot; said Frank Biondi of Universal Studios.</p>
<p>He and other executives who participated in the summit, most of which was closed to the press, said Microsoft was not out selling its products overtly at the meeting.</p>
<p>But Gates encouraged the executives to keep their employees' personal computers &quot;reasonably up to date,&quot; replacing them every three years, among other suggestions that advanced Microsoft's business goals.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope ... they leave feeling good about the meeting and good about us,&quot; said Microsoft vice president Bob McDowell. &quot;We hope it reinforces the relationship that we're trying to establish between ourselves and our largest corporate customers.&quot;</p>
<p>To help ensure that, the executives were whisked from a hotel ballroom to a boat for a ride to Gates' $50 million mansion, which has been under construction for nearly five years in the exclusive Seattle suburb of Medina.</p>
<p>Guests were to enjoy a dinner including fiddlehead fern bisque, &quot;artichoke and Skagit Valley vegetable salad&quot; and lightly smoked salad in the huge reception hall of the 20,000-square-foot home, due to be completed sometime this year.</p>
<p>On Friday the chief executives, including Robert Crandall of AMR Corp., Stave Case of America Online Inc. and Gerhard Schulmeyer of Siemens Nixdorf Informationssysteme AG were to visit the Microsoft campus in suburban Redmond, Wash.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
