<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="576291" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bertelsmann-Lycos team up for European Web venture.</title>
<headline>Bertelsmann-Lycos team up for European Web venture.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's largest media company, Bertelsmann AG, and Lycos Inc, have formed a joint venture to create Internet navigation sites throughout Europe, company officials said Monday.</p>
<p>Bertelsmann contributes $10 million and content to the 50-50 partnership while the Framingham, Massachusetts-based Lycos kicks in its search engine technology under the terms of the deal, executives said.</p>
<p>The two companies already have a licensing agreement and sites up in Germany, France and the United Kingdom.  </p>
<p>The joint venture will take over those sites and establish others in Italy, Belgium, the Netherlands, Luxembourg and Spain, officials said.  &quot;It positions us to be the strongest Internet player in all of the European continent,&quot; Lycos President and Chief Executive Officer Robert Davis said in a conference call for reporters.</p>
<p>The new company, Lycos-Bertelsmann, will be headed by Christopher Mohn, son of Bertelsmann Chairman Emeritus Reinhard Mohn.  He said under the licensing agreement advertising revenues had grown 40 percent each month for the past three months.  </p>
<p>The joint venture will be part of Bertelsmann Internet Services, headed by Wolfgang Kitza.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe 20 percent of the sites are going to have 80 percent of the traffic,&quot; Kitza said, describing Bertelsmann, which had a total of $15 billion in revenues in fiscal year 1996, as a &quot;relatively large and conservative&quot; firm.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in this for the long term and we believe in the long term strategy of our partner,&quot; Kitza said, adding that Bertelsmann had reviewed a number of search engines in Europe and found Lycos to be &quot;much more successful&quot; on the Continent.  </p>
<p>Lycos's Davis said his company was the number one search engine in Europe. In the United States it trails Yahoo! Inc. At least one analyst was uncertain whether the addition of Bertelsmann as a partner for Lycos would be enough to propel it into the first place slot.</p>
<p>&quot;I keep wondering in the Web business if there is a prize for second place,&quot; Keith Benjamin, an analyst with Robertson Stephens, said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Lycos appears to be slightly ahead of some of its competition by lining up the right partner for Europe...and it is a positive step in the right direction, but it is not enough for me to change my rating to a buy,&quot; he said. Benjamin has a neutral position on Lycos.</p>
<p>But Hambrecht &amp; Quist analyst Paul Noglows said the deal &quot;is a pretty significant international opportunity.&quot;  Having previously covered the cable industry, Noglows said he realizes the need for a small company like Lycos to partner with a strong partner and &quot;Bertelsmann is a very strong partner.&quot;</p>
<p>Noglows had a buy out on Lycos prior to Monday's announcement and said after the conference call, &quot;This gives me the confidence to reiterate that buy. They're doing exactly the kind of thing that they set out to do.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Leslie Gevirtz, 617-367-4142))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
