<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="577215" id="root" date="1997-05-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bertelsmann, Lycos in Internet deal.</title>
<headline>Bertelsmann, Lycos in Internet deal.</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-05-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>German media conglomerate Bertelsmann AG and the U.S. Internet services company Lycos Inc. said Monday they formed a European joint venture.</p>
<p>Lycos, whose search engine allows users of the global Internet to locate pages on the World Wide Web, and Bertelsmann plan to offer the directory services in 37 European countries in local language versions.</p>
<p>Bertelsmann, which also has a joint venture with commercial online service America Online, plans to invest $10 million in the Lycos venture, which will be called Lycos-Bertelsmann.</p>
<p>In addition to search engines operating in local languages in Germany, Britain and France, the new venture will expand services to Italy, Belgium, the Netherlands and Spain this year, with other European countries to follow next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The European Internet market is demonstrating very strong growth,&quot; said Christoph Mohn, the new venture's managing director, in a statement. &quot;We expect to operate at break-even within a year,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Jupiter Communications, a U.S. consultancy, estimates that 3.7 million European households now have access to the Internet or online services. This figure is expected to grow at an annual rate of 48 percent to 16.5 million by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Wolfgang Kitza, director of Bertelsmann subsidiary Telemedia, said the company planned to continue expanding its Internet activities.</p>
<p>The German-language version of Lycos, which began in cooperation with Bertelsmann in September, currently registers about six million &quot;hits&quot; a month, a reference to the number of times the page is called up by Internet users.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
