<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582791" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intel likely to countersue Digital - lawyers.</title>
<headline>Intel likely to countersue Digital - lawyers.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Digital Equipment Corp.'s patent infringement lawsuit against Intel Corp. is a risky and expensive assault likely to prompt a counterstrike from the world's biggest chip maker, legal experts said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Intel said Wednesday it did not believe any of its products infringe on Digital's patents, and that it intended to vigorously defend itself. But for now at least, Intel stopped short of filing a countersuit.</p>
<p>Digital's lawsuit surprised the computer industry and legal experts, some of whom were startled by DEC's brazen approach. The company trumpeted its complaints in full-page advertisements in the San Jose Mercury News, Intel's hometown newspaper, as well as national dailies.</p>
<p>&quot;It is inconceivable to me that Intel would not sue them back,&quot; said Michael Barclay, an intellectual property lawyer in Palo Alto, Calif., home for many high-technology companies.</p>
<p>Digital said on Tuesday it had filed suit in U.S. District Court in Worcester, Mass., claiming Intel's popular Pentium, Pentium Pro and Pentium II chips -- key component's in 85 percent of the world's personal computers -- had infringed on 10 Digital patents.</p>
<p>Digital offers the competing Alpha chip, which works at faster speeds than Intel's chips but has met with little success in the market.</p>
<p>Legal experts said Digital has taken on a superpower with many patents to its credit, which could help Intel fight back. Not only did Intel virtually invent the microprocessor, but the company has bet its future on the wildly successful chips.</p>
<p>&quot;They're not suing a copycat. Intel invented this,&quot; said Barclay, who worked as an engineer for Intel 20 years ago, before entering the legal profession.</p>
<p>Intel noted it has about 1,000 patents for semiconductors, microprocessors and other high-technology computer components, an arsenal of intellectual property that could come in handy in any counterclaims, experts said.</p>
<p>Digital, based in Maynard, Mass., is a big Intel customer whose heyday was in the mid-1980s. It has struggled for years to turn around its business, which faltered partly because it did not anticipate the rapid growth of personal computers based on technology from Intel and Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>Margreth Barrett, intellectual property professor at Hastings College of Law in San Francisco, said patents have become more valuable in the past 15 years because of some protection offered by federal courts.</p>
<p>Digital's quick-strike action -- it did not approach Intel to try to settle the claims -- was a risky strategy that has not always worked for chip makers in the past, experts said.</p>
<p>In 1990, for example, a federal judge ordered Motorola Inc. and Hitachi Ltd. each to stop shipping their chips while a patent suit was underway, saying such cases should not end up in federal courts in the first place.</p>
<p>That ruling threatened the supply of Motorola's popular high-end 68030 microprocessor, then used by Apple Computer Inc., Hewlett-Packard Co. and others, and the dispute was quickly settled out of court.</p>
<p>Digital has asked for similar relief from the courts to force Intel to stop shipping chips it claims use Digital technology, and has sued to collect triple monetary damages.</p>
<p>Legal experts believe Digital fired the first salvo partly to ensure any trial would take place in federal court in its home territory of Massachusetts, which one litigator described as &quot;the original Xenophobic jurisdiction.&quot;</p>
<p>If the two sides cannot settle their differences, lawyers said preparations for trial could take years, involving dozens of lawyers, scores of depositions and millions of dollars in legal fees.</p>
<p>&quot;I can see that this thing is just going to be embroiled in litigation for years,&quot; said Barclay. &quot;Unless these parties get together and quickly resolve it, you supsect that the lawyers are going to make more money than their clients.&quot;</p>
<p>Separately, Cyrix Corp. said on Tuesday it also filed a patent infringement suit against Intel, alleging that Intel products infringed on patents issued to Cyrix on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Intel stock rose 37.5 cents to $152.75 and Digital fell 75 cents to $34.625 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
