<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="582880" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Africa without the parasites.</title>
<headline>Africa without the parasites.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>How about a trip to Africa with a top-notch guide, the sounds and smells of wildlife in the air, and the chance to come face to face with truly wild animals?</p>
<p>What? You only want to spend $30?</p>
<p>Okay. How about a trip to Africa with a guide who can barely remember where he put his trousers, a few sounds but none of the smells, and animals that are two-dimensional creatures that become globs of coloured squares if you get too close to them?</p>
<p>It's true that you miss the full sensory experience of a real safari when you spend $30 on &quot;Survival's Virtual Safari,&quot; a CD-ROM from Fujitsu Interactive (Windows95, $30, http://www.fujitsu-interactive.com). But that may not be a bad thing.</p>
<p>On this virtual reality trip through parts of Africa there are no voracious insects, no poisonous reptiles, no tropical diseases and you don't have to worry about having your rib bones used as oversized toothpicks by a pride of hungry lionesses.</p>
<p>Your host for this sometimes-charming game is The Colonel, who informs you right away that (a.) &quot;You can call me The Colonel,&quot; (b.) &quot;It's a jungle out there,&quot; and (c.) he's misplaced virtually everything you might need for your safari, including the keys to the land rover.</p>
<p>Therefore, your first job is to wander aimlessly around the compound looking for a map, compass, guide books, keys and other objects you'll need.</p>
<p>&quot;Feel free to come back and pester me with your bothersome questions,&quot; the Colonel says. From that point onward, he won't tell you anything.</p>
<p>In &quot;Virtual Safari&quot; you can float across the landscape or move through rooms in the lodge, drifting from side to side or looking up and down. When you find some interesting animals, you can pull out your camera and use the telephoto lens to get closeup views. One wing in the lodge is inspired by &quot;Alice in Wonderland,&quot; where you can munch on the food that says &quot;eat me&quot; to shrink to the size of a dung beetle.</p>
<p>And if you want to know something about an animal, a few clicks of the mouse will take you to an encyclopaedia-style guidebook with plenty of facts.</p>
<p>&quot;Virtual Safari&quot; has a few drawbacks. The videos are extremely short. And because there's no system for uninstalling it, chunks of it can linger on your computer long after the game has outlived its usefulness.</p>
<p>In some ways, the experience is more surreal than real. Some of the giraffes became frozen in mid-air. One herd of animals I tried to photograph would walk in place, completely disappear for a few seconds, and then magically reappear, still walking in place.</p>
<p>The virtual reality experience in &quot;Virtual Safari&quot; is still a long way from the real thing.</p>
<p>But then, this is Africa. You'll just have to rough it.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>&quot;Disney's Ready to Read with Pooh&quot; (Disney Interactive, Windows/Macintosh, $35, 800-900-9234) is pretty standard fare for 3- to 6-year-olds who are ready to master the alphabet, basic spelling, letter sounds and other important pre-reading skills. But the characters from Disney's Winnie the Pooh cartoons are so familiar to youngsters, kids may be willing to keep playing this game long after they've grown tired of similar products.</p>
<p>&quot;Ready to Read&quot; features all of the voices, mannerisms and music of the Pooh cartoons, along with a system for getting around that preschoolers will find easy to use -- as long as they know their colours.</p>
<p>If the computer is hooked to a colour printer, there are real-life rewards for succeeding at the games. In Tigger's detective game, which encourages a child to listen carefully, correctly placing the proper pieces on a storyboard will earn the child a Detective License. A child who helps Eeyore match words to a picture can get three personalized bookmarks.</p>
<p>For a family without a printer, Gopher rewards the child by furnishing a treehouse with all kinds of animated items. Parents can track a child's progress by seeing what kinds of rewards have been earned. The game's handbook also suggests additional activities for parents.</p>
<p>The game isn't flawless. When it's printing something, &quot;Ready to Read&quot; gets the hiccups, with irritating pauses between words.</p>
<p>In addition, the detective game is too forgiving. At one point, a child is told to &quot;give the pinwheel to Pooh and the busted balloon to Eeyore.&quot; But if you give the pinwheel to Eeyore instead, the pinwheel jumps into Pooh's hand and the child gets credit for a correct action.</p>
<p>One thing the game won't do: improve a child's sense of direction. If you go north from Mr. Sanderz's treehouse and then west, it will magically bring you back to Mr. Sanderz's treehouse. Unless you realise that the &quot;north&quot; and &quot;west&quot; signs were meant to point to &quot;North Woods&quot; and &quot;West Woods,&quot; &quot;Ready to Read&quot; seems to have been designed by the geographically impaired.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
