<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="583494" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: BAAN SEES Q4 EARNINGS IMPACT FROM AURUM.</title>
<headline>BAAN SEES Q4 EARNINGS IMPACT FROM AURUM.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch business software company Baan Co NV said on Wednesday its agreed acquisition of Aurum Software would enhance earnings per share right after completion of the deal, expected in August.</p>
<p>&quot;We see a contribution to earnings per share right from the start, right in August. August is in the middle of our third quarter, so a real contribution will be visible in Q4,&quot; Baan's company secretary Wim Heijting said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Baan announced late on Tuesday it had agreed to aquire U.S. marketing software company Aurum in a share deal worth around $250 million.</p>
<p>Baan's software is used to boost production efficiencies across a broad spectrum of industries ranging from automotive and aerospace manufacturers to communications firms.</p>
<p>&quot;Our system is production driven, based on what the shop floor does. The system like Aurum's is more based on marketing and sales information,&quot; said Heijting explaining the synergies behind the acquisition.</p>
<p>&quot;The beauty is that the combination gives the customer a suite of software to manage their business, not only to make production more efficient but also to make sure production is up to date and doing what the customer wants it to do,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're buying this company because of its technology, also because it has a strong management, fantastic customers, so for a number of reasons it's a very attractive company,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he declined to say how big a boost Aurum would give to earnings per share, saying that the 4.2 million Baan shares issued to Aurum shareholders would not be dilutive of earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;All I can say is that from the moment we acquire this company it will add value to our company,&quot; Heijting said, adding, &quot;We're acquiring technology, management, sales, customers - they have significant value.&quot;</p>
<p>Heijting said Aurum would retain its independence as a stand alone company within Baan, adding to Baan's own organic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see growth through independent autonomous growth of the company itself, but also through acquisitions - through this acquisition and through future ones,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
