<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60285" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ziff-Davis, SpotMedia to form Web gaming company.</title>
<headline>Ziff-Davis, SpotMedia to form Web gaming company.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ziff-Davis Publishing Co and SpotMedia Communications on Thursday will announce plans to form a company to operate a Web site featuring comprehensive information about computer and video games.</p>
<p>The new company will be run by the existing SpotMedia management team and majority-owned by Ziff Davis. SpotMedia, a private San Francisco company started in January, operates the popular &quot;GameSpot&quot; site on the Internet's World Wide Web.</p>
<p>The two companies together plan to invest $15 million to $20 million in the venture, according to sources close to the deal. Ziff-Davis is owned by Softbank Corp  9984.T.  </p>
<p>Once a definitive agreement has been reached, SpotMedia's GameSpot site and the on-line content of Ziff-Davis -- including Computer Gaming World, Electronic Gaming Monthly, CyberSports, Intelligent Gamer and -- will be merged into a single Web site, sources close to the deal said.</p>
<p>Since its launch, the GameSpot site has become one of the PC game industry's preferred on-line advertising vehicles. Advertisers on the site have included Microsoft Corp, Sierra On-Line, Interactive Magic and other game and hardware developers.</p>
<p>By combining GameSpot and Ziff-Davis's content, the companies hope to double their combined traffic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
