<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="60297" id="root" date="1996-09-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: This 'Pandora' Box Is Tough To Close.</title>
<headline>This 'Pandora' Box Is Tough To Close.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I. 1996-09-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The people who believe that space aliens have captured millions of humans for examination and experimentation also believe that if you can't remember several hours of your life, you have probably been abducted by extraterrestrials. The phenomenon is called &quot;missing time.&quot;</p>
<p>I've discovered another cause of missing time -- an interactive movie called &quot;The Pandora Directive&quot; (Access, DOS/Windows95, $50).</p>
<p>This detective thriller, which plays out on six CD-ROMs, is the sequel to &quot;Under A Killing Moon,&quot; an extraordinary game that was years ahead of its time because it offered a thoughtful plot, great characters, a delightful sense of humour, an online system for getting hints, and virtual reality that lets players walk just about anywhere.</p>
<p>The sequel has the same winning features.</p>
<p>The plot revolves around a 1947 incident in Roswell, N.M., where a flying saucer is alleged to have crashed and the bodies of space aliens were supposedly recovered.</p>
<p>Now the year is 2043 and Tex Murphy -- who fancies himself an old-time, hard-boiled gumshoe in an age of flying cars and human mutants created in the aftermath of World War III -- has been hired to find a missing scientist.</p>
<p>Faster than you can say &quot;cranial hematoma,&quot; Tex gets banged around by black-suited government agents, one of whom seems to have taken up serial killing as a hobby.</p>
<p>Over time, Tex discovers that the missing scientist, part of a team that had been studying the Roswell remains, has been sending mysterious boxes to his friends and family.</p>
<p>The government will stop at nothing to get at the secrets in those boxes. Your job is to get them first, figure out how to open them, and solve the mystery before the feds cure your addiction to oxygen.</p>
<p>Today, the Roswell affair is a genuine American legend, spawned by some Cold War half-truths and promoted by people devoted to keeping the mystery alive.</p>
<p>Although the debris found near Roswell came from a train of about 20 weather balloons and radar targets launched June 4, 1947, as part of a top-secret experiment for sensing Soviet nuclear tests, modern-day storytellers have embraced it as an interesting premise for a rash of books, TV shows and movies.</p>
<p>&quot;The Pandora Directive&quot; uses the legend well. It has UFO gadflies who think the Kennedy assassination was part of the UFO conspiracy, an &quot;Alien Autopsy&quot; film that looks more authentic than the hoaxy movie repeatedly shown on the Fox network, and a visit to Area 51, the top-secret Air Force base in Nevada where legend says an alien spacecraft is stored.</p>
<p>The result is all of that missing time. I started playing it around 10 a.m. Saturday and had to be dragged away at 4:30 p.m. I got back to the computer at 9 p.m., and the next time I looked up, it was 1:30 a.m. Sunday.</p>
<p>The game features well-known actors Kevin McCarthy, Tanya Roberts and Barry Corbin. But the real star is Chris Jones, who has created a wonderful character in Tex, the hapless P.I. who would love to work out with his barbell &quot;if it weren't so darn heavy.&quot;</p>
<p>You'll need a heavyweight system to run the game, with at least 8 megabytes of random access memory (RAM) if you use the DOS version and 12 megabytes of RAM if you run it through Windows 95. Sixteen megabytes are recommended.</p>
<p>If you have the computer power and you love a good mystery adventure game, &quot;The Pandora Directive&quot; is one box definitely worth opening.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in stores:</p>
<p>&quot;Mummy: Tomb of the Pharaoh&quot; (Interplay, Windows, $48) sends players on a mission to discover whether a mining site in Alexandria, Egypt, is as cursed as the workers say it is. The CD-ROM stars Malcolm McDowell.</p>
<p>&quot;Where in the World is Carmen Sandiego?&quot; (Broderbund, Windows, $40) -- Billed as &quot;the next generation&quot; in Carmen Sandiego titles, this update version of the hit geography game features 360-degree walking tours (instead of the previous picture postcard scenes), 50 locations and &quot;The Chief&quot; from the PBS show.</p>
<p>&quot;How to Draw Comic Book Heroes and Villains&quot; (DiAmar, Windows/Macintosh, $40) is an easy-to-use drawing tutor based on the book by cartoonist Christopher Hart. But for people who want to learn to create oversexed figures whose costumes look like they've been painted on, this CD-ROM has so little animation, it doesn't seem to offer much more than you could find in a book.</p>
<p>&quot;Inside the SAT &amp; ACT '97&quot; ($30) and &quot;College Adviser '97&quot; ($20) are programmes for Windows and Macintosh from The Princeton Review designed to help students prepare for the college admission tests and help find the right institution from a selection of 1,200 colleges and universities. &quot;College Adviser&quot; also has hints for applying for financial aid.</p>
<p>&quot;Right's Animal Farm&quot; and &quot;The Sailor Dog&quot; (Powerhouse Entertainment, Windows, $30) -- Two children's storybooks based on the popular Golden Books products for youngsters age 3 to 7. The first deals with animals who think the farm is a little too neat and orderly. The second features Scuppers, the seafaring dog. Children can have the story read to them in English or Spanish.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
