<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="605296" id="root" date="1997-05-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: KDD posts lacklustre results, sees tough year ahead.</title>
<headline>KDD posts lacklustre results, sees tough year ahead.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's biggest international call operator KDD Co unveiled a lacklustre set of earnings on Thursday and predicted another tough year ahead as painful cut-rate competition continues in Japan's telecoms market.</p>
<p>Domestic service operator Japan Telecom Co also revealed a cautious earnings outlook for this year, citing heavy pressure to cut rates, but added that a planned merger with an international operator would help to raise profits in the following year.</p>
<p>Under drastic structural changes ongoing in Japan's telecoms market, Kokusai Denshin Denwa Co (KDD), as well as two other Japanese international call operators, are hardest hit by deregulation and competition, analysts say.</p>
<p>KDD, whose service until recently had been limited to Japan's small international call market, now faces massive competition from foreign operators and domestic operators such as Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp (NTT) and is hastening to cut rates.</p>
<p>KDD said its profit from the telephone business was halved to 11.35 billion yen ($97.8 million) in the year ended March 31, 1997, as a result of large rate cuts and the introduction of volume discount services.</p>
<p>Its parent current profit slid to 20.81 billion yen ($179 million) in 1996/97 from 31.25 billion yen ($269 million) the previous business year. KDD forecast profit would slide further to 17 billion yen ($146 million) in 1997/98.</p>
<p>Current profit is pre-tax and includes gains and losses from securities investments and other non-operating activities.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible the forecast could be revised downward following a possible cut in international call rates later this year,&quot; KDD managing director Noriyoshi Tanaka told a news conference.</p>
<p>Deregulation of the resale of international leased lines planned later this year will allow foreign telecoms carriers to start low-cost international call services in Japan, and is expected to put further pressure on KDD.</p>
<p>Parliament's Lower House on Thursday passed a bill to approve NTT's entry into the international call market and its restructuring plans, which will make the giant company into a set of leaner firms from around 1999.</p>
<p>The Lower House also passed a bill on a revision of the law governing KDD's business, allowing it to enter into domestic phone services.</p>
<p>Long-distance carrier Japan Telecom managed to inch up profit in 1996/97 thanks mostly to sharp gains in sales of cell phone handsets. But it expects profit to slide in 1997/98, affected by a large rate cut implemented in February.</p>
<p>The company posted parent current profit of 44.5 billion yen ($383 million) in 1996/97, but expects it to fall to 41 billion yen ($353 million) in 1997/98.</p>
<p>Japan Telecom, which is to merge with International Telecom Japan Co later this year, said the merger will start contributing to its profits in the year beginning April 1, 1998. The two firms on Thursday signed an agreement to merge on October 1.</p>
<p>A Japan Telecom official earlier this year said it had hopes for further tie-ups in the future, including with KDD.</p>
<p>One exception to the harshly competitive telecoms market is data communications services, which is benefiting fully from the Internet craze and growing investment by Japanese firms in digital information.</p>
<p>NTT unit NTT Data Corp, said its parent current profit grew 22.2 percent to 27.04 billion yen ($233 million) in 1996/97. It expects profit to climb to 29 billion yen ($250 million) in 1997/98. ($1=116 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
