<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="615710" id="root" date="1997-05-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft cancels planned Montreal online guide.</title>
<headline>Microsoft cancels planned Montreal online guide.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-05-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp.  has canceled plans to open a Montreal version of its Sidewalk online guide as the company wrestles with its media strategy for markets outside the United States, a company executive said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Frank Schott, general manager of Microsoft Sidewalk, confirmed online reports the company has closed its Montreal office and eliminated the jobs of its nine full-time employees.</p>
<p>Instead, all Canadian online operations will be folded into the Toronto office of the Microsoft Network, the software giant's Internet access service, Schott said.</p>
<p>He said the same strategy would be followed in other international markets, including Munich, Germany, and Sydney, Australia, where the first two overseas versions of the online city guide are scheduled to make their debut by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;In the small markets, which all of the international markets by definition are, we have found that getting the content and cost leveraging really pays off,&quot; Schott said in an interview.</p>
<p>Microsoft launched Sidewalk last month with initial sites in New York and Seattle and a menu of features heavy on restaurant and entertainment listings. Sites will be launched next month in Boston and Minneapolis-St. Paul, Minn., with additional sites to roll out at the rate of &quot;a city or two a month,&quot; Schott said.</p>
<p>In the United States, where the online market is relatively large and hotly competitive, Microsoft is setting up dedicated offices in each city to develop editorial content.</p>
<p>But overseas, where the market is smaller, a single staff can handle marketing and content for both Sidewalk and the Microsoft Network, Schott said.</p>
<p>Schott said the company has been pleased so far by response from consumers and advertisers to the new service, which is available free over the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers for the first month were very good,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
