<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="623643" id="root" date="1997-05-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intuit to sell Parsons unit, reports flat earnings.</title>
<headline>Intuit to sell Parsons unit, reports flat earnings.</headline>
<dateline>MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif. 1997-05-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intuit Int. said Thursday it agreed to sell its Parsons Technology unit, a maker of consumer software, to Broderbund Software Inc.</p>
<p>Terms were not disclosed.</p>
<p>Intuit, publisher of the electronic checkbook programme Quicken, also reported fiscal third-quarter earnings that were less than Wall Street expected and warned that revenue could grow more slowly this year than previously anticipated.</p>
<p>The sale of Parsons, which publishes products such as Family Lawyer and Family Tree Maker, will help Intuit concentrate on its financial and tax products, the company said.</p>
<p>Intuit said profit from operations for its fiscal third quarter fell to $7.6 million, or 16 cents a share, from $7.7 million, also 16 cents a share, a year earlier.</p>
<p>Wall Street expected Intuit, based in Mountain View, Calif., to earn 17 cents a share, according to a recent survey of analysts by Zacks Investment Research.</p>
<p>With a $6.1 million charge for an acquisition of a Japanese software company, Intuit had net income of $488,000, or one cent a share, in the most recent quarter.</p>
<p>Revenue for the quarter ended April 30 rose 3 percent to $136.3 million from $132.1 million.</p>
<p>Like many consumer software companies, Intuit has had to slash its prices to fight rivals such as Microsoft Corp. for space on overcrowded retail shelves.</p>
<p>In recent months, Intuit has sold businesses not directly related to its financial and tax software. It had bought Parsons in 1994 for about $67 million in cash and stock.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clear Parsons didn't fit with our strategic direction,&quot; said Bill Campbell, Intuit chief executive.</p>
<p>In a call with analysts to discuss the sale, Intuit executives also said revenue for the fiscal year could fall below the $600 million to $620 million range the company had been previously told investors to expect.</p>
<p>Weak consumer software sales throughout the industry contributed to Intuit's slow growth during the quarter, Chairman Scott Cook said.</p>
<p>Broderbund, publisher of educational games such as the Carmen Sandiego series, said the Parsons acquisition will expand its line of products for families. Parsons specialises in selling products through the mail, which will help Broderbund depend less on retail sales, Broderbund said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
