<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="629703" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PointCast extends advertising-based service model.</title>
<headline>PointCast extends advertising-based service model.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA CLARA, Calif. 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Privately-held PointCast Inc said Monday it will focus its business model on providing an advertising-based news and information service while making tools available to corporate users for free.</p>
<p>PointCast chief executive Chris Hassett also said in a conference call the firm's previously announced search for a new &quot;world class&quot; executive with substantial media experience to succeed him as chief executive officer and president would likely be concluded in &quot;a very short period of time.&quot;</p>
<p>PointCast pioneered the concept of direct broadcasting over the Internet through so-called &quot;push&quot; technology.  </p>
<p>Choice of the new chief executive would set the stage for an initial public offering of the company, which reportedly brushed off an offer earlier this year from Rupert Murdoch's News Corp to buy out the company for a figure the Wall Street Journal has put at $350 million to $450 million.    In</p>
<p>the conference call, Hassett declined to discuss any takeover discussions the company has held and would not discuss any details of its plans for a initial share offering (IPO).</p>
<p>&quot;We have never speculated on an IPO. It's obviously a path for growth and PointCast is a growth company and that path is available to us,&quot; Hassett told reporters in the call.  </p>
<p>Hassett, whose company is seen facing growing competition from Microsoft Corp and Netscape Communications Corp, also declined to discuss PointCast's profitability.</p>
<p>&quot;Relative to revenue growth and profitability, I can tell you that we're operating ahead of plan,&quot; he said. &quot;We're extremely pleased with the growth of the company. Some of the management changes you are seeing are indicative of a growing company.&quot;</p>
<p>Profits are elusive in the fast-growing Internet sector as many companies concentrate on investing to build revenues and market share in the emerging sector before reaping profits.  </p>
<p>Hassett said the search for chief executive and the choice of Phil Koen, former chief financial officer of Etec Systems Inc, as a PointCast senior vice president and chief financial officer, were intended to &quot;make sure we're executing in perfection against those (growth) opportunities.&quot;</p>
<p>Hassett would not say whether the company planned another round of private financing ahead of any initial offering, as have many other companies that have attracted strategic corporate investors before to their IPOs.</p>
<p>PointCast raised about $36 million in July 1996 in a private round, valuing the company at about $250 million.  </p>
<p>Previously, the company aised $12 million in a round of financing from venture capital firms including Benchmark Capital, whose newly named general partner David Beirne, a well-regarded headhunter, is leading PointCast's search for a chief executive.</p>
<p>&quot;We since last July have begun to increase the revenue side of our businesses quite a bit. The company has grown quite a bit and is extremely healthy from a cash point of view,&quot; Hassett said  He declined to provide further details.</p>
<p>Hassett said he did not view Netscape's Netcaster and Microsoft's upcoming Active Desktop as competition to PointCast's Internet news and advertising distribution.</p>
<p>PointCast estimates it has more than one million active users of its service, which is free and generates revenues through advertising sales. Hassett said he viewed the Microsoft and Netscape moves as validating PointCast's approach.</p>
<p>Earlier, PointCast released a beta version of its PointCast Network software, which it said improves performance and pares network traffic. It is also providing utilities that will allow companies to manage what information employees are able receive on their desktops. Final versions will ship this summer.</p>
<p>The software tools are free to companies that allow employees to view advertisements on their screens.</p>
<p>((sam.perry@reuters.com, in Palo Alto +1 415 846 5400))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA CLARA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
