<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="632604" id="root" date="1997-06-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FEATURE - Germany's SAP growth to continue despite hurdles.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Germany's SAP growth to continue despite hurdles.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>At first glance, German software developer SAP AG could hardly face a tougher situation.</p>
<p>Key competitors are growing at torrid rates, SAP has reacted slowly to the Internet phenomenon, and it needs new customers to keep its run of sterling growth from petering out.</p>
<p>And as if that wasn't enough, the company is at the centre of an insider trading investigation.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no doubt they've got a lot of challenges in front of them,&quot; said Clare Gillin, an International Data Corporation market analyst who follows makers of so-called enterprise software.</p>
<p>Yet despite the high hurdles SAP must overcome, financial analysts still rate the company as one of the most solid investments in the technology sector -- right up there with Microsoft or Intel.</p>
<p>&quot;In their industry, SAP is the closest thing you can get to another Microsoft,&quot; said Andreas Wahl at Credit Lyonnais in Frankfurt. &quot;Their problems are really very few.&quot;</p>
<p>Another analyst in London, who did not want to be identified, said SAP's market share may slip, but its overall market was still expanding rapidly. &quot;I think in the next year they will really come through,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>SAP GROWING AT SLOWER RATE THAN RIVALS</p>
<p>That wasn't so clear six months ago, when a surprisingly weak third quarter forced SAP to cut its forecast for 1996 sales growth to 33 percent from 40 percent.</p>
<p>The news prompted SAP shares to plummet 26 percent within hours on October 23. It also reinforced speculation that SAP's R/3 software -- which controls sales, production, purchasing and personnel data in large companies -- was seen as too complex, difficult to install and unprepared for the Internet.</p>
<p>SAP recovered after the fourth quarter proved unexpectedly strong and it went on to post a 1996 sales rise of 38 percent in 1996 to 3.72 billion marks ($2.2 billion). The strong dollar then helped boost first-quarter sales 49 percent to 1.03 billion marks and on May 13 SAP shares climbed to an all-time high of 325 marks.</p>
<p>But even with those gains, SAP is still growing at slower rates than its rivals.</p>
<p>PeopleSoft Inc., for example, expects sales to rise about 70 percent for 1997 after first quarter revenue jumped 86 percent to $153.6 million. Baan Co NV of the Netherlands is on a similar track.</p>
<p>&quot;For solving complex problems of multinational companies, R/3 is unique, but Baan and PeopleSoft have done well in companies with less than $1 billion in revenue,&quot; Gillin said.</p>
<p>SAP has flourished over the last 25 years because of an ability to tap into shifts in corporate computing.</p>
<p>In 1972, Dietmar Hopp and three colleagues left IBM with the idea that companies wanted standard business control software -- not the hard-to-maintain custom programmes IBM and other were supplying with mainframe computers.</p>
<p>R/1 took off in Germany and sales reached 10 million marks in 1979. Then SAP released a version tailored for international business functions and multiple languages -- and sales of R/2 soared as multinationals began tying together previously separate computer systems.</p>
<p>SAP was correct again in the early '90s when it recognised that inexpensive machines such as personal computers were reducing the need for big mainframes. It developed R/3 to run on a variety of different types of machines -- just in time to catch the trend toward client-server networks.</p>
<p>SALES HAVE QUADRUPLED SINCE 1990</p>
<p>Propelled by R/3, sales have more than quadrupled since the 1990 level of 831 million marks.</p>
<p>SAP hasn't been as prescient on the Internet. A year ago SAP shares fell after a market research report said the company was way behind Oracle Corp. in adapting enterprise software to provide information and allow sales over the worldwide computer network.</p>
<p>SAP added Internet capabilities in R/3 version 3.1, which arrived this year. That version also has special features that accommodate for the year 2000 and the euro -- the single currency Europe plans to launch in 1999.</p>
<p>The company also aims to keep sales rising by targeting new customers -- small and medium sized companies, especially ones in growing vertical markets like financial and health services.</p>
<p>But it won't be easy for SAP to win over these companies, analysts said. R/3 is notoriously difficult to install -- it can take three or more months -- and requires a change from the direct sales approach SAP is used to.</p>
<p>To reach them, SAP is joining forces with computer consultants who specialise in setting up computer systems for small companies, but it's not clear if this will be successful.</p>
<p>&quot;This is totally different than what SAP has done before,&quot; Gillin said. &quot;It is not their core competency.&quot;</p>
<p>SAP is confident 1997 will be another boom year. At its May 7 annual meeting, Hopp predicted sales would rise by 25 to 30 percent -- or about one billion marks -- with pretax profit increasing at a slightly faster rate.</p>
<p>But an insider trading investigation related to the stock plunge last year could spoil the party. SAP has said no top executives engaged in any trading based on the October 23 news that caused the shares to drop.</p>
<p>Frankfurt prosecutors last month narrowed the probe to four lower level employees, but Germany's BAWe securities watchdog retorted that five to 10 insiders &quot;certainly engaged in insider trading.&quot;</p>
<p>PROFITS COULD RISE 35 PERCENT THIS YEAR</p>
<p>The probe is continuing but has yet to shake financial analysts because it focuses on the actions of individuals, not the company. &quot;No one on the board is affected, so investors shouldn't lose sleep. There's nothing in there that we are really worried about,&quot; said the London-based analyst.</p>
<p>Furthermore, stock analysts said SAP had the competitive pressures well under control.</p>
<p>While R/3 3.1 solves most of the Internet concerns for now, SAP should have enough time to prepare R/3 4.0, due by the end of the year, to ease installation, said Wahl, the Credit Lyonnais analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;SAP is well established enough to make applications for new segments, and they are so far ahead of the others,&quot; he said -- noting that SAP's 1996 sales were 16 times that of Baan.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais forecast sales would rise 35 percent to 5.03 billion marks this year, and another 28 percent to 6.28 billion marks in 1998.</p>
<p>Wahl said net profit would grow at similar rates and the share price could rise to 380 to 390 marks. &quot;Companies like Baan will grow very rapidly, but whether they can ever catch up, I don't know,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($ = 1.702 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
