<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="633184" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Royalblue to float on June 9, signs large BZW deal.</title>
<headline>Royalblue to float on June 9, signs large BZW deal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK software supplier Royalblue Group Plc said on Tuesday it raised 5.2 million stg via an institutional placing and, in a seperate development, said it signed its biggest contract to date with investment bank BZW.</p>
<p>At the placing price of 170p per share, Royalblue, which supplies software products to financial trading systems, corporate call centres and customer helpdesks, has an approximate market capitalisation of 46.7 million stg. Dealings are expected to begin on June 9.</p>
<p>Royalblue said it sold its Fidessa trading support software to BZW. The equities division of the investment bank will use Fidessa to access the London Stock Exchange's electronic order driven market (SETS), scheduled to start in October.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Royalblue said the contract was worth in excess of one million stg to the group.</p>
<p>Chris Aspinwall, the managing director of Royalblue's financial division, said the BZW contract also involved the development of the investment bank's global equity order routing management system in addition to its standard order management and trading in SETS.</p>
<p>Royalblue's customers in the financial division also include Cazenove &amp; Co, CS First Boston Ltd, Hoare Govett, Dresdner Kleinwort Benson, Merrill Lynch and SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>The group made a pre-tax profit of over two million pounds to the year ended December 31 1996. Its turnover and pre-tax profits had achieved a compound annual growth rate of 50 per cent and 184 per cent respectively in the last three years.</p>
<p>Royalblue said the June 9 float would raise the profile of the company and, in conjunction with the company's share incentive schemes, would help attract and retain high calibre employees.</p>
<p>-- Andrew Langlands, London Newsroom +44 171 642 3496</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
