<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="634349" id="root" date="1997-06-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Europe management in high-tech drift, Novell says.</title>
<headline>Europe management in high-tech drift, Novell says.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>European companies are in danger of falling behind U.S. competitors because managements are slow to embrace new high technology ideas, U.S. software group Novell Inc said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Troubled Novell, which is also finding U.S. competition hard to bear, said the results of a survey it commissioned showed a lack of vision among European company directors.</p>
<p>&quot;Major European companies are slow to embrace new Intranet and communications technologies because of an alarming lack of understanding among board directors,&quot; Novell, based in Provo, Utah, said.</p>
<p>Intranets are private, internal networks linking personal computers but use the same software and search standards on which the Internet is based.</p>
<p>Last month Novell cut its workforce by 1,000 or 18 percent and said it expects a third quarter loss.</p>
<p>Novell, which said in an interview that it is in a transitional stage, reported a second quarter loss of $14.6 million compared with a loss of $55.3 million in the same period last year.</p>
<p>&quot;In the next nine to 12 months our new products will hit the market, the first in the middle of this year,&quot; Roland Richter, vice-president Europe, Middle East and Africa said.</p>
<p>Richter said Novell was moving into a new business where it offered its services managing the flow of information for business using high-tech directories on Intranets and the Internet, the loose world-wide network of personal computers linked by telephone lines.</p>
<p>&quot;This segment will be worth $20 billion worldwide by the end of 2000,&quot; Richter said.</p>
<p>Analysts say Novell faces tough competition from the likes of Microsoft Corp, Netscape Communications Corp, International Business Machines Corp and Oracle Corp.</p>
<p>Richter said Novell's traditional operating system business had stagnated.</p>
<p>&quot;This old business will continue, but there's not much growth left there,&quot; Richter said.</p>
<p>He said American companies adopted new technology ideas much faster than Europeans. This made them more profitable, and swifter to take advantage of new niches.</p>
<p>Britain was the fastest adopter of new ideas among Europeans followed by the Netherlands.</p>
<p>&quot;After an idea hits in the U.S., it will start appearing in the UK after about one year, then the Netherlands and move slowly into Germany after about 24 months then drift into France and Italy,&quot; Richter said.</p>
<p>The survey, commissioned by Novell among businesses in eight countries across Europe, also found discontent among employees about the inefficient dissemination of information internally. They worried that failure to embrace new ideas jeopardised their jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;Technology, such as the Intranet, has the potential to change the way companies operate and allows fast and effective communications and access to shared information within seconds right across the company,&quot; Richter said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our survey suggests that it is often managers that are contributing to the communications problems. Europe is stalling on the implementation of a technology solution that is predicted to revolutionise the way we do business,&quot; said Richter.</p>
<p>Neil Winton 44-171-542-7975 neil@jinks.demon.co.uk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
