<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="635792" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Electronic Arts to buy Maxis for $125 mln.</title>
<headline>Electronic Arts to buy Maxis for $125 mln.</headline>
<dateline>SAN MATEO, Calif. 1997-06-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Electronic Arts Inc. agreed to buy rival video game software company Maxis Inc., and its hot-selling line of &quot;SimCity&quot; products, for about $125 million in stock, the companies said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Under terms of the transaction, Electronic Arts, the biggest video game software company, will pay 0.3644 of its shares for each of Maxis' 11.26 million shares outstanding.</p>
<p>Based on Electronic Arts' Wednesday closing stock price of 30-3/8, Electronic Arts would pay about $11.07 for each Maxis share.  </p>
<p>Maxis, based in Walnut Creek, California, is best known for its line of &quot;Sim&quot; games, which allow players to construct cities, ant colonies, planets or golf courses.</p>
<p>Although Maxis' products consistently land in top-10 software charts, the company has struggled in the past few quarters. It has had to cut its prices and has been elbowed aside by bigger video game companies, such as Electronic Arts and Microsoft Corp, on retail shelves.</p>
<p>&quot;This will allow Maxis to have access to EA's worldwide distribution organization, one of the strongest in the industry,&quot; said Sam Poole, Maxis chief executive.  </p>
<p>In recent years, Electronic Arts, based in San Mateo, Calif., has been acquiring or investing in smaller software companies to insure that it has a steady supply of hit video games.</p>
<p>Maxis' &quot;flagship title, SimCity, is one of the most valuable franchises in our industry,&quot; said Larry Probst, Electronic Arts CEO. &quot;We believe the addition of the Sim product line will help us achieve our goal to be the number one publisher of entertainment software for the PC.&quot;</p>
<p>The companies said they expect to complete the transaction in August. Electronic Arts said it expects the deal to be tax-free.</p>
<p>((--Kourosh Karimkhany, in Palo Alto, 415 846 5401))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN MATEO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
