<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="637136" id="root" date="1997-06-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Four CD-ROMs for kids.</title>
<headline>Four CD-ROMs for kids.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>For years, mankind has been sending signals into space via radio and television broadcasts. Because the speed of light is so sluggish compared to the vast distances between stars, intelligent life that picked up those signals would be listening to radio waves generated many years ago.</p>
<p>Maybe that's why Interplanet Janet talks like she's a child of the '60s.</p>
<p>Janet is the heroine of &quot;Exploration Station&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $35, 800-543-9778, http://www.creativewonders.com) the latest in the &quot;School House Rock&quot; series from Creative Wonders. Janet sprinkles her sentences with words like &quot;Peace&quot; and &quot;Man,&quot; giving the impression that she's been studying Earth culture from 30 light years away.</p>
<p>But some of the skills needed by youngsters ages 6 to 10 to get through this game and rebuild Janet's crashed spaceship so she can get back to her planet are anything but old-fashioned. They have to learn how to read a wiring diagram to catch a burglar, combine genes to clone space creatures, match sounds to communicate with a dolphin, and even diagnose a few illnesses that have become prevalent in recent years like carpal tunnel syndrome.</p>
<p>But &quot;Exploration Station&quot; teaches a lot of old-fashioned skills as well. The cloning game requires logic, the light lab teaches about mirrors and lenses, and there's even a Hangman-style game where you have to try a little Morse code.</p>
<p>It has bad jokes (&quot;What holds up a sunroof? Beams!&quot;), songs from the &quot;School House Rock&quot; show, and the ability to download new questions from the Internet.</p>
<p>It has some flaws. At times, especially during the cloning game, Janet seems to blather on too long. The hardest level seems a little too hard. In the diagnosis game, for example, how many 10-year-olds are going to know that multiple sclerosis involves the nervous system? Also, the game gives the false impression that the source of MS is at one spot on the spinal column.</p>
<p>Yet even with its flaws, &quot;Exploration Station&quot; is head and shoulders above other educational games I've seen in recent months. As Janet might say: Groovy.</p>
<p>    -    -    -    -</p>
<p>&quot;Ringling Bros. and Barnum &amp; Bailey: The 12 Circus Rings&quot; (Windows, $25) is another CD-ROM in a time warp. Games like this were state-of-the-art 10 years ago.</p>
<p>The animation is sparse, the lips and voice are as synchronized as a dubbed Godzilla movie, and you can't take any action until, in many cases, the animation has played itself out.</p>
<p>Designed for ages 3 to 6 and based on &quot;The Twelve Circus Rings&quot; by Seymour Chwast, Byron Preiss Multimedia bills this computer game as &quot;Your child's 1st math software.&quot; But in many cases, the four songs, the videos and activities have little to do with math.</p>
<p>Even when you get to the math problems, it's hard for a youngster to get an answer wrong. If you have to subtract something, you simply take objects away until the game informs you that you've won. You don't learn anything.</p>
<p>And unlike virtually every other CD-ROM product released today, there's no simple method for uninstalling it. The best way to avoid that problem may be to refrain from installing it in the first place.</p>
<p>    -    -    -    -</p>
<p>&quot;Disney's Magic Artist&quot; (Disney Interactive, Windows95/Macintosh, $35, 800-900-9234) is an electronic draw and paint programme that stands above the crowd in some ways, but has some important drawbacks.</p>
<p>Good points: It teachers users to draw Mickey Mouse, Minnie, Goofy, Pluto, Donald Duck and Daisy. It has a huge assortment of colours to choose from and lets you precisely match colours with a few clicks of a mouse. Prepared pictures of the characters and objects can be altered in size and flipped. It also has lots of textures, including chalk, paint and pen.</p>
<p>Bad points: You can't undo your work at multiple levels. The sounds can be annoying (including the sound of the chalk on a chalk board, which can send a chill up your spine). Even though children will be attracted to it because of the Disney motif, there is no screen tutorial to help a youngster learn how to use all the features.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Headbone Interactive has some innovative titles for kids, but &quot;Iz and Auggie: Escape From Dimension Q&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $20) isn't one of them. The plot will give you a headache.</p>
<p>During an audition for a big record company, a talented musician and her robot lose the ability to play their songs. As they leave the audition, the robot is kidnapped by government agents and dumped into a recycling bin, which is actually a passageway to an alternative dimension. The girl follows.</p>
<p>Once in Dimension Q, the pair must rescue five secret agents who have been turned to green jelly, and then thwart an evil recording studio executive who is stealing music from our dimension (which supposedly is why the two couldn't play their songs during the audition).</p>
<p>&quot;Iz and Auggie&quot; may have lots of puzzles that require good thinking skills, but it's clear that not a lot of thought went into the plot, whose silliness will only be overlooked by younger players.</p>
<p>Finally, the sound isn't always in synch, and some words or syllables are lost completely. But maybe that's normal in Dimension Q.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
