<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="639883" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan cloner cautiously welcomes new Apple system.</title>
<headline>Taiwan cloner cautiously welcomes new Apple system.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Chen</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Taiwanese firm that has tied its fortunes to Apple Computer Inc's success cautiously welcomed on Thursday Apple's planned multi-platform operating system.</p>
<p>In May, Apple unveiled radical plans for a next-generation system, Rhapsody, which would run on both Apple and rival computers that use Intel Corp chips and Microsoft Corp Windows software.</p>
<p>But Taiwan's Umax Data Systems, which makes clones of Apple products, has some reservations about the plans.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously if Apple could develop Rhapsody with all its promises of being able to run on both PCs and Macs, that would be a big step in the right direction,&quot; Umax chairman Frank Huang told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;But while we are cautiously optimistic that Rhapsody would be developed, nothing is for sure because Apple has cancelled plans before,&quot; Huang said.</p>
<p>In an ambitious attempt to prevent software companies from jilting its products, Apple said it would develop Rhapsody to allow Apple-based software to be converted for PCs powered by Intel chips.</p>
<p>But some programmers fear Rhapsody would not run the products they designed for the older Macs.</p>
<p>Apple so far has released operating system software that runs only on Apple-designed hardware.</p>
<p>Umax and its U.S. unit, Umax Computer Corp, are among several Asian manufacturers licensed to design and make Mac-compatible &quot;clones&quot; that run on Apple's current Macintosh Operating System.</p>
<p>In 1996, Apple abandoned a mired effort to revamp the Mac OS system. Instead, the company bought Next Software Inc and used its software as the foundation for Rhapsody.</p>
<p>For the past two years, Apple has scrambled to improve the Macintosh and set it apart from other personal computers.</p>
<p>Until 1995, Apple had relied on the famed ease-of-use of its products as a key selling point, but Microsoft's release of Windows 95 dealt a blow to that pitch.</p>
<p>In a bid to reclaim lost market share, Apple began licensing its operating system to companies like Umax.</p>
<p>But while Umax and other such cloning firms have thrived on selling Apple clones at a discount to Apple products, their success has meant dwindling Macintosh shipments for Apple.</p>
<p>However, Umax's Huang said his company has helped keep the embattled California-based firm alive.</p>
<p>&quot;If it weren't for the clonemakers to promote its products, Apple would be even worse off right now,&quot; Huang said. &quot;Several years ago Apple absolutely hated the idea of clones, but now it absolutely depends on clones.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts have said the Macintosh operating system's share of the market has increased in recent months because of the success of the cloning companies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302015">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
