<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="640288" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IndustryWeek list spotlights top manufacturers.</title>
<headline>IndustryWeek list spotlights top manufacturers.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Oatis</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp. drove to the top of the IndustryWeek 1000 list of the 1,000 biggest publicly traded manufacturers worldwide, fuelled by $164 billion in 1996 revenue that was second to none.</p>
<p>The list, compiled by IndustryWeek magazine, Dun &amp; Bradstreet Corp. and Dun &amp; Bradstreet's Moody's Investors Service, gave GM top honours for the second year in a row. Ford Motor Co. was second with $147 billion in revenue and the Netherlands' Royal Dutch Petroleum Co. third with $139 billion.</p>
<p>Royal Dutch Petroleum also had the highest profit of the 1,000 manufacturers that made the cut: $9.6 billion in net income, according to IndustryWeek's June 9 issue, which was mailed to subscribers Thursday.</p>
<p>Petroleum was the leading manufacturing industry with $1.15 trillion in total revenue, the auto industry took second place, trailing by about $20 billion, and electronics and electric equipment was third.</p>
<p>&quot;The one thing, I think, that will be surprising again to a lot of people is the continuing strength of manufacturing, both in the United States and around the world,&quot; IndustryWeek Editor in Chief John Brandt said in an interview.</p>
<p>Speaking by telephone from the magazine's Cleveland offices, he said the survey found a trend among U.S. companies away from cost-cutting measures like layoffs and toward growth strategies such as boosting sales and winning customers from competitors.</p>
<p>About 75 percent of the companies on the list come from five countries -- the United States, Japan, Britain, Germany and France.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of new entries on this list,&quot; said Dun &amp; Bradstreet economist Steven Hess. &quot;Israel, Chile and Colombia are all new entrants.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The United States still dominates this list in a pretty dramatic way,&quot; said Hess, contrary to the perception that U.S. manufacturers are having trouble competing internationally.</p>
<p>The United States led in the number of IndustryWeek 1000 companies on the list, 329, to 221 for No. 2 Japan.</p>
<p>Britain, however, had the highest average profit margin for the top 20 companies for the second straight year: 7.8 percent, compared with 5.5 percent for top U.S. companies.</p>
<p>The top global manufacturing cities were Tokyo, with 143 companies on the list, London (50), Osaka, Japan (26); New York (19) and Seoul, South Korea (16). The top three U.S. states in terms of number of manufacturers were California with 36, New York with 30 and Illinois with 29.</p>
<p>U.S. manufacturers, especially high-technology companies, dominated IndustryWeek's elite &quot;20-4-50 club&quot;: the largest companies on the list with 20 percent or better annual profit growth, profit margins of at least 4 percent a year and revenue gains of at least 50 percent over five years.</p>
<p>Leading the eight-member &quot;club&quot; in revenue growth was Compaq Computer Corp., the world's largest personal computer maker, whose revenues jumped 454 percent over five years. Microsoft Corp. was No. 2 with 371 percent growth, followed by computer chip maker Intel Corp., Lockheed Martin Corp. and British drug maker Glaxo Wellcome Plc. Rounding out the list were Finnish cellular phone maker Nokia Oy, its Swedish rival L.M. Ericsson Telephone Co. and automaker Chrysler Corp.</p>
<p>Pointing to Chrysler, Brandt said, &quot;Companies that have been around for a while can still compete quite effectively.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition to the magazine, a free, searchable version of the list was being published Thursday on IndustryWeek's Web site: http://www.industryweek.com. IndustryWeek and Dun &amp; Bradstreet are also selling software that allows one to sort the data in a variety of ways. The software costs $99.</p>
<p>After Royal Dutch Petroleum, the manufacturers earning the highest profits were Exxon Corp., with $7.5 billion in net income and General Electric Co. with $7.3 billion. The top 10 profit-makers also included Philip Morris Cos. Inc., International Business Machines Corp., Intel, GM, Ford, British Petroleum Co. Plc and Merck &amp; Co. Inc.</p>
<p>Following GM, Ford and Royal Dutch Petroleum on the top 10 sales list were Exxon Corp., Mobil Corp., GE, IBM, British Petroleum, Japanese electronics giant Hitachi Ltd. and Toyota Motor Corp. Number 1,000 was Forbo Holding SA of Switzerland, a maker of plastics and other products, with sales of $1.42 billion.</p>
<p>Publicly traded subsidiaries of parent companies were also listed, as were information on earnings per share, return on equity and other financial measures.</p>
<p>GM reported $168 billion in total revenue, but that was before adjustments, which brought the figure to $164 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I48300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
