<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="642250" id="root" date="1997-06-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Novell says president to resign this month.</title>
<headline>Novell says president to resign this month.</headline>
<dateline>PROVO, Utah 1997-06-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novell Inc said Friday that Joseph Marengi will resign as president and chief operating officer of the networking company at the end of this month.</p>
<p>Marengi had served as president of the company since September of last year during a critical period while the company was searching for a new chief executive following the departure last August of CEO Bob Frankenberg.</p>
<p>Marengi, who joined Novell in 1989, had previously been executive vice president of worldwide sales at the company from 1992 to 1996 and had been considered among the candidates for the top position himself.  </p>
<p>Even after the selection of Eric Schmidt, the former chief technology officer of Sun Microsystems Inc., to take the spot of chairman and chief executive earlier this year, Schmidt said Marengi was a friend he had hoped would stay on.</p>
<p>But last week Novell announced plans to cut 1,000 workers -- equal to about 18 percent of its workforce -- after it was hit by declining sales of its computer network software.</p>
<p>The dramatic cuts for Novell, based in Provo, Utah, and the second biggest publisher of personal computer software behind Microsoft Corp., rank among the largest ever by a computer software company.</p>
<p>The company last week reported a loss of $14.6 million, or 4 cents a share, in its fiscal second quarter ended on April 30, compared with a loss of $55.4 million, or 15 cents, a year earlier. Sales rose to $273.1 million from $188.2 million.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Novell said the decision to leave was a personal decision by Marengi, and that he would be departing on amicable terms at the end of the month.</p>
<p>&quot;Joe has made a personal decision to move on,&quot; the spokesman said. &quot;He has been pretty instrumental in driving the company and also in bringing Eric Schmidt in.&quot;</p>
<p>Rumors of Marengi's departure were reported on Thursday by Computer Reseller New Online, which cited sources close to the company as saying the Novell marketing veteran had received a lucrative severance package.</p>
<p>Novell officials would not discuss the amount of severance compensation the executive may be receiving.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no information about the size of the severance package. We don't disclose that information,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The company has already said it will take a third-quarter charge of $25 million to $35 million to pay for the layoffs as the company realigns resources.</p>
<p>Neither Schmidt nor Marengi were immediately available for comment. Schmidt will take over the responsibilities of president temporarily after Marengi's departure, Novell said. (sam.perry@reuters.com, in Palo Alto, +415 846-5400)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVO, Utah"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
