<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="647510" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft expands cable tv reach with Comcast deal.</title>
<headline>Microsoft expands cable tv reach with Comcast deal.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. Monday expanded its foray into the cable television business with a $1 billion investment in Philadelphia's Comcast Corp., one of the biggest U.S. cable operators.</p>
<p>Microsoft Chairman Bill Gates described the deal as a chance to further the software giant's interest in providing multimedia services for home users.</p>
<p>&quot;Our vision connecting the world of PCs and TVs has long included advanced broadband capabilities to deliver video, data and interactivity to the home,&quot; Gates said in a news release. &quot;Comcast's integrated approach to cable distribution, programming and telecommunications complements that vision of linking PC and TV.&quot;</p>
<p>The deal gives Microsoft an avenue into the control and distribution of television programming, expanding on its MSNBC cable television joint venture with NBC.</p>
<p>For Comcast, the deal brings a &quot;significant cash infusion&quot; to pay off debt and repurchase stock, and access to Microsoft's expertise in computer operating systems and software management, said Comcast President Brian Roberts.</p>
<p>Roberts said the link-up with Microsoft will &quot;help us facilitate the deployment of high-bandwidth applications and lead to more sophisticated services.&quot;</p>
<p>The &quot;high bandwidth&quot; Roberts referred to is cable lines that have huge capacity to carry data and could help the development of a high-speed Internet for consumers. The relatively low-bandwidth, low-speed lines now in place have kept a lid on the amount of traffic the Net can handle.</p>
<p>&quot;We weren't out looking to raise capital,&quot; Roberts said in a telephone interview. &quot;It's more of an opportunistic situation. We're not going to change our strategy.&quot;</p>
<p>Roberts said the investment by Microsoft would accelerate the company's deployment of digital television and cable computer modems.</p>
<p>Technology and media companies have been betting heavily on the growth of a consumer and business market for multimedia applications that range from e-mail to gobal videoconferences. Cable systems, with their heavy-duty coaxial cable lines, have higher-speed pipelines to handle such traffic than traditional telephone lines.</p>
<p>In the deal announced Monday, Microsoft will buy 24.6 million shares of Comcast Class A special common stock for $500 million, and $500 million of a new issue of Comcast Series B convertible preferred stock.</p>
<p>The Comcast Class B shares will have a 5.25 percent pay-in-kind dividend and will be initially convertible into 21.2 million shares, which equals an initial conversion price of $23.54 a share, the company said. The conversion price will increase proportionately to the amount of accrued dividends.</p>
<p>The deal is expected to close in &quot;weeks, not longer,&quot; said Greg Maffei, Microsoft's vice president for corporate development, in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Federal antitrust approval is not required because Microsoft is not buying voting shares of Comcast, he noted.</p>
<p>The investment gives Microsoft the right to a seat on Comcast's board but for now the software giant will post only an &quot;observer,&quot; Maffei said.</p>
<p>Microsoft and Gates also will offer &quot;guidance&quot; to Comcast in its deployment of new technologies such as cable modems from At Home Corp., in which Comcast holds a stake, Maffei said.</p>
<p>Prior to the Comcast deal, Microsoft had agreed to invest in MSNBC as well as acquire WebTV, which has hardware to convert televisions into Internet receivers, in a $425 million deal. WebTV can also be used through cable systems to fine-tune interactive Internet applications.</p>
<p>Comcast's stock jumped $3.875 to $22.125, and Microsoft slipped $1.6775 $125.75 on Nasdaq in the afternoon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
