<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653305" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New magazine targets a high-tech niche -- the Netplex.</title>
<headline>New magazine targets a high-tech niche -- the Netplex.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Fromartz</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>It may not be as well known as Silicon Valley in California, but the Washington, D.C., area known as Netplex is fast attaining a major place in the high-tech world.</p>
<p>Part of it owes to visible players in the area such as America Online Inc., the online service, or UUNet and PSINet, two Internet communications companies, or upstarts like CyberCash, involved in electronic transactions.</p>
<p>But even more important are the hundreds of small start-ups now being formed in the region around the new technologies. They are attracting venture capitalists, adding employees and expanding the economy. Since 1994, they have raised nearly $1 billion in initial public offerings.</p>
<p>That last statistic comes from TechCapital, a new publication started by a subsidiary of The Washington Post Co. that focuses on the high-tech expansion in the region. A resource for entrepreneurs, venture capitalists, lawyers and deal-makers, it is the latest evidence of Netplex's coming of age.</p>
<p>Washington has a natural political focus, and defence-related contracting has been a traditional big business. But the new image of Netplex companies goes far beyond those roots, changing the business character of the region.</p>
<p>Doug Poretz, an investor relations specialist at the Poretz Group, said that technology has only recently reached a critical mass in the area, spurred in part by dreamers who left bigger, more established companies to start their own businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;The tech industry here is starting to rival Silicon Valley, and it will soon surpass Route 128 outside Boston,&quot; predicted Andrew Jacobson, president and chief executive of TechNews Inc., the Vienna, Va.-based Post subsidiary that publishes TechCapital.</p>
<p>The Washington Post last year bought TechNews because of the industry's growing prominence in the region, Jacobson said. TechNews is about 10 years old and its flagship is Washington Technology, a business newspaper for computer systems integrators serving the government. TechCapital was launched in April.</p>
<p>The new publication is targeted at the movers and shakers in the new economy -- 60 percent of its first mailing went to high-level executives -- by focusing on investment and business issues faced by small and growing companies. Its focus is similar to publications like Red Herring in California or Alley Cat News in New York, which target a similar market.</p>
<p>&quot;It gives the Washington Post Company the opportunity to get closely involved with tech companies in the area,&quot; Jacobson said. &quot;We're covering them, getting to know them better and if they take off, that's good for the regional economy and good for the Post.&quot;</p>
<p>In its premier issue, the magazine wrote about four people in the area who are at the centre of the new economy; another piece was on venture funds and had profiles of hot, local companies. Columns include IPO Watch and Desperately Seeking Schmoozin', covering technology business and networking events, including one upcoming investor conference sponsored in part by the Post.</p>
<p>After the first issue, TechCapital editor Trish Williams said there was so much demand for the magazine that the focus would be expanded to cover the mid-Atlantic region, since many venture capitalists based in Philadelphia are interested in the Washington area.</p>
<p>&quot;After the premier issue we were just inundated with calls from the Philadelphia and New York region,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>The magazine is just the latest and most visible sign of the region's development. But other important venues are in place, including a technology conference June 15-17 that will give regional public companies the chance to pitch to investors.</p>
<p>The conference, hatched by Poretz and sponsored by the Nasdaq market, The Washington Post and investment banks and law firms, seeks to create a greater buzz on Wall Street about the region's tech firms. About 70 are signed up to participate, Poretz said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>(Sam Fromartz, a Washington-based journalist, frequently writes about entrepreneurs and emerging companies. Any opinions expressed in this column are his own. He can be reached by email at sam1on1(at)aol.com)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I4752105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
