<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="656337" id="root" date="1997-06-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japanese animation publisher links up with DirecTV.</title>
<headline>Japanese animation publisher links up with DirecTV.</headline>
<byline>Yuzo Saeki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Satellite broadcaster DirecTV gained a new weapon against its rivals in Japan's entertainment market on Thursday, winning the backing of a publisher with a programme library full of Japanese animation and movies.</p>
<p>DirecTV, part of the Hughes Electronics Corp group, said that Tokuma Shoten Publishing Co Ltd will take a 10 percent equity interest in its Japanese unit.</p>
<p>&quot;This partnership will offer us access to Tokuma's rich library of popular Japanese animation and classic Japanese movies, as well as future products,&quot; Gareth Chang, chairman of DirecTV Japan Co Ltd, told a news conference.</p>
<p>Tokuma Shoten, which also inked a distribution deal last year with Walt Disney Studios, boasts a large programme library that includes animated movies by Hayao Miyazaki, one of Asia's top animators and creator of box office hits such as &quot;My Neighbour Totoro,&quot; featuring a rabbit-like sprite.</p>
<p>DirecTV Japan, which is also seeking partnerships with Japanese television broadcasters, is one of three satellite broadcasting groups scrambling for popular programmes to win over Japan's many avid television viewers.</p>
<p>Hughes chairman Michael Armstrong told Thursday's news conference that DirecTV was also in &quot;serious discussions&quot; with a Japanese terrestrial broadcaster about a stake in DirecTV Japan.</p>
<p>He declined to name the broadcaster, although when asked if his group was in talks with Nippon Television Network Corp, Armstrong said, &quot;We would be honoured if they would consider participation.&quot;</p>
<p>DirecTV Japan will probably start broadcasting in November or December and offer 72 to 96 channels, he said. It will be the second operator to begin satellite broadcasting in Japan.</p>
<p>PerfecTV, owned by a consortium of Japanese trading firms, began services last year and plans to boost its number of channels to 100 later this year.</p>
<p>Japan Sky Broadcasting Corp (JSkyB), led by media tycoon Rupert Murdoch's News Corp, Japan's Softbank Corp, electronics and entertainment giant Sony Corp and powerful terrestrial broadcaster Fuji Television Network, aims to start a 150-channel service next spring.</p>
<p>DirecTV unveiled its partnership with Tokuma just one day after an announcement that Japan's first 24-hour animation channel will begin airing on rival PerfecTV in September.</p>
<p>The channel, created by the Japanese units of Turner Broadcasting System Inc and Time Warner Inc, and giant Japanese trade house Itochu Corp, would feature animation from more than 10,000 titles in Time Warner's library, including Wacky Races, Popeye, Daffy Duck and Bugs Bunny.</p>
<p>Armstrong did not give any target for DirecTV subscribers in Japan, although he said half of Japan's 40 million households are potential subscribers.</p>
<p>Armstrong, who is in charge of worldwide strategy for DirecTV, was in Tokyo to meet DirecTV partners, which include Matsushita Electric Industrial Co Ltd, Mitsubishi Corp and four other Japanese companies, and with officials of Japan's Ministry of Posts and Telecommunications.</p>
<p>DirecTV Japan is 35 percent-owned by DirecTV International Inc, a unit of General Motors Corp subsidiary Hughes Electronics.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
