<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66237" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TALKING POINT-Hughes deal may speed spin-off.</title>
<headline>TALKING POINT-Hughes deal may speed spin-off.</headline>
<byline>Mark Egan</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hughes Electronics Corp's buyout of PanAmSat Corp is another aggresive move by Hughes into high growth data and communications services and gives General Motors Corp further reason to sell the rapidly changing company.</p>
<p>&quot;This purchase tells me that this entity isn't long for the General Motors mix of business because they're going into businesses that are just not a part of GM,&quot; said John Modzelewski, an analyst at PaineWebber Group Inc.  </p>
<p>Hughes agreed to buy PanAmSat on Friday in a deal worth $3 billion. The companies will merge their satellite services into a new public company using the PanAmSat name.</p>
<p>For months Wall Street has speculated that GM may want to spin off Hughes, which the automaker acquired in 1985 for more than $5 billion. Hughes Chairman Mike Armstrong has suggested in the past that he would prefer his company to operate independently.</p>
<p>At a news conference in New York, Armstrong declined to speculate on a possible spinoff.  </p>
<p>Hughes has been diversifying in recent years away from its traditional staple as a maker of satellites and missiles into high growth consumer services such as DirecTV, its consumer satelite television operation.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clear to everybody that the value of Hughes is becoming less and less what it was just a year or two ago,&quot; Modzelewski said. &quot;This was a defense company that was going to link up with Delco and we were going to have aerospace technology make its way into GM cars.&quot;  </p>
<p>Modzelewski said Hughes' traditional defense business coupled with automotive unit Delco account for some 85 percent of profits, while the high growth space and communications side accounts for almost half of the company's value.</p>
<p>&quot;What they're trying to do is push into some real high growth areas where the cost is a function of what the benefit is to you,&quot; Modzelewski said.</p>
<p>&quot;Selling satellites is a competitive business, but if you're the only person selling a TV service to someone who can't get cable&quot; profits can be higher.  </p>
<p>Modzelewski said Hughes has effectively split itself into steady growth companies and speculative high growth potential innovative companies. However, analysts said the new structure may not fit with GM, which bought Hughes to offset the cyclical nature of the automotive market.</p>
<p>&quot;Can a GM auto company and a Hughes defense company...get into the multi-billion data communications business. Can this be like a Microsoft ? Do they have the same corporate culture? Can they pull it off?,&quot; Modzelewski said.  </p>
<p>Modzelewski said GM may want to bring back Delco into the parent company and sell off the defense business and the  space and communications (which includes PanAmSat and DirectTV), as two separate companies.</p>
<p>He estimates DirectTV alone would fetch $6 billion.</p>
<p>Analysts said the PanAmSat acquisition establishes Hughes as a major force in satellite services.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an excellent idea for Hughes, strategically what it does is make them a global leader in satellite services,&quot; said Cai Von Rumohr of Cowen &amp; Co.</p>
<p>An added benefit of the new PanAmSat's global position is that DirecTv may find it easier to get early access to international markets.</p>
<p>&quot;It will provide them potential for earlier access for some of their own services, like DirecTv, into international markets&quot; he said. &quot;As a separate entity PanAmSat could have directed that capacity elsewhere.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
