<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="665547" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Micron puts sold after earnings.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Micron puts sold after earnings.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A big buyer of Micron Technology Inc June 40 puts was selling them out Tuesay as the shares lost a bit of ground, traders said.</p>
<p>The June 40 puts traded a total of nearly 11,000 contracts. Traders said about 9,500 was from one customer that had been buying them in recent weeks expecting bad news.</p>
<p>But after the market close Monday, Micron reported fisacal third quarter earnings of $0.44 a share, up from $0.27 a share in the year ago quarter.</p>
<p>The earnings beat Wall Street's estimate of $0.39 per share. In afternoon trade, Micron was down one at 41-12.  </p>
<p>&quot;The numbers were a little better-than-expected but the stock's not done much,&quot; said Rob Kovell, a lead market maker in Micron options at the Pacific Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;The big put buyer came in and sold them out this morning,&quot; he said, adding the puts were sold at 7/16 and 3/8.</p>
<p>Jon Najarian, president of Mercury Trading in Chicago, said Micron shares have stiff resistance in the 42-1/2 to 45 zone but their trading pattern is improving.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock looks like it's holding a lot better,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The stock touched 45 in early June and has been trading up in that region ever since, but earlier in the year, it declined sharply after hitting that 45 level.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a much more bullish chart pattern now than it was,&quot; Najarian said.</p>
<p>He said that was one reason the options volume was centered around the 42-1/2 and 45 strike prices.</p>
<p>After the June 40 puts, the most active Micron option was the June 42-1/2 call, which traded a total of 6,270 contracts. The July 45 calls traded 2,260.</p>
<p>Traders said volatility in Micron options fell sharply.  </p>
<p>Najarian said volatilities had backed down to the 60 area from the 70-80 region.</p>
<p>&quot;Once the news is out they're not as nervous and they take the air out of it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In other trading, a U.S. brokerage firm rolled a large position in the Bay Networks Inc June 20 calls out to the July 20 calls for a customer, traders said.</p>
<p>The June 20 call traded 7,660 contracts by afternoon and the July 20 call traded about 7,560.  </p>
<p>&quot;They sold the Junes and bought the Julys for a quarter of a dollar,&quot; said Najarian, whose Mercury Trading is a market maker for both Bay Networks and Micron Technology.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Gateway 2000 Inc options were fairly busy as the stock rallied on its first session after a two-for-one split.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing unusual. A lot of call sellers,&quot; said a market maker at the CBOE.</p>
<p>Gateway shares were up 2-3/8 at 36 on volume of more than 6.2 million shares in consolidated late session trading.</p>
<p>((Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
