<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="669038" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Warnings from key tech firms raise sector concerns.</title>
<headline>Warnings from key tech firms raise sector concerns.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Warnings from two key computer stocks jolted technology stocks Wednesday and analysts cautioned that the sector, which has run up in the past month, may face greater difficulties in the weeks ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;Aside from the warnings about second quarter profits, there are several problems facing technology,&quot; First Albany investment strategist Hugh Johnson said, mentioning in particular the sector's high valuations.</p>
<p>He also pointed to indications that technology upgrade spending may be slowing as companies re-direct 1998 capital spending to remedy Year 2000 software glitches.  </p>
<p>He cautioned that a correction of 10 to 15 percent may lay ahead this summer as investor awareness of the issue takes hold.</p>
<p>The Wednesday morning selling began with profit warnings by Gateway 2000 Inc and Seagate Technology Inc and a lackluster earnings report from Oracle Corp, analysts said.</p>
<p>Technology indexes, weighed down by losses in the computer maker, semiconductor and software sectors, depressed the broader market. By mid-morning Wednesday, the Dow Jones Industrial index was off nearly 54 to 7706.95.  </p>
<p>The Dow Jones Computer sector index was the hardest hit of the technology groups, with all fourteen components trading in negative territory, led by Seagate, which was off 5-1/4 at 36-1/8.</p>
<p>Gateway 2000, which is not part of the index, was down 3 at 31-3/4.</p>
<p>Most of the 35 components in the Morgan Stanley High Technology index opened lower, although selected software, semiconductor and services companies in the index gained ground into positive territory by mid-morning.  </p>
<p>Wednesday's sell-off put a halt to the healthy gains seen among technology stocks during the past week, which built on the sector's strong showing throughout May.</p>
<p>Nervous investors saw the bad news from leading computer names as an occassion for profit-taking, traders said.</p>
<p>Gateway, a direct marketer of personal computers, said after the market close Tuesday that it expected revenues for the second quarter to be about even with the first quarter's level of $1.42 billion.</p>
<p>The warning followed weeks of rumors it was preparing to pre-announce lower than expected earnings for the quarter.</p>
<p>Also on Tuesday, Seagate, a computer disk drive maker, issued its second earnings warning in as many weeks.</p>
<p>The company said revenues were expected to be between $2 billion and $2.1 billion for the quarter ended later in June, below its earlier forecast.</p>
<p>Oracle, the database software leader, posted fourth quarter earnings that met the Street's consensus expectations, but disappointed investors hoping for an upside surprise.</p>
<p>-- E. Auchard, New York newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
