<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670316" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Technology stock likely won't flag in second half.</title>
<headline>Technology stock likely won't flag in second half.</headline>
<byline>Kourosh Karimkhany</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Don't panic.</p>
<p>That's what computer industry executives told investors Wednesday after a new round of warnings about weak earnings sent technology stocks plummeting.</p>
<p>Even though key companies such as Intel Corp. and Seagate Technology Inc. will have lower-than-expected profits in the second quarter, most of the computer industry will continue to see strong growth in the second half of the year, executives said.</p>
<p>Plenty of companies still need new personal computers to run a new generation of software, a majority of U.S. households do not yet have PCs and the U.S. economy is not expected to slow down before the end of the year, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;People who are strong in the industry are getting stronger,&quot; said Jim Halpin, chief executive of CompUSA Inc., one of the biggest retailers of PCs and software. &quot;We're pleased with our own business.&quot;</p>
<p>Added Kevin Rollins, president of Dell Computer Corp.'s America operation: &quot;You can't say just because Intel is slowing, the PC companies are doing poorly.&quot;</p>
<p>After the market closed Tuesday, Seagate, the world's biggest maker of computer disk drives, said its June quarter results will be even worse than the company warned they would be two weeks ago.</p>
<p>In addition, Gateway 2000 Inc., the fifth-biggest U.S. PC maker, said it will report second-quarter revenues that were &quot;basically flat&quot; compared with the $1.42 billion reported in the first quarter.</p>
<p>The warnings came two weeks after Intel, the world's biggest chip maker and a bellwether for the whole industry, said its second-quarter earnings will be less than Wall Street estimates.</p>
<p>The bad news hammered technology stocks Wednesday. Seagate fell $5.25 to $36.25 and Gateway fell $1.75 to $32, both in consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange. Intel slipped $3.0625 to $146.625 on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp. declined 87.5 cents to $89 on the NYSE and Microsoft Corp. fell $4 to $130.1875 on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>Investors were particulary concerned about this round of profit warnings because key companies in each hardware niche -- semiconductors, disk drives, networking gear and PCs -- have warned of disappointing earnings, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our sense is that some slowing is likely,&quot; said Neil Hokanson, president of investment management firm Hokanson Financial Management. &quot;But slow in this business still means double-digit growth.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he probably will buy more shares of the stronger companies, such as Dell, Intel and No. 1 PC maker Compaq Computer Corp.</p>
<p>Even some of the companies that warned about slowing business this quarter said they expect better days.</p>
<p>&quot;We see a softness in the marketplace. ... But I don't see it as a trend going into the second half,&quot; said Beny Alagem, chairman of No. 2 U.S. PC maker Packard Bell NEC Inc.</p>
<p>Gateway also said it expects business to pick up by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Still, an investment in any old technology company is not a sure bet anymore, said Bill Schaff, chief investment officer of money management firm Bay Isle Financial in San Francisco.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to be much more company-specific going forward,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
