<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670566" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Gateway volatility drops.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Gateway volatility drops.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatility in Gateway 2000 Inc options dropped sharply as the stock recovered from an early drop to trade higher in afternoon action, traders said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Late Tuesday, the computer maker said it expected second quarter revenues to be about flat with the first quarter and attributed the outlook to weaker-than-expected demand early in the quarter.</p>
<p>Gateway shares, which fell to 29-5/8 in after hours trading Tuesday, were up 1-5/8 at 31-7/8 on 7.65 million shares in consolidated trading Wednesday afternoon.  </p>
<p>In New York Stock Exchange trading, Gateway was down 2-7/8 at 31-7/8 after falling to 30-3/4 off the opening. Turnover topped 5.45 million shares.</p>
<p>One options trader in Chicago said his firm had traded a good deal of Gateway options, with order flows fairly balanced between calls and puts.</p>
<p>He added that some investors were exiting June positions and rolling out to July and farther-dated options. The June series expires at the end of the week.  </p>
<p>&quot;What's happening is volatility's starting to decline,&quot; said a Gateway options market maker at the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE). &quot;A lot of news has been out over the last few days and the stock has been very volatile.&quot;</p>
<p>He said volatilities in Gateway options, which typically hover around the 60 area, had spiked toward 90 recently but were now back down to around 65.</p>
<p>&quot;The anticipation is for less volatile times in the near future,&quot; the market maker said. &quot;So we have option sellers.&quot;</p>
<p>The most active Gateway option was the June 35 put, which traded 4,000 contracts all on the Pacific Exchange (PCX).  </p>
<p>After that, the July 35 call was most active, with total volume of about 2,775 contracts. The June 32-1/2 call traded 1,550 and the June 30 put traded 1,375. The June 30 call traded roughly 1,315 contracts.</p>
<p>Gateway options trade on the CBOE, the PCX and the American Stock Exchange (AMEX).</p>
<p>In other trading, volatility in Oracle Corp also declined after the software company reported fiscal fourth quarter earnings late Tuesday, traders said.</p>
<p>Oracle shares were down 2-15/16 at 50-5/16 on turnover of more than 10 million shares in late action.  </p>
<p>Traders said Oracle's $0.54 per share profits were in line with most estimates but fell short of optimistic forecasts.</p>
<p>Pat Hickey at LETCO in Chicago said volatilities in the June and July series declined significantly after the earnings.</p>
<p>One model showed June and July volatilities ranging from the low 40s to about 60.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not really seeing any kind of directional paper,&quot; he said of options activity. He added that trading was relatively quiet Tuesday also, with no large bets on whether the earnings would be bullish or bearish for the stock.</p>
<p>((Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
