<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670959" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gateway, Seagate warn about quarterly results.</title>
<headline>Gateway, Seagate warn about quarterly results.</headline>
<byline>Jerry Dubrowski</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gateway 2000 Inc. and Seagate Technology Inc., two key computer industry companies, warned Tuesday their quarterly results would fall below expectations due to lackluster demand.</p>
<p>Gateway, a direct marketer of personal computers, said it expects revenues for the second quarter to be about flat with the first quarter's level of $1.42 billion. In the year-ago second quarter, Gateway reported a profit of $51 million, or 66 cents a share, on revenues of $1.14 billion.</p>
<p>The North Sioux City, S.D.-based computer maker attributed the revenue outlook to weaker-than-expected demand earlier in the second quarter. While demand has picked up somewhat in recent weeks, the company said it would not be enough to meet analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though the second quarter is weaker than what we would have anticipated, we continue to feel very good about our competitive position heading into the last half of the year, the period that historically accounts for the biggest percentage of our business,&quot; Gateway Chairman Ted Waitt said in a statement.</p>
<p>Gateway said operating expenses for the quarter were running higher than analysts' expectations, mainly as a result of investments to provide support for the anticipated strong sales in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>Gateway's forecast came as another key computer component maker was warning analysts it would also post weaker-than-expected results.</p>
<p>Seagate, the leading maker of computer disk drives, issued its second earnings forecast in two weeks, telling investors revenues for the quarter ended June 27 were now expected to be between $2.0 billion and $2.1 billion. The company also warned that weak demand for high-end products and some internal production issues would result in a &quot;significant impact&quot; on earnings.</p>
<p>On June 2, Seagate said fourth-quarter operating earnings were likely to fall short of its third-quarter profits of $1.01 a share. In its revised outlook, the company did not provide a specific range for earnings.</p>
<p>According to First Call, which monitors earnings expectations, analysts on average had expected Seagate to report a fourth-quarter operating profit of 94 cents a share.</p>
<p>In the year-ago quarter, Seagate reported a profit of $101 million, or 84 cents per fully diluted share, on revenues of $2.0 billion. The year-ago earnings-per-share figures were before a 2-for-1 stock split.</p>
<p>The warnings from Seagate and Gateway 2000 sent a chill down Wall Street. Gateway 2000 traded down to $29.625 in after-hours trade from its earlier close of $34.75 on the New York Stock Exchange. Seagate was halted before its news came out.</p>
<p>Industry experts said the news could hurt other technology stocks Wednesday as investors fear the personal computer business is experiencing a slowdown.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow is shaping up to be a bad day for tech stocks,&quot; one trader said, adding database software giant Oracle Corp. could also come under pressure after the company's fourth-quarter profits failed to exceed analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>Oracle reported a fiscal fourth-quarter profit of $359.9 million, or 54 cents a share, on sales of $1.95 billion. That compared with a profit of $266.3 million, or 40 cents a share, a year ago on sales of $1.46 billion.</p>
<p>The fourth-quarter profit met Wall Street's consensus estimate of 54 cents, disappointing some investors who had expected slightly higher profits. In after-hours trade, shares of Oracle fell $2 to $53.25.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
