<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="671109" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oracle fourth-quarter earnings surge on strong sales.</title>
<headline>Oracle fourth-quarter earnings surge on strong sales.</headline>
<dateline>REDWOOD SHORES, Calif. 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oracle Corp. said Tuesday its fiscal fourth-quarter earnings rose 35 percent, close to Wall Street expectations, on strong sales of its database software and applications.</p>
<p>Oracle, the second-biggest software company after Microsoft Corp., said net income for the quarter ended May 31 rose to $359.9 million, or 54 cents a share, from $266.3 million, or 40 cents a share, in the same quarter a year ago. Revenue rose 33 percent to $1.95 billion from $1.46 billion.</p>
<p>Oracle's earnings -- which were released after the market closed -- matched Wall Street's consensus forecast of 54 cents a share, according to a recent analyst survey by Zacks Investment Research.</p>
<p>Oracle's shares closed up 94 cents at $53.25, an all-time high, on Nasdaq. But the shares slipped as low as $51.25 in after-hours trading, partly because the results did not exceed more optimistic forecasts, analysts said.</p>
<p>Oracle, based in Redwood Shores, Calif., specializes in writing database software, the computer programs that big companies use to store heaps of vital information, such as financial records, inventory lists and customer names.</p>
<p>The company also writes financial and manufacturing applications that help managers sort through the information to run day-to-day operations.</p>
<p>Revenue from sales of database products rose 26 percent in the quarter, Oracle said. Revenue from the applications business rose 78 percent.</p>
<p>The company also had strong sales across all geographic regions.</p>
<p>&quot;We're real pleased with the quarter because we had an awesome fourth quarter last year,&quot; said Oracle Chief Financial Officer Jeff Henley. &quot;I'm always concerned when we have to do a tough comparison with a strong quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>The company is also about to ship Oracle 8, a new version of its flagship database product. Henley said the new product puts Oracle in a strong position in the new fiscal year.</p>
<p>For the fiscal year, Oracle's profit from operations rose 33 percent to $845 million, or $1.26 a share, compared with $636 million, or 95 cents, in the previous year.</p>
<p>Sales for the year rose 35 percent to $5.68 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="REDWOOD SHORES, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
