<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67727" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PSINet to build European Internet network.</title>
<headline>PSINet to build European Internet network.</headline>
<dateline>HERNDON, Va. 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>PSINet Inc., a commercial Internet service provider, said Friday it plans to build a $100 million Internet network across Europe and begin offering related services in mid-1997.</p>
<p>The Herndon, Va.-based company said its partner in the joint venture is an investment group led by Chatterjee Group, an affiliate of investor George Soros' Soros Fund Management.</p>
<p>The project, called PSINet Europe, will eventually be integrated with PSINet's existing European operations, including PSINet UK Ltd.</p>
<p>PSINet will provide the project with all of its Internet networking expertise and its intellectual property developed within the United States. PSINet said it will take four years to build the infrastructure needed to reach all its targeted European markets.</p>
<p>PSINet is also planning to contribute its equity and operating interests in its Amsterdam, Netherland-based operation, World Online. Partners in World Online include the Audax, B.V. publishers, De Vereniging TROS communications, and NS Telecom, B.V.</p>
<p>With these plans, a single PSINet product line will be available across Europe, in addition to the United States, Canada, Japan and Korea, it said.</p>
<p>The Chatterjee Group is an active investor in the telecommunications industry worldwide, with more than $1 billion under management. It serves as an investment adviser to Soros Fund Management, principal investment adviser to the Quantum Group of Funds, to George Soros as an individual investor, and to the Winston Partners Funds.</p>
<p>PSINet's stock rose 37.5 cents to $12.375 on Nasdaq at mid-morning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HERNDON, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
