<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="683236" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Digital to integrate AltaVista Internet unit.</title>
<headline>Digital to integrate AltaVista Internet unit.</headline>
<dateline>MAYNARD, Mass. 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computer maker Digital Equipment Corp. Tuesday announced a change in plans for its AltaVista Internet software company, saying it will integrate the unit with its other businesses instead of spinning it off.</p>
<p>Digital said last August that it would spin off as much as 20 percent of AltaVista, which offers one of the Internet's most powerful search engines or catalogues of Internet content.</p>
<p>But Digital Chief Executive Robert Palmer said Tuesday that under the company's new corporate structure of integrated business units, which takes effect July 1, it made more sense to keep AltaVista and leverage its brand name.</p>
<p>&quot;Digital's new organisation emphasises solutions and the synergies between our product and service business,&quot; he said in a statement. &quot;To achieve this kind of integration that customers value, it is more appropriate to take advantage of the AltaVista brand and technology as part of Digital's overall product portfolio.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said AltaVista has been one of the few strong growth areas for the troubled Maynard, Mass.-based company, which has recently suffered lackluster sales of its Alpha microprocessor-based systems.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not at all surprised they are not going to spin it off,&quot; said William Milton, an analyst with Brown Brothers Harriman. &quot;It may be one of the few businesses that's growing there. It's been a well-received service.&quot;</p>
<p>Digital stock gained 62.5 cents to $36 in consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAYNARD, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
