<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684944" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP potential seen even after stock rise.</title>
<headline>SAP potential seen even after stock rise.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software developer SAP AG, after seeing contracts with major mutlinational companies push up its share price 10 percent in the last five trading days, still had potential to climb another 10 to 20 percent in the next two to three quarters, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;If business goes well and increases they way they expect, there should be no problem for the stock to go further,&quot; said Hans-Peter Wodniok at Credit Lyonnais in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>SAP shares closed bourse trading on Monday at 348 marks, up two marks from the end of the previous week, and up 29.70 marks from June 17. At the same time, Germany's blue-chip DAX index rose 13.24 points, less than one percent, to 3,754.72.</p>
<p>&quot;It could eventually get to 400 in the next six or eight months,&quot; Wodniok said.</p>
<p>Wodniok attributed SAP's recent rise to deals the company signed in the last two weeks with Hewlett-Packard Co. Volkswagen AG, and Daimler-Benz AG.</p>
<p>On June 9, Volkswagen selected HP to install a global bill of materials system using SAP's R/3 software. On June 17, Daimler, which already uses R/3 worldwide, decided to add a contract for finance and controlling applications. The pact was worth a &quot;high double-digit million&quot; mark sum, SAP said.</p>
<p>&quot;The impact of those contracts was probably the main factor (in the share price rise),&quot; Wodniok said.</p>
<p>High expectations for SAP's first-half results on July 24 and favourable currency rates probably also helped the share, he said.</p>
<p>Wodniok expected SAP to show a first-half sales rise of 40 percent and a higher increase in orders of 45 percent, &quot;and possibly even 50 percent.&quot; He forecast a 45 percent rise in first-half pretax profit.</p>
<p>In the first-half of 1996, SAP's sales rose 38 percent to 1.59 billion marks while operating profit soared 60 percent to 374 million marks.</p>
<p>Last year's first-half results were followed by a disappointing third quarter that caused SAP shares to tumble 23 percent within hours, and later led to suspicions of insider trading. An investigation on those allegations is continuing.</p>
<p>-- Neal Boudette, Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
