<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686033" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Microsoft unveils Japanese version of Windows CE.</title>
<headline>Microsoft unveils Japanese version of Windows CE.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp on Wednesday unveiled the Japanese version of the Windows CE operating system for handheld personal computers.</p>
<p>The Japanese version of Windows CE, built for use in non-desktop handheld devices and mobile computing, will run on the new line of handheld computers unveiled by Japanese computer manufacturers NEC Corp and Casio Computer Co Ltd.</p>
<p>The English version was launched in the United States in November last year, Microsoft said in a statement.</p>
<p>NEC Corp separately announced on Wednesday that it would introduce new models of hand-held computers which run on the Japanese version of Windows CE. NEC's MC-CS11 will be launched on July 18 and is priced at 73,000 yen. The other model, MC-CS12, will be put on the market on August 28 and is priced at 89,000 yen.</p>
<p>Casio also unveiled similar hand-held computers which feature the Japanese version of Windows CE.</p>
<p>Casio's Cassiopeia A-50 will be priced at 75,000 yen and A-51 at 88,000 yen, and will be on sale from July 10, the company said on Wednesday. -- Tokyo Equities Desk +81-3-3432-9404</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
