<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69732" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Micrografx sees Q1 eps at $0.02 to $0.04.</title>
<headline>Micrografx sees Q1 eps at $0.02 to $0.04.</headline>
<dateline>RICHARDON, Texas 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Micrografx Inc said on Monday it expected net earnings for the first quarter ending September 30 to be $0.02 to $0.04 per share, because of non-recurring restructuring expenses.</p>
<p>Analysts had estimated the company would earn $0.09 per share in the quarter, the company said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Non-recurring costs related to domestic and European organization changes were expected to hurt the first quarter, it said.</p>
<p>Revenues were expected to be in the $16 million to $17 million range, against $15.7 million in the same period last year and analysts estimates of $17.5 million, it said.</p>
<p>Micrografx also said it estimated second quarter revenues would be 85 percent to 90 percent of second quarter restated revenues last year.</p>
<p>Third and fourth quarter revenues were expected to be well above the same period last year, it said.  </p>
<p>Micrografx said it had revenues of $20.3 million in the second quarter 1996, $17.4 million in the third quarter 1996 and $16.7 million in the fourth quarter 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased by the channel's response to American Greetings CreataCard Plus, announced earlier this month,&quot; Chairman and Chief Executive Officer J. Paul Grayson said in a statement. &quot;Compared with our greeting card software launch last year, we're in 2,500 more stores and the stocking orders have increased by 130 percent, which reflects increased confidence by retailers in the product and the category.&quot;  </p>
<p>Grayson also said the company had decided to shift the release of its next cycle of business software until the firscal third quarter 1997, after the Christmas selling season.</p>
<p>&quot;This year we expect to release a number of major business products in the quarter ending March, including: Micrografx Graphics Suite 2, Micrografx FlowCharter 7, an innovative new graphics solution for the Internet and a revolutionary 3D product from our Visual Software acquisition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RICHARDON, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
