<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699747" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.S. auto, tech stocks lower in London trade.</title>
<headline>U.S. auto, tech stocks lower in London trade.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. auto and technology stocks were quoted lower in London trading on Tuesday, pointing to a weaker opening on Wall Street, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;With those two sectors under pressure we would be looking for a slightly lower start on the Street,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>A two-day meeting of the Federal Reserve's monetary policy committee (FOMC), due to get under way later on Tuesday, was not expected to raise interest rates.</p>
<p>Yet markets were seen continuing cautious ahead of Thursday's U.S. jobs report, which will give an indication of the pace of growth in the economy in the past month.  </p>
<p>Amid talk of weak used-car prices and rising consumer debt levels, General Motors, Chrysler and Ford shares all dipped as a report in the Wall Street Journal said they were expected to post weak sales for the month of June.</p>
<p>GM was down $3/8 at $55-1/4, Chrysler was down $3/8 at $32-3/8 and Ford nudged $1/8 lower at $37-5/8.</p>
<p>Separately, a warning from chipmaker Cyrix that it expected to post a loss in the second quarter, due to weak demand and pricing pressures from its older-generation microprocessors, depressed other leading technology stocks.  </p>
<p>Intel was down $1/2 at $141-1/8, Motorola dipped $1/4 to $75-3/4 and International Business Machines (IBM) was quoted $1/4 lower at $90.</p>
<p>Also in the technology sector, Microsoft was down $1/2 at $125-7/8 after a press report of a possible bid for broadcaster CBS, owned by Westinghouse which was up $1/4 at $23-3/8, dealers said.</p>
<p>Elsewhwere most of the interest focused on Office Depot and Staples after a judge's decision to grant a preliminary injunction to their $4 billion merger, first announced last September.  </p>
<p>Dealers said both stocks were expected to come under pressure since the two were expected to abandon the merger plan.</p>
<p>U.S. economic reports later on Tuesday include the National Association of Purchasing Managers report for June, expected to show a drop in the purchasing managers' index to 56.4 from 57.1 a month before.</p>
<p>Other indicators include construction spending and lead indicators for May.</p>
<p>Yet investors were seen more likely to be waiting for Thursday's nonfarm payrolls -- brought forward from thier usual Friday release because of the Independence Day public holiday.  </p>
<p>Recent economic reports have almost unanimously suggested a cooling in the pace of growth and slack inflation pressures. The payroll report will be closely scrutinised for confirmation of this trend.</p>
<p>S&amp;P 500 June futures were trading down 6.25 points at 920.35 by 1105 GMT, after the S&amp;P 500 index on Monday fell 2.16 points to 885.14.</p>
<p>September futures on the 30-year U.S. Treasury bond were up 1/32 at 111-3/32. At Monday's close the benchmark long bond was yielding 6.8 percent.</p>
<p>-- David Holmes, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4367</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
