<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="703318" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Mooted Internet trade pact seen as boon to U.S.</title>
<headline>Mooted Internet trade pact seen as boon to U.S.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton's proposed Internet free trade pact could bring huge benefits to the United States and other powers with a developed software industry, trade diplomats and analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But they said the idea, launched by Clinton on Tuesday with what he said was the aim of creating a &quot;free trade zone&quot; for electronic commerce within a year, was likely to meet a sceptical response from many emerging economies.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a huge potential for expanding trade in items that can be downloaded onto a personal computer from producer to consumer, especially if it were covered by a global agreement exempting it from tariffs,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;From what I can see, the U.S. would be the prime beneficiary since it has the world's most powerful software sector and could quickly dominate a global free market,&quot; said a trade official from a key developing country.</p>
<p>Announcing the initiative at a White House ceremony, Clinton said he had directed U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky to work with the Geneva-based World Trade Organisation (WTO) to get the project off the ground.</p>
<p>WTO sources told Reuters there had been no previous indication from Washington of its ideas, while a U.S. trade official said the United States &quot;has not yet engaged our partners in Geneva on this subject.&quot;</p>
<p>A European Union official said Brussels welcomed any move that might lead to further liberalisation of world trade, but the U.S. plan would need careful study to see how it could be fitted into WTO open trading rules.</p>
<p>The U.S. proposal apparently refers only to items ranging from computer programmes to music and films -- that can be transmitted electronically, and not to goods ordered through the Internet which then have to cross physical borders.</p>
<p>&quot;In a way, this is only recognising the inevitable -- that there are very few ways electronic commerce can be effectively monitored and controlled for customs tariff purposes,&quot; said one trade analyst.</p>
<p>Discussions have been under way for some time at the Brussels-based World Customs Organisation on how products transmitted over the Internet can be evaluated for the levying of tariffs, but have reportedly made little headway.</p>
<p>However, trade sources say many governments, especially in developing countries, are keen to see development of some form of control that could ensure such trade was subject to their tariff regulations.</p>
<p>One way, these sources said, was national supervision of cross-border credit card transactions. Customers buying items over the Internet normally pay for them by providing their credit card number.</p>
<p>With a possible eye to such developments, Clinton said he was directing Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin to negotiate agreements to prevent new taxes on electronic commerce.</p>
<p>Trade diplomats said the U.S. proposal could be launched like the WTO Information Technology Agreement (ITA), which quickly gathered momentum after its launch by the United States late last year and was finalised in March.</p>
<p>Under the ITA, to which 42 countries now subscribe, tariffs on much computer and related hardware will be eliminated by the year 2000. New talks are due at the WTO in October to try to expand the product coverage and the signatory list.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
