<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712195" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP sees Q2 profit growth similar to Q1.</title>
<headline>SAP sees Q2 profit growth similar to Q1.</headline>
<dateline>WALLDORF, Germany 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software group SAP AG said on Monday that profit growth in the second quarter of 1997 would be similar to the 54 percent rise in pretax profit posted in the first three months of the year.</p>
<p>The company also said growth rates in the second half of the year would be slower than the high levels seen in the first half. SAP would give precise first-half results on July 24.  </p>
<p>SAP sees Q2 profit growth similar to Q1</p>
<p>Analysts have expected SAP to report gains in second quarter sales due to the strong dollar and a string of major contracts with global companies including Volkswagen AG and Daimler-Benz AG.</p>
<p>Since June 10, SAP shares have climbed more than 50 marks, or more than 15 percent, and closed bourse trading last Friday at 378.50 marks. In the same period the German DAX index has risen 7.5 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts last week said SAP shares could reach 400 marks within six to eight months.</p>
<p>SAP's first-quarter sales rose 49 percent to 1.032 billion marks, boosted some 55 million marks by favourable exchange rates as the dollar appreciated from 1.54 marks at the beginning of the year to 1.67 at the end of the first quarter.</p>
<p>The dollar has traded at about 1.70 marks for most of the second quarter.</p>
<p>-- Neal Boudette, Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WALLDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
