<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712334" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Big trades in Bay, Republic.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Big trades in Bay, Republic.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A big spread crossed in options on shares of Bay Networks Inc and an institutional investor placed a sizable bullish bet in Republic Industries Inc, options traders said Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Bay Networks July 22-1/2 call and August 22-1/2 call each traded about 11,900 contracts.</p>
<p>Jon Najarian, president of Mercury Trading, the designated primary market maker in Bay Network options, said an institution rolled the July position out to August for a customer.  </p>
<p>In afternoon trading, Bay Network shares were up 9/16 at 27-3/4.</p>
<p>In Republic Industries, an institutional investor bought 6,000 January 2000 20 puts and sold 6,000 January 2000 30 calls, a market maker said. He added that the investor also bought 480,000 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a real bullish, real bullish trade,&quot; he said, adding that the investor appears to be growing bullish on Republic's plan to buy auto dealerships and rental agencies.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Republic said it agreed to acquire Snappy Car Rental Inc of Tulsa, Okla. for $26 million in cash or stock.  </p>
<p>The market maker said interest in Republic options has been increasing recently but that Tuesday's action in the long term options appeared to come from a new investor.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this is a new bet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In other activity, traders said investors were lining up positions ahead of second quarter earnings reports, which are beginning to trickle in. The onslaught of earnings begins next week.</p>
<p>Among the first key companies to report is Motorola Inc, which is scheduled to release second quarter numbers after the close of trading Tuesday.  </p>
<p>In late action, Motorola shares were up 1-1/4 at 81-5/8.</p>
<p>Among the Motorola options, the July 85 call traded nearly 4,300 contracts and the July 80 call traded more than 4,100.</p>
<p>The Motorola calls were busy out to the January series, where the 70 strike option traded 1,115 contracts and the 60 strike traded 1,045.</p>
<p>On the put side, the July 80 traded about 4,200 contracts and the July 75 traded 3,760.</p>
<p>According to First Call, analysts' consensus estimate for Motorola's second quarter is $0.56 a share, up from $0.54 last year. The estimate excludes a $170 million charge.  </p>
<p>One options analyst said put volume in PairGain Technologies Inc was particularly heavy Monday ahead of its earnings Wednesday, which suggested some investors were betting on disappointing numbers.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the stock was up 2 at 17-7/8 in active trading.</p>
<p>Among the options, the July 15 put was most active, with turnover of 1,355 contracts. The July 17-1/2 call traded nearly 1,300 contracts and the July 20 call traded 760. The July 17-1/2 and 22-1/2 put each traded well over 600 contracts.</p>
<p>((Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
