<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716567" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Citicorp stake boosts MECA software pact.</title>
<headline>Citicorp stake boosts MECA software pact.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The MECA software alliance of some key players in North American financial services got a big boost Wednesday with the announcement that Citibank, the second-largest U.S. bank, was joining the group.</p>
<p>Financial terms were not disclosed. A spokeswoman for MECA Software LLC said the agreement calls for Citibank, a unit of Citicorp, to make a cash outlay. A Citibank spokesman declined to provide any figures.</p>
<p>Including Citibank, the group will consist of five U.S. banks, Royal Bank of Canada and The New England, an insurance affiliate of Metropolitan Life Insurance Co.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the things that attracted us to MECA is that they have shown a willingness to be a content provider for branded financial services,&quot; Citibank spokeman John Morris said. &quot;We look to them for integrating and enhancing our products.&quot;</p>
<p>Explaining the difference between MECA and other home banking products such as Microsoft Corp's Microsoft Money, MECA spokeswoman Melissa Krantz said &quot;our paradigm is very different from theirs. Ours is bank and financial institution-specific software. Software and the communication is developed by MECA with the bank and is brandable and customizable.&quot;</p>
<p>MECA develops electronic banking products that use the Internet or private networks.</p>
<p>Morris said by joining the alliance, Citicorp was not changing its strategy in technology. &quot;I think in the past half dozen years we've been conspicuous in our partnering on technology,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He noted that Citibank offers customers Intuit Inc's Quicken banking service in addition to its proprietary products. While Citibank does not offers it customers the Microsoft Money product, it is an adviser to a bill payment service recently announced as a joint venture by Microsoft and First Data Corp.</p>
<p>Krantz declined to say if the seven MECA partners own equal shares in the alliance. Citicorp's purchase of a stake is subject to regulatory approval.</p>
<p>Asked if any Citibank employees would be affected, Morris said &quot;not at all.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition to Citibank, Royal Bank of Canada and The New England, other owners of MECA are BankAmerica Corp, NationsBank Corp, First Bank System Inc and Fleet Financial Group Inc.</p>
<p>((--Cal Mankowski/New York Newsdesk/212 859 1732))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
