<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722855" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft treasurer Greg Maffei to become CFO.</title>
<headline>Microsoft treasurer Greg Maffei to become CFO.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. Treasurer Greg Maffei will become chief financial officer effective July 24, succeeding Mike Brown, who will retire at the end of the year, the software giant said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Maffei, 37, joined Microsoft in 1993 and as treasurer has been responsible for managing the company's giant cash hoard, which had grown to more than $9 billion by the end of the last reported quarter.</p>
<p>Since last year Maffei has served as vice president of corporate development, engineering a wave of purchases large and small culminating with the company's $1 billion investment in Comcast Corp. last month, its biggest deal ever.</p>
<p>&quot;This ought to be a very easy transition,&quot; Microsoft Chief Operating Officer Bob Herbold said in an interview, noting that Maffei had taken on Brown's responsibilities for the company's budgeting organization last year.</p>
<p>Maffei is a familiar figure to Wall Street analysts and investors and frequently has served as a stand-in for Brown, whose retirement had been rumored.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's going to likely be a very smooth transition,&quot; Montgomery Securities analyst David Readerman said. &quot;I've been working with Greg Maffei for a long time. I think he has a lot of credibility with Wall Street.&quot;</p>
<p>Brown, 51, joined Microsoft in 1989 but had worked with the company since 1979 as a partner at the public accounting firm of Deloitte &amp; Touche. He was a key member of the team that brought Microsoft public in its celebrated 1986 initial stock offering.</p>
<p>&quot;Mike helped lead the company through many important financial achievements -- our initial public offering, the development of global financial systems and our growth to $10 billion of revenue,&quot; Microsoft Chairman Bill Gates said in a statement.</p>
<p>In his remaining months with the company, Brown will work on several projects, including an effort to promote more conservative accounting in the industry, Microsoft said.</p>
<p>He also will devote time to his role as chairman of the board of the Nasdaq stock market, Microsoft said.</p>
<p>In retirement, he plans to spend more time sailing his 50-foot yacht and will remain active in financial standards groups, Herbold said.</p>
<p>Maffei, who has an undergraduate degree from Dartmouth College and a master's degree from Harvard Business School, worked for Citicorp and for an investment firm before joining Microsoft.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
