<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723679" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE-Drugs software, steam age meet in Oxford.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Drugs software, steam age meet in Oxford.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Birt</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 60 years and a technological chasm separate the heyday of Britain's steam locomotives in the 1930s and the information technology revolution of the 1990s.</p>
<p>But a fortune made from the latter has allowed Oxford Molecular Group Plc boss Tony Marchington to bridge the gulf, funding the purchase of the famous Flying Scotsman engine, which pulled trains from London to Edinburgh, and the planned rescue of a scenic railway in the Peak District of central England.</p>
<p>The money for indulging such romantic passions has come from Marchington's hard-headed recognition of the drug industry's desperate need for specially-created information technology (I.T.) to process a deluge of information which threatens to drown researchers.</p>
<p>After a fallow period for new discoveries, breakneck progress in areas like human gene and protein sequencing means researchers cannot keep up. &quot;Companies can get data now much quicker than they can analyse it. That's why they are screaming for I.T,&quot; said Marchington.</p>
<p>And in a so-far smaller but potentially hugely profitable move, OM is also aiming to exploit the shift by large pharmaceutical companies to farm out early-stage research to contain costs and maximise returns.</p>
<p>MULTINATIONAL GROWS FROM SMALL HUT</p>
<p>With high-profile customers like Britain's Glaxo Wellcome Plc and Sweden's Astra AB already signed up for its software skills, Marchington is confident both businesses are ready to soar.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters he predicted annual sales of between 500 and 600 million pounds ($840 million and $1 billion) in the next five to 12 years from less than 10 million last year. &quot;I can't tell you when we'll get there, but I can tell we'll get there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Oxford Molecular has grown from a small hut on the Oxford University science campus in 1989 to a multi-national operation with subsidiaries in Europe and the dominant U.S. market, where it has acquired a string of niche I.T. players and has more than 90 staff.</p>
<p>A similar number now work on a brand new Science Park on the fringes of Oxford, in cool open-plan offices where smoking and alcohol are banned and all employees, from Marchington down, are expected to work with a personal fitness trainer twice a week to monitor their health and mental agility.</p>
<p>Marchington believes that single-mindedness has made Oxford Molecular a world leader in the rapidly-emerging sector of drug-development software, with no single competitor able to match its broad range of skills.</p>
<p>&quot;We are one of the few companies in Britain you can point to and say they are leading the world in what they are doing. That is a very exclusive club,&quot; said Marchington. His driving confidence has been backed with varying enthusiasm by the stock market, which currently values Oxford Molecular at more than 160 million pounds, though it has yet to turn in a profit.</p>
<p>SOFTWARE THE GLUE OF FUTURE DRUG DISCOVERY</p>
<p>&quot;I.T. is in its infancy in drug discovery but it is clear it will be the glue that holds all future drug discovery together,&quot; said Marchington, who estimated the market for such technology will rise rapidly to one billion pounds a year, and could be double this.</p>
<p>Oxford Molecular's most powerful supporter has been Britain's Glaxo Wellcome. Glaxo supported the start-up company financially and has awarded it a multi-million dollar contract to create a system allowing its 3,000 researchers around the world to access, analyse and exchange data on one screen, replacing a plethora of incompatible systems and databases.</p>
<p>The results will be available to other drug companies. Sweden's Astra AB has already signed up for a similar network, and Oxford Molecular told Reuters another big name announcement was &quot;imminent&quot;.</p>
<p>Astra said the fledgling company &quot;currently has the most-user friendly software on the market for biologists,&quot; while Glaxo head of research and development I.T. Philip Loftus said it had clearly understood Glaxo's needs and come up with a solution.</p>
<p>Marchington said he wanted a 25 percent share of the global I.T. drug market. And he is equally determined to profit from the drive by big pharma groups to use external researchers for early-stage work to identify disease targets and potential new drugs.</p>
<p>CONTRACT RESEARCH PROMISES HUGE PROFITS</p>
<p>Although it will account for only one-fifth of an estimated 20 million pounds of sales this year, Marchington believes contract research could be &quot;at least as big as I.T,&quot; not least because of staggeringly high margins, which mean half of every million pound contract is pure profit.</p>
<p>If research comes up with results, Oxford Molecular will expect milestone payments and royalties of three to seven percent of any sales. So far nine projects are under management and it wants to add four every year.</p>
<p>In February it took a 20 percent stake in a new company, Cambridge Combinatorial, allowing it to offer customers libraries of chemical molecules, and has plans for a high-speed drug molecule screening service.</p>
<p>Despite knowing where the company is heading, Marchington is irritated by a failure amongst others to understand what Oxford Molecular is about. In the spirit of someone passionate about both steam trains and computers, he hates being put into a compartment labelled &quot;biotech&quot; or &quot;information technology&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;People try to box us, and there is no box for Oxford Molecular yet. We're a new type of business offering a new type of service,&quot; he said. ($ = 0.593 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
