<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72785" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: NIIT sees huge expansion in SE Asia.</title>
<headline>NIIT sees huge expansion in SE Asia.</headline>
<byline>Angela Tan</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top Indian technology and computer education company NIIT Ltd sees no slowdown in the software business and plans a tenfold increase in its Southeast Asian turnover, senior officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not see a slowdown in the software sector..If anything, with Internet, there has been a rapid ramp up of that sector,&quot; Rahul Patwardhan, president of NIIT ASEAN, told a news conference.</p>
<p>Patwardhan said many companies, especially in ASEAN -- the Association of Southeast Asian Nations grouping Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam -- did not have the software to supply demand.</p>
<p>&quot;In the next two years, most software companies worldwide will be so hardpressed to cater to these opportunities. This is the area we will focus on,&quot; Patwardhan said.</p>
<p>Vijay Thadani, president and chief executive officer of NIIT Ltd, said the company had &quot;a four pronged strategy for growth (that) includes a tenfold rise in turnover in the next four years&quot;.</p>
<p>Thadani said the implementation of this expansion plan would propel NIIT's ASEAN turnover to over S$100 million (US$71 million) by September 1998 and over Singapore $500 million by the turn of the century.</p>
<p>The company hoped turnover would more than double to S$50 million in the region next year from S$20 million now, he said.</p>
<p>The strategy included setting up a dedicated division to cater to the systems integration needs of the government sector in Singapore and a specialised information technology manufacturing solutions group for the Asia Pacific region.</p>
<p>It also included setting up research and development centre for software and education in Singapore, would be responsible for supporting all ASEAN operations, Thadani said.</p>
<p>NIIT also launched Netvarsity, a cyber learning facility on the Internet which NIIT hoped to target the 50 million Internet users in the developed world, said research vice president Sugata Mitra.</p>
<p>Thadani said he was optimistic about the growth prospects of professional services in ASEAN, which he estimated would see an annual growth of 20 to 35 percent, depending on the country.</p>
<p>&quot;The systems integration component for some countries in the region is as high as 40 percent,&quot; Thadani added.</p>
<p>Patwardhan said NIIT had budgeted about S$0.5 million in the coming year for its research and development in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;To support our aim to achieve a turnover of S$50 million in the region, we definitely have to spend S$4 to S$5 million on fresh investment in non-working capital areas like hardware, software and in facilities and so on,&quot; Patwardhan said.</p>
<p>NIIT, which belongs to the HCL Group, has annual sales of over S$125 million through its operations and subsidiaries in over 15 countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
