<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732738" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intel, Microsoft stocks surge.</title>
<headline>Intel, Microsoft stocks surge.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stock in Intel Corp. soared to new highs Wednesday as Wall Street analysts said its second-quarter results showed Intel is powering through a major product shift.</p>
<p>The stock of software giant Microsoft Corp., which is expected to report its latest earnings Thursday, also jumped.</p>
<p>Intel reported late Tuesday that its second-quarter profits jumped 58 percent to $1.6 billion, or 92 cents a share, in the three months ended in June. That was slightly ahead of Wall Street's muted expectations for a profit of 90 cents a share.</p>
<p>Intel's stock jumped as high as $86.94 in early trading, exceeding its previous high of $84.875. It was at $86.375 on Nasdaq at midday.</p>
<p>Microsoft climbed to $146.875 in the morning and traded at $146.125, up $7.66, well above its previous peak of $139.25 on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>Several Wall Street analysts renewed their &quot;buy&quot; ratings on Intel, saying the dominant supplier of microprocessors for personal computers is successfully shifting to next-generation products that use its new MMX multimedia technology.</p>
<p>Intel Chied Executive Andrew Grove said in a statement accompanying its results that demand for the new products is strong and the company is shifting production to its newest computer chips &quot;at a record rate.&quot;</p>
<p>Intel, based in Santa Clara, Calif., is benefiting from its own success in generating demand for its newest chips. But it has had to scramble to shift production since customer demand for the new chips shifted more rapidly than it had expected.</p>
<p>Intel executives said the company stopped making silicon wafers for its older Pentium models and is introducing production of new, denser and more cost-effective designs ahead of schedule.</p>
<p>As expected, several analysts pared their third-quarter and full-year earnings estimates for Intel, based on expectations for sequentially flat earnings per share after Intel said it expects third-quarter revenues to be flat to only slightly higher than the $6.0 billion it reported for the second quarter.</p>
<p>But analysts said investors were focusing on the prospect that Intel will sustain its earnings levels despite expectations it will make deep cuts in the prices of existing chips later this month.</p>
<p>PaineWebber analyst John Lazlo said in a market note that Intel was poised to produce a substantial increase in revenues and profits in the fourth quarter, followed by 20 percent to 25 percent earnings growth over the next several years.</p>
<p>Intel's microprocessors power at least 80 percent of world's PCs, and Lazlo said the rapid shift in customer demand to new processors may help Intel use its market dominance and financial strength to limit incursions by rivals like Advanced Micro Devices Inc. and Cyrix Corp.</p>
<p>More importantly in the near term, analysts said Intel should be hitting full stride in its manufacturing of the new-generation processors in the fourth quarter, traditionally the strongest period of the year for the PC industry.</p>
<p>Robert Chaplinsky, an analyst at Hambrecht &amp; Quist, a San Francisco investment bank, said he was confident Intel's business will pick up in the fourth quarter &quot;because basically the product transition issues will be over.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
