<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735876" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft reports 88 percent rise in profits.</title>
<headline>Microsoft reports 88 percent rise in profits.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. Thursday reported an 88 percent rise in its fiscal fourth-quarter profit, in line with expectations, reflecting strong sales of its Windows operating systems and other personal computer software.</p>
<p>The Redmond, Wash.-based software giant earned $1.05 billion, or 80 cents a share, in the three months ended June 30, up from $559 million, or 43 cents a share, in the year-earlier quarter. Revenues rose 41 percent to $3.18 billion from $2.26 billion.</p>
<p>On average, Wall Street analysts had expected Microsoft to report earnings of 79 cents a share, according to First Call.</p>
<p>The quarter capped a year that saw Microsoft profits soar 54 percent to $3.44 billion, or $2.63 a share, from $2.2 billion or $1.71 a share. Revenue rose 31 percent to $11.36 billion from $8.67 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Microsoft has enjoyed two incredible years due to the success of its 32-bit products,&quot; Chief Financial Officer Mike Brown said in a statement. &quot;However, we continue to expect our revenue growth rates to slow down next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Such comments have become a familiar refrain to analysts and investors and others who follow the company.</p>
<p>Industry analysts estimate Microsoft's earnings growth could slow to 20 percent in the year to come, with the company's release schedule devoid of products likely to match the blockbuster performance of past best-sellers like Windows 95 and Office 97.</p>
<p>But investors have turned a deaf ear, bidding up Microsoft stock some 150 percent over the past year. Just this week, the stock has surged 15 percent in anticipation of strong earnings, closing Thursday at a record $149.50 on Nasdaq, up $1.06, before the results were announced.</p>
<p>After the results were announced, the stock fell $3.50 in after-hours trading, traders said.</p>
<p>At current levels, Microsoft's stock is trading at a lofty 47 times next year's projected earnings, and Microsoft officials have gone to great lengths to try to dampen enthusiasm.</p>
<p>But the company consistently beats analysts' expectations, and they say investors are willing to pay a premium for steady, predictable growth in earnings.</p>
<p>In addition, investors are betting that Microsoft's investment in the Internet, including news, entertainment and television, will put it at the hub of the coming &quot;digital convergence&quot; and ultimately lead to a new source of growth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
