<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737857" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore electronic shares rally along with U.S..</title>
<headline>Singapore electronic shares rally along with U.S..</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Electronic shares in Singapore rose swiftly on Thursday morning, spurred by a bull run on Wall Street, dealers said.</p>
<p>At 0330 GMT, the SES electronics index was up 2.68 points, or 1.96 percent, at 139.56 after touching a new year high of 139.76.</p>
<p>Among the stocks fueling the index were multimedia Creative Technology, which hit a three-year high at S$33.20, Electronic Resources, which rose 11 cents to S$2.52 and Flextech Holdings which gained three cents to S$1.83.  </p>
<p>&quot;They are up on Wall Street's bullishness and anticipation that when the U.S. market improves, local firms, especially personal computer-related ones, would benefit from a pick up in orders,&quot; said a dealer with a local dealer said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, U.S. technology stocks surged amid announcements of robust earnings, pushing the Nasdaq up a record 38.52 points to an unofficial close of 1,580.63.</p>
<p>Analysts were optimistic there would be a pickup in the second half of 1997 in Singapore's electronic sector, which accounts for about 58 percent of total domestic exports, after an insipid first half.  </p>
<p>&quot;The second half is looking more positive, particularly with some new orders coming in the third quarter,&quot; said investment analyst Pearly Yap at SocGen Crosby.</p>
<p>Among the stocks recommended were Advanced Systems Automation, Wong's Circuit, Elec &amp; Eltek as well as peripheral stocks like Lung Kee Metals and Thakral.</p>
<p>Yap said there was good value in ASA, which could see a 50 percent earnings growth for the financial year ending March 1998.  </p>
<p>&quot;They have got their own proprietory technology and they are doing well. Orders have picked up,&quot; Yap said.</p>
<p>Flextech, now trading around S$1.83, up three cents, was seen as a trading buy by analysts who are expecting it to rally towards S$2.20 in about three months.</p>
<p>&quot;This is because of the new businesses it is in,&quot; research house Fraser-AMMB said.</p>
<p>Fraser said its acquisitions of two business units of Texas Instruments would impact earnings positively.</p>
<p>-- Angela Tan, Singapore newsroom (65 8703083)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
