<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739629" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft seen lower after merely good Q4.</title>
<headline>Microsoft seen lower after merely good Q4.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Microsoft Corp are expected to open lower on Friday, after the company reported fourth quarter earnings that fell shy of Wall Street's most optimistic expectations for the quarter.</p>
<p>But analysts said Microsoft's earnings, which included a revenue reserve that depressed results for the quarter, were better than a first glance would indicate and weakness in the shares would likely be greeted as a buying opportunity.</p>
<p>Microsoft reported earnings late Thursday of $0.80 per share, up 88 percent from $0.43 a year ago and a penny better than First Call's consensus estimates.  </p>
<p>Even so, analysts said, the market's first response was likely to be disappointment, because expectations had been running extremely high for the quarter, producing a frenzied 20-point runup in the week ahead of Microsoft's results.</p>
<p>Shares in Microsoft fell in after-hours activity late Thursday and slipped lower early today, trading at 143-3/4 in pre-open activity, down from Thursday's close of 149-1/2.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem was two-fold,&quot; said Phil Orland, chief investment officer at Value Line Asset Management. &quot;First, the stock rallied some 20 points in the last week and second, the whisper number was in the neighborhood of $0.85-0.90 a share.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Whisper numbers&quot; refer to unpublished analyst estimates that circulate on Wall Street. The figures often run higher than analysts are comfortable publishing.</p>
<p>While Microsoft missed the whisper number in this case, analysts said the quarter was not nearly as disappointing as it appeared on first glance, due to an accounting tactic Microsoft used that essentially deferred some income.</p>
<p>&quot;It was hardly a terrible quarter,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, market analyst at Prudential Securities. &quot;The company had a contingency reserve of $0.07 per share and if you throw that in, they met the whisper number.&quot;</p>
<p>As a result, analysts said, short-term pressure could present a rare opportunity to buy the stock on the cheap.</p>
<p>&quot;We would use any weakness as an opportunity to accumulate the shares for long-term investor accounts,&quot; Orlando said. &quot;This is going to be a limited impact affair.&quot;</p>
<p>Some on Wall Street did muster sympathy for those whose very impressive recent paper profits stood to go up in smoke, if only temporarily. &quot;I do feel sorry for Bill Gates,&quot; said one trader of Microsoft's billionaire co-founder and chairman. &quot;He only lost two or three billion this morning.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- R. Melville, Wall Street desk, 212-859-1731))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
