<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739613" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Marcam Corp holders approve unit spin-off.</title>
<headline>Marcam Corp holders approve unit spin-off.</headline>
<dateline>NEWTON, Mass. 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marcam Corp said Friday its stockholders approved the previously announced spin-off of Marcam Solutions Inc.</p>
<p>The spin-off will be accomplished through a tax-free distribution to Marcam Corp stockholers of all of the outstanding shares of common stock of Marcam Solutions, the company said.</p>
<p>Marcam Solutions has been formed to continue to conduct the portion of the company's business relating to its Prism, Protean and Avantis product lines, it said.  </p>
<p>In the spin-off, the company's common stockholders will receive one-half of a share of Marcam Solutions common stock for each share of the company's common stock held as of the close of business on July 23, it said.</p>
<p>Also, the company's convertible preferred stockholders will receive five shares of Marcam Solutions common stock for each share of the company's convertible preferred stock held as of the close of business on July 23, it said.</p>
<p>The company said it anticipates that trading in shares of Marcam Solutions common stock will begin on the Nasdaq National Market under the symbol &quot;MRCM&quot; on July 30.</p>
<p>In addition, stockholders approved the change of Marcam Corp's name to Mapics Inc, which is currently expected to become effective on July 29, it said.</p>
<p>After the spin-off, Mapics will continue to conduct the portion of the company's business relating to its Mapics product line, it said.</p>
<p>The company said it anticipates that the trading symbol for the Company's common stock on the Nasdaq National Market will be changed to &quot;MAPX&quot; effective July 30.  The symbol currently is &quot;MCAM.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWTON, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
