<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74582" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Compaq laps Packard-Bell in US retail-survey.</title>
<headline>Compaq laps Packard-Bell in US retail-survey.</headline>
<dateline>LA JOLLA, Calif. 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Compaq Computer Corp became the number-one U.S. retailer of personal computers in July, outpacing Packard Bell Corp for the first time, according to a survey of retailers by Computer Intelligence.</p>
<p>The market research firm's &quot;StoreBoard Channel&quot; survey tracks sales data from PC superstores, consumer electronic stores, and office superstores throughout the United States, outlets that account for about 85 percent of retail PC sales.</p>
<p>It does not cover mass merchants like Wal-Mart, whose sales represent about 15 percent of the U.S. retail market for PCs.  </p>
<p>Traditionally, this market has been dominated by Packard Bell, whose primary focus is U.S. retail sales, as opposed to corporate or direct, mail-order distribution methods.</p>
<p>But Compaq's market share steadily increased throughout the second quarter of 1996, and in July finally surged ahead of the long-time leader.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly, we're now seeing the effects of the PC market shifting to a second-time buyer situation,&quot; said Matt Sargent, a Computer Intelligence industry analyst.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's hurting vendors that cater to low-end, first-time purchasers, while helping those that target second-time buyers, who typically emphasize quality over price and favor premium brands,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although Compaq has long held the title of number one PC supplier overall, its strength lay in corporate and portable PCs, as opposed to retail sales, where consumers predominate.</p>
<p>Packard Bell built up its business using a low-cost retail strategy to become the dominant supplier of PCs via retail distribution in the United States. The strategy made the brand name particularly popular with first-time computer buyers.  </p>
<p>Packard Bell is now owned by Japan's NEC Corp.</p>
<p>The Computer Intelligence study found that market shares for the top four vendors in the overall retail sales have shifted significantly since the first quarter of this year.</p>
<p>The survey showed Compaq held 22.7 percent of overall retail business in July, up from 18.0 percent in February.</p>
<p>By contrast, Packard Bell slid to 17.5 percent in July from 30.1 percent in February, when it was far and away the dominant retail PC supplier.  </p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp and Hewlett-Packard Co also posted impressive gains in recent months, according to the survey data.</p>
<p>IBM rose to 11.7 percent in July from 6.7 percent in February. H-P accounted for 10.6 percent of the product sold in those stores surveyed versus 7.4 percent in February.</p>
<p>It noted that the most dramatic market share gains for Compaq occurred in the consumer electronic stores market segment, causing Packard Bell to lose market share in a distribution channel it had pioneered.  </p>
<p>Compaq nearly doubled its share of the consumer electronics market to 21.2 percent, up from 11.0 percent in February. Packard Bell's share was cut in half to 19.3 percent in July from 41.8 percent five months before.</p>
<p>The shift away from the two previous low-price leaders in this channel, Taiwan's Acer Inc and Packard Bell, seriously hurt the two vendors' overall positions within retail.  </p>
<p>Although Acer does not figure among the top four in overall retail sales, it held third position in the consumer electronics segment, with 15.7 percent in July, about even with its 16.1 percent share in February.</p>
<p>&quot;As if the shift away from first-time buyers weren't enough,&quot; Sargent said. &quot;Compaq went on to challenge Packard Bell's and Acer's price leadership, and actually managed to under-price these vendors in the months of May and June.</p>
<p>&quot;After May, both Packard Bell and Acer responded to the pricing challenge and managed to lower prices just under Compaq's for July,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Computer Intelligence said it expected that Acer and Packard Bell will continue to lose retail market share if Compaq stays as close in price as it has in recent months.</p>
<p>The survey of 1,100 retail sites tracks over the counter sales of computers to consumers.</p>
<p>Computer Intelligence is a unit of Softbank Corp's Ziff-Davis Publishing Co.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LA JOLLA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
