<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747266" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Analysts comfortable SAP will hit Q2 goals.</title>
<headline>Analysts comfortable SAP will hit Q2 goals.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Results of German software group SAP AG, due on Thursday, should avoid unpleasant surprises after its recent forecast of strong second-quarter profit growth, financial analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The company's forecast came out only a few weeks ago, so that should give a pretty good indication of the results,&quot; said Deutsche Morgan Grennfell's Juergen Hackenberg.</p>
<p>Based on SAP's July 7 advisory that profit growth would be similar to the first quarter's 54 percent rate, Credit Lyonnais analyst Hans Peter Wodniok said he expected pretax profit of about 580 million marks for the first half of 1997, up from 374 million marks a year ago.</p>
<p>Pretax profit above 600 million marks would be very positive and could spur SAP shares to another sharp rise, Wodniok said. Anything under 560 million marks would be a disappointment.</p>
<p>Wodniok predicted six-month sales would reach 2.4 billion marks, compared with 1.594 billion in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm looking for a 45 to 50 percent increase in pretax profit in light of their prognosis and the favourable currency situation,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>In the first quarter, currency effects accounted for about 55 million marks, or eight percentage points of its 49 percent rise in sales to 1.032 billion marks.</p>
<p>The company draws about a third of its sales from the U.S. market, where the dollar stands at an eight-year high of 1.80 marks, even higher than the 1.67 rate at the end of the first quarter.</p>
<p>Its shares were trading at 414.50 marks at 1140 GMT, up 9.30, with the blue-chip DAX index showing a gain of around three percent to around 4,230. They have risen 19 percent in the last 30 days as Daimler-Benz AG, Volkswagen AG and Bayer AG signed deals to use SAP's R/3 software in global computer projects.</p>
<p>R/3 allows large companies to control manufacturing, purchasing, personnel and financial data from computers spread throughout their organisations.</p>
<p>The strength of the dollar is likely to enable SAP to exceed its full-year estimates of a sales rise of 30 percent and a profit increase of a few percentage points more, Wodniok said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are forecasting more than 30 percent sales growth and clearly more than 30 percent profit growth because of the currency,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hackenberg predicted 1997 earnings per share of eight marks, up 46 percent from last year's 5.48 marks.</p>
<p>However, SAP shares could still be in for a bumpy if upward ride in the second half, Wodniok said.</p>
<p>Third-quarter results are likely to show large gains compared to a year ago, when SAP reported an unexpected slowdown in sales and profit growth that led to a sharp drop in its share price, he said.</p>
<p>In this year's fourth quarter, growth rates could show much slower growth against the year ago period, when SAP rebounded and returned to dramatic growth rates.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the real question,&quot; Wodniok said. &quot;What will the second half be like?&quot; -- neal.boudette@reuters.com (Bonn =49-228 26097150)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
