<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748365" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IXC Communications, PSINet form alliance.</title>
<headline>IXC Communications, PSINet form alliance.</headline>
<dateline>AUSTIN, Texas 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>IXC Communications Inc said Wednesday it and PSINet Inc. have agreed to form a long-term alliance.</p>
<p>In the agreement, IXC, a supplier of  digital transmission and long distance services in the U.S., will take a 20 percent stake in PSINet, an Internet service provider, it said.  </p>
<p>In return, IXC will provide PSINet 10,000 equivalent route miles on its nationwide fiber optic network for a 20-year term.</p>
<p>IXC said that if the value of the PSINet common stock is less than $240 million at one year after delivery of all of the capacity, PSINet would give IXC cash and or additional stock or both, at PSINet's option, to bring the value to $240 million.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Ralph Swett, IXC's chairman and chief executive officer, will be elected to PSINet's board of directors.  </p>
<p>IXC and PSINet also will enter into a strategic marketing alliance in which each company will sell each other's products and services, giving both companies an expanded line of customer offerings, it said.</p>
<p>Swett said IXC entered into the deal because it wanted to add Internet services to its product portfolio and found that PSINet shared its vision and philosophy.</p>
<p>&quot;For our part, IXC is building its new fiber network based largely on requirements being driven by the Internet, and companies such as PSINet.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>William Schrader, chairman, president, chief executive and founder of PSINet noted that the  new fiber capacity to be provided by IXC is a key component to its ability to meet the big demand for bandwidth and speed.</p>
<p>He said PSINet has been an IXC customer for several years and his company looks forward to a more formal, long-term alliance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUSTIN, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
