<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="750961" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPO VIEW-Summer months fail to deter LSE entrants.</title>
<headline>IPO VIEW-Summer months fail to deter LSE entrants.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The London Stock Exchange (LSE) is expected to welcome a variety of newcomers this week, despite the traditionally slow summer season and recent postponements to some planned flotations.</p>
<p>British clothing designer and retailer Ted Baker Plc makes its debut on the LSE on July 24 following a placing of 19.26 million shares at 135p each.</p>
<p>The company said the placing raised around 26 million stg and capitalised the company at 55.7 million stg.</p>
<p>Ted Baker designs, wholesales and retails fashionable shirts, knitwear, jeans and jackets which are sold in Britain through its seven stores, a concession in Harrods and selected retailers.</p>
<p>The company made operating profits of 4.2 million stg in the year to January 25 1997 and said retail sales in the first 20 weeks of its current financial year rose by more than 25 percent in Britain.</p>
<p>Making their debut on the same day will be shares in video software group Gremlin plc. Gremlin makes games for PC CD Rom, and for dedicated games consoles such as the Sony PlayStation, Sega Saturn and Nintendo 64. The shares have been paced at 159p each.</p>
<p>The company earned pre-tax profits of 2.5 million stg in the nine months to April 30 1997.</p>
<p>Share dealing in pan-European airline owner Debonair Holdings Plc is due to take-off on the new growth stock market EASDAQ on July 24 and the company is expected to be valued at around 100 million stg.</p>
<p>Debonair said it planned to take advantage of the deregulation process in Europe's airline industry and pledged to establish itself as a low fare, &quot;home-based&quot; airline in many European destinations.</p>
<p>The company hopes to raise around 25 million stg from its flotation and the shares have been placed at 450p.</p>
<p>--Andrew Langlands, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4026</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
