<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="751141" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore beefs up fight against software piracy.</title>
<headline>Singapore beefs up fight against software piracy.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Wong</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore intensified its fight against software piracy on Wednesday with the launch of an auditing programme targetted at businesses.</p>
<p>A leading software piracy watchdog promised corporations and small businesses that agreeing to having their software examined would ensure a year's immunity from raids and possible civil suits.  </p>
<p>The private watchdog, the Business Software Alliance (BSA) told a software conference that its new Corporate Recognition Programme, endorsed by the government, aimed to curb rising rates of software piracy in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;(It) will 'protect' companies against raids, civil suits and possible embarrassment that result from tip-offs or sabotage attempts by disgruntled current or ex-employees,&quot; BSA vice president Stuart Ong told Reuters on the sidelines of the conference.  </p>
<p>He said auditors would conduct checks on companies and certify them free of illegal software. If fake software were found later on their premises, they would not be prosecuted.</p>
<p>According to BSA figures, Singapore's software piracy rate rose in 1996 by six percentage points to 59 percent.</p>
<p>Businesses must pay for genuine software and need to understand the implications of a civil suit, in which they can face heavy financial damages as well as a loss of reputation, brought for using fakes, Ong said.  </p>
<p>Ong said five firms had already agreed to take part in the programme and that he hoped to get another 100 to 200 members in a year.</p>
<p>Singapore's software piracy rate has increased by more than 10 percent since 1995, according to the latest BSA figures.</p>
<p>&quot;With the advent of CD-ROMs, the pirates have found an ideal mechanism to distribute 20, 30 sometimes up to 50 programmes,&quot; Ong said. There was good demand for it, he added.  </p>
<p>A compilation CD-ROM, the most common method of data storage for high-end computers and multimedia equipment, cost only a few dollars to produce and sold for about Singapore $15 (US$10.3), Ong said.</p>
<p>But he said raids on software retailers at shopping complexes around Singapore had only affected retailers and not users.</p>
<p>Ong said piracy syndicates were getting very sophisticated, operating across the music, video and computer software industries.  </p>
<p>So far, an engineering and one design and publishing firm had been sued, and a third case was being settled, Ong said.</p>
<p>Singapore courts have adopted stiff penalities -- jail terms of up to 36 months and Singapore $180,000 in fines for those found selling illegal software.</p>
<p>The engineering company found guilty of using fake software was ordered to pay S$42,000 in damages and costs.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-870-3080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
