<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754656" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP ups growth outlook with note of caution.</title>
<headline>SAP ups growth outlook with note of caution.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>SAP AG said on Thursday favourable exchange rates could push its 1997 sales well past previous growth targets, even as the software company tried to remain cautious after a recent insider trading investigation.</p>
<p>If the dollar remains at its current level, SAP sales for the full year could rise 37 to 42 percent -- 10 to 12 percentage points higher than its original forecast, the company said at a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Bearing in mind the positive environment, we are optimistic of beating our sales forecast from the beginning of the year of 25 to 30 percent growth in sales,&quot; chief executive Dietmar Hopp said. &quot;We see our chances for further growth as very positive.&quot;</p>
<p>In the first six months of 1997, sales rose 51 percent to 2.4 billion marks ($1.3 billion), with currency effects boosting the total by 145 million marks, or nine percentage points. Pretax profit rose 56 percent to 582 million marks, with a gain of 61 million marks, or 16 percentage points, from exchange rates.</p>
<p>Its original forecast was based on an exchange rate of 1.50 marks to the dollar, compared to today's rate of 1.81.</p>
<p>But SAP, which was probed after an unexpectedly weak third quarter a year ago, said it expected growth to moderate in the second half and could not rule out another slackening in the third quarter this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering the high (growth in the first half of 1997) the second half should slow down,&quot; Hopp said, adding that &quot;we cannot rule out that the third quarter this year perhaps also brings a weakening of the growth dynamic again.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts discounted some of the cautions. &quot;I wouldn't expect him to be too bullish because of the insider investigation,&quot; said Credit Lyonnais' Hans Peter Wodniok.</p>
<p>Wodniok said he expected the first-half results and new forecast would prompt several analysts to upgrade ratings on SAP shares. They closed floor trading on Thursday up 2.20 marks at 433.50 as the DAX index slipped 63.71 points to 4,342.01.</p>
<p>&quot;In the long view, they could get to 500 if the stock market stays positive,&quot; Wodniok said.</p>
<p>Hopp said SAP shares have undergone a renaissance since last year's disappointing third quarter caused them to plunge 23 percent to about 210 marks.</p>
<p>The insider trading investigation stemming from the drop originally looked at trades by dozens of SAP employees. But only one remains under scrutiny, he said. &quot;We are happy that the suspicion against SAP has evaporated.&quot;</p>
<p>Since the probe was made public in May, the company has tightened access to insider information.</p>
<p>SAP has also begun preparing to issue shares in the United States in 1999, or late 1998 at the earliest, said chief financial officer Dieter Matheis.</p>
<p>The company had not yet decided whether to list shares on the New York Stock Exchange or the electronic NASDAQ exchange, which lists many technology companies such as Microsoft Corp. and Intel Corp.</p>
<p>SAP wanted to be able to offer shares to employees in the U.S., where 21 percent of its 11,084 employees work and where it gets a third of its sales.</p>
<p>In the first half of the year, U.S. sales rose 78 percent to 798 million marks. German sales increased 17 percent to 455 million marks, while sales in the rest of Europe climbed 40 percent ot 542 million marks. Sales in Asia-Pacific rose 55 percent to 315 million marks.</p>
<p>Revenue from sales of it s R/3 software rose 43 percent to 1.6 billion marks. Costs increased 49 percent to 1.9 billion marks, including 913 million marks in personnel costs. R/3 is a sprawling programme used by large corporation to control manufacturing, purchasing, personnel and accounting data on computers located through out their organisations.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom, +49-228 26097150 ($ = 1.824 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
