<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="755802" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Court rules against Microsoft on worker benefits.</title>
<headline>Court rules against Microsoft on worker benefits.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal appeals court ruled Thursday that certain temporary and contract workers at Microsoft Corp. are eligible for the company's stock purchase plan and may be entitled to pension benefits.</p>
<p>The ruling, issued by an 11-member panel of the 9th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals in San Francisco, upheld the bulk of last year's decision by a three-judge panel of the same court.</p>
<p>The Microsoft case, brought by former contract workers who said they were eligible for the same benefits as permanent company employees, has attracted national attention because of the increasing prevalence of temporary workers throughout the U.S. economy.</p>
<p>A Microsoft spokesman said the company would review Thursday's decision and consider its legal options. Microsoft could seek an appeal to the U.S. Supreme Court.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't made a decision on that,&quot; Microsoft spokesman Mark Murray said.</p>
<p>Last October, a panel of the appeals court ruled two-to-one against Microsoft in the class-action lawsuit.</p>
<p>Microsoft's attorneys asked for a larger panel of judges to reconsider the decision.</p>
<p>In Thursday's ruling, the expanded appeals court panel affirmed the October decision, concluding that the reasons for rejecting the workers' participation in the stock and pension plans &quot;were invalid.&quot;</p>
<p>The workers were entitled to participate in the stock purchase plan, the court said, but it left the issue of determining remedies to the district court.</p>
<p>The appeals court also ruled, however, that the right of any or all of the workers to participate in the pension plan must be decided by the company's plan administrator.</p>
<p>&quot;We see it as a mixed decision,&quot; Murray said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased by the (pension plan) result,&quot; he said. &quot;We are obviously disappointed by the ruling on the employee stock purchase plan because we believe we were very clear with our workers and that our workers had a very clear understanding that they did not qualify for that particular benefit.&quot;</p>
<p>Attorneys for the workers said the ruling was a victory.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not as big a victory, but it's a victory,&quot; plaintiffs' attorney David Stobaugh said.</p>
<p>The class-action lawsuit was brought in 1993 on behalf of workers who had been at Microsoft beginning in 1987.</p>
<p>Stobaugh said at least 800 workers and possibly thousands would be benefit from Thursday's ruling. Plaintiffs' lawyers argue that the class includes the company's temporary and contract workers through the present.</p>
<p>Microsoft, by contrast, contends that the case covers the period ending in 1990. Thursday's ruling supported Microsoft's stance on that issue, Murray said.</p>
<p>Microsoft said that since the late 1980s the company has restructured the way it handles contract workers. Now &quot;virtually all&quot; of these workers are hired through agencies that handle pay and benefits, Murray said.</p>
<p>&quot;While we didn't get everything we wanted from this decision, there are several very bright spots and we're confident that we've treated all of our workers in a fair and equitable manner,&quot; Murray said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
