<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75603" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reuters previews Web network.</title>
<headline>Reuters previews Web network.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reuters America Inc and Netscape Communications Corp on Wednesday unveiled Reuters Web, a private, high-performance network based on Web technologies to deliver Reuters financial service products.</p>
<p>The companies said Reuters Web will incorporate Netscape's Internet client and server software and serve as a value-added feature of the Reuters 3000 Series, a new line of products for the equities, fixed-income and money markets.</p>
<p>&quot;It will deliver high-performance, secure connectivity and information to some 340,000 Reuters financial services clients worldwide,&quot; the companies said in a statement.</p>
<p>The enabling technology at the core of Reuters Web includes Netscape SuiteSpot server software, which the companies said would provide distribution of database information and online applications.</p>
<p>The Netscape Navigator Internet browser will be packaged with Reuters 3000 Series this autumn, providing customers a desktop interface for accessing Reuters Web.</p>
<p>&quot;Reuters is demonstrating its role as a leader in information services by taking advantage of the open standards and cross-platform characteristics of Netscape's Internet technology to deliver valuable information to its customers,&quot; Netscape Chief Executive James Barksdale said in a statement.</p>
<p>Michael Sanderson, chairman and chief executive of Reuters America Holdings Inc, said the launch of the 3000 Series comes &quot;at a time in which we see dramatic developments within the financial services community.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The thirst for information, analytics and connectivity has never been stronger...,&quot; he said, noting Internet technology made it possible for Reuters to meet these demands rapidly by making it a key feature of the product line.</p>
<p>Sanderson said the 3000 Series introduction was &quot;Reuters's most aggressive and important information product development in more than a decade.&quot;</p>
<p>The 3000 Series integrates real-time prices and news with historical data and sophisticated analytics on a single screen, taking advantage of the company's new High Performance Shared Network (HPSN) and open systems standards.</p>
<p>This enables the products to be integrated into clients' own Intranets, or private networks that use Web technology, permitting more rapid deployment of new resources.</p>
<p>Customers can also use Reuters HPSN to send secure messages to one another via Reuters Mail, a proprietary electronic messaging service which the company said knits together a variety of functions on both the buy-side and sell-side of the financial services industries.</p>
<p>Reuters America Holdings Inc oversees the primary American business operations of Reuters Holdings Plc, the international news and information organization.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
