<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756989" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore sound makers in battle for PC market.</title>
<headline>Singapore sound makers in battle for PC market.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Electronics-based Venture Manufacturing's new multimedia software will give Creative Technology's sound card business some competition, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>But they were divided over the extent of impact on the business of Creative, maker of the SoundBlaster card.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be some impact,&quot; Siew Teng Kean, assistant manager at Ong Research said.</p>
<p>&quot;The product could erode Creative's earnings by at least 10-20 percent in six to 12 months' time,&quot; said another analyst, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>On Friday, Venture Manufacturing launched NovaStation, a software that upgrades any SoundBlaster-16 or compatible 16-bit sound card to a high quality wavetable synthesizer.</p>
<p>Personal computer (PC) users will be able to hear 128 instruments simultaneusly from a choice of 676 instruments and 21 drum kits.</p>
<p>NovaStation is designed for Windows 95 and can be used on PCs based on Intel's MMX processors and older Pentium 100 MHZ systems.</p>
<p>The news sent Creative Technology's share price plummeting as much as S$1.90 (US$1.29) to S$34.60, after surging in the past week on expectations of strong earnings. Venture's share price rocketed to a high of Singapore $7.10, up S$1.95.</p>
<p>Creative recently launched its latest sound card, the AWE64 Value card, at US$99 each, targetted at replacing older 16-bit cards. The AWE64 can play 64 instruments simultaneously.</p>
<p>NovaStation, developed by Venture subsidiary Innovative Trek Technology Pte Ltd, will have a recommended retail price of US$49 when it zrrives in stores in two months' time.</p>
<p>Innovative general manager Christopher Ng said that as NovaStation was a software, PC users need not throw out their old soundcards.</p>
<p>Notebook computers will also be able to deliver realistic sounds with NovaStation, which they cannot now because they do hot have enough space to plug in a new sound card, he said.</p>
<p>Some analysts said Creative would face a limited threat from NovaStation at least in the first 12 months as the two companies' products were pitched at different markets.</p>
<p>Venture is targetting original equipment manufacturers (OEMs) which will bundle NovaStation with their products.</p>
<p>&quot;Creative is targetting the retail market,&quot; David Toh, electronics analyst at ING-Baring said, adding that Creative also had a lot of clout with its brand name.</p>
<p>Analysts however conceded that NovaStation could take some of Creative's share from the OEM market.</p>
<p>But OEMs which produce top-of-the-line systems may still prefer Creative for its brand name, Siew added.</p>
<p>Ng said Innovative had already secured five OEM customers, the first of which will ship NovaStation with its CD-ROM drives next week.</p>
<p>The analyst who thought NovaStation would hit Creative's business quite hard said:</p>
<p>&quot;It is a software product where Venture has the flexibility to move it down to a very low price. They can also sell it cheaply on the Internet which will attract the retail buyers.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said NovaStation would be a catalyst to Venture's share price moving as high as S$7-8.</p>
<p>US$1.00 = S$1.47</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
