<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762278" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Display.IT says won't be paid for supplies.</title>
<headline>UK's Display.IT says won't be paid for supplies.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Display.IT Holding, the troubled UK internet software company, on Tuesday retracted an earlier statement that it had received about 5.7 million pounds for supplying workstation licences and added that it was unlikely to be paid.</p>
<p>To add to its woes, Display.IT -- whose Ofex, over the counter market traded shares were suspended on July 17 -- also announced the resignation of its auditors and a director. The group's solicitor and financial public relations adviser have already terminated their relationship.</p>
<p>Managing director and chief executive Peter Levin said director Gerald Giombetti would step down on July 22 and the auditors, Deloitte &amp; Touche, were also abandoning the group from July 24.</p>
<p>Display.IT announced on June 2 that it had entered into a contract to supply 920,000 workstation licences to a Luxembourg-registered company called Alsina. The company then stated that it had received about 5.7 million pounds from Alsina.</p>
<p>&quot;Contrary to these announcements the money has not in fact been received by the company or its subsidiary,&quot; Levin said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The company has been in discussions with lawyers representing Alsina about honouring the contract, but now understands that it is not Alsina's intention to do so.&quot;</p>
<p>Display.IT has seen its shares dive after doubts over sales forecasts. Both its solicitor, Taylor Joynson Garrett, and financial public relations firm, College Hill, resigned because they said key information they had asked for was not forthcoming.</p>
<p>Newspapers said concerns had arisen mainly about Alsina, which accounted for about 90 percent of the UK group's sales forecasts.</p>
<p>-- Kirstin Ridley, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4020</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
