<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763069" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FTC will not duplicate Justice efforts on Microsoft.</title>
<headline>FTC will not duplicate Justice efforts on Microsoft.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>As expected, the Federal Trade Commission told three senators Tuesday it cannot conduct an investigation of Microsoft Corp because to do so would duplicate efforts of the Justice Department.</p>
<p>Three senators, unhappy the Justice Department has not taken more action against Microsoft, asked the FTC to intervene.</p>
<p>But in letters to Republican Senators Ted Stevens of Alaska, Conrad Burns of Montana, and Craig Thomas of Wyoming, FTC Chairman Robert Pitofsky said the commission &quot;has concluded that to exercise its authority ... could involve a substantial duplication of effort.&quot;  </p>
<p>Pitofsky said that so far as he knew the FTC had never invoked its authority to investigate &quot;in the context of an active investigation of the same subject by the Department of Justice.&quot;</p>
<p>Pitofsky declined to say specifically that the Justice Department was in fact conducting such an investigation, although the letter certainly left the door open to that possibility.</p>
<p>But he said that the FTC had decided &quot;that it cannot responsibly commence the investigation that you have requested.&quot;</p>
<p>One of the Senate aides who helped draft the letter said the response was as expected.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not particularly a surprise,&quot; said the aide.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
