<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76613" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft to launch city news service in early '97.</title>
<headline>Microsoft to launch city news service in early '97.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. said Tuesday its widely anticipated online city entertainment guide, code-named &quot;Cityscape,&quot; will be launched in the first quarter of 1997 with Seattle as the debut coverage area.</p>
<p>Guides for New York, Boston and San Francisco will follow by midyear with 10 to 15 cities worldwide to be covered by the year-end, the computer software giant said in a statement.</p>
<p>The advertiser-supported service will be available at no extra charge to users who have access to the Internet. It will feature information about movies, restaurants and arts and entertainment events.</p>
<p>Cityscape has been hiring journalists led by Editor in Chief Michael Goff, founder of Out magazine, to provide content for the service, seen by many publishers as a direct threat to traditional daily and weekly newspapers.</p>
<p>Microsoft is not alone in trying to fill the Internet's lack of local information. America Online Inc. has launched a similar service, and AT&amp;T Corp. is backing a rival venture.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
