<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771385" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: CCT Telecom in China joint ventures.</title>
<headline>CCT Telecom in China joint ventures.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>CCT Telecom Holdings Ltd said on Thursday it had agreed to form a joint venture company with Tesonic International Ltd, a company partly owned by China's Ministry of Electronics Industry.</p>
<p>CCT China Ltd, which will be 67 percent owned by CCT Telecom and 33 percent by Tesonic International, will form three Sino-foreign joint ventures to produce and distribute telecommunications equipment and networks, and provide management consultancy services to China's satellite industry.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an important corporate move of the company since it paves the way for us to step into the telecommunications industry in the PRC (People's Republic of China) market,&quot; CCT Telecom managing director Bankee Kwan said in a statement.</p>
<p>Tesonic International is 60 percent owned by Time Line and 40 percent owned by China National Electronics Import and Export Corp, a state-owned enterprise wholly owned by the Ministry of Electronics Industry.</p>
<p>Each of the joint ventures will be 90 percent owned by CCT China and 10 percent owned by Tesonic Industrial, a mainland collective ownership enterprise which is involved in the manufacture, marketing and research and development of electronic and communication products.  </p>
<p>The total registered capital of the joint ventures will be HK$220 million. CCT Telecom said it would invest HK$132 million, paying HK$50 million in cash through internal resources and the balance, at its discretion, funded by Tesonic International.</p>
<p>CCT Telecom said it would repay Tesonic International on or before February 28, 1998 either by cash or through the issue of 82 million new shares at an issue price of HK$1.00 each.</p>
<p>Tesonic International would contribute HK$66 million in cash to the total registered capital of the joint ventures and Tesonic Industrial HK$22 million by way of asset injections.</p>
<p>The joint ventures will acquire the assets owned by Tesonic Industrial's Tesonic Communication Co Ltd, Tesonic Satellite Network Co Ltd and Tesonic Electronics Co Ltd subsidiaries.</p>
<p>Tesonic International and Time Line have guaranteed that the aggregate net profit after tax but before extraordinary items of the joint ventures for 1998 will not be less than HK$25 million or Time Line and Tesonic International will pay the shortfall.</p>
<p>Trading in shares of CCT Telecom, a telecommunications equipment maker, was suspended on Monday and was due to resume on Thursday. The stock last traded at HK$1.35.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
