<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77454" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE - Internet shopping threatens retailers.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Internet shopping threatens retailers.</headline>
<byline>Isadore Barmash</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Starting this fall, four big companies are creating Internet malls in perhaps the biggest test yet of whether cyberspace can become profitable.</p>
<p>Putting the department store on the computer screen may ultimately replace or drastically change the suburban mall, some say, based on the high number of households with personal computers.</p>
<p>Among themselves, the Internet mall operators will undoubtedly draw lots of blood because of their large financial commitment and ambitious goals.</p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp. says that its &quot;World Avenue&quot; will become the &quot;world's leading Internet mall,&quot; primarily because of the company's advanced technology, spokesman said in an interview.</p>
<p>Time Warner Inc. believes that its &quot;Dream Shop&quot; will show superiority coming from its pioneering efforts on cable television and its extensive marketing know-how, according to its spokesman.</p>
<p>The other two principal contenders are the Microsoft Corp. and America Online Inc., both capable of delivering effective shopping systems.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T reportedly is mulling over its involvement in Internet shopping. As results begin to show, a host of smaller companies are expected to enter the competition.</p>
<p>&quot;Dream Shop&quot; includes such famous names as Burdine's department stores of Florida, Williams-Sonoma, Eddie Bauer, Spiegel and Sharper Image.</p>
<p>&quot;World Avenue&quot; has the Express division of The Limited, Hudson Bay Co. of Canada and Robert Waxman Cameras of Denver. IBM will soon announce 15 to 20 more retailers on its site, while Time Warner already has 14 and expects more soon.</p>
<p>&quot;I can foresee 30 percent of American households eventually buying their clothing and home needs over the Internet,&quot; predicts Rod Parker, vice president for interactive merchandising at Time Warner.</p>
<p>Ambitious claims for Internet shopping can be expected from the companies involved, of course. But a highly qualified, independent observer is perhaps even more optimistic for the Internet players, although pessimistic for traditional retailers.</p>
<p>&quot;Internet retailing will play an important role in the future so that 10 to 15 years from now, the American retail centre of gravity will swing from stores to screens,&quot; said New York's Walter K. Levy, one of the nation's leading retailing consultants.</p>
<p>&quot;Once you have enough people raised on the computer as a household appliance, a tremendous amount of merchandise will be sold on the Internet,&quot; Levy said. He sees stores remaining &quot;for 'emotional' purposes, such as fashion, colour match and individual preferences.&quot;</p>
<p>IBM's marketing launch for its &quot;World Avenue&quot; focused on banner ads in various Web sites such as those used by The New York Times, Sports Illustrated, C-Net and ESPN, as well as in several search engines such as Yahoo.</p>
<p>The general theme was on &quot;shopping conveniently and safely,&quot; said Tim Breuer, spokesman for IBM's Distribution Industry activities. &quot;The ads brought the consumer our 'World Avenue' but also rotated around the stores already operating in it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The customer clicks on the store he or she prefers, and is then presented with various merchandise.</p>
<p>The shopper can load up computer &quot;shopping baskets&quot; and click on &quot;pay&quot; by credit card number. Merchandise is then delivered to the customer's home.</p>
<p>Any results yet? &quot;We've gotten some but can't say what they are at this point,&quot; Breuer said. &quot;We are tracking them carefully. But we are convinced that the Internet is the right medium for 'World Avenue' and is a very effective electronic commerce medium.&quot;</p>
<p>Stressing that IBM's technology &quot;sets us apart,&quot; he said that several technical features in &quot;World Avenue&quot; provide important benefits to consumers and retailers.</p>
<p>One is &quot;Accessorization,&quot; in which a particular store will be able to suggest complementary merchandise to a viewer who has already made a selection. Another is assembling information about each customer's shopping and buying habits so the retailer can have an Internet customer database.</p>
<p>Time Warner's &quot;Dream Shop&quot; has similar features.</p>
<p>Parker thinks that Internet shopping is much superior to TV shopping because &quot;the upscale customer and others really want shopping on demand while TV is so linear, meaning that the TV customer has to sit there and wait for the merchandise to come to her. The interactive shopping allows the customer to take the initiative,&quot; said Parker.</p>
<p>Levy said the success of the Internet as a selling medium &quot;depends on how many people in the country become as used to the personal computer as they are with the gas or electric range, the telephone and the television set.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Once that number reaches a threshold point, there's no question that shopping on the Internet will thoroughly change American retailing.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
