<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77771" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reality Interactive sees slower sales.</title>
<headline>Reality Interactive sees slower sales.</headline>
<dateline>EDEN PRAIRIE, Minn. 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reality Interactive Inc said Thursday it expects revenues in 1996 to be in the $500,000 to $800,000 range, slower than the company had previously expected.</p>
<p>Reality chief financial officer Wes Winnekins said the company's expected revenues for the year had previously been pegged at $2 million.</p>
<p>The company said it has sufficient capital to continue with its current business plan.  </p>
<p>Reality Interactive said the slower growth is a result of unexpected problems in setting up a direct sales force, and longer-than-expected sales cycles in businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;Sales growth for 1996 has developed slower than we initially expected,&quot; Paul Wendorff, chief executive, said in a statement. &quot;While this is disappointing to us, the company is performing well and the reaction to our products from existing and potential customers has been favorable.&quot;</p>
<p>CFO Winnekins said the company believes its basic sales strategy is correct, but he said it is too early to make projections for 1997.</p>
<p>The company began shipping this month its QS-9000 product, a CD-ROM series to help companies comply with quality standards of the major U.S. automakers.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point in time it's probably too early to assess opportunities for '97,&quot; Winnekins said in a telephone interview, adding that QS-900 is considered one of the company's most important products.</p>
<p>Reality Interactive provides multi-media educational and training products to industrial companies.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EDEN PRAIRIE, Minn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
