<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777947" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Power Computing CEO blasts Apple, Jobs.</title>
<headline>Power Computing CEO blasts Apple, Jobs.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A key manufacturer of clone Macintosh computers blasted Apple Computer Inc on Tuesday for dragging out negotiations to license its technology and urged buyers to pressure Steven Jobs to break the deadlock.</p>
<p>Speaking to hundreds of mass volume buyers ahead of Jobs' keynote address at the Macworld Expo trade show on Wednesday, Power Computing Corp Chief Executive Joel Kocher said Apple is showing little commitment to share its technology.</p>
<p>&quot;You'd be real safe if you assumed they're doing nothing,&quot; Kocher told a questioner from the audience.  </p>
<p>&quot;It appears at this point that Steve's attitude toward licensing is permeating throughout the organization,&quot; he later told reporters.</p>
<p>Jobs has assumed a more powerful role at Apple since the sudden resignation of Chief Executive Gil Amelio last month following pressure from the board of directors.</p>
<p>The Apple co-founder, who is now officially an advisor, has a negative attitude towards the clone manufacturers and may have been responsible for a recent tougher stance in licensing negotiations, Kocher said.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw much more positive attitude 30 days ago then we're seeing today,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;In fact, I was extremely optimistic 30 days ago we were finally going to bring this to a positive conclusion.&quot;</p>
<p>Kocher, rumored to be among those considered for the Apple chief executive slot, said: &quot;I am not a candidate for that job.&quot;</p>
<p>Apple executive vice president of marketing Guerrino De Luca told the crowd that Apple had an &quot;absolute intention of coming to a positive conclusion&quot; on the question of licensing.</p>
<p>But he said Apple was bound not to discuss the negotiations and he offered few details about the talks.</p>
<p>&quot;We can not take away the ability of Apple to drive the Macintosh forward in order to preserve higher margins and short-term benefits for the licensees,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kocher told the crowd of buyers they should demonstrate when Jobs speaks on Wednesday and voice their support for allowing clone manufacturers access to future versions of the Macintosh operating system and other Apple technology.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to get Apple and Steve Jobs to address this issue. Be heard, carry a sign, light a candle,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Following repeated requests from the audience, Kocher said Power Computing will supply &quot;Freedom of Choice&quot; signs at Macworld Expo and at Jobs' speech.</p>
<p>Apple launched an updated version of the Macintosh operating system, Mac OS 8, late last month, but Kocher said Power Computing is not able to ship the Macs with the new software. He said he also is not certified to begin manufacturing a new hardware design called the Common Reference Hardware Platform or CHRP.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't have Mac OS 8. I have no CHRP roadmap. No CHRP, no Mac. I don't know if we can last another year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Power Computing recently announced plans to diversify and sell &quot;Wintel&quot; computers based on the Microsoft Corp and Intel Corp platform.</p>
<p>((Boston bureau, (617) 367-4106))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
