<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780859" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CORPORATE BONDS-Prices firm ahead of new supply.</title>
<headline>US CORPORATE BONDS-Prices firm ahead of new supply.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. corporate bond prices remained firm on Wednesday ahead of a pickup in new issue supply expected later in the week, traders said.</p>
<p>Prices of junk bonds were steady to slightly higher on modest volume on Wednesday. Junk traders reported good buying of media and telecom credits in particular.</p>
<p>Spreads on high-grade corporates were unchanged amid sparse trading, traders said.</p>
<p>Syndicate officials said market demand appeared on track for a series of junk bond offerings as well as a large investment-grade debt deal from Raytheon Co.  </p>
<p>In credit-specific news, traders bid up the junk bonds of Apple Computer Inc on news that Microsoft Corp agreed to make a $150 million equity investment in its former computer rival.</p>
<p>Despite the surge in bids, no Apple bonds actually traded, market players said. Traders speculated investors may be waiting for prices to firm or rise even higher before taking profits.</p>
<p>The computer maker's 6.50 percent bonds due 2004 were quoted up 5-1/2 points at 88-92 at the end of the day.  </p>
<p>On Wednesday, electric and gas utility, Western Resources sold $520 million in seven- and 12-year first mortgage bonds (A3/BBB-plus) via Dillon Read &amp; Co. The notes are convertible into senior unsecured notes at the discretion of the issuer.</p>
<p>Among junk bond issuers, Mark IV Industries priced $250 million in debt (Ba2/BB-plus) to yield 7.575 percent via Bear Stearns &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Also, B&amp;G Foods priced $120 million in debt (B3/B-minus) to yield 9.625 percent via Lehman Brothers Inc. The deal was increased from an original size of $100 million.</p>
<p>In other markets, the Dow Jones Industrial Average rose 71.77 points to end the day at 8259.31.</p>
<p>Treasuries closed higher as the bond market absorbed a Treasury auction of $12 billion in 10-year notes with little trouble. The U.S. Treasury is expected to auction $10 billion in 30-year bonds tomorrow.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year bond rose 4/32 to close at 101-28/32. Its yield fell to 6.48 percent.</p>
<p>-Douglas Brown, U.S. Corporate Bond Unit, 212-859-1662  </p>
<p>Among new-issues, Raytheon plans to add a tranche of up to $500 million in three-year debt to its mega-debt offering expected to price on Thursday, sources said.</p>
<p>The new tranche, added to meet strong investor demand, could increase the deal to $3.0 billion from an original size of $2.5 billion.</p>
<p>Relatively few new corporate bond issues priced on Wednesday, although sources said a large calendar is building for later in the week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
