<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="782003" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Solving some mysteries about Magritte.</title>
<headline>Solving some mysteries about Magritte.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most people would ask, &quot;What does it mean when someone paints a portrait of a man with a big green apple covering his face?&quot;</p>
<p>Rene Magritte, the surrealist artist who gained fame by doing precisely that (along with creating even weirder visions) would explain that there is no real explanation.</p>
<p>The public, he once said, &quot;gives a painting meaning it doesn't have,&quot; trying to conjure complicated motives for the artist when the painter may simply have wanted to create something that tickles the mind. Bestowing meaning on an odd image, Magritte contended, is as foolish as trying to leave a room through a wall instead of the door.</p>
<p>Perhaps he was right, perhaps he was attempting a little misdirection, or perhaps Magritte underestimated the effect that his subconscious had on his work.</p>
<p>You get a chance to judge for yourself on &quot;The Mystery of Magritte.&quot; This CD-ROM from Byron Preiss Multimedia (Windows/Macintosh, $30), released in Europe last year, offers glimpses of the artist whose images may be familiar, but whose life is not.</p>
<p>Magritte mixed daytime skies and nighttime terrain. He used a single leaf to evoke a tree. His paintings were filled with stones, men with bowler hats, apples, clouds, birds and pipes, usually in a way that produced visual paradoxes.</p>
<p>He delighted in catching people off guard, once painting a picture of a pipe and insisting, in a caption, that &quot;This is not a pipe.&quot; Those who forgot that the painting was only a representation of a pipe, and not the real thing, were confused. In 1965 he revised the pipe illustration and gave it a new caption: &quot;This continues not being a pipe.&quot;</p>
<p>Wandering through this CD-ROM gives the impression that Magritte loved being enigmatic. In the opening section, where the artist offers opinions on his work and his fame, he says, &quot;Painting evokes what is most important to us, which I believe is the mystery of the world.&quot; The painting &quot;doesn't mean anything because mystery means nothing either. It's unknowable.&quot;</p>
<p>He might believe so, but some mysteries can be solved.</p>
<p>The CD-ROM makes a convincing case, for example, that some of Magritte's work was deeply influenced by his mother's suicide. During an episode of depression, she was found drowned in a river, her night clothes floating up to cover her face like a shroud. Magritte was 12 at the time, and you see the imagery of her death in several of his paintings.</p>
<p>&quot;The Mystery of Magritte&quot; suffers a bit, as do many multimedia educational products, from a lack of focus and narrative. You can jump from one topic to another, discovering bits of information as you go and weaving them into your own mental picture. But the result may be a feeling that you're stumbling around, missing important pieces of the puzzle along your convoluted path.</p>
<p>I explored the CD-ROM for two evenings and still felt that I was being forced to learn through soundbites. So I went to an encyclopaedia and quickly discovered that Magritte's birth name was actually Francois Ghislain Magritte, and that he apparently learned about the impact of repeated patterns and the illusion of depth during a phase in his life when he designed wallpaper.</p>
<p>Those are key pieces of information. But because of the format of &quot;The Mystery of Magritte,&quot; I don't know if I simply missed them, or they are missing from the CD-ROM.</p>
<p>Still, the world was never simple, straightforward, logical or linear to Magritte. So maybe this fascinating CD-ROM, being issued in the United States during the 30th anniversary of his death on Aug. 15, is a fitting tribute in more ways than one.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software:</p>
<p>&quot;Mangia&quot; -- Named after the Italian word for &quot;eat,&quot; this cookbook and recipes-rating CD-ROM features over 800 recipes. It also lets you eliminate recipes with certain ingredients so it becomes easier to plan a menu for someone with a food allergy. It's from SierraHome (Windows/Macintosh, $20, 800-757-7707, http://www.sierra.com).</p>
<p>&quot;Math for the Real World&quot; -- A fictional band's 10-city tour is the premise for more than 4,000 word problems that teach anyone over 9 to cope with real-life math problems. I know plenty of adults who could use it. It's from Davidson (Windows/Macintosh, $30, 800-545-7677, http://www.education.com).</p>
<p>&quot;The Stock Shop with Peter Lynch,&quot; vice chairman of Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, is a CD-ROM that uses 15 interactive lessons to train folks about making wise choices in buying and selling stocks. It's from Houghton Mifflin Interactive (Windows, $70, 800-829-7962, http://www.hminet.com).</p>
<p>&quot;StrataJams&quot; has six types of strategy puzzles similar to the ones featured in last year's delightful &quot;Smart Games Challenge 1.&quot; For example, you have to figure out how to extract a car from a jammed parking lot by moving other cars a space or two. It's from Smart Games (Windows, $30, http://www.smartgames.com).</p>
<p>&quot;Ultimate Speed Reader&quot; is supposed to teach speed reading using arcade-style games to improve peripheral vision and hone other skills. It's another Davidson product (Windows/Macintosh, $30).</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
