<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783955" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Investors snap up Sunglass Hut.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Investors snap up Sunglass Hut.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors were buying options on shares of Sunglass Hut International Inc Thursday, as the stock rallied after the company posted a 7.8 percent increase in July same store sales.</p>
<p>&quot;Sales came in better-than-expected,&quot; said John Colletti, a market maker in Sunglass Hut options at the Chicago Board Options Exchange.  &quot;I've had customers buying options all day long.&quot;</p>
<p>By 1400 CDT/1900 GMT, Sunglass Hut was up 1-9/16 at 10 on solid turnover of 7.5 million shares.  </p>
<p>In addition to the same store sales increse, the sunglasses retailer said its inventory levels were cut to $115 million from $145 million since the beginning of the year and its revolving debt borrowings were paid back in full by the end of the second quarter.</p>
<p>Montgomery Securities upgraded the stock to buy from hold and Colletti said the upgrade was probably a main factor driving the stock higher.</p>
<p>The company reminded investors that its ongoing plan to reduce and refresh inventory levels was expected to cut gross margins in the second quarter and the rest of the year.  </p>
<p>Among the Sunglass Hut options, the December 10 call was most active, with volume of 2,190 contracts.  The option, which had open interest of 388 contracts, gained 3/4 to 1-5/8.</p>
<p>The September 10 call traded 1,440 contracts.  It rose 11/16 to 1.0 and had open interest of 1,246.</p>
<p>Other active calls included the September 7-1/2 and March 10, which traded 755 and 540 contracts, respectively.</p>
<p>The busiest Sunglass Hut put was the December 7-1/2, which traded about 85 contracts.</p>
<p>Colletti said volatility in the options was up about five percentage points to the 68 to 70 percent level.  </p>
<p>In other trading, Apple Computer Inc options remained busy as the stock extended its sharp Wednesday gains on optimism the $150 million cash injection from Microsoft Corp and a new board of directors will help the company.</p>
<p>The stock was up 2-3/4 at 29-1/16 after reaching 29-3/4, a level not seen since late February 1996.  Volume continued heavy, topping 31.4 million shares.</p>
<p>The August 30 calls were the most popular, with turnover of about 7,375 contracts, but activity in both puts and calls was strong through the January series.  </p>
<p>The January 30, September 30 and October 30 calls drew the most interest among the calls.  Put activity was led by the August 27-1/2 and 30, which traded 2,675 and 2,465 contracts, respectively.  The January 25 and 27-1/2 and the September 25 puts also were fairly active.</p>
<p>Options on a couple other technology stocks were also active, including Compaq Computer Corp on the Pacific Exchange.</p>
<p>Compaq calls were particularly active as the stock rallied 3-3/4 to 62-3/8. The September 65 call traded 5,600 contracts.</p>
<p>((Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: chicago.derivatives.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
