<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785073" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apple's software licensing still unclear.</title>
<headline>Apple's software licensing still unclear.</headline>
<byline>Therese Poletti</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A day after Apple Computer Inc. and Microsoft Corp. ended their bitter rivalry, some software developers and Macintosh loyalists said the Microsoft pact did nothing to clarify issues over licensing of Apple software.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we got no clarity,&quot; Power Computing Corp. President Joel Kocher said Thursday at the MacWorld trade conference. &quot;There are very strong signals out there that Apple is reversing (its stance) on licensing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Apple's Steven Jobs announced the pact on Wednesday to the conference of Apple dealers, software writers and users.</p>
<p>Apple and the companies that make Mac clones are in discussions over the future of licensing, but neither side would comment on the negotiations. Apple is believed to be seeking bigger licensing fees in the talks.</p>
<p>Apple for years had steadfastly refused to allow other companies to copy the software that ran its Macintosh line of computers -- the machine that was to no small extent responsible for making the personal computer a home appliance.</p>
<p>It was only two years ago that Apple finally relented and licensed its software to other companies so that they could sell clones of the Mac.</p>
<p>&quot;The objectives were to expand the Mac platform,&quot; said Fred Anderson, Apple's chief financial officer. But instead, the clones ate into Apple's market share, which has been declining and is now estimated at 7 percent of the worldwide PC market.</p>
<p>Another objective, he said, was to give the customer more freedom of choice. &quot;We are honouring the current agreement and talking to them about the future,&quot; Anderson said. He declined to comment further.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to work the issues, we have confidence that the entire issue will settle down,&quot; said Dennis Schneider, vice president of business development at Motorola Inc.'s computer products group. &quot;It's a whole new management team at Apple and they are questioning everything.&quot;</p>
<p>Software developers and the clone makers said they believe having clones of the Mac was essential for Apple to survive. Some software developers who still develop for both the Microsoft/Intel-based PC and the Mac said the issue of halting Mac development was a recurring one.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been an issue that has come up,&quot; said a product marketing manager at a major software developer who requested anonymity. &quot;I'm going to wait and see. The Mac users really ask for a lot. But you wonder if they are all bootlegging (the software) or what, because the sales don't come in.&quot;</p>
<p>These developers were heartened by the $150 million investment by Microsoft, Apple's rival and its biggest software developer, and its five-year commitment to develop future versions of products such as Microsoft Office and Internet Explorer for the Mac.</p>
<p>&quot;There were some conerns about the wolf being in the chicken coup,&quot; said Marc Radosevic, a territory manager for Multi-Ad Services Inc., which develops advertising applications software for the Mac in Peoria, Ill. &quot;But I think long term, it's going to help Apple.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that because co-founder Jobs comes from the &quot;closed-shop&quot; mentality of Apple's early days, the clone makers are more skittish about the ongoing discussions with Jobs now on the board.</p>
<p>&quot;But I don't think Apple can go back,&quot; Radosevic said. &quot;Let's face it, Steve put the sword down against Microsoft. He can probably put down the sword against the clone makers.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
