<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786025" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW-MICROSOFT SEEKS APPLE ALIGNMENT.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-MICROSOFT SEEKS APPLE ALIGNMENT.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp Chief Financial Officer Greg Maffei said a $150 million cash infusion into Apple Computer Inc and a broad-based technology accord are geared at boosting the Macintosh computer platform on which Microsoft has made a lucrative applications business.</p>
<p>&quot;It's about how the two of us can actually serve customers and make dough together,&quot; the Microsoft executive said in an interview after the investment was disclosed.  </p>
<p>Microsoft will end up with a special class of preferred stock in Apple which will give it roughly seven percent of the company. In exchange, Microsoft has agreed to hold on to the non-voting shares for at least three years, after which they are convertible to common stock, according to both companies.</p>
<p>Shares of Apple soared 6-9/16 to 26-5/15 on the news, announced by Apple co-founder Steve Jobs at the MacWorld Expo trade show in Boston, along with the naming of four computer industry executives, incluing Jobs, to Apple's board.  </p>
<p>&quot;Part of the goal is to help inject additional funds in the company,&quot; said Maffei. &quot;A big part of the goal from their perspective was to see some endorsement and alignment, and I think it's hopefully having both these effects.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is to better align the companies,&quot; he said, noting that Microsoft has traditionally had very high market share in applications for the Macintosh computer because it was an early developer for the Apple system.</p>
<p>&quot;Mac revenues have declined over the last few years,&quot; for Microsoft, he added. Maffei would not comment on an analyst's estimate that Macintosh products currently account for around $300 million a year for Microsoft.  </p>
<p>Under the agreement, Microsoft has committed to developing future versions of its Office productivity suite for the Mac OS for the next five years, while Apple will bundle Microsoft's Internet Explorer and other Microsoft tools for the Macintosh.</p>
<p>The latter deal was viewed as a blow to Netscape Communications Corp, which was a pioneer of commercial Web browser software, because Microsoft's browser effectively becomes available free on nearly all new personal computers.</p>
<p>The companies also reached a broad patent cross-licensing accord, allowing them to work more closely on Mac technologies and which Maffei and his Apple counterpart said in a conference call will result payments by Microsoft to Apple.  </p>
<p>Maffei and Apple Chief Financial Officer Fred Anderson said the payments would not be material to either company's financial results, however. An Apple spokeswoman said the payments will likely be made over two to three years.</p>
<p>The Microsoft investment will be priced at trailing market average prices, which are below the shares' recent uptick, but above $16 dollars a share, officials at the companies said.  </p>
<p>The agreement with Apple does not restrict Microsoft from acquiring further shares of Apple on the public market, Maffei said, but because the initial investment will be for more than five percent of Apple, Microsoft would have to file a 13-D on any changes with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
<p>Maffei declined comment on any future investment plans.</p>
<p>Nether company said it expected regulatory hurdles to the $150 million investment by Microsoft, which Apple said it expects to be completed within the next several days.</p>
<p>Analysts noted Microsoft's agreement provides further support for the viability of the Macintosh system for the next five years, while not committing Microsoft on whether it will support Apple's new system, known as Rhapsody, due next year.</p>
<p>&quot;We've not committed to do anything about Rhapsody as part of this agreeement. We're not precluding Rhapsody development, but it didn't fall under this agreement,&quot; Maffei said.</p>
<p>((sam.perry@reuters.com, in Palo Alto, +1 415 846 5400))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
