<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786208" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU unlikely to review Microsoft's Apple investment.</title>
<headline>EU unlikely to review Microsoft's Apple investment.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission is unlikely to review under competition law the alliance between U.S. computer software company Microsoft Corp and Apple Computer Inc , a commission spokesman said on Thursday .</p>
<p>&quot;My personal impression is that it does not fall under merger rules,&quot; the spokeman, Thierry Daman, said. The European Union executive body is practically closed in August for its annual break.</p>
<p>Daman  said he was unaware whether the Commission had been informed in advance of Microsoft's investment of $150 million into the troubled maker of Macintosh computers and of a broad-based technology agreement between the two firms.</p>
<p>The Commission has in the past worked with the U.S. Justice Department to prevent Microsoft from making deals which might restrict competition or abuse its dominant position -- both prohibited in the European Union under articles 85 and 86 of the EU's founding treaty.</p>
<p>The EU's competition watchdog is also still investigating a complaint by Britain's Personal Computer Association about Microsoft selling practices for its MS Office software.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the agreement announced on Wednesday, the world's largest software company will develop more programmes for Macintosh computers, including a new version of its Office package of business software.</p>
<p>Microsoft will also include its Internet browser in the Macintosh operating system.</p>
<p>Following the cash injection, Microsoft will have about seven percent of Apple in non-voting shares. Microsoft must hold on to the shares for three years, after which time they become convertible to common stock. Microsoft said it does not expect any regulatory problems with the investment in Apple.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
