<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786488" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan unit says Apple to keep strong identity.</title>
<headline>Japan unit says Apple to keep strong identity.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Apple Computer Inc's Japanese unit said on Thursday that the identity of its parent company would remain strong despite a tie-up with Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Japanese personal computer makers said they were still evaluating the impact of the surprise move on the domestic market and would continue to watch developments closely.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday's announcement (on Apple's tie-up with Microsoft) does not mean at all that Apple has been taken over,&quot; said Eiko Harada, president of Apple's Japanese unit.</p>
<p>Harada said Apple will focus on a business strategy that will bring out its originality, addressing concerns among avid Japanese fans of Macintosh computers.</p>
<p>Harada also said the tie-up ensures further growth of Apple Computer's business and would not bring any change in how Apple conducted business in Japan.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Apple Computer and Microsoft announced a broad product and technology development agreement.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Microsoft will invest $150 million in non-voting stock of the troubled PC maker.</p>
<p>Microsoft will also develop more programmes for the Macintosh, including future versions of its Office software, Internet Explorer browser and other software.</p>
<p>Concurrently, Apple also replaced all but two of its directors, but stopped short of naming a new chairman of the board.</p>
<p>&quot;It was surprising to hear Microsoft offering a hand to Apple to prop up its long-time rival,&quot; said a spokesman for NEC Corp, Japan's top personal computer maker.</p>
<p>&quot;Nevertheless, Microsoft will be able to expand the market for its application software through the tie-up,&quot; the spokesman said. &quot;In the long term, Microsoft's Windows (operating system) may also be improved with technology employed from Apple.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for Fujitsu Ltd said the company had yet to fully evaluate the impact of the tie-up on the Japanese PC market, but that it would watch future developments closely.</p>
<p>In Japan, however, personal computer manufacturers are being hit by slackening demand.</p>
<p>Shipments of personal computers in Japan in the April-June period rose an anemic four percent from the same period last year to 1.7 million units, the Japan Electronic Industry Development Association said on Thursday.</p>
<p>This paled in comparison with 51 percent year-on-year growth in the April-June quarter last year.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the industry organisation blamed the waning growth in PC demand in large part on April's increase in the national sales tax.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
