<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788708" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apple shares continue to rise on Microsoft deal.</title>
<headline>Apple shares continue to rise on Microsoft deal.</headline>
<dateline>CUPERTINO, Calif. 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Apple Computer Inc. continued to soar on Thursday, reaching the highest level in 18 months amid optimism that the $150 million investment from Microsoft Corp. and a new board of directors will bolster the fortunes of the computer maker.</p>
<p>Separately, a source close to Grupo Carso said the Mexican conglomerate bought a 3 percent stake in Apple for $60 million at $16 per share. The source declined to give a date for the transaction.</p>
<p>Apple closed at $29.19, up $2.875 or 10.8 percent on Nasdaq, where it was the most active stock with 33 million shares changing hands. Earlier, the stock hit a 52-week high of $29.75. In the past month, the stock has more than doubled from $13.</p>
<p>Apple's surge on Wall Street made the stock options some Apple employees receive as part of their compensation extremely valuable for now.</p>
<p>&quot;I am doing great -- getting better. I'm selling all my Apple stock,&quot; said Dale Fuller, the former head of Apple's Powerbook division. &quot;Whoohoo!&quot; he shouted into his cellular phone as he drove down the freeway.</p>
<p>Options allow employees to buy their company's stock at a discount to the market price. Silicon Valley companies rely heavily on options to pay their employees.</p>
<p>In Apple's case, key employees were given stock options in July with an &quot;exercise price&quot; of $13.25 a share. One thousand of those options had a paper value of $16,500 Thursday as Apple stock hit $30 a share. Those same options were nearly worthless a month ago, when Apple's stock lingered at about $14.</p>
<p>There's one catch: Employees have to wait at least a year from this past July to cash the options in. Depending on various terms, they can only cash them in batches stretched over three to five years.</p>
<p>But Gilbert Amelio, the former Apple chairman who was ousted last month, may not have to wait as long to cash in on the company's revival.</p>
<p>Under his employment contract, Amelio received options on one million shares of Apple stock with an exercise price of $26.25 a share, making them worth nearly $2.94 million.</p>
<p>The options became vested after he left Apple.</p>
<p>On Wednesday Microsoft agreed to invest $150 million in one-time mortal enemy Apple, promised to continue to write business software for the Macintosh and agreed to share its technology with Apple.</p>
<p>Apple also revamped its board of directors. It named four computer industry heavyweights, including Oracle Corp. Chairman Larry Ellison, Intuit Inc. President Bill Campell, Apple co-founder Steve Jobs and former International Business Machines Corp. finance chief Jerome York.</p>
<p>&quot;Can you think of better news? This is very good for Apple,&quot; said Daniel Kunstler, analyst at JP Morgan Securities in San Francisco. Kunstler Thursday lifted Apple's stock rating to &quot;long-term buy&quot; from &quot;market performer.&quot;</p>
<p>Added David Wu, analyst at ABN AMRO Chicago Corp.: &quot;Yesterday, I would have said Apple doesn't have a future. Today I say it does.&quot;</p>
<p>The new board members bring lots of financial and marketing experience, something shareholders had criticised the previous board for not having, analysts said. The new all-star board also could make it easier for Apple to find a new chief executive.</p>
<p>The Cupertino, Calif., company has been without a CEO and chairman since Amelio was ousted a month ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CUPERTINO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
