<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="809004" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ADR REPORT - Oils strengthen in quiet trade.</title>
<headline>ADR REPORT - Oils strengthen in quiet trade.</headline>
<byline>Ian Simpson</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign oil companies strengthened Tuesday to highlight quiet trade in American Depositary Receipts (ADRs).</p>
<p>Traders said activity was subdued as the central bank's  Federal Open Market Committee met to map interest rate strategy. The policy-setting panel is expected to announce results of the meeting at 1415 EDT/1815 GMT, but analysts have said they expect no change in short-term rates.  </p>
<p>British Petroleum Co Plc rose 1-11/16 to 82-13/16 after NatWest analyst Fergus MacLeod raised his earnings forecast for the company.</p>
<p>MacLeod also reiterated his add recommendations for Royal Dutch Petroleum Co and Shell Transport and Trading Co Plc. Shell rose one to 41-1/2 and Royal Dutch, among the most-active ADRs in New York, was up 1-1/8 to 53-1/4.  </p>
<p>French oil major Elf Aquitaine rose 2-13/16 to 55-9/16 after it reported an oil discovery off Angola. The company called the find one of the biggest in Africa.</p>
<p>Israel's Check Point Software Technologies Ltd rose 15/16 to 23-15/16 after Morgan Stanley said it had started coverage of the ADRs with a rating of outperform. Check Point, which makes network security software, was the most-active ADR, with 1.1 million ADRs traded by mid-morning.  </p>
<p>Among other technology stocks, Franco-Italian semiconductor maker SGS-Thomson Microelectronics NV rose 3-3/16 to 95-3/16, a 12-month high.</p>
<p>Traders said the boost could have come because computer technology firm Bay Networks Inc said it expected first-quarter revenues to exceed analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>Leading Chinese ADRs sagged amid concerns about a speculative attack on the Hong Kong dollar. Beijing Yanhua Petrochemical Co Ltd fell 1-3/16 to 16-1/2 and Brilliance China Automotive Holdings Ltd was off 1/2 to 8-1/2.  </p>
<p>Both ADRs were among percentage-loss leaders on the New York Stock Exchange. Joining them were Japan's Sony Corp, which fell 3-1/16 to 94-11/16, and Kyocera Corp, which dropped 5-1/4 to 150.</p>
<p>Latin American ADRs were quiet.  Brazil's Telebras SA rose 3/16 to 126-15/16 and was among the most-active issues on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;Volumes have been down and clients are not doing anything at all,&quot; a Latin American trader said. &quot;Most of these markets are being driven by traders -- those that are in the office.&quot;  </p>
<p>Advancers led decliners 257 to 173 among 814 ADRs. The ADR group was up 0.36 percent and volume was 24 million ADRs.</p>
<p>ADRs allow U.S. trade of foreign shares.</p>
<p>((-- Wall Street desk, (212) 859-1879))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
