<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81554" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ted Turner and Rupert Murdoch are at war.</title>
<headline>Ted Turner and Rupert Murdoch are at war.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rupert Murdoch and Ted Turner, two of the world's most powerful media barons, are at war with each with Turner comparing Murdoch to Adolf Hitler and Murdoch vowing to get even.</p>
<p>While the two men and their surrogates trade verbal blows, their respective corporations are conducting a behind the scene battle that could wind up in court.</p>
<p>At issue is whether Time Warner, the nation's second largest cable operator, will carry Murdoch's soon to be launched competitor to CNN, the Cable News Network that is becoming part of the Time Warner empire.</p>
<p>Time Warner says no and in a brief encounter with reporters on Thursday, Turner accused Murdoch of using his newspapers as weapons in a media war, saying, &quot;Talking to Murdoch is like confronting the late Fuhrer.&quot; He also called the reporters who work for Murdoch, &quot;yellow journalists.&quot;</p>
<p>Murdoch later told the Wall Street Journal, &quot;Ted Turner will say much worse before it's through. I believe what (Joseph) Kennedy said: 'Don't get mad, get even'.&quot;</p>
<p>But on Friday, a top executive at Murdoch's News Corporation Ltd, decided to get mad at Turner's comments.</p>
<p>&quot;This kind of venal rhetoric has no place in a civilized society. Mr Turner's statement, which is one more expression of his personal animosity toward Mr Murdoch, must be viewed as deeply offensive not only to Mr Murdoch and his associates ... but to all people of good will,&quot; said Arthur Siskind, a News Corp. vice president and its general counsel.</p>
<p>He added, &quot;Mr Turner should not be allowed to utilize the monopolistic power of Time Warner to deprive programmers access to its cable systems to further his own personal vendetta.&quot;</p>
<p>Nor was Siskind the only angry man around. The head of the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, a leading Jewish civil rights organization, said he found Turner's remarks &quot;quite disturbing.&quot;</p>
<p>In a letter to Turner, the ADL's national director Abraham Foxman said, &quot;As many and as serious as your business or personal differences with Mr Murdoch are, comparing him to Hitler trivializes a profound historical tragedy. The comparison is an insult to the memory of the millions of victims of Nazism.&quot;</p>
<p>Murdoch plans to launch his 24-hour-a-day cable news channel on Oct. 7 and has billed it as a conservative alternative to what he perceives as Turner's liberal CNN, a cable operation he has often publicly stated he would love to buy and make the centerpiece of a media empire that spans the globe.</p>
<p>News Corp. executives are still smarting at Time Warner's decision to carry MSNBC's all news channel on about half its cable systems instead of Murdoch's Fox News Channel.</p>
<p>When the Federal Trade Commission gave its agreement for Time Warner to absorb the Turner Broadcasting System Inc at a cost of $6.7 billion, it said Time Warner had to offer its subscribers a second all-news channel.</p>
<p>News Corp thought it had a deal to be that second all news channel and was shocked to find out that it was not. But a Time Warner spokesman insisted no agreement was reached with Murdoch. Instead, one was reached with MSNBC, the news channel being offered by Microsoft and NBC.</p>
<p>A News Corp. spokeswoman said the company was pursuing all its options.</p>
<p>One strong possibility is going to court but company sources said that no decision had yet been made.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
