<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83433" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gates tops richest list for third time. [CORRECTED 30/9 15:10 GMT]</title>
<headline>Gates tops richest list for third time. [CORRECTED 30/9 15:10 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. co-founder Bill Gates is the richest person in America for the third year in a row, according to Forbes magazine.</p>
<p>In its issue reporting on the 400 wealthiest Americans, Forbes said the net worth of the 40-year-old billionaire has jumped to a staggering $18.5 billion, up almost $4 billion in just the last year.</p>
<p>The stock market's bull run had much to do with the big gain in the fortunes of those who made the Forbes list. &quot;That was a big part of it,&quot; said magazine spokesman Ray Healey. &quot;A lot of them have huge stock fortunes.&quot; </p>
<p>A prime example is Warren Buffett, 66, the famed Nebraska investor who came in second with a net worth of $15 billion. Third place was taken by another Microsoft billionaire, Paul Allen, 43, who helped Gates start the company 11 years ago and is worth $7.5 billion, according to Forbes.</p>
<p>To gain admission to this exclusive club, one needed a net worth of at least $415 million this year, up $75 million from 1995. And thanks in part to the strong stock market, the average net worth of those on the list exceeded $1 billion for the first time.</p>
<p>What can aspiring billionaires learn from this group? </p>
<p>&quot;Start a fabulous company -- and make sure you retain a hefty portion of the stock,&quot; said Healey.</p>
<p>Stock was a big reason the number of billionaires on the list this year grew to 135 (corrects from 121). The wealth of all 400 on the list totalled  $477 billion, (corrects combined net worth).</p>
<p>Interestingly, the magazine pointed out that ideas now lead to great fortune, where in years past wealth was made through owning hard assets such as land, steel or oil.</p>
<p>In the last decade the number of fortunes made in heavy industry has dropped from 103 to just 35. </p>
<p>This year eight of the new members of the list made their fortunes in computer software, and 20 who made the list got wealthy in that industry.</p>
<p>The financial field remains the top area where the wealthy made their money, with 51 members. The second field was gas or oil, with 29 of the wealthiest in the energy industry. Real estate was third, with 28 people making their money in land, followed by 20 people in software and 18 in retailing.</p>
<p>In the entertainment field, Star Wars producer George Lucas led with a net worth of $2 billion, followed by Steven Speilberg who is worth $1 billion, according to Forbes. </p>
<p>The wealthiest woman in entertainment is talk-show queen Oprah Winfrey, who is worth $415 million.</p>
<p>Like Oprah, more than half of those who made the list were not born wealthy -- 217 were self-made millionaires, Forbes said. One of them was Pamela Lopker, now worth $425 million, who made her fortune by starting a private software company and was the wealthiest self-made woman in the group.</p>
<p>The magazine found that 30 of its 400 richest Americans never attended college. And the 63 people on the list who did not have a college degree had a much higher average net worth than the college graduates on the list. </p>
<p>The two basic qualifications were U.S. citizenship, and a net worth -- assets minus liabilities -- of at least $415 million, up from the $340 million minimum for 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
