<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84422" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AOL to spend over $100 mln in new campaign.</title>
<headline>AOL to spend over $100 mln in new campaign.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>America Online Inc said on Monday that it plans to spend over $100 million on a new marketing campaign this quarter, which includes ads during prime-time U.S. network television, beginning this evening.</p>
<p>AOL chairman and CEO Steve Case told reporters on a conference call that the ad campaign is just &quot;one piece in the puzzle&quot; of the company's revamp into the new AOL.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to show how AOL is different,&quot; Case said. &quot;It really is the Internet and a whole lot more.&quot;</p>
<p>Case said the Dulles, Va.-based online service provider will spend more than $100 million this quarter on marketing.  </p>
<p>The television ads will be set to the theme music from the classic cartoon &quot;The Jetsons.&quot; The 60-second spot follows an entire family through its daily routine highlighting their individual uses of technology, from digital satellite televisions to cellular telephones to online services.</p>
<p>A series of 30 second spots will highlight individual family members using specific differentiated service features.</p>
<p>The campaign is targeted to PC owners who are not current AOL members and to AOL's current 6.2 million plus members, with the aim of distinguishing AOL from other online services and Internet access providers.  </p>
<p>Two weeks ago, America Online shares began trading on the New York Stock Exchange, and at the same time, it launched a revamp of its service with a new version of its software, more customer support, a focus on retaining current customers and an initiative to gain new members.</p>
<p>Case said that AOL has &quot;been in a period of rethinking, refocusing and seeing where consumer preferences are shifting.&quot;</p>
<p>AOL plans to continue spending heavily on marketing, and said that its spending will go beyond but will still include the mailing out of floppy disks of its service software. AOL will now work with several marketing partners in this effort.  </p>
<p>AOL will also develop a 1/2-hour infomercial and a video cassette that it expects will help it retain members and entice new members to join.</p>
<p>&quot;If each member of the AOL team could go personally to our customers and just spend 1/2 hour with them and show them features of the service, they would be in love with AOL forever,&quot; Case told reporters.</p>
<p>Case also said that AOL is on target to reach 10 million members next summer, up from over 6.2 million now.</p>
<p>&quot;We do think we can get to the 10 million by next summer,&quot; Case said. &quot;We think word of mouth is going to be very strong.&quot;  </p>
<p>Case said that AOL will achieve that goal by doing a better job than its rivals and because, as a service, AOL is a better interactive experience and it has greatly improved its Internet access and experience, with marketing deals with Microsoft Corp and Netscape Communications Corp.</p>
<p>AOL is also starting to label itself as an &quot;Internet online service&quot; because Case said AOL is the world's largest Internet access providers, because it brings the most users to the Internet.</p>
<p>-Therese Poletti.212/859-1728.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
