<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87329" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Vantive Corp drops on profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Vantive Corp drops on profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of software maker Vantive Corp fell more than eight percent on Nasdaq on Tuesday morning due to profit-taking, analysts said.</p>
<p>Shares of the Santa Clara, Calif.-based firm fell 5-1/4 to 59-1/2 in light trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a stock that has been very much on an upswing lately,&quot; said James Pickrel, an analyst at research firm Hambrecht &amp; Quist.</p>
<p>He said of the stock's decline, &quot;Given their run-up on fairly thin trading volume, I think it's just a couple of people doing a little profit-taking.&quot;  </p>
<p>Eric Upin, an analyst at Robertson Stephens, cited some insider selling by management and comments in the September 30 issue of Barron's that the stock may be overvalued.</p>
<p>&quot;It's frankly a difficult company to value ... there is a lot of difficulty in establishing what the long-term growth rate for the company is,&quot; Upin said.</p>
<p>&quot;Almost anyone that owns the stock, even if they bought in August, are up substantially, so there is a lot of profit,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Vantive's stock price has risen steadily from 25-1/2 on July 16 to 64-3/4 yesterday.</p>
<p>Company officials were not available for comment.</p>
<p>Pickrel said that despite today's sell-off, the company's fundamentals remain strong.</p>
<p>&quot;The company has been on a very strong product and market cycle, so the fundamentals and the performance of the stock have been very strong,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Vantive operates in the rapidly growing new area of customer interaction software, which allows clients to communicate more effectively with a customer support group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
