<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98058" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: School-yard slaughter computer game slammed in UK.</title>
<headline>School-yard slaughter computer game slammed in UK.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britons campaigning against guns following the massacre of 16 children in their Scottish village school called on Saturday for a ban on a computer game depicting a mass shooting in a schoolyard.</p>
<p>The American CD-ROM, entitled Schoolyard Slaughter, has been on sale in Britain for a year and has been distributed to many of the country's computer libraries.</p>
<p>Players are required to shoot at schoolchildren as they walk across the playground and score points if they hit them in the head.</p>
<p>The computer game was dreamed up before crazed gunman Thomas Hamilton opened fire on the four-and five-year-olds and their teacher in their school at Dunblane in March.</p>
<p>But Jacqueline Walsh, an organiser of the anti-handgun Snowdrop Campaign set up after the shooting, told reporters;</p>
<p>&quot;This should never have come into the country in the first place...the idea of shooting at children has never been socially acceptable.</p>
<p>&quot;It shows that computer libraries have to be more vigilant about what they've got, what images they promote. They should look through their stock and throw them out,&quot; Walsh said.</p>
<p>The British government is awaiting the conclusions of an independent inquiry into the Dunblane tragedy before deciding whether to tighten up restrictions on the ownership of handguns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
