<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99260" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Quarterdeck restructures, sees Q4 net loss.</title>
<headline>Quarterdeck restructures, sees Q4 net loss.</headline>
<dateline>MARINA DEL REY, Calif. 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Quarterdeck Corp said Monday its fourth quarter and year-end results will fall &quot;well below expectations&quot; because it is undertaking a comprehensive restructuring meant to return the company to profitability.</p>
<p>Costs associated with the restrcturing, previously announced acquisition-related charges and less-than-expected revenues will cause a significant charge to fourth quarter results, the company said.  </p>
<p>The company didn't specify the charge amount but said it will contribute to a net loss for the fiscal year ended September 30.</p>
<p>The restructuring includes about a 40 percent work force cut, a refocusing of its management around two business units and a new, direct marketing unit and plans to release a new version of its CleanSweep software and a new hard drive optimization utility, Partition-It, in the near future.</p>
<p>The company said it also completed a $20 million convertible preferred offering whose proceeds will be used for restructuring, working capital and general corporate purposes.  </p>
<p>Quarterdeck said the layoffs announced today were in addition to an 11 percent workforce cut announced in June.</p>
<p>At that point, the company had a total of 1,300 employees. A spokeswoman said Quarterdeck was now seeking to reduce its remaining 1,100 employees by about 40 percent.</p>
<p>According to First Call, analysts' mean estimate for the fourth quarter was for Quarterdeck to report earnings of $0.12 a share versus earnings of nil in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>For full year 1995, Quarterdeck reported earnings of $0.45 a share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARINA DEL REY, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
