<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99792" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Big Japanese bank sells part of Softbank holding.</title>
<headline>Big Japanese bank sells part of Softbank holding.</headline>
<byline>Kayako Watanabe</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Industrial Bank of Japan (IBJ) said on Monday it had sold part of its stake in aggressively expanding personal computer software wholesaler Softbank Corp, a move brokers said could weaken the share in the near term.</p>
<p>IBJ denied a weekend report in business daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun that said it planned to sell all of its Softbank holdings by March 31, but the article nevertheless helped push the share down by 330 yen (nearly $3) to 9,970 yen ($89) in Monday trade on the Tokyo Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the reason for IBJ's sale was that Softbank had been relying more on the capital market and short-term bank loans to fund its expansion than on IBJ, one of Japan's three long-term credit banks.</p>
<p>A Softbank spokesman said IBJ had sold 220,000 shares, worth five billion yen ($45.0 million), in June, lowering its stake to 0.4 percent, against 0.9 percent at the end of March. The bank now owns 223,000 Softbank shares, he said.</p>
<p>Although IBJ held less than a one percent stake in Softbank before the share sale, it was one of its main shareholders.</p>
<p>An IBJ spokesman confirmed the bank had sold part of its holding this year but declined to why or how many shares it had sold.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not comment on why we sold the shares as we do not comment on parties we have business relations with,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Softbank spokesman said the shares were purchased by a Softbank group company. He did not know whether IBJ would continue selling Softbank shares. &quot;The fact that we are reducing our business ties with the bank could be one reason for the bank's sale of our shares,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Since we publicly offered our shares in July 1994, our short-term demand for funds has been covered by bank loans and our long-term demand by funds raised from the capital market.&quot;</p>
<p>As of September 30, the major shareholders in Softbank were president Masayoshi Son, with about three percent, and Son's asset management firm MAC Inc with 47.85 percent.</p>
<p>Softbank is Japan's largest software distributor and has made a series of high-profile purchases or tie-ups.</p>
<p>Purchases include U.S. computer magazine publisher Ziff-Davis Publishing and tie-ups such companies as Australia's News Corp, Yahoo! Inc and Sega Enterprises Ltd. In September, Softbank announced the launch of 85 billion yen ($765 million) worth of domestic straight bonds. In August it said it would issue about 2.6 million new shares in a third-party allocation.</p>
<p>Hisao Suzuki, deputy general manager at Yamaichi Securities Co Ltd, said the IBJ sale meant a dissolution of the bank's cross-holding in Softbank, and this would put downward pressure on Softbank shares.</p>
<p>But the Softbank spokesman said the firm had no plans to sell the 20,000 IBJ shares it owns.</p>
<p>Cross-shareholding is a peculiarly Japanese business practice in which companies hold shares in each other to cement business relations and protect against hostile takeovers.</p>
<p>Ryoichi Ohta, general manager at Tokyo Securities, said as Softbank's share price had fallen below 10,000 yen ($90), this would invite some short-term buying, but overall, buying factors had been exhausted for the time being. ($1=111 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
