<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100297" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIAN IPO - VisualSoft (India) Ltd opening Oct 7.</title>
<headline>INDIAN IPO - VisualSoft (India) Ltd opening Oct 7.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following initial public issue (IPO) by India's Visualsoft (India) Ltd is open for public subscription on October 7, 1996:</p>
<p>						 -----oOo-----</p>
<p>			   VISUALSOFT (INDIA) LTD</p>
<p>Issue opens on October 7, 1996</p>
<p>			   No of Shares	  Aggregate</p>
<p>			   Face value Rs 10     value</p>
<p>			   (No millions)	 Rs million</p>
<p>Present Issue		  4.66		46.60</p>
<p>Reserved for promoters,</p>
<p>associates, banks,</p>
<p>  mutual funds		 2.27		22.70</p>
<p>Offer to Indian Public     2.39		23.90</p>
<p>The company is coming out with this public issue to finance a 100 percent export oriented software development centre. Set up under the government software technology park scheme, the unit will have the infrastructure adaptable to fast changing software technologies and training facility for employees.</p>
<p>The total cost of the project estimated at 67.50 million rupees is to be financed through 62.50 million rupees equity capital and five million rupees term loans. Out of the equity component promoters would bring in 31.50 million rupees and 31 million rupees will be from the promoters.</p>
<p>The company has entered into a marketing agreement with VisualSoft Inc. Dallas of the U.S. in which the American company will utilise the services of the company for all its off-shore software projects. Areas of operation of the company will be value added information services, internet applications, SAP consultancy, turnkey projects, migration, re-engineering, contract programming and system integration.</p>
<p>Premises for the unit has been taken on lease. Plant and machinery mainly comprises computer hardware equipment, networking equipment, communicating equipment and software packages. Machines and related equipment are in the process of being installed.</p>
<p>The company claims to orders worth 17.34 million rupees. This constitutes over 75 percent of the turnover projected for the first half of 1996-97. However the major part of the order in hand shown is from VisualSoft USA. Financial projections given by the company for the next three years are as follows:</p>
<p>						  (Rs. Million)</p>
<p>			   1996-97    1997-98     1998-99</p>
<p>Sales			22.50	56.25	 70.31</p>
<p>Profit after tax	 10.75	27.00	 32.00</p>
<p>Share capital	    62.50	62.50	 62.50</p>
<p>Reserves and surplus    7.62	22.16	 38.60</p>
<p>EPS (Rs)		    3.44	 4.33	  5.13</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
