<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100385" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Computer Associates to buy Cheyenne for $1.2 billion.</title>
<headline>Computer Associates to buy Cheyenne for $1.2 billion.</headline>
<byline>Eric Auchard</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computer Associates International Inc., a leading maker of software for businesses, said Monday it agreed to pay about $1.2 billion for Cheyenne Software Inc.</p>
<p>Computer Associates, the largest independent maker of business software for mainframe computers, said it will offer $30.50 in cash for each share of Cheyenne. Cheyenne's stock jumped $7.625 to $30 in afternoon trading on the American Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Computer Associates' stock gained 62.5 cents to $63.375 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>While investors applauded the announcement, industry analysts said they were puzzled by what they viewed as the expensive price Computer Associates agreed to pay.</p>
<p>&quot;This is departure from their standard practice,&quot; said UBS Securities analyst Joseph Farley. &quot;They are paying more than they ever have. There's clearly some synergies,&quot; he added. &quot;The question is whether those synergies are worth seven times sales.&quot;</p>
<p>Cheyenne reported revenues of $174.1 million in its fiscal year ending June 1996.</p>
<p>The deal, which has been rumoured for several months, has been unanimously approved by the boards of directors of both Cheyenne and Computer Associates, the companies said.</p>
<p>Roslyn, N.Y.-based Cheyenne makes storage management, anti-virus and communications software products designed to run on client/server networks in which personal computers are tied together in a network run by a larger computer, or server.</p>
<p>Computer Associates said Cheyenne's products will bolster its own systems management software offerings, which run on both client/server and mainframe computer networks. CA derives a majority of its revenues from mainframe software.</p>
<p>&quot;We are extremely excited by the synergistic nature of this acquisition,&quot; said CA Chairman Charles Wang.</p>
<p>Computer Associates said it will fund the acquisition through cash balances and existing credit facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;Cheyenne is the recognised leader in storage management solutions for the Windows NT and NetWare environments,&quot; Wang said in a statement. &quot;The addition of its product suite will strengthen our efforts in the desktop and LAN environments.&quot;</p>
<p>Computer Associates said it intended to retain all of Cheyenne's employees. It is expected that Cheyenne will operate as a division of Computer Associates and will continue to support its current distribution channel strategy.</p>
<p>Both companies are based on New York's Long Island.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Cheyenne successively waged an aggressive fight to fend off a $1 billion unwelcome takeover bid by McAffee Associates Inc, a rival maker of systems management and anti-virus software.</p>
<p>Since 1976, Computer Associates has grown through a campaign of approximately 60 acquisitions to become of the world's leading independent supplier of software.</p>
<p>Paul Mason, a software analyst with technology research firm International Data Corp. in Framingham, Mass., said the latest acquisition does not fit what he called &quot;the CA model, both in terms of acqusisitions and product strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to see where this fits in. If they were getting this at a great price, I could understand the deal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The companies scheduled a teleconference with Wall Street analysts Monday afternoon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
