<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100474" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cheyenne sees merger closing in two months.</title>
<headline>Cheyenne sees merger closing in two months.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cheyenne Software Inc said it expects the merger of the company into Computer Associates International Inc to close within the next two months, pending the receipt of federal regulatory approvals.</p>
<p>In a phone interview, Jeff Finkle, Cheyenne's vice president of corporate development and communications, also said Computer Associates had agreed to pay a breakup fee for an unspecified amount if the deal were to unwind.</p>
<p>Earlier Monday, the two companies said they had agreed to a merger in which Computer Associates would acquire Cheyenne Software for $30.50 per share, or about $1.2 billion in total.  </p>
<p>Folllowing the announcement, Cheyenne shares jumped to within a fraction of the share offer price.  At mid-morning Monday, they were at $30, up 7-5/8 points from Friday's close.</p>
<p>Trading was active with 5.9 million shares trading hands. Cheyenne had 38.9 million shares outstanding at June 30, 1996.</p>
<p>Computer Associates shares bounded back into postive territory Monday after intitially declining by as much as 1-5/8 points. Its shares were trading at 62-3/4, up 3/8 of a point in midmorning. Volume was a slim 5535,600 shares.</p>
<p>Asked if the acquisition deal involved a breakup fee, Finkle answered, &quot;Yes, but we are not quantifying&quot; the amount.  </p>
<p>The Cheyenne official declined to comment on when merger talks began between the two companies, or which side intitated the discussions.</p>
<p>The deal had been rumored for several months and comes after Cheyenne's successful effort earlier this year to rebuff an unwelcome takeover bid by McAfee Associates Inc, a direct Cheyenne rival.</p>
<p>Computer Associates officials declined to comment further on the merger agreement, saying they would answer questions at a press conference the two companies have scheduled in Manhattan at 1300 EDT/1700 GMT Monday afternoon.</p>
<p>Finkle said that besides the product synergies that will result from the merger, an attractive feature of Cheyenne's deal with Computer Associates was that &quot;fair treatment of our employees was specifically discussed&quot; as part of the talks.</p>
<p>In their joint statement, the two companies had said they expected to retain all of Cheyenne's employees.</p>
<p>Since 1976, Computer Associates has grown through a campaign of approximately 60 acquisitions to become of the world's leading independent suppliers of software.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
