<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100491" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Computer Assocs to buy Cheyenne for $1.2 bln.</title>
<headline>Computer Assocs to buy Cheyenne for $1.2 bln.</headline>
<dateline>ISLANDIA, N.Y. 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computer Associates International Inc and Cheyenne Software Inc said Monday they agreed to a merger in which Computer Associates will acquire Cheyenne through a cash offer of $30.50 per Cheyenne share.</p>
<p>The roughly $1.2 billion merger deal, which has been rumored for several months, has been unanimously approved by the boards of directors of both Cheyenne and Computer Associates, the companies said.</p>
<p>Computer Associates said it will fund the acquisition through cash balances and existing credit facilities.</p>
<p>Cheyenne stock closed at 22-3/8 Friday.  </p>
<p>Cheyenne offers a series storage management, anti-virus, and communications software products designed to run on client/server networks largely composed of personal computers.</p>
<p>Computer Associates said Cheyenne products will bolster its own systems management software offerings, which run on both client/server and mainframe computer networks. CA derives a majority of its revenues from mainframe software.</p>
<p>&quot;We are extremely excited by the synergistic nature of this acquisition,&quot; said CA Chairman and Chief Executive Charles Wang.  </p>
<p>&quot;Cheyenne is the recognized leader in storage management solutions for the Windows NT and NetWare environments,&quot; Wang said. &quot;The addition of its product suite will strengthen our efforts in the desktop and LAN environments.&quot;</p>
<p>Computer Associates said it intends to retain all of Cheyenne's employees.</p>
<p>It is expected that Cheyenne will operate as a division of Computer Associates, and that it will continue to aggressively support its current distribution channel strategy.</p>
<p>Both companies are based on Long Island, New York.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is a tremendous opportunity for our clients, business partners, employees, and shareholders,&quot;  said Cheyenne Chairman and CEO ReiJane Huai.</p>
<p>In the tender offer, Computer Associates said it seeks to purchase at least a majority of Cheyenne's outstanding shares.</p>
<p>It said consummation of the tender offer will be subject to the expiration or termination of any applicable antitrust waiting period and the receipt of all regulatory approvals.</p>
<p>Following completion of the tender offer, the subsidiary of CA will be merged into Cheyenne, and all of Cheyenne's shares not owned by Computer Associates will be converted into the right to receive $30.50 per share in cash.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the Roslyn Heights, N.Y.-based Cheyenne successively waged an aggressive fight to fend off a $1 billion unwelcome takeover bid by McAffee Associates Inc, a rival maker of systems management and anti-virus software.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLANDIA, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
