<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101518" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PC DOCS sinks after Q1 warning.</title>
<headline>PC DOCS sinks after Q1 warning.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in PC DOCS Group International Inc sank on Tuesday after the company warned its first quarter results would be below analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>PC DOCS was off 5.0 at 11.90 in heavy late morning turnover of 1.2 million shares on the Toronto Stock Exchange. The stock earlier plummeted to a low of 10.85.</p>
<p>On Nasdaq, the technology company's shares fell 3-3/4 to 8-7/8 on volume of 2.09 million shares.</p>
<p>PC DOCS said late Monday that its first quarter ended September 30 was softer than expected, resulting in weak revenue growth and lower earnings.  </p>
<p>PC DOCS said it expects revenues of about C$20 million, approximately 21 percent over the C$16.5 million revenues for the first quarter last year, but 17 percent below analysts' estimates.</p>
<p>First quarter earnings are expected to be break-even or slightly positive, compared with a restated C$0.12 per share in the first quarter last year.</p>
<p>&quot;This summer quarter, traditionally the weakest and most unpredictable quarter of the year, was softer than expected,&quot; said PC DOCS chairman, president and chief executive officer Rubin Osten.  </p>
<p>The revenue shortfall was due primarily to delays in contracts which are expected to be signed by the end of September, PC DOCS said.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel that our target markets, especially enterprise document management, are robust and continue to grow, and that this fluctuation in first quarter results is not necessarily indicative of our future growth trend,&quot; Osten said.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, some investment firms quickly lowered their recommendations on the company. U.S.-based Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette reduced its recommendation on PC DOCS to market perform from outperform, according to a DLJ source.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
