<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102931" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Phoenix rises from ashes of Europe Online.</title>
<headline>Phoenix rises from ashes of Europe Online.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Luxembourg-based online information service Europe Online SA, which shut down in August after going bankrupt, relaunched itself on Tuesday as a non-profit organisation promoting Europe on the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe Online is now a navigation service, a European gateway to the Internet,&quot; new president of the board Candace Johnson told Reuters.  </p>
<p>The association - Europe Online Asbl - is sponsored by Luxembourg P&amp;T state telecommunications company and was founded by former Europe Online SA employees. It said Jim Clark, chairman of Netscape Communications Corp, was among members of its honorary advisory board.</p>
<p>Europe Online Asbl said it was providing consumers with a user-friendly interface, easy navigation and information retrieval service for the Internet in various languages.</p>
<p>It does not provide Internet access itself, but acts as a framework for information and content providers in Europe to put their content on the World Wide Web.  </p>
<p>Johnson said a number of Internet service providers had shown interest in incorporating Europe Online in their services.</p>
<p>Membership dues and sponsors would finance the association's activities.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going back to the original idea (of Europe Online), which was to inspire and be a catalyst for all those people who were not online, to serve as a standardised platform on which people could put their content,&quot; added Johnson, who was previously a board member of Europe Online SA.  </p>
<p>The old company shut down in mid-August after last-ditch operation running failed.</p>
<p>Liquidators said at the time Europe Online had debts of about $40 million, of which about $30 million was in the form of loans from shareholders.</p>
<p>But Johnson said the sums were in part investments, adding, &quot;debts were closer to five million dollars.&quot;  </p>
<p>The unprofitable company suffered a financial blow in July when its biggest single shareholder, German publisher  Burda Holding GmbH, said it was pulling the plug on further funding.</p>
<p>Other shareholders included AT&amp;T Corp, Pearson Plc, and Luxembourg's Banque et Caisse d'Epargne de l'Etat (BCEE) and Societe Nationale de Credit et d'Investissement (SNCI).  </p>
<p>Despite its potential for growth in a burgeoning Internet market, Europe Online SA was plagued by shareholder disagreements over strategy since its formation in 1994 as a European-language alternative to U.S. services.</p>
<p>With about 25,000 subscribers, the multilingual Europe Online had national services in Germany, Britain and Luxembourg, as well as an international service in English, which included news, weather, travel, sports and entertainment.  </p>
<p>Tuesday's relaunch resulted from former supporters and employees of Europe Online SA purchasing the rights to the name, software and service of the company.</p>
<p>Over the next few weeks the group planned to re-install some features of the old service. These included &quot;Member City,&quot; which lets people make home pages on the Internet, and &quot;Chat&quot; -- a facility to tap into live news from radio stations around the world, as well as Internet video conferencing possibilities.  </p>
<p>The group said it was providing gateways to the Internet for France, Germany, Britain, Sweden, The Netherlands and Luxembourg. It hopes to add Italy, Portugal, Belgium, Finland, Austria and Spain in the next few months, followed by the remaining countries of Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
