<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105518" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New CD-ROM for teen girls has benefits, blemishes.</title>
<headline>New CD-ROM for teen girls has benefits, blemishes.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Attention teenagers! Did it ever dawn on you that the clueless behaviour of your parents might be an early warning sign that they are actually Martians posing as Earthlings? Ask yourself these questions:</p>
<p>Does your parent spit on a finger to remove dirt from your face?</p>
<p>Has your parent's hair style remained unchanged since the Stone Age?</p>
<p>Does your parent think communication means listening respectfully to his or her two-hour lectures?</p>
<p>Does your parent usually call you by the name of your brother or sister?</p>
<p>Do your parents live by the slogan: &quot;If at first they don't succeed, nag, nag again?&quot;</p>
<p>If you answered &quot;yes&quot; to enough of these questions, it's clear that your home is harbouring extraterrestrials, according to one of the activities &quot;Let's Talk About Me&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $30), Simon &amp; Schuster Interactive's new CD-ROM for preteen and teenage girls.</p>
<p>This is the latest in a small assortment of computer products designed for young women, none of which have been extraordinarily successful. The computer market is still overwhelmed by male-oriented shoot-em-ups and other products that appeal primarily to testosterone-enriched consumers.</p>
<p>With a sense of humour and a smart, hip perspective on a difficult time in a woman's life, &quot;Let's Talk&quot; offers a password-protected diary, address book, virtual hair salon, horoscopes, interviews with 23 successful women and a lot of other features.</p>
<p>Like the teenage years themselves, &quot;Let's Talk&quot; is an uneven mixture of good and bad.</p>
<p>The &quot;My Body&quot; section has great information about the physical changes that take place in the teenage years, along with general answers to questions about sexual issues, and a game show called &quot;I Kid You Not,&quot; which pretends to award fabulous prizes as it queries players on &quot;the most awkward and embarrassing time of your life -- puberty!&quot; (Unfortunately, the game doesn't always explain why the wrong answers are wrong).</p>
<p>The &quot;Parents From Mars&quot; section offers well-reasoned tips on how to survive your parents' upbringing. The &quot;True Stories&quot; section features crude cartoons designed to help a girl weigh her options when dealing with important real-life issues, such as buying feminine hygiene products.</p>
<p>There are quizzes designed to convey information about the ways of avoiding AIDS and other sexually-transmitted diseases.</p>
<p>It's all done in a way that makes teens want to listen instead of feeling they're being lectured to.</p>
<p>While other sections demonstrate some care, sensitivity and research, &quot;Let's Talk&quot; completely loses its down-to-earth attitude in the &quot;My Future&quot; section. Instead of giving girls more information to help them take control of their lives, the game promotes superstitions like astrology, palm reading, biorhythms, and psychic powers.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's Talk&quot; also has intimate interviews with 23 successful women, but most of those &quot;interviews&quot; are nothing more than some pictures and text. Only a few women are shown in video clips.</p>
<p>The games in &quot;Let's Talk&quot; appear under the heading &quot;Waste O' Time.&quot; You'll agree its an appropriate name after you've played the handful of picture jumbles and two memory games a few times. They don't hold your attention for long. Also, the repetitive music can get annoying very quickly.</p>
<p>Finally, there's an electronic scrapbook, planner, address book and computerized diary, where a teen can type her most private thoughts. Unfortunately, the diary entries may not stay secret. Even though it's protected by a dual password system (you need one password to log into &quot;Let's Talk&quot; and another when you actually go into the diary), it took me less than five minutes for me to open the diary files using a standard word processing programme and decode the messages.</p>
<p>And, believe me, if a brother or sister doesn't try to peek in your &quot;secret&quot; diary, your parents from Mars might.</p>
<p>Now if you'll excuse me, I have to go. I just spotted some dirt on my daughter's face.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;MegaRace 2&quot; (Mindscape, DOS, $50) -- Lance Boyle, the world's most annoying game show host, is back as the star in this racing simulation against seven bloodthirsty opponents who can resort to bombs, missiles and oil slicks to win.</p>
<p>&quot;Azrael's Tear&quot; (Mindscape, DOS, $45) -- You need to find the Holy Grail &quot;and return its healing power to a foresaken planet&quot; by getting past all sorts of creatures guarding the legendary chalice of the Last Supper.</p>
<p>&quot;9&quot; (GT Interactive, Windows95, $55) -- The voices of Cher, Jim Belushi and Christopher Reeve give life to this story about &quot;The Last Resort,&quot; a getaway for artisans who need inspiration. You must enlist the help of nine muses to find out who is ruining the resort.</p>
<p>&quot;Area 51&quot; (GT Interactive, Windows95, $55) -- Admit it. You've read the supermarket tabloids. You know the U.S. government is hiding space aliens and their UFO at Area 51, the top-secret military base in Nevada. Now you can do something about it. This game lets you blast extraterrestrials and wipe out an alien infection in a site. The product claims to offer &quot;an accurate recreation of the most secretive airbase in the world.&quot; But if the air base is so secret, how will we know if GT Interactive is lying to us?</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
