<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107254" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Microsoft CFO on spending.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Microsoft CFO on spending.</headline>
<dateline>REDMOND, Wash. 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp will spend more than $500 million, or 25 percent of its research and development budget for the current fiscal year, on media efforts such as its on-line service and MSNBC news venture, a top executive said Thursday.</p>
<p>Microsoft Chief Financial Officer Mike Brown said in an interview that the remaining 75 percent of the company's $2.1 billion R&amp;D budget for the year ending June 30, 1997, is reserved for projects related to the company's core businesses of computer operating systems and desktop applications.  </p>
<p>Earlier Microsoft officials said they planned to spend $100 million in the current fiscal year on marketing the MSN on-line service, which they did not expect to become profitable for at least three years.</p>
<p>In addition, the software giant has committed $230 million over five years, in addition to its $220 million initial investment, in the MSNBC cable television and Internet news venture.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're making an investment. It's a very serious investment. It'a very important investment,&quot; Brown said. Still, he said, it was not yet &quot;clear whether they would become profitable.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's an evolving business model,&quot; he said. &quot;But the business model for software wasn't clear 21 years ago when our company was started.&quot;</p>
<p>He emphasized that the company relied on its &quot;strong billing engines&quot; of desktop applications and operating systems, and poured the bulk of its R&amp;D spending back into those businesses.</p>
<p>And he acknowledged that the on-line ventures represented &quot;a big bet.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;That's why it's great to have Bill,&quot; he said, referring to Microsoft Chairman Bill Gates. &quot;He's good at making big bets.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Seattle bureau 206-386-4848</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="REDMOND, Wash."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
