<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108730" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft's new MSN to be heavy on entertainment.</title>
<headline>Microsoft's new MSN to be heavy on entertainment.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>REDMOND, Wash. 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Declaring their belief that the Internet will be the &quot;next mass medium,&quot; Microsoft Corp. executives Thursday unveiled the new version of the company's MSN online service, with a heavy emphasis on entertainment programming.</p>
<p>Despite bandwidth limitations and other technical obstacles that make full-motion video impractical, many of the new MSN programmes resemble daily and weekly television shows, with the service organised into six core &quot;channels&quot; aimed at specific demographic groups.</p>
<p>In little more than a year, MSN has become the No. 3 online service, with 1.6 million subscribers. Company executives told a news briefing they expected to double that figure by mid-1997 and take market share from leader America Online Inc., relying in large part on a $100 million marketing campaign.</p>
<p>But the executives, conceding that the older America Online had a deeper and broader selection of content, said they planned to compete for new online customers, especially those under 30, rather than trying to persuade existing AOL customers to switch.</p>
<p>They were eager to heap criticism on the existing MSN service, launched along with the Windows 95 operating system in August 1995 but almost immediately overtaken by the rapid growth of the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;MSN was probably the worst of the bunch in terms of ease of use,&quot; said Laura Jennings, Microsoft vice president for the online service.</p>
<p>But she also noted that the service had been gaining 100,000 subscribers a month despite virtually no advertising and problems, including a computer snafu that has delayed bills to most customers for three months or more.</p>
<p>The new ad campaign will begin almost immediately with billboards and print advertisements followed by television commercials beginning in early November, when the service officially launches.</p>
<p>Microsoft also announced a new pricing scheme with an offer of unlimited access for $19.95 a month, instead of 20 hours for the same price under the current service. The minimum monthly fee will rise to $6.95 for five hours, in line with rival services and up from $4.95 for three hours under the current service.</p>
<p>The heart of the relaunched MSN is an uncluttered browser interface dominated by a promotional &quot;billboard&quot; in the centre of the screen and the six &quot;channels&quot; at the bottom corresponding to broad categories such as news, entertainment, education and children.</p>
<p>Clicking on the channels leads into programming developed by Microsoft and its partners that ranges from the MSNBC news service to new interactive serial programmes. Among the programmes demonstrated were quiz shows, a humorous daily news audiocast and magazine-type presentations such as &quot;Underwire,&quot; produced by and for women.</p>
<p>The service also includes electronic mail, &quot;chat&quot; and a more traditional menu of online categories that leads users to areas within MSN or out on the Internet.</p>
<p>Most content in the service will be restricted to subscribers using the company's Windows 95 computer operating system and Internet Explorer browser, and executives would not say whether they have plans to produce a version for the older Windows 3.1 system still used by tens of millions of computer owners.</p>
<p>Some features of MSN, including MSNBC news, electronic shopping and the planned Expedia consumer travel service, will be available at no cost to anyone with access to the Internet.</p>
<p>Patty Stonesifer, Microsoft senior vice president for interactive media, said the company's broad involvement in online consumer services was driven by &quot;our belief that the Internet is the next mass medium.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to provide compelling reasons to go online and stay online,&quot; she said. &quot;There aren't enough compelling reasons to do that today.&quot;</p>
<p>By some estimates, only 10 million of the nation's 99 million households are currently online, though others say even that figure is high.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="REDMOND, Wash."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
