<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110338" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada team seeks rich pickings in Russia, Poland.</title>
<headline>Canada team seeks rich pickings in Russia, Poland.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A trade mission heading next week for Russia and Poland will try to make the hottest areas for Canada in Eastern Europe even hotter, Canadian foreign affairs officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>International Trade Minister Art Eggleton will lead the trip to Poland from October 13 to 15 and to Russia from October 15 to 19.</p>
<p>&quot;We're nowhere near our potential (in Russia),&quot; one Canadian official told a briefing. &quot;There's a lot of good money to be made.&quot;  </p>
<p>Representatives from nearly 60 companies are heading to Russia and from nearly 30 companies are doing the Poland leg.</p>
<p>&quot;Poland has become, perhaps to the surprise of many observers, the darling of Central European countries,&quot; a Canadian official with Polish expertise said.</p>
<p>Canada directly exported about C$200 million (US$150 million) in goods and C$300 million ($225 million) in services to Russia in 1995, and in the first half of this year it has already sold C$150 million ($112 million) of goods. It exports a lot more through third countries.  </p>
<p>In return it bought about C$500 million ($375 million) in Russian goods last year, though imports this year are down.</p>
<p>Forty to 50 percent of its exports to Russia are in the oil and gas industry, but it has also made inroads in advance technology and telecommunications and in agri-food.</p>
<p>Exports of Canadian goods to Poland were only slightly below that to Russia, at C$180 million ($145 million) while imports from Poland were C$120 million ($90 million).</p>
<p>Montreal-based aircraft maker Bombardier Inc is heading to both countries. In Poland it is interested in the reshaping of the national airline PLL LOT.  </p>
<p>Numerous high-tech companies are going, among them Northern Telecom Ltd, Newbridge Networks Corp and Corel Corp. Within the next month, Corel is expected to launch a Russian version of its Word Perfect Suite.</p>
<p>The Canadian Wheat Board, interested in promoting cash rather than credit sales, is also participating. Russia used to be one of its largest customers but is not buying CWB grain currently.</p>
<p>Officials say hundreds of Canadian companies have inquired in the last year about the possibility of doing business in Russia.</p>
<p>The Canadian government stresses the market carries the risk of political and financial uncertainty and possible changing regulations but encourages companies, particularly with export experience, to take the plunge.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Ottawa Bureau (613) 235-6745</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
