<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111037" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Time Warner sues NYC over use of channels. [CORRECTED 12/11 10:05 GMT]</title>
<headline>Time Warner sues NYC over use of channels. [CORRECTED 12/11 10:05 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Time Warner Entertainment Co said Friday it has filed a lawsuit to prevent New York City from forcing it to carry News Corp Ltd's Fox News Service or Bloomberg News Service on its municipally owned cable television system in the city.</p>
<p>The lawsuit is the latest in a series of legal tangles over the proposed merger of Time Warner and Turner Broadcasting System Inc. The lawsuit was filed in the Federal District Court for the Southern District of New York.  </p>
<p>Time Warner said it also is seeking a temporary restraining order, and a preliminary and permanent injunction barring the city from carrying Fox News Service or Bloomberg News Service on the city's cable channels.</p>
<p>Time Warner contends that the city has been trying to force it to carry those programs, which it said is a violation of its constitutional rights.</p>
<p>Time Warner, which holds city cable-television franchises serving 1.2 million New Yorkers, and Turner Broadcasting System are in the midst of a pending merger.  </p>
<p>The deal has prompted News Corp, the owner of the new 24-hour Fox News Channel, to file a lawsuit seeking to block it. News Corp alleges that the merger would violate antitrust laws.</p>
<p>News Corp also has accused Time Warner of backing out of a deal to carry its Fox News Channel at the behest of Ted Turner, the founder of Turner Broadcasting (TBS) and Cable News Network (CNN), a Fox competitor.  </p>
<p>In Time Warner's suit against the city, the company said it never ruled out carrying the 24-hour Fox news channel. The company said it only decided to support the MSNBC channel to honor an agreement with the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;Time Warner has never decided not to enter into an agreement with Fox News, but only chose to enter into an immediate agreement with MSNBC in order to timely fulfill its obligations under the consent decree,&quot; the suit said.  </p>
<p>Time Warner reached an agreement in September with the FTC for a consent decree that would permit its merger with Turner. As part of that pact, Time Warner was obligated to run independent news programming on some of its cable systems.</p>
<p>In New York City, Time Warner carries CNN, CNNfn, Headline News and CNN Classroom, all owned by Turner.  It also carries MSNBC, a joint venture of General Electric Co's NBC unit and Microsoft Corp, (corrects to clarify programs owned by Turner).</p>
<p>Time Warner said it had talked with both Fox and MSNBC about programming, but chose MSNBC.  </p>
<p>&quot;Notwithstanding the absence of any commitment from Time Warner, Rupert Murdoch and his Fox News employees had apparently been assuming that their channel would be carried by Time Warner instead of MSNBC. That assumption was baseless,&quot; Time Warner said in the suit.</p>
<p>Spokesmen for Fox were not immediately available.</p>
<p>Time Warner alleges that the city's efforts violate the company's right to &quot;exercise editorial discretion over its cale system.&quot;</p>
<p>The suit also says that what the city is doing is a violation of their Franchise Agreements and of federal cable laws &quot;which limit governmental and educational access channels to educational and government purposes, not commercial ones.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
