<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114393" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SoftKey signs new distributor pacts in Asia.</title>
<headline>SoftKey signs new distributor pacts in Asia.</headline>
<dateline>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>SoftKey International Inc., a leading provider of educational computer software, said Monday it signed multimillion-dollar agreements for the distribution of its products in South Korea, Taiwan and eventually China.</p>
<p>SoftKey, creator of educational software ranging from the Reader Rabbit series for pre-school children to preparation programmes for college entrance exams, said it signed exclusive distribution agreements with Daekyo Computer Systems Co. Ltd. of South Korea and MiTac Inc. of Taiwan.</p>
<p>Financial terms of the agreements were not disclosed.</p>
<p>&quot;These two exclusive agreements should give SoftKey a substantial foothold in Pacific Rim markets,&quot; said David Patrick, president of SoftKey's International Division.</p>
<p>Under the agreements, SoftKey's products will be made and sold in South Korea and Taiwan. SoftKey's units include the Learning Co., MECC and Compton's.</p>
<p>SoftKey, which is based in Cambridge, Mass., said the new distributor partnerships will focus on adapting SoftKey products to correspond with regional teaching methods and to reflect local cultures.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to distributing the English-language versions of our programmes, we will be translating SoftKey's award-winning educational products into the local languages,&quot; Patrick said.</p>
<p>A leader in multimedia education in Korea, Daekyo Computer Systems is part of Daekyo Group, which has interests in trade, broadcast, publishing, computer distribution and education.</p>
<p>SoftKey said its products will be distributed through Daekyo's extensive network of consumer retail and educational outlets, and its correspondence-education business, which boasts more than 1.5 million members.</p>
<p>MiTac's distribution network covers consumer retail and educational outlets throughout Taiwan. It is developing a similar infrastructure in China.</p>
<p>SoftKey's stock added 50 cents to $21.125 in late trading on the Nasdaq market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAMBRIDGE, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
