<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114457" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft to appeal ruling on workers.</title>
<headline>Microsoft to appeal ruling on workers.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp plans to appeal a ruling that its temporary and contract workers may be eligible for stock options and pension benefits, a spokesman for the software company said Monday.</p>
<p>Earlier this month an Appeals Court panel ruled two to one against Microsoft in a class-action lawsuit brought by former contract workers, who said they were eligible for the same benefits as permanent company employees.</p>
<p>The case has attracted national attention because of the increasing prevalence of temporary workers throughout the economy.  </p>
<p>Microsoft spokesman Mark Murray said the company plans to seek review by a full nine-judge panel of the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit in San Francisco.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident this recent decision is not going to be the last word in the case,&quot; Murray said.</p>
<p>Murray said &quot;potentially hundreds of people&quot; could be affected by the ruling, but plaintiffs' lawyers argued the number would be well over 1,000, with some former workers eligible for options worth hundreds of thousands of dollars due to the rapid rise in Microsoft's stock price.</p>
<p>The case was brought in 1993 on behalf of workers who had been at Microsoft beginning in 1987.  Plaintiffs contend the class includes the company's temporary and contract workers through the present, while Microsoft says the case only covers the period ending in 1990.</p>
<p>Murray also said that since the late 1980s the company has restructured the way it handles contract workers.  Now &quot;virtually all&quot; such workers are hired through agencies that handle pay and benefits, Murray said.</p>
<p>-- Seattle bureau 206-386-4848</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
