<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118697" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: DirecTV to launch satellite broadcasting in Japan.</title>
<headline>DirecTV to launch satellite broadcasting in Japan.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>DirecTV Japan Inc, a group company of Hughes Electronics Corp of the United States, said on Tuesday that it would start a digital satellite broadcasting service in Japan in autumn 1997.  </p>
<p>DirecTV will become the third digital satellite broadcasting company to start broadcasting in Japan after PerfecTV, which is owned by a consortium headed by trading company Itochu Corp, and J-SkyB, which is due to be launched next April.</p>
<p>J-SkyB is a venture between Australian media tycoon Rupert Murdoch's News Corp Ltd and Japan's Softbank Corp.</p>
<p>PerfecTV launched its service earlier this month.</p>
<p>A statement from DirecTV did not say exactly when in  the autumn of 1997 its service would be launched.  </p>
<p>Michael Armstrong, chairman of Hughes Electronics, said DirecTV would differentiate itself from two other services by offering a higher quality service and competitive pricing.</p>
<p>&quot;We have experience in the United States,&quot; he told a news conference. &quot;We came to the U.S. market second ... and today we have two million subscribers.&quot;</p>
<p>Armstrong also said DirecTV would join a study group to develop a common receiver if the government agreed.</p>
<p>Such receivers would allow users to access broadcasting services provided by the three firms. Murdoch has said he hopes to tie up with PerfecTV by sharing a receiver.  </p>
<p>It also said that Mitsubishi Corp and Mitsubishi Electric Co  6503 T had each acquired a five percent stake in DirecTV, raising its total capitalisation to 10.3 billion yen.</p>
<p>Matsushita Electric Industrial Co, Dai Nippon Printing Co, and the Mitsubishi group's satellite company Satellite Communications Corp (SCC) already own stakes in DirecTV.</p>
<p>DirecTV said it would launch its 100-channel service using SCC's Superbird C communications satellite, which will be launched in June 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
