<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120646" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: &quot;Pyst&quot; CD-Rom Parody is a &quot;Myst&quot; Opportunity.</title>
<headline>&quot;Pyst&quot; CD-Rom Parody is a &quot;Myst&quot; Opportunity.</headline>
<byline>GENE EMERY</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's a parody of the best-selling computer game &quot;Myst.&quot; It was developed by two guys from the old Firesign Theatre troupe. It stars actor John Goodman as the king. It has Goodman singing the theme song. How can you resist?</p>
<p>Take some advice. Resist.</p>
<p>&quot;Pyst&quot; (Parroty Interactive, Windows/Macintosh) is a big disappointment, apparently created by some buddies at a party who ran out of funny ideas long before their clever concept for a &quot;Myst&quot; spoof was fully fleshed out.</p>
<p>The premise: Beautiful Myst island has been turned into a dump by the four million people who have come to visit.</p>
<p>Instead of the sounds of waves serenely lapping against the wharf, you get the gurgling of toxic waste and Octoplex tour guides telling you about the plans to give the island a jet-ski marina, ferry landing, and underground casino topped by a 96-hole miniature golf course.</p>
<p>Goodman's brief efforts are wasted as King Mattruss. His two sons, Prince Syrup and The Prince, &quot;formerly known as Prince,&quot; don't get to do much either.</p>
<p>The animation is crude and there are only 10 scenes in the parody (unless you count some of the pseudopostcards whose only apparent purpose is to fatten the product).</p>
<p>There are humorous video clips on the Pyst Mumbo-Jumbo TV Network, which are reminiscent of Peter Bergman and Phil Proctor's wacky stint with The Firesign Theatre. There are several inside jokes, one of which is in the form of a pseudo advertisement for a group called Gamer's Anonymous. &quot;Are you an addict?&quot; it reads. &quot;Meeting every night in the tower -- if you can find us.&quot;</p>
<p>But most of the material in this parody is neither witty nor funny.</p>
<p>If you spend $15 on this product expecting lots of laughs, the island won't be the only thing that's &quot;Pyst.&quot;</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Here's a bizarre concept: a game involving Beavis and Butt-head where you're expected to know something.</p>
<p>That's what you get in &quot;Weiner Takes All&quot; (Viacom NewMedia, Windows95, $20), a trivia game featuring America's best-known morons where the emphasis is on questions involving musical groups or flatulence.</p>
<p>Although I love trivia games, &quot;Weiner Takes All&quot; is an exercise in annoyance. It's hard to concentrate on which type of bean produces the most intestinal gas when the Beav &amp; Butt are constantly blathering during the questions.</p>
<p>This game is best played during drunken parties where people on the other side of the room are coming up with ideas for Myst parodies.</p>
<p>Viacom is also releasing &quot;Little Things,&quot; which consists of seven Beavis and Butt-head mini-games, four of which were already released as part of &quot;Beavis and Butt-head in Virtual Stupidity.&quot;</p>
<p>Like &quot;Weiner Takes All,&quot; these games are rated for ages 13 and older, which brings up a problem for Viacom: The games are so mindless and technically crude, most kids would have outgrown them by the time they're 13.</p>
<p>Even if you're entranced by games involving spitting, burping and, well, you know, here's another case where self-restraint will serve you well.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>&quot;Nine Worlds&quot; from Palladium Interactive (Windows/Macintosh, $40) has its share of silliness, but this delightful multimedia look at our solar system doesn't let the whimsy overwhelm all the NASA photographs, animations and computer simulations that bring the sun, its nine planets, and the rings and moons to life.</p>
<p>Although the resolution in the videos is a little grainy, the music is wonderful and Star Trek captain Patrick Stewart provides the narration for this easy-to-use planet-by-planet primer, which also explores the history of astronomy over nine time periods, touching on topics such as &quot;Science Fiction&quot; and &quot;Women in Astronomy.&quot;</p>
<p>If you want a lighter approach, you can click on the &quot;Nine Worlds&quot; Vacation Planner to see postcards from the planets, discover how much you would weigh on each surface, and figure out how many years it would take to reach a planet going at the speed of a passenger jet. For a trip to Saturn, expect to get there on October 16, 2147.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Space Station Alpha: The Encounter&quot; (TeraMedia, Windows/Macintosh, $45) is part of the &quot;Time Blazers&quot; series and provides both education and entertainment for ages 8 to 12. This adventure requires players to enter an abandoned alien spacecraft, then master strange devices and new skills to find out what's behind a secret door.</p>
<p>&quot;Bedlam&quot; (GT Interactive, DOS/Windows95, $55) -- Biomechanical creatures that once handled menial household chores have mutated and taken over the planet. Guess who has to stop them. Guess who gets to shoot lots of weaponry.</p>
<p>&quot;Mike Mulligan and His Steam Shovel&quot; (Houghton Mifflin Interactive, Windows/Macintosh, $20) -- This computerized version of the 50-year-old children's story is narrated by actress Madeline Kahn. It also has biographical information on author Virginia Lee Burton.</p>
<p>&quot;Learn to Speak French&quot; (The Learning Company, Windows/Macintosh, $90) is billed as a complete interactive course designed for adults, high school and college students. It also covers history, geography and customs.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
