<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124809" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Artisoft, Dialogic collaborate.</title>
<headline>Artisoft, Dialogic collaborate.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senior executives of Artisoft Inc and Diologic Corp said they will unveil the first phase of a strategic relationship to provide computer telephony for small- and medium-sized businesses on Thursday.</p>
<p>The two companies plan to develop products that combine Artisoft's expertise in networking, communications software and computer channel with Dialogic's hardware and computer telephony capabilities to expand use of the technologies.</p>
<p>The companies initially plans to introduce an information- on-demand product, InfoFast v1.0, during a three-week, 16-city recruitment and training tour next month for prospective value- added channel partners.</p>
<p>The product, to be initially demonstrated in the United States and Canada and due to ship on November 18, offers 24- hour automated access to fax documents, Web documents and voice recordings via facsimile or phone for a suggested price of $1,995. An enhanced version is due in first half of 1997.</p>
<p>The training includes 3.5 hours of technical instruction.</p>
<p>The companies did not disclose financial details.</p>
<p>One of the executives said they were working with Ingram Micro as distribution partner for the products.  </p>
<p>&quot;The CT market has been growing very rapidly, but not yet really within the traditional computer channels, and I think both companies are taking significant investment of money, time, effort to take open systems and bring it into the computer channel,&quot; said Dialogic Chief Executive Howard Bubb.</p>
<p>Will Keiper, chairman and chief executive of Artisoft, said the partnership grew out of a relationship between Dialogic and Stylus Innovation Inc, a Cambridge, Mass.-based company Artisoft acquired in February for $12.8 million cash.</p>
<p>Artisoft has a network of around 20,000 PC resellers worldwide and is rated top in market share in interactive voice response systems, according to Dataquest, while Dialogic has a leading position in open systems computer telephony.</p>
<p>The U.S. computer telephony integration market is expected to grow from shipments valued at around $2.0 billion in 1996 to nearly $7.0 billion in 1999, according to Dataquest.  </p>
<p>Keiper, who said last month the company's objective is to accelerate the development, delivery and customer acceptance of new communications products, said that &quot;in the case of our solutions the software we expect to be north of 90 percent margins...that's the model that we have been moving toward.&quot;</p>
<p>Bubb said the products will be essentially bundled by the distributor, but require close technological cooperation to make them work successfully.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clear our margins are in a high volume segment. Our gross margins are in the 50 percent range. Obviously we're doing significant promotional support activities so our actual margins on this program are much less,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
