<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128289" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian Artwork Systems paints rosy picture.</title>
<headline>Belgian Artwork Systems paints rosy picture.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Artwork Systems, a Belgian hi-tech company specialising in graphic design processing software and looking to list on Europe's growth stocks market Easdaq, expects further heady growth of sales and profits.</p>
<p>Started just over four years ago with a capital of three million Belgian francs, Artwork Systems wormed itself into the lucrative niche of pre-press software, either supplying printers themselves or via distributors.</p>
<p>Founders Guido Van der Schueren, Peter Denoo and Bart Denoo, all three managing directors, identified a hole in the post-design and pre-printing market, which will have netted them over 200 million Belgian francs in the year to September 30, 1996.</p>
<p>On sales of over 385 million francs that is a chunky margin, mainly because the bulk of costs for research and development and marketing are fixed and covered for, Denoo said. Taxes were the chief factor biting in profits.</p>
<p>Sales in 1995/96 were almost three times the 1994/95 level, profits almost four times the year-ago level and the bull run was not over yet, Denoo said. He forecast an average growth rate of 40 percent for the years ahead for sales and profits.</p>
<p>Sales in the year just ended -- 90 percent went abroad -- were mainly of Artworks' primary product ArtPro, which runs on Power MacIntosh computers, the print industry's standard. ArtPro is aimed at the packaging and labelling market.</p>
<p>The new addition to the range, ArtPro Repro, is for the catalogue, brochure, magazine and advertising markets and together with ArtPro will give Artwork comprehensive cover of the market for products converting a designer's work into print.</p>
<p>The tools allow users to turn the design, often still on paper, into a digital picture which can be adjusted to the size of the product to be packaged, coloured in and the colours turned into electronic print instructions.</p>
<p>The Artwork managers told a presentation of the company other desk-top publishing software was either less expensive but also much less sophisticated or was part of expensive hi-end systems encompassing the whole design-to-print run.</p>
<p>They say their products are open, meaning they can run on any hardware.</p>
<p>The market for ArtPro label and packaging software packages is estimated at over 12,000, Van der Schueren said. Unaudited figures showed Artwork sales in 1995/96 were close to 2,000, up from 200 in January 1995 just before Artwork's breakthrough.</p>
<p>The market for ArtPro Repro is estimated at 80,000 packages.</p>
<p>But the Artwork managers say they are not seeking a market listing to fund growth. Instead, they are looking for media attention -- Easdaq companies will have to report quarterly -- while they also believe the listing will give Artwork credibility.</p>
<p>Currently the founders hold all shares in Artwork, but via the listing they aim to offer part of an increased capital base to their independent distributors and to their staff of 87.</p>
<p>Details of the capital increase and the listing are not yet finalised, but 25 to 35 percent of the capital is expected to be offered to the public before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Artwork plans to pay out at least 35 percent of profits to shareholders, Van der Schueren noted.</p>
<p>He said Artwork would be looking for a price/earnings ratio similar to that of other listed companies in graphics area -- Adobe Systems Inc has a P/E of 37.8, MacroMedia Inc 27.5.</p>
<p>Both are U.S. companies listed on Nadaq, Easdaq's New York based sister market. Brussels-based Easdaq is aimed at all European growth stocks.</p>
<p>Artwork's listing will be sponsored by  KB Securities, the brokerage unit of Belgian Kredietbank, which together with  Hambrecht &amp; Quist of the U.S. will act as market makers for the stock. Both are shareholders of Easdaq.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
