<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128942" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WALL ST WEEK AHEAD -  Microsoft, IBM net.</title>
<headline>WALL ST WEEK AHEAD -  Microsoft, IBM net.</headline>
<byline>Andrej Gustincic</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>High tech heavyweights Microsoft Corp and International Business Machines Corp kick off earnings this week with markets seen settling into a trading range after the Dow topped 6000 last Monday.</p>
<p>Analysts said that the U.S. elections will again enter the picture on Wall Street with many now worrying that Democrats may take control of one or both of the houses of Congress on President Clinton's coattails.  </p>
<p>Microsoft is expected to report fiscal first quarter earnings per share of $0.90 compared to $0.78 a year ago on Monday, according to First Call while IBM is seen reporting third quarter EPS of $2.43 compared to $2.30 a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been assuming good earnings and, at these lofty levels, if they are in line or disappointing, the two of them could catch cold and move lower,&quot; said Alfred Goldman, technical analyst at A.G. Edwards &amp; Sons.  </p>
<p>&quot;If they are better than expected then the market will be pleased for about 20 minutes because right now investors are trying to gauge earnings for the next two quarters and if the market has enough momentum left to go forward.&quot;</p>
<p>Even more important than the actual earnings will be what the company says when it issues them and whatever forecasts it gives for future earnings and the prospects for the industry.  </p>
<p>&quot;The real issue is what they say about what the future hold over the next six to eight months,&quot; said Peter Cardillo, director of research at Westfalia Investments. &quot;The key is not so much whether they meet expectations but what they divulge regarding what the industry is looking at.&quot;</p>
<p>Another problem facing high techs in particular is whether they live up to &quot;whisper&quot; earnings, or unofficial forecasts which exceed the official ones on Wall Street. This is true especially of stocks which have had strong runs in anticipation of the quarterly reports.  </p>
<p>Earnings aside, analysts expect the market to enter a trading range or even pull back now that the Dow Industrials have topped the 6000 level.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the primary markets to establish a relatively tight trading range where we will spend a period of time attempting to define the upper and lower boundaries,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd. He said he expected a range between 5900 and 6100.</p>
<p>Westfalia's Cardillo said that he saw a pullback as the November 5 elections approached.  </p>
<p>&quot;Fundamentally nothing has changed but from a technical perspective we are just about overbought and could pull back to to low 5900s by election time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While most on Wall Street believe Clinton will defeat Republican challenger Bob Dole, they are afraid Democrats regain a considerabele measure of control in Congress.</p>
<p>The Street has been more than satisfied with the executive and legislative branches being controlled by rival parties and are afraid of a breakdown in fiscal discipline.  </p>
<p>&quot;Business likes the fact that neither the Congress nor the President have been in a position to do anything of a dramatic nature,&quot; said Peggy Farley, chief executive officer at Amas Securities. &quot;There is the fear that a coalition between the President and the Democratic majority on the liberal side.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dow Industrials closed at 6094.23 on Friday, up about 125 points for the week. The S&amp;P 500 closed at 710.82 and the Nadsdaq Composite closed at 1242.49</p>
<p>Companies expected to report earnings this week, followed by the First Call estimate and the year-ago period, include:</p>
<p>Knight-Ridder Inc Q3 $0.37 v $0.07</p>
<p>Times Mirror Co Q3 $0.37 v $0.21</p>
<p>Washington Post Co Q3 $4.66 v $3.79</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers Squibb Co Q3 $1.48 v $1.36</p>
<p>Avon Products Inc Q3 $0.46 v $0.41</p>
<p>Dial Corp Q3 $0.13 v $0.45</p>
<p>Kimberly Clark Q3 $1.21 v $1.15</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
