<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129300" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bumper crop due, Wired and Wild Oats ahead.</title>
<headline>Bumper crop due, Wired and Wild Oats ahead.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A packed schedule of initial public offerings are due this week, with over 40 companies slated to go public and still more on the way as underwriters try to squeeze deals in before year-end.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a wild week coming up, potentially the heaviest to date&quot; this year, said John Fitzgibbon, editor of the IPO Aftermarket newsletter.</p>
<p>Wired Ventures Inc, which publishes Wired magazine and the HotWired Internet site, and natural foods supermarket chain Wild Oats Markets Inc are among the most-watched IPOs this week.</p>
<p>The heavy supply could be taming after-market premiums as investors pass on speculative deals opting to see what lies ahead, analysts said. U.S. IPOs raised over $36 billion so far this year despite a sluggish third quarter, shattering the 1993 annual record of $33 billion.</p>
<p>Fitzgibbon said Wild Oats could be the hottest deal this week, garnering premiums of over two or three points. The Colorado chain operates 38 stores in seven states and offers in-store massage therapists and espresso and fresh juice bars.</p>
<p>Wild Oats had sales of $118.8 milion in the first half of 1996, according to its prospectus and said it plans to expand into Florida.</p>
<p>Several high tech deals have also caught the attention of IPO investors. Wired Ventures, which publishes Internet magazines in the United States, Britain and Japan gets mixed reviews from financial analysts. The offering is due this week or next week, according to underwriter Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>Manish Shah, IPO analyst and publisher of the IPO Maven, said Wired &quot;will get a lot of attention because its one of the best known brands on the Internet. But is it a good long-term hold for investors? It's highly questionable.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an evolving industry, and they have had an enormous jump in advertising revenues, which are still miniscule, and whether they can remain profitable on an advertising-supported revenue model is questionable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wired pulled the plug on an offering this summer when a downturn in the broader market triggered a bloodbath for technology stocks.</p>
<p>Other tech deals that could prosper next week are Infinity Financial by Goldman and CyberMedia Inc, according to Fitzgibbon.</p>
<p>Infinity develops software for financial trading and risk management and could garner premiums of over two points. CyberMedia could see gains of one to 1-1/2 points, he said.</p>
<p>CyberMedia sells &quot;First Aid&quot; kits for personal computers, aimed at helping customers cut down on lengthy, frustrating calls to computer centres and helping PC companies cut down on expensive technical support. Technology market research firm Dataquest estimates the PC industry will spend about $4.0 billion in 1996 on technical support.</p>
<p>Other companies that could do well are Lehman's International Telecommunications Data Systems Inc, United Auto Group Inc, Award Software Inc, Amerisafe Inc and PJ America, which franchises Papa John's pizza restaurants.</p>
<p>The Birmingham, Alabama, company operates 42 stores and is recommended by the IPO Insider newsletter for its solid historic performance, strong management and its 4.4 percent profit margin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
