<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13086" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: For surfers, the browser is the message.</title>
<headline>For surfers, the browser is the message.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two companies are offering top flight pieces of software with a lot of free frills thrown in. Company A gives away its product but company B charges a fee.</p>
<p>Which company do you think would sell the most product?</p>
<p>Normally, that would be easy to answer, because free normally wins over just about anything.</p>
<p>But when it involves Microsoft Corp. and Netscape Communications Corp. and the recently declared Browser War, the answer would not be so simple.</p>
<p>Netscape, the market leader, officially unveiled Aug. 19 its latest version of its Navigator software. The announcement came hard on the heels of Microsoft's free offer for its latest browser update, Internet Explorer 3.0. Netscape, which normally costs $49 after a three-month trial offer.</p>
<p>Analysts believe Microsoft has pretty well leveled the playing field with Netscape with its Explorer 3.0 release. &quot;They've achieved a point of relative functional parity,&quot; said Clay Ryder, senior analyst with Internet researcher Zona Research Inc.</p>
<p>In addition to their great new products, both companies now feel compelled to offer free, but time-limited subscriptions to some popular content providers. Explorer fans will be able to peruse the Wall Street Journal while Navigator types get the New York Times.</p>
<p>Netscape holds up to 80 percent of the market for browser software, which helps users painlessly cruise the Web. But while you could characterize Netscape as the market Goliath, it would be foolhardy to dismiss Microsoft -- the world's most successful software company -- as the David in this battle.</p>
<p>The question of whether Netscape could hold its commanding position should not be dismissed when it is remembered how fast giants can fall. Does anybody out there still use Mosaic to rumble around the Web?</p>
<p>And of course we are dealing with Microsoft, the giant from Redmond, Wash. which generates so much in revenues from everything else its sells that Bill Gates could afford to promise that he would give away its browser for free, forever. The key thing about Microsoft is that they have the staying power, the smarts and the cash to finance a battle over the longer term.</p>
<p>Microsoft has been talking about making Explorer part of its operating system, a powerful move as the company already controls most operating systems on personal computers today. That could sound the death knell for Netscape, according to some.</p>
<p>&quot;If the browser becomes the OS shell in Windows 97 then it'll be hard not to use Explorer,&quot; said Steven Harmon, senior investment analyst for Mecklermedia Corp. &quot;You will have to go out of your way to launch anything outside Microsoft.&quot;</p>
<p>Not to be dismissed, however, is the fact Netscape could win a fair amount of support from individual and corporate users alike just by the virtue of the fact they offer an alternative to acompany many see as far too powerful already.</p>
<p>In the end, however, this &quot;war&quot; could all be viewed in an entirely different way.</p>
<p>Both companies have been throwing a lot of resources into delivering the best browsers for Internet fans. No doubt a dizzying array of features will be added to the products  that already contain a dizzying array of bells and whistles.</p>
<p>Savvy surfers can simply keep downloading the latest versions from both companies, using one when it suits and using the other when another mood strikes, to take maximum advantage of free grace periods and the like.</p>
<p>So perhaps, in the end, it will be the surfer that will ultimately win the browser war.</p>
<p>(To comment on this weekly column, Russell Blinch can be reached at: russell.blinch@reuters.com)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
