<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134014" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-Stealth warships steal limelight at show.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Stealth warships steal limelight at show.</headline>
<byline>Pierre Tran</byline>
<dateline>LE BOURGET, France 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Just as the submarine changed the face of naval warfare in World War Two, Europe's shipbuilders are hoping a new breed of &quot;stealth&quot; warships will do the same in the 21st century.</p>
<p>At a trade fair at Le Bourget airport, north of Paris, three shipbuilders presented their own version of combat ships with the ability to hide and deceive the enemy.</p>
<p>Britain's Vosper Thornycroft on Tuesday unveiled its design for the futuristic Sea Wraith corvette.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe it has the potential to make other vessels of its class obsolete,&quot; Brian Spilman, Vosper's manager of future projects shipbuilding, told a news conference at the Euronaval exhibition, which gathers the world's navies.</p>
<p>BAeSema, a joint venture between British Aerospace and France's Sema Group, presented its Cougar corvette on Monday.</p>
<p>And French state-owned DCN shipyard presented its La Fayette frigate which it boasted was the first operational warship fully to use stealth features in its design.</p>
<p>Unlike the first two, designed for patrolling regional waters, the French ship is a full-scale deep-water frigate.</p>
<p>Stealth warships use similar principles to the radar-beating technology developed by the U.S. aircraft industry and used in the 1991 Gulf War against Iraq. The diamond-shaped F117 and batwing B2 bombers were designed to absorb or deflect radar.</p>
<p>Built in flat, angular shapes, stealth warships are &quot;platforms&quot; for weapons and detection systems.</p>
<p>The La Fayette uses a slab-sided superstructure and non-metallic materials to confuse radar. The second of eight La Fayette-class ships ordered by Taiwan entered service last week, while Saudi Arabia has also ordered the French ship.</p>
<p>The British are in hot pursuit with their own designs for a new generation of stealth vessels.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe this is the warship of the future and all warships will need to use these techniques,&quot; Vosper's Spilman said. &quot;We have made it difficult to detect, classify and engage with a missile,&quot; he told the news conference.</p>
<p>The Sea Wraith design puts the distinctive clutter of mast, radar dishes and aerials inside flat-sided towers and has shaped topsides, rather like diamond facets, to make it hard for radar to lock on. It also uses non-reflective composites.</p>
<p>Sea Wraith can alter its &quot;radar signature&quot; by lowering or raising the mast, making it difficult to recognise the craft. Two asymetrically-located masts are meant to confuse radar-guided missiles.</p>
<p>To counter new infra-red, or heat-seeking, missiles, the ship sprays a fine mist of water to conceal itself.</p>
<p>BAeSema is showcasing its low angular Cougar patrol vessel, which uses low-acoustic waterjet propulsion instead of traditional noisy engines which are easily picked up by sonar.</p>
<p>The basic Cougar &quot;hull-in-the-water&quot;, excluding weapons and other systems, costs around 30 million sterling ($37.56 million), according to Keith Figg, the craft's designer.</p>
<p>BAe last week announced it was merging its naval systems activities into BAeSema, to boost its prime contractor role.</p>
<p>Prime contractors bid for contracts in which integration of radar, communications and defence provide the added value.</p>
<p>BAeSema would act as prime contractor while the ship would typically be built in the customers' own shipyards.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going for indigenous building and procurement, which would be a more cost-effective solution and involve ownership at an earlier stage&quot; Figg said.</p>
<p>South East Asian delegations have shown interest in both the Cougar and Sea Wraith, company executives said. &quot;We view that part of the world as a very important market,&quot; Spilman said.</p>
<p>Strong economic growth and regional rivalries particularly over natural resources and territorial waters have fuelled an arms race in South-East Asia.</p>
<p>French defence electronics group Thomson-CSF TCFP.PA is the prime contractor for the La Fayette under Sawari 1 and 2 contracts signed with Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>($1=.7986 Sterling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LE BOURGET, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
