<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134138" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP 9-mth sales behind expectations.</title>
<headline>SAP 9-mth sales behind expectations.</headline>
<dateline>WALLDORF, Germany 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nine months to Sept 30</p>
<p>(in millions of marks unless stated)</p>
<p>    Group profit on ordinaries	     509     vs 385</p>
<p>    Group sales				  2,372   vs 1,790</p>
<p>Sales breakdown by segment:</p>
<p>    Products				     1,625   up 30 pct</p>
<p>    Consulting				     501   up 45 pct</p>
<p>    Training					 208   up 26 pct</p>
<p>Sales breakdown by region:</p>
<p>    United States				  841   vs 596</p>
<p>    Germany					  658   vs 603</p>
<p>    Europe (excl Germany)			535   vs 397</p>
<p>    Asia					     299   vs 169</p>
<p>    Africa					    39   vs  25</p>
<p>NOTE - Full name of the German business software company is SAP AG.</p>
<p>Management board chairman Dietmar Hopp noted that rate of sales growth slowed unexpectedly to 33 percent to the end of September after 38 percent at the end of June.</p>
<p>&quot;The rather moderate growth in the third quarter was unexpected and attributable to a few countries,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Nevertheless we continue to see very strong demand for R/3,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Revenues in the first nine months of 1996, while highest in the group's history, were below both the company's and market's expectations.</p>
<p>Independent analysts had been expecting sales growth of around 40 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have recognised the causes of this surprising weakness in growth and have implemented corresponding steps,&quot; Hopp added.</p>
<p>&quot;The moderate growth in the third quarter means that the previous sales target is no longer achievable. We now expect 1996 revenues to be 3.5 billion marks.&quot;</p>
<p>Hopp said SAP had expended much of its efforts recently on development and that it would now refocus on sales.</p>
<p>Paul Wahl, chief executive for SAP in North America, said the company had added 70 new employees to its sales force.</p>
<p>&quot;The market opportunities for SAP in North America remain strong and as we continue our expansion into the mid-market and new vertical industries we will continue to realise significant growth,&quot; Wahl said in the statement.</p>
<p>SAP's group workforce increased by 1,614 employees to 8,471 at the end of September. Of the total increase, 1,144 new staff were added outside Germany.</p>
<p>-- William Boston, Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WALLDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
