<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136041" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Midisoft sanctioned over inflated revenues.</title>
<headline>Midisoft sanctioned over inflated revenues.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Commission said Wednesday it sanctioned Midisoft Corp for allegedly inflating its 1994 revenues by 16.3 percent or $811,000.</p>
<p>In an order, the SEC told the Issaquah, Wash.,-based provider of software for sound amd music on personal computers, to &quot;cease and desist&quot; from further violations of federal reporting, books and records and internal accounting regulations.</p>
<p>Midisoft consented to the order without admitting or denying the SEC's findings, the agency said.  </p>
<p>The SEC alleged that Midisoft overstatement of its 1994 revenues stemmed from two operations.</p>
<p>First, it recorded revenues on goods that the company did not ship to its customers during the year but held at an off-site storage.</p>
<p>Second, the company under-reported sales returns it received for products shipped during the same year.</p>
<p>The agency said certain officers and employees of the company falsified the company's books and records and knowingly circumvented Midisoft's internal accounting controls.  </p>
<p>In a separate order, the SEC said it issued another &quot;cease and desist&quot; order against Calvin Dyer, former chief financial officer of the company for his alleged role in the overstatement of the company's revenues.</p>
<p>Dyer, who agreed to the order without admitting or denying any wrongdoing, allegedly caused the books and records of Midisoft to be falsified and circumvented the company's accounting controls.</p>
<p>In addition, the SEC said Dyer lied to Midisoft's auditors and signed the company's 1994 financial statement with knowledge that the document materially misstated Midisoft's financial results.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
