<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137085" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Superhero Pajama Sam has the power to captivate.</title>
<headline>Superhero Pajama Sam has the power to captivate.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>His costume: Blue flannels, a big red cape and a purple mask.</p>
<p>His weapons: A big bright flashlight and a signature-edition all-metal lunch box.</p>
<p>His mission: Capture Darkness, put Darkness in the lunch box and pick up his socks.</p>
<p>The outcome: A great time for kids three to eight years old.</p>
<p>&quot;Pajama Sam in 'No Need To Hide When It's Dark Outside'&quot; (Humongous Entertainment, Windows/Macintosh, $40) is everything a kid's game should be.</p>
<p>It's got a plucky hero, cute supporting characters, top-quality animation, a real plot children can relate to, interesting puzzles, and a touch of humour. It's hard to believe that older kids won't enjoy it as well.</p>
<p>It begins in Sam's room, where he has promised his mother that he's finally ready to go to sleep without the lights on. The problem is, Sam knows that the evil Darkness is lurking in his closet, and he can't fall asleep until he's captured Darkness and imprisoned him in the lunch box.</p>
<p>So Sam decides to become Pajama Sam, the world's youngest superhero.</p>
<p>After players have helped Sam find his lunch box, mask and flashlight, the boy ventures into the closet and stumbles into the Land of Darkness, where the trees quickly snatch away his belongings. The only way for Sam to get his equipment back is to convince a reluctant boat to float, fix the wheels of King the mine car, and help Carrot X liberate his fellow vegetables from Darkness's refrigerator.</p>
<p>At least, that's what had to be done when I played it. &quot;Pajama Sam&quot; has several different versions, which means that the second time around, a new set of puzzles may appear.</p>
<p>Few reading skills are required, but that doesn't mean getting through the game is child's play. To go over the bridge, for example, players must figure out how to get some gold; but they can't get inside the mine to get the gold until the figure out how to get the rust off King's wheels; and they can't find the oil to remove the rust until they convince Otto the Boat that wood does indeed float.</p>
<p>Kids who help Sam in his quest will find that the youngster ultimately conquers his fear of Darkness.</p>
<p>The game is first rate. Few products for kids can measure up.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>&quot;The Berenstain Bears In the Dark&quot; (Living Books, Windows/Macintosh) focuses on the same theme. It's the tale of Sister Bear learning not to be frightened by scary stories.</p>
<p>But this CD-ROM is an all-too-typical example of what passes for children's computer products these days. Designed for the same age group as &quot;Pajama Sam&quot; (ages three to seven), the story and much of the artwork are taken directly from the Random House book of the same name. In fact, the book is included in the package.</p>
<p>Why buy this $30 product when you can get the original book at most stores for $3.25 or less?</p>
<p>For one thing, the computer will read the story to your child. This is not necessarily a good thing. Reading to our children is one of the best things you can do for them, something busy parents do much too infrequently.</p>
<p>Unlike the book, the objects and characters in the story become animated when you click on them. The CD-ROM also has two games: a matching game and eight picture jumbles. And there's activity book for parents, which contains suggestions on how to cope with nighttime noises and spooky shapes.</p>
<p>Personally, I don't think it's worth the extra $26.75. And when a product like &quot;Pajama Sam&quot; offers so much more at a price that's only $10 higher than &quot;The Berenstain Bears In the Dark,&quot; it convinces me that some of the folks who give us children's books-on-a-disk could be offering more value for the money.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores:</p>
<p>&quot;Putt-Putt and Pep's Balloon-O-Rama&quot; and &quot;Putt-Putt and Pep's Dog on a Stick&quot;, also from Humongous Entertainment (Windows/Macintosh, $15 each) are two new animated arcade games based on the cartoon car and designed for three-to-eight year-olds. The second title refers to an animal on a pogo stick, not a food related to the corn dog.</p>
<p>&quot;After Dark 4.0&quot; (Berkeley Systems, Windows95/Macintosh, $30) -- This new version of the popular screen saver features 20 new animations, including the dueling Hula Twins. For Internet subscribers, it also includes a system for turning the latest news into screen saver screens.</p>
<p>&quot;Barbie Storymaker&quot; (Mattel Media, Windows, $30) -- Part of a new line of Barbie CD-ROMs, it lets youngsters over age five create Barbie movies by selecting locations, characters and sound effects. There's also &quot;Barbie Fashion Designer&quot; ($45, for electronically dressing up Barbie) and &quot;Barbie Print 'n Play&quot; ($30, for creating stationery, stickers, banners and calendars).</p>
<p>&quot;Amazing Learning Games&quot; (Ubi Soft, Windows95, $40) features Rayman, the goofball superhero with invisible arms and legs (but you can see his hands and feet). It offers 1,800 exercises in reading, counting and spelling for ages six to 10.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
