<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13839" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Netscape Navio have separate focus -- Clark.</title>
<headline>Netscape Navio have separate focus -- Clark.</headline>
<byline>Barbara Grady</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Netscape Communications Corp's founder James Clark said he and his co-founder started Navio Communications as a separate company using Netscape's technology in consumer appliance software &quot;to keep our focus&quot; at Netscape on the business Internet and intranets market.</p>
<p>Yet Navio's charter of peppering the consumer appliance market with versions of Netscape's Navigator browser adapted for various consumer devices also will help Navigator become a standard computer platform, co-founder Marc Andreessen said.  </p>
<p>Making Navigator an industry platform upon which outsiders would develop applications is what many analyts say Netscape needs to do to assure its ongoing dominance of the Internet market in the wake of Microsoft Corp's new determination to usurp it.</p>
<p>&quot;We think it will expand the client base for products of ours,&quot; Andreessen said at a press conference about Navio.</p>
<p>He went on to say that, over the next 12 months, Navigator will increasingly become like an operating system or a desktop environment to host applications and the things people want to do with their computers.  </p>
<p>Analyst David Readerman of Montgomery Securities, attending the Navio event, said: &quot;Netscape needs to evolve the Navigator as its operating system&quot; to succeed in its escalating battle with Microsoft. He said Microsoft and Netscape each threaten the core business of the other.</p>
<p>Microsoft, though it sells millions of units of applications software yearly, is at its core a platform or operating system company, its officials say.</p>
<p>Another anlayst, Gret Blatnick of Zona Research Inc, said there is a lot of interest in getting Internet access from consumer appliances, so Netscape's plan has good chances.  </p>
<p>Clark said Netscape believes there is going to be an explosion of opportunities in the next year for Internet access and browsing on consumer devices like TVs and phones.</p>
<p>&quot;The immediate market for Internet technology came from business and that market exploded in our faces,&quot; he said. &quot;If more business opportunity that we can possibly handle is coming from the business side, how can we possibly attack this new market,&quot; he said of Netscape's move to form Navio.</p>
<p>He said Sony Corp, NEC Corp, International Business Machines Corp, Oracle Corp, Nintendo Ltd and Sega are working with Navio, but he would not identify them as the investors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
