<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140894" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP could fall more as analysts do homework.</title>
<headline>SAP could fall more as analysts do homework.</headline>
<byline>Emma Thomasson</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in German business software firm SAP AG, which lost almost a quarter of their value in one day, could slide further as analysts revise their forecasts following the firm's surprise profit warning.</p>
<p>&quot;Most analysts are still doing their homework and if the people who were bulls change their forecasts there could be more selling,&quot; Michael Boston, German strategist at Credit Suisse First Boston in London, said on Thursday.</p>
<p>SAP dived in heavy pre-bourse trade on Wednesday, falling as much as 26 percent at one stage and dragging down the DAX index of 30 leading shares.</p>
<p>Its preference shares recovered slightly on Thursday to end up 2.30 marks at 214 marks in post-bourse IBIS dealings.</p>
<p>The company had stunned markets on Tuesday evening with an unexpectedly sharp slowdown in growth in the third quarter that forced the firm to revise down its 1996 revenue forecast to 3.5 billion marks ($2.30 billion) from 3.8 billion.</p>
<p>Dealers said there was a psychological level of 200 marks for the preference shares and below that at 184 marks, the stock's year low.</p>
<p>But Stefan Schiesser, analyst at SGZ Bank in Frankfurt, said: &quot;Anything under 200 will be a buy signal.&quot;</p>
<p>Between April and October the stock had added over 100 marks, climbing to a high of 284 marks from a low of 182.</p>
<p>&quot;For the last two or three years the stock has been a one way bet. It has made its forecast every time,&quot; said Brian Wilkinson, German analyst at HSBC James Capel.</p>
<p>Analysts said the stock could take up to a year to recoup the ground lost on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Given our reduced expected results we think that a fair level would be 240 marks, but we won't get that in the next few months,&quot; said Juergen Poellmann, analyst at Bayerische Vereinsbank.</p>
<p>HSBC's Wilkinson said he was particularly worried about the slowdown of sales growth in Germany, where sales were 658 million marks for the first nine months, compared to 603 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Wilkinson said he had revised his earnings per share forecast for 1996 down to 4.4 marks from 5.8 marks and had also lowered his forecasts for 1997 and 1998.</p>
<p>Analysts said all attention would be now be focused on the company's fourth quarter results, expected in January. They said if the firm disappointed for another quarter, then investors could panic even more.</p>
<p>SAP warned late on Wednesday it did not expect sales growth to exceed 30 percent and said the company must get used to lower growth rates in the future.</p>
<p>It had been one of Europe's best performing stocks with up to fifty percent of the company's shares held by British and American investors, but analysts said that could change now.</p>
<p>&quot;For some time it will be a fallen star. SAP has been in everyone's portfolio as one of the few climbers in Germany and now some people are pulling out. They've made pretty good money over the year. So there's a good incentive for profit taking,&quot; said HSBC's Wilkinson.</p>
<p>Analysts said the fate of the SAP share price would also be linked to the performance of the high technology sector in the United States, currently showing nervousness.</p>
<p>They said jitters in the sector on Tuesday night in the U.S., sparked after Microsoft announced earnings gains below expectations, had also put pressure on SAP.</p>
<p>&quot;How quickly SAP picks up depends on how the technology sector in the U.S. develops,&quot; said Schiesser of SGZ.</p>
<p>But others said the company still had good long-term prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally the growth story is intact, their products are good and their dollar exposure should help them for the rest of the year,&quot; said Credit Suisse's Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that investors with a longer term investment horizon are likely to be rewarded over the long-term given the company's dominant position in the industry and the strong underlying fundamentals of the client-server applications business,&quot; said Neil Herman, of Salomon Brothers in a research note.</p>
<p>SAP dominates global business in client-servers, computer programmes that control core processes of companies and link their far-flung operations to central computers.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($1=1.5230 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
