<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146967" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bay Networks says no consolidation planned.</title>
<headline>Bay Networks says no consolidation planned.</headline>
<dateline>MONTEREY, Calif. 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bay Networks Inc has no plans to consolidate its operations on the U.S. East and West coasts as part of a drive for greater efficiency, Paul Severino, the company's chairman and acting chief executive, said Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be lunacy to consolidate in our situation,&quot; Severino told a group of investors at the American Electronics Association conference in Monterey.</p>
<p>Bay Networks was created in 1994 when Silicon Valley-based Synoptics Communications Inc merged with Masschusetts-based Wellfleet Communications Inc.</p>
<p>After the merger, Bay kept operations of both companies almost intact on both coasts. That division has contributed to the company's declining gross margins in recent quarters, analysts said.  </p>
<p>In recent quarters, Bay Network's revenue growth has slowed and its share price has declined amid intense competition with Cisco Systems Inc, sales organization turmoil within the company and high employee turnovers.</p>
<p>Severino said Bay Networks, which makes electronic equipment that allows computers to share information through networks, has seen employee defections rise in recent months.  </p>
<p>Earlier this month, Andrew Ludwick, Bay's chief exeuctive officer, said he planned to step down to let another executive take over the company's day-to-day operations.</p>
<p>Severino said Monday that his top priority was finding a good chief executive to to replace him.</p>
<p>He also said that while the search continues, he would work to improve the company's operations.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm going to be aggressive in this time frame,&quot; he said, adding, &quot;I'm not just here to hold you off and sign checks.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTEREY, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
