<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147925" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Asia launches forum for speeding core projects.</title>
<headline>Asia launches forum for speeding core projects.</headline>
<byline>Priya Ramani</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than a dozen Asian countries teamed up with private firms on Monday to launch a forum to speed investments in core projects across the region.</p>
<p>The Asia Infrastructure Development Alliance (AIDA) was launched on the inaugural day of a four-day meeting of the United Nations Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP) in the Indian capital.</p>
<p>&quot;AIDA provides a vehicle to improve the processes by which we can improve public and private sector participation,&quot; said Indian Minister of Surface Transport T.G. Venkatraman.</p>
<p>Delegates to the conference said AIDA would seek support from governments, the private sector and multilateral agencies to fund the region's huge infrastructure needs.</p>
<p>ESCAP estimates developing countries in the Asia-Pacific region need $1.5 trillion in new core sector development between 1993 and 2000, of which $500 billion has been committed.</p>
<p>&quot;AIDA brings together the three groups outside the framework of a specific project to discuss policy issues,&quot; John Trew, business development director of North West Water International, told a news conference to announce the launch.</p>
<p>The forum will be funded largely by the private sector through annual fees and, later, from revenues generated by the products and services that AIDA will introduce. Annual corporate membership is expected to be around $20,000.</p>
<p>Private sector participants include Coopers and Lybrand, North West Water International, Microsoft, PowerGen, Linklaters and Paines, Lend Lease Capital Services and Gazprom.</p>
<p>Countries including Australia, Canada, China, India, Indonesia, Iran, Laos, Malaysia, Pakistan, Philippines, Republic of Korea, Russian Federation, Singapore, Sri Lanka and Thailand are members of or have indicated their intention to join AIDA.</p>
<p>&quot;AIDA will take up issues relevant for increasing the pace of investment, particularly from the private sector, in Asian infrastructure projects,&quot; Graham Galloway, chairman of consultancy firm Infrastructure Development Group, told Reuters earlier on Monday.</p>
<p>A unit of his group, the Development Forum Administrators Pte Ltd, has been apppointed as AIDA's secretariat.</p>
<p>Galloway said AIDA will set up a detailed database of people and organisations for infrastructure development in participating countries.</p>
<p>&quot;The database will also have details about infrastructure environment and regulations governing various sectors. It will be an easy route to information,&quot; Galloway said.</p>
<p>Some 30 Asian nations are participating in the ESCAP conference which is aimed at improving the transport, communication and infrastructure facilities of developing countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
