<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149256" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FEATURE - Digital TV is new source of income for Hollywood.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Digital TV is new source of income for Hollywood.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Film studios in Hollywood and elsewhere could soon find a new source of income as broadcasters scramble for audiovisual rights to get fresh films on digital satellite television services.</p>
<p>Germany's Leo Kirch and France's Canal Plus own important catalogues of films, both old and new, forcing newer arrivals to the digital television scene to open their wallets.</p>
<p>TPS, a French digital service due for the end of the year and run by private broadcaster TF1 and state-owned France Television, paid big money recently for film deals when signing up Paramount and MGM.</p>
<p>The 10-year Paramount deal is rumoured to be worth more than $500 million while the MGM contract is reported to be for $13 million a year.</p>
<p>&quot;In the digital future there will still be big shows on the large generic channels and they will get lots of ad money,&quot; said Nicolas Duhamel, finance director of media group Havas.</p>
<p>&quot;For the premium programmes on pay television you need to have quality products to get a large audience,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, the big issue is to get as many of your decoders in the homes as possible. That gives you a subscriber base and leverage in any standardisation negotiations. After that, it's the quality of programmes that will make the difference,&quot; Duhamel said.</p>
<p>DIGITAL MEANS MULTITUDE OF NEW CHANNELS</p>
<p>The marriage of computer technology and television, replacing &quot;analogue&quot; electrical wave technology with a &quot;digital&quot; system, opens up a broad range of possibilities for the entertainment industry by creating a multitude of new channels.</p>
<p>At the very least, it will dramatically improve the picture and sound quality of existing television.</p>
<p>&quot;It's like suddenly having eight telephone lines instead of one. It means that you can either tell one woman you love her over eight lines, or tell eight women you love them over one line each. The change is dramatic,&quot; quipped Canal Plus chairman Pierre Lescure at an industry conference.</p>
<p>Digital TV technology, by compressing and decompressing signals, can use far more channels on existing frequencies and allows for interactive applications such as pay-per-view, multicasting (showing the same film at different times) and even access to the Internet network of computers.</p>
<p>STILL A LONG WAY TO THE VIEWER</p>
<p>Potentially, the global digital TV market is worth hundreds of billions of dollars in revenue from subscriptions to commercials.</p>
<p>But there is a long way between the broadcaster and the viewer.</p>
<p>For the moment, hardware issues are claiming a lot of attention. A broadcaster needs to have space on a satellite, a transponder, to be able to transmit images to the dishes.</p>
<p>If the number of satellites in orbit is increasing, the optimum orbital positions are rare and expensive.</p>
<p>A broadcaster also needs uplink equipment to beam to the satellite, as well as digital studios and sophisticated production equipment, although these are becoming common in the industry.</p>
<p>The viewer needs to have a box connected to the television set -- in the future they will be part of the set -- to unscramble and decompress the digital signal, as well as an antenna, a dish, to capture the signal.</p>
<p>Dishes are getting smaller and existing cable television networks could assure part of the transportation of the signal to the viewer. But at the moment, a viewer would have to pay hundreds of dollars to get equipped.</p>
<p>Some broadcasters subsidise the acquisition of the equipment, adding to start-up costs.</p>
<p>Part of the equipment is called access control. It is able to determine on a real-time basis whether a viewer is watching, and what is being watched, to calculate the premium for pay-per-view, multicasting and other paying services.</p>
<p>In Europe, technicians are working on what is called Multiscrypt or Simulscript which would allow a single set-top box to &quot;talk&quot; with all the broadcast service providers.</p>
<p>BUT WHAT IS THERE ON THE BOX?</p>
<p>When the hardware issues are settled and the broadcaster can beam its &quot;bouquet&quot; of tens of different digital TV services to the viewer, the big question turns to the old cry of &quot;What is there on the box?&quot;</p>
<p>Broadcasters need content -- and far more than there is now.</p>
<p>Media groups such as Kirch Group, BSkyB, Canal Plus and others are out in the market buying up audiovisual rights.</p>
<p>They are bidding big money for sports events, to the dismay of existing analogue broadcasters, because these are deemed to be tailor-made for pay-per-view.</p>
<p>Instead of a broadcaster deciding which of a dozen or so soccer matches, which start at almost the same time, will be shown live, the viewer can decide which match he wants to see live at a premium price and which matches later.</p>
<p>THE SPREAD OF DIGITAL TV</p>
<p>In Europe, only a handful of companies already offer digital satellite television -- Telepiu in Italy since November, Canal Plus and AB Productions in France since April, and Leo Kirch's companies in Germany since July -- but a host of others are preparing services.</p>
<p>The biggest European alliance is a planned merger between Canal Plus and Dutch-based Nethold, controlled by Richemont .</p>
<p>In Scandinavia, Kinnevik has digital ambitions on an ASTRA satellite and in France TPS is gearing to offer a &quot;free&quot; digital satellite service at the end of the year.</p>
<p>In Germany, the Pro Sieben station run by Leo Kirch's son Thomas is to start digital pay television in November.</p>
<p>In Italy, Silvio Berlusconi's Mediaset is eager to move to digital satellite television as new media laws seek to limit its hold on the terrestial market.</p>
<p>In Spain, Radio Television Espanola (RTVE) is rumoured to be talking with Brazil's El Globo, Time Warner and Rupert Murdoch to launch eight digital channels in 1997.</p>
<p>In Britain the industry is taking a different route. While BSkyB, controlled by Murdoch's News Corp, is studying the possibilities of digital satellite TV because it is already on satellite, others are keeping their feet on the ground.</p>
<p>The British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) and the Independent Television (ITV) commercial stations are drawing up plans for terrestial digital television.</p>
<p>Outside Europe, digital TV operations are appearing all over the globe.</p>
<p>Projects are either in operation or on the drawing board in South Africa, Japan, Hong Kong and in several Latin American countries.</p>
<p>In the United States, DirectTV started digital satellite television in October 1994. Echostar Communications is rumoured to be in talks with Sprint Corp to launch a rival service.</p>
<p>The big exisiting television companies, united in the so-called &quot;Grand Alliance&quot;, recently agreed on a standard for digital HDTV and came close to getting approval from the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) for spectrum allocation.</p>
<p>But, as television exploits computer technology, computer companies are looking for ways into the moving images business. Microsoft and Apple Computer argued that the Grand Alliance standard would freeze digital television and image technology at an already outdated level.</p>
<p>The FCC is now reconsidering.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
