<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156817" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Corporate America embraces Internet commerce.</title>
<headline>Corporate America embraces Internet commerce.</headline>
<byline>Michelle V. Rafter</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES</dateline>
<text>
<p>- No more fun and games. The Internet is getting down to business.</p>
<p>Internet commerce is the latest, biggest buzz in corporate America, with thousands of companies lining up to buy and sell online, and hundreds more standing ready to provide the tools to get them there.</p>
<p>The obstacles are daunting, but if optimists' predictions come true, the Internet could become the biggest marketplace on the globe by the beginning of the next century, an electronic bazaar that will change forever the landscape of domestic and international trade.</p>
<p>&quot;The net's created an open market for anyone who wanted to jump in,&quot; said Jay &quot;Marty&quot; Tenenbaum, chairman of CommerceNet, the Internet commerce consortium.</p>
<p>What is Internet commerce?</p>
<p>It's retailers selling music CDS, flowers or books on the World Wide Web, and consumers paying for them from virtual wallets stuffed with secured credit cards, digital dollars and electronic checks.</p>
<p>It's investors buying stock through online brokers. It's bank customers logging on to move funds from checking accounts to savings, and pay bills. It's companies using the Internet to reach suppliers and customers, and transferring purchasing, distribution and other corporate functions onto intranets.</p>
<p>Because Internet commerce encompasses so many things, it's hard to get a handle on exactly how large a market it is, or will be.</p>
<p>Today, business-to-business transactions account for the biggest piece of the electronic-commerce pie. Revenue from corporate e-commerce could explode to $13.4 billion next year, from $2.8 billion in 1996, according to a recent poll of 1,100 commercial Web sites by ActivMedia, a Peterborough, N.H., Internet researcher.</p>
<p>Online retailing, merchandise sales to the general public from stores on the Web and online services, should reach $6.6 billion by 2000 from $518 million this year, according to Forrester Research, the Cambridge, Mass., research outfit.</p>
<p>But electronic commerce isn't there yet.</p>
<p>Most consumers still shun using credit cards online, despite recent studies that show electronic transactions are less susceptible to fraud than offline purchases. Privacy is another big concern.</p>
<p>What's more, early Internet stores and online malls were unattractive, disorganized, understocked and lacking conveniences such as online ordering. It's no surprise shopping ranked dead last in a recent Advertising Age poll of Internet users' online activities, well behind news gathering and e-mail.</p>
<p>On the merchant side, off-the-shelf solutions for building Internet storefronts were nonexistent until the past six months. Web-based business is still hampered by lack of infrastructure and standards, regulatory constraints and societal barriers, according to a recent electronic-commerce study conducted by consultants Arthur D. Little and Giga Information Group.</p>
<p>The Internet industry is working double time to remove these impediments.</p>
<p>In recent months, a Who's Who of Internet giants has announced a dizzying array of products meant to smooth the way for retailers, direct-mail marketers and others itching to get wired. Offerings include hosting services from AT&amp;T, MCI, IBM, BBN and others who will create and run a company's Web business.</p>
<p>Companies that want to run their own transaction-based Web sites can buy software building blocks from Netscape, Microsoft, Open Market Inc., Connect Corp. and dozens of second-tier competitors.</p>
<p>Among the latest brace of announcements, Oracle said it would begin selling a line of Web commerce servers next year, going up against Netscape and Microsoft, which itself is expected to begin shipping Web-commerce software by the end of this month.</p>
<p>Commerce servers are software packages that turn a high-performance workstation into a Web site capable of handling online transactions and associated billing, security and customer-service functions. In recent weeks, Federal Express and PSINet Inc. have also announced e-commerce products.</p>
<p>Joining the fray are successful online merchants who have started second businesses selling the front- and back-end systems they developed for their own Web enterprises.</p>
<p>That group includes CyberSource, parent of Software.net, the online software store, NetContents, parent of online wine distributor Virtual Vineyards, and Cyberian Outpost, the online computer vendor.</p>
<p>To deal with perceived fears of the Internet not being safe, AT&amp;T, America Online and other cyberspace mall managers are guaranteeing credit cards against theft, promising that if card data is stolen while customers shop, the companies will pay the $50 liability deductible if credit-card issuers don't cover it.</p>
<p>No America Online subscriber has ever had credit-card information stolen while shopping online, but company officials are offering the guarantee anyway as a security blanket.</p>
<p>&quot;We carry the burden of helping customers overcome that anxiety, whether it's real or perceived,&quot; said Mike Minigan, vice president of the online service's interactive division.</p>
<p>In another effort to bolster public trust of online commerce, the non-profit Electronic Frontier Foundation and CommerceNet, the Internet commerce trade group, recently announced eTRUST, a set of stringent privacy guidelines for online merchants due in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, dozens of banks and merchants have endorsed the SET standard for secured credit-card transactions created by a consortium led by MasterCard and Visa. Financial institutions are currently testing SET protocols with an eye toward building the safety procedures into the electronic payment services they offer merchants next year.</p>
<p>Other companies are devising online payment mechanisms that one day will fill in for cash.</p>
<p>Market leader CyberCash has struck deals with Netscape, Oracle, America Online, Sun Microsystems, Checkfree, CompuServe and others to distribute the company's virtual wallet or build it into their respective commerce software.</p>
<p>CyberCash has already distributed 700,000 virtual wallets, which by year's end will contain secured credit cards, electronic checks, and Mondex's smart card. Wallets will also contain a form of pocket change called CyberCoins consumers can use to buy a single newspaper story, play a video game or download a software upgrade.</p>
<p>&quot;You'll be able to pay by the sip rather than by the gulp,&quot; said Larry Gilbert, a CyberCash vice president.</p>
<p>CyberCash rivals DigiCash and First Virtual are marketing their own electronic payment schemes. Other companies are developing keyboards with built-in smart-card readers that consumers could use to make purchases from their PCs.</p>
<p>Despite these efforts, it could be years, even decades, before the public embraces alternatives to cold, hard cash, paper checks and plastic cards.</p>
<p>&quot;It isn't something customers are begging for,&quot; said Bill Rollinson, marketing vice president at Internet Shopping Network. &quot;Something like this almost takes a generation&quot; to assimilate.</p>
<p>Likewise, it's doubtful consumers will adjust any time soon to shopping online for clothes and other items people like to touch or try on before they buy.</p>
<p>However, a growing number of virtual companies selling computers, software, music, books, flowers, wine, gifts and other speciality items are already seeing revenue grow, and in some cases, turning a handsome profit.</p>
<p>For example, Cyberian Outpost, the Kent, Conn., Internet computer store, expects revenue to hit $20 million in fiscal 1997. Internet Shopping Network, a division of Barry Diller's Home Shopping Network, is reaping revenue of $1 million a month.</p>
<p>Their success is luring other, established retailers into the electronic marketplace, including big names such as Wal-Mart and Price Costco.</p>
<p>The next big thing in online sales could be information consumers buy a la carte and receive digitally. CommerceNet Chairman Marty Tenenbaum believes by 2000, half of all software sold will be downloaded rather than delivered in a shrink-wrapped box.</p>
<p>&quot;The economics are absolutely compelling,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
