<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162702" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Eltrax changes terms of Atlantic purchase.</title>
<headline>Eltrax changes terms of Atlantic purchase.</headline>
<dateline>ST. PAUL, Minn. 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eltrax Systems Inc said Monday it completed its acquisition of Atlantic Network Systems Inc, a Raleigh, N.C.-based distributor of data and voice communication products, though terms of the transaction were changed.</p>
<p>The transaction is expected to be treated as a pooling of interests. This accounting treatment, a change from the previously announced purchase accounting method, will enhance the earnings per share of the combined company, Eltrax said.  </p>
<p>To qualify for that accounting treatment, the transaction was restructured. The provision for the distribution of $1 million of s-corporation retained earnings was eliminated, which increased the capital accounts of Atlantic Network, on a post-closing basis.</p>
<p>Also, the merger consideration was increased by 300,000 shares to 950,000 shares of Eltrax common stock, it said.</p>
<p>Eltrax's outside auditors are expected to complete a review of Atlantic Network's financial statements before the end of the year.  </p>
<p>Directors of Eltrax have also voted to increase the number of seats on its board to eight. Effective November 1, Walt Lovett, a co-founder and former principal of Atlantic Network, would take up a seat on the Eltrax board.</p>
<p>The acquisition of Atlantic Network and a previously announced acquisition of California-based Datatech would bring Eltrax's annual revenue to about $42 million.</p>
<p>In an unrelated transaction, Eltrax said it closed on a  $5 million revolving line of credit with State Street Bank SST.N and Trust Company of Boston. Proceeds of the loan are expected to be used for general working capital.</p>
<p>Finally, Eltrax said it filed with the Internal Revenue Service to change its fiscal year-end from March 31 to the end of the calendar year, effective December 31, 1996.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk, 312 408 8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. PAUL, Minn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
