<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162845" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oracle - six use Network Computer specifications.</title>
<headline>Oracle - six use Network Computer specifications.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oracle Corp announced six manufacturers are making small computers, set-top boxes and other electronic devices using its &quot;Network Computer&quot; technology specifications.</p>
<p>The Network Computer is Oracle's long-touted design for an inexpensive Internet-based computer that would pull applications off the Internet rather than needing applications to be installed into the computer itself. Because of their dependence on the Net for applications, the NCs don't need memory or hard disks and they can use simple microprocessors.  </p>
<p>None of the six manufacturers is a major personal computer makers.  However, Sun Microsystems Inc separately announced its JavaStation based partly on the Network Computer architecture.  The six companies include Akai Electric Co Ltd, whose &quot;Akai Internet Connection&quot; is a $349 network computer device for attaching to televisions to get e-mail and Internet access.</p>
<p>Also Thomson SA's RCA division is making an NC device for TVs -- a set-top box that allows someone to surf the Web and send and receive e-mail from their TV priced at $300 in the U.S.  Both companies plan early 1997 availability.  </p>
<p>Funai Electric Co Ltd of Japan is making a small computer it calls the JANESA based on the NC design it will price at less than $500 in the U.S. Funai said it will begin mass production in December.  Also applying the NC design to set-top boxes, Proton Industrial Electronic Co Ltd of Taiwan announced a set-top box NC priced at $499 to ship in 1997's first half.</p>
<p>Uniden Corp plans a wireless network computer which it says will be available in 1997.  </p>
<p>IDEA, a Massachusetts-based data communications solutions company, announced the IDEA Internet Client Station, a network computer targeted toward the corporate market, is available immediately at a price of $500 with optional $150 software from IDEA.</p>
<p>Lastly, Acorn Computer Group Plc, an early supporter of Oracle's NC ideas, said it has developed a range of NC devices including the Acorn Network Computer, which it has been producing since August and selling in volume to corporations, mostly telecommunications companies, for $400 each.  </p>
<p>&quot;Several partners in the telecom and cable market are currently evaluating the device for integration into their network infrastructures,&quot; Acorn said. These computers use a chip that Acorn developed.</p>
<p>Acorn said its other NC devices are tailored for customers wanting to distribute them, but such devices include Office NC, Set-top box NC, ExecPhone NC and NC TV.</p>
<p>Oracle announced this line-up of NC makers at its Oracle OpenWorld Conference.</p>
<p>Larry Ellison, Oracle's chief executive officer, has been evangelizing the idea of the Network Computer for a year, saying it is an alternative to more complex and expensive personal computers.</p>
<p>While his many speeches and discussions about the NC have generated a lot of talk and speculation about a battle between traditional PCs and NCs, the market for the NC is yet to really surface and PC makers have not generally yet been persuaded to become NC manufacturers as well.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
