<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164117" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Easdaq sees first quotations towards end-November.</title>
<headline>Easdaq sees first quotations towards end-November.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's new growth stocks market Easdaq expects its first initial public offerings in late November, and is still on target to see up to 15 stocks listed by the year-end, the exchange said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The first company is aiming for the 28th of November but another (company) has just submitted a prospectus and wants to go on the 18th. There is a tussle to be the first,&quot; Easdaq spokesman Chris Pickles told Reuters. He declined to name the firms.</p>
<p>Two companies planning IPOs on Easdaq are Belgian biotechnology firm Innogenetics, which is 12.5 percent owned by Kredietbank, and Belgian-based software firm Artwork Systems. Kredietbank unit KB-Securities is lead managing their flotations.</p>
<p>Pickles said Easdaq was looking at five prospectuses in detail now, from French, Belgian and U.K.-based companies.</p>
<p>The pan-European exchange, which is modelled on New York's Nasdaq, became technically operational on September 30, but due to a procedural delay its rules were not published in Belgium's legal gazette until October 26.</p>
<p>Pickles said between 12 and 15 firms should be listed by end-December, and the exchange hopes the number of Easdaq-quoted companies will build up to 50 in 12 months.</p>
<p>These would include some of the 80 or so European companies already listed on Nasdaq which are seeking a dual listing.</p>
<p>However Easdaq says Nasdaq-listed stocks are generally finding it difficult to get Easdaq market makers because they are not well followed in Europe.</p>
<p>To be admitted, firms must be supported by at least two Easdaq-registered market makers. They must have total assets of 3.5 milliion Ecus and capital and reserves of two million Ecus.</p>
<p>Pickles said 36 financial institutions had so far applied for membership as Easdaq dealers, market makers or sponsors.</p>
<p>The Easdaq project originated from contacts between the European Venture Capital Association, the European Commission and various market players.</p>
<p>Nasdaq is one of Easdaq's 91 shareholders which brought about 370 million Belgian francs together to finance its launch. About twenty percent each of the capital came from French and British institutions.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6812, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
