<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164754" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Europe told catch up with Americans in computers.</title>
<headline>Europe told catch up with Americans in computers.</headline>
<dateline>CANNES, France 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>European business must take more risks and accelerate investment otherwise it will never match Americans in the business of information technology, industrial leaders told a conference here on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to get more risky and more aggressive in this knowledge-based economy. If we are too slow it will roll over us,&quot; said Gerhard Schulmeyer, President and Chief Executive Officer of Germany's Siemens Nixdorf.</p>
<p>Schulmeyer was on a panel with leaders of COMPAQ Computer Corp, French computer maker Groupe Bull, International Business Machines Corp and German software giant SAP AG to discuss the impact of information technology in Europe .</p>
<p>&quot;Europe is investing less than north America and Pacific Rim countries. We have to do all we can to get Europe to do more,&quot; Lucio Stanca, general manager of IBM told the conference.</p>
<p>The conference was organised by U.S. technology consultancy Gartner Group. The business leaders were interviewed by Gartner Group analysts.</p>
<p>One delegate said that the U.S. lead in high technology was not just down to business performance.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a state of mind. Americans are much more open to new technology; Many European companies are very conservative,&quot; said Andreas Barth, Senior vice-president and General Manager of COMPAQ, the world's biggest manufacturer of personal computers.</p>
<p>Sales of personal computers have exploded across the world in the 1990s, with many consumers inspired by the possibilities of the Internet.</p>
<p>Many experts believe that a huge amount of the world's commerce will be transacted in coming years across the Internet, a world-wide network of personal computers linked by telephone lines. They believe consumers will buy things like holidays, cars, properties and groceries with their personal computers.</p>
<p>Countries that lag behind will find living standards falling. So far Americans have led the way. About 35 percent of American households now have computers compared with less than 20 percent in Europe.</p>
<p>Not all Europeans were prepared to concede defeat to the Americans.</p>
<p>&quot;We can still catch up, after all we are only at the start (of the information technology revolution). We will be late, but it's not yet too late,&quot; said Jean Marie Descarpentries, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of Groupe Bull.</p>
<p>The French company has been pursuing an aggressive strategy, and its Zenith Data Systems personal computer division merged earlier this year with Packard Bell of the U.S. and NEC of Japan's PC subsidiary.</p>
<p>But Descarpentries conceded that investment hasn't been enough so far and attitudes have to change..</p>
<p>&quot;We have to invest more in IT (information technology), and we have to change minds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Siemens' Schulmeyer added a reassuring note for Europeans.</p>
<p>&quot;Europeans don't have to feel second-rate. When we get people involved, and our own operations in the U.S. bear this out, Europeans are as good as anyone,&quot; Schulmeyer said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANNES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
