<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170755" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Acclaim, Spectrum to settle suit.</title>
<headline>Acclaim, Spectrum to settle suit.</headline>
<dateline>ALAMEDA, Calif. 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spectrum HoloByte Inc and Acclaim Entertainment Inc said on Tuesday they had reached agreement on settling litigation regarding their games in development for use on personal computers.</p>
<p>Acclaim and Spectrum have been involved in litigation since July 9, 1996, over their respective license rights to the &quot;Magic: The Gathering&quot; card game and intellectual property.</p>
<p>Terms of the agreement include differentiation of each of the titles in the market.</p>
<p>Acclaim Entertainment will market its product for Windows 95 under the name &quot;Magic: The Gathering - BattleMage.&quot; The product is being developed and positioned as a real-time, multi-player strategy game, based on the characters and scenarios of the fantasy adventure world of &quot;Magic: The Gathering&quot;.</p>
<p>To further differentiate the products and avoid confusion at the time of product launch, Spectrum HoloByte and Acclaim have agreed to coordinate release dates for their respective products.</p>
<p>Acclaim anticipates releasing &quot;Magic: The Gathering - BattleMage&quot; prior to Christmas.  Spectrum HoloByte has agreed, subject to Acclaim completing its release by January 10, 1997, to release its &quot;Magic: The Gathering&quot; game no earlier than February 1, 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALAMEDA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
