<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170713" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: California shareholder suit opponents declare win.</title>
<headline>California shareholder suit opponents declare win.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opponents of California's Proposition 211 declared victory on Tuesday as early returns showed the controversial measure on shareholder lawsuits heading for defeat by a wide margin of two to one.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm going to declare victory,&quot; said Tom Proulx, the co- founder of Intuit Corp and a leader of the opposition effort, which was backed by major Silicon Valley high tech firms.</p>
<p>With 13 percent of precincts reporting, the measure was opposed by 69 percent of voters, with 31 percent in favour.</p>
<p>The ballot measure would have expanded the definition of fraud, reduced obstacles to filing shareholder lawsuits and lifted limits on fees of lawyers bringing the lawsuits.</p>
<p>Opponents, including a blue-ribbon list of Silicon Valley high-tech and biotech companies, raised some $38 million to oppose the legislation, outspending plaintiffs' lawyers and others who backed the initiative by up to three-to-one.</p>
<p>&quot;A year ago this valley was naive, not very well organised and not effective,&quot; venture capitalist John Doerr, another leader of the campaign against the measure.</p>
<p>Doerr said businesses were now prepared to work on issues such as education, economic growth, and litigation reform.</p>
<p>Both presidential candidates and the Securities and Exchange Commission chairman, Arthur Levitt, had come out against the measure, which Levitt said would have made California &quot;a magnet for class action suits.&quot;</p>
<p>Nearly half the American Electronics Institute's (AEA) high tech member firms said in a survey they would consider leaving California if the initiative passed, and economists warned it would have had a damaging effect on the national economy.</p>
<p>One economic study last month by the Economic Strategy Institute in Washington, D.C., projected that passage of 211 could have prompted a loss of up to 1.8 million jobs and a net loss to U.S. gross domestic product of up to $102 billion.</p>
<p>The study projected that a damaging increase in &quot;frivolous lawsuits&quot; could have resulted in a 12 to 24 percent drop in stock market values.</p>
<p>But members of the Taxpayers against Frivolous Lawsuits warned such measures could reappear on the ballot here or in other states unless national pre-emptive law is passed.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is to face the fact that this campaign, this kind of campaign, will be recreated across the nation and the only way to effectively do this is to make a major movement for federal pre-emption,&quot; said George Sollman, president and chairman of Centigram Communications Corp and chairman of the AEA trade group.</p>
<p>Opponents credit their early television campaign, its battle to restrict the language describing the initiative on the ballot, and companies own education programmes for employees as key to the effort to defeat the legislation.</p>
<p>Proponents of 211, including lawyers who bring shareholder lawsuits and are poised to benefit directly from it, said they drew up the measure when it was clear that anti-business sentiment appeared to be strong in California.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
