<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171161" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PC boom continues in Japan, buoyed by Internet.</title>
<headline>PC boom continues in Japan, buoyed by Internet.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's personal computer market continued robust growth in the first half of this business year as the Internet boom boosted PC sales despite a cooling of Windows 95 fever, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sales will get stronger toward the year-end as various new PC models hit the market, including lower-priced products,&quot; said Takashi Umeyama, an analyst at research company IDC Corp.</p>
<p>The Japan Electronic Industry Development Association (JEIDA) said on Wednesday that April-September PC shipments in Japan market grew a strong 39 percent from last year to 3.38 million units.</p>
<p>The trade group did not raise its forecast of 7.5 million PC shipments for the full year to March 31, but hinted that an upward revision was possible after December.</p>
<p>&quot;Sales are expected to continue to be solid in the second half, despite a lack of a strong attraction like last year's Windows 95,&quot; said Tetsuya Mizoguchi, the head of JEIDA's PC group and a vice president at Toshiba Corp.</p>
<p>Last business year, the November 1995 launch of the Microsoft Corp operating software and an aggressive pricing strategy adopted by newcomers like Fujitsu Ltd sharply expanded the lower end of Japan's PC market.</p>
<p>The market surged 70 percent during the year to 5.7 million units. The growth was also helped by the introduction of easy-to-use, all-in-one type PCs with pre-installed operating software, as well as various popular software.</p>
<p>This year there are new carrots, such as the Internet boom and new Microsoft operating software, Windows NT 4.0, analysts said. Windows NT 4.0 is used in network PCs by corporate customers.</p>
<p>Fujitsu's sales target is particularly bullish.</p>
<p>The company said on Wednesday it had raised its target for domestic PC sales in the current business year to 2.2 million units, up from the goal of two million set in April.</p>
<p>A favourable market environment made Fujitsu confident that a gain of more than 30 percent in sales was possible, Fujitsu executive director Takeshi Maruyama told a news conference.</p>
<p>Fujitsu sold 900,000 PCs in Japan in the April-September period, up from 500,000 units in the same period last year. Fujitsu said it sold 1.45 million PCs in Japan in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Maruyama said the company aims to sell three million PCs worldwide this business year, including 600,000 in Europe and 100,000-150,000 in the United States.</p>
<p>It entered the U.S. market for the first time at the end of June, selling notebook-type laptops.</p>
<p>IDC's Umeyama said Fujitsu could boost its Japanese market share for calendar 1996 to somewhere close to 30 percent from the 18 percent the research firm estimated in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
