<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173933" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intuit jumps on America Express buyout talk.</title>
<headline>Intuit jumps on America Express buyout talk.</headline>
<byline>Kourosh Karimkhany</byline>
<dateline>MENLO PARK, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intuit Inc. shares jumped 24 percent Wednesday amid market speculation that American Express Co. is about to buy the struggling financial management software company.</p>
<p>Shares of Intuit, which publishes the best-selling Quicken personal finance computer program, surged $7 to close at $36.50 on Nasdaq. American Express rose 12.5 cents to $48.50 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Officials of both companies declined to comment about &quot;market rumors,&quot; and an Intuit spokeswoman called the speculation &quot;wild.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said American Express, the charge card and financial services company, would be interested in buying Intuit to enable it to jump into the booming online banking industry.</p>
<p>Intuit, analysts said, might be receptive to an offer because of increasing doubts about its future.</p>
<p>Even if American Express is not interested in acquiring Intuit, other companies may be, analysts said.</p>
<p>More than 9 million people, most of them affluent, use Intuit's Quicken to manage their finances and do their banking chores through their personal computers.</p>
<p>But Intuit's growth has stalled amid fierce competition with Microsoft Corp., a one-time suitor of Intuit, and a handful of banks which are offering online banking to their customers through the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;Intuit is staring down the barrel of a gun, and that gun is the Internet, which is making financial management easier,&quot; said Karen Epper, an online banking analyst at market researcher Forrester Research Inc in Cambridge, Mass.</p>
<p>Until two years ago, Intuit relied heavily on sales of its financial and tax software for its growth. Those sales have slowed as Intuit has cut prices.</p>
<p>Intuit also faces renewed competition from Microsoft, which tried to buy it in 1994. Microsoft dropped the acquisition in May 1995 because of opposition from government antitrust officials.</p>
<p>Since then, Microsoft, the world's biggest PC software company has spent hundreds of millions to take on Intuit.</p>
<p>To fuel its growth, Intuit set up a business two years ago to process online banking transactions between banks and depositors. Some investors saw the transaction business as a promising source of growth.</p>
<p>In September, however, Intuit sold its transaction processing unit, Intuit Services Corp., to rival CheckFree Corp.</p>
<p>Epper said Intuit's biggest challenge is figuring out how to grow. She said the company needs the backing of a bank or bigger computer company to fuel expansion into any new business.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MENLO PARK, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
