<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181868" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Best new products of the year.</title>
<headline>Best new products of the year.</headline>
<byline>Judith Schoolman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>The time is upon us to start making lists. Popular Science magazine, leading the pack, has taken on the task of finding the best new products of 1996.</p>
<p>From Barbie's Fashion Design software to an aerodynamic bicycle to the world's smallest camcorder, these products are on the cutting edge of entertainment, transportation and computer technology, the magazine says in its December issue.</p>
<p>&quot;The main criterion for an invention or discorery is how it made a difference in our lives,&quot; said Fred Abatemarco, editor in chief of the magazine.</p>
<p>Ten grand prizes were awarded. The grand prize winner in the photography category is the Nikon 5, &quot;setting a new standard for professional-level, single-lens reflex 35mm cameras,&quot; Popular Science says. At $3,350 for the body only (lenses separate), this camera has an advanced autofocus system that allows shots at eight frames per second.</p>
<p>In automotive technology, the grand prize winner is the EV1, the first electric car sold to the public in decades. Available for lease from Saturn dealers in Arizona and Southern California, the car can go 70 to 90 miles before recharging. Rental price, $35,000 for three years.</p>
<p>In cars, the grand prize winner is Ford's 1997 Expedition, &quot;setting the standard for packaging in big sport utilities,&quot; Popular Science said. &quot;A new engine establishes the leading edge of trailer-towing power and fuel economy simultaneously,&quot; it said. Base price: $28,000.</p>
<p>Snuggle up to concrete? Scientists at Canada's National Research Council have come up with a concrete that conducts electricity, to warm up the material. Potential uses for this grand prize winner in the home technology category include residential driveways, airport runways, home heating and thermal storage units.</p>
<p>For style and capacity, Compaq's Presario 3000 home computer was given the grand prize in the computers and electronics category. At about $3,500, the computer has a high-speed Pentium processor and other features, and can easily be packed up and moved from room to room.</p>
<p>To energise your roof to trim energy bills, the grand prize winner in the environmental technology category is United Solar Systems's shingles that incorporate solar cells. In a sunny region, a 400-square-foot solar shingle roof could generate enough electricity to meet the demands of an average household. Price has not yet been set.</p>
<p>A smart recreational ski, by ski makers Ks and ACX Inc., is the winner in the recreation category. The K2 Four ski contains circuitry and a special ceramic that together detect and control vibrations, for a smooth glide down the slopes. A pair of skis sells for about $625.</p>
<p>WebTV, an add-on box, provides Internet access on your television. Te be marketed by Sony and Philips, this grand prize winner in the audio and video segment was developed by WebTV Networks. A price has not yet been set.</p>
<p>Protease inhibitors, a new type of drugs used to help combat AIDS, were given the grand prize in the science and technology category.</p>
<p>In aviation and space, the grand prize winner may be among one of the universe's oldest &quot;products.&quot; A meteorite discovered in Antarctica and believed to be from Mars provides strong evidence that primitive life once existed there.</p>
<p>Among other best new products of 1996 is JVC's camcorder. The GR-DV1 is so small it can travel right in your pocket. It weighs only 1.1 pounds fully equipped and has all the newest features of larger versions. Price: about $3,000.</p>
<p>More earthbound winners include Mattel Inc.'s Barbie Fashion Designer ($40) software, which allows kids to use a computer to craft designs for the famed doll.</p>
<p>Chrysler's &quot;skunk works&quot; programme has come up with the design for the 1997 Plymouth Prowler, an all-aluminum roadster. Base price: about $35,000.</p>
<p>Rollerblade's Xtenblade, adjustable inline skates that can &quot;grow&quot; with your child, was another winner. Because the shoes expand only at the front of the skate, no rear-balance problems are created. Price: about $100.</p>
<p>The SuperBike 2, which helped Olympic riders record their fastest times so far, marks a turning point in bicycle development, Popular Science said. Shaped like a V, the carbon-fiber composite frame is superlight, even lighter than previous aluminum SuperBikes. Made by GT Bicycles, a price has not been set.</p>
<p>One of the best new products this year for the home was found to be Black &amp; Decker's Scumbuster, a submersible power scrubber that handles long-neglected scummy messes, such as bathtubs and &quot;and other nasty cleaning jobs,&quot; the magazine said. Battery-powered, it does the work, not you. It sells for about $60.</p>
<p>Popular Science's December issue will be on newsstands shortly. Its cover price is $2.50, $3.50 in Canada.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
