<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182814" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fidelity's Stansky cautious on stock buys.</title>
<headline>Fidelity's Stansky cautious on stock buys.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fidelity Investments' Magellan Fund manager Bob Stansky said with price-to-earnings ratios near five-year highs, he wants to be &quot;especially careful not to pay too much when buying a stock.&quot;</p>
<p>In the fund's semiannual report for the period ended Sept. 30, Stansky struck a note of caution, warning that if the economy slowed it could hurt stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;If world economies slow, or we begin to see widespread interst rate hikes, the entire U.S. market could be negatively impacted,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>However, he added that &quot;there will always be companies of all sizes that achieve success; my job is to find them.&quot;</p>
<p>Stansky said he has found such companies in the technology sector.  Companies such as Intel Corp, Cisco Systems Inc, Oracle Corp and International Business Machines Corp performed strongly during the last few months, which boosted the fund's performance &quot;as I acquired increasingly larger stakes in these companies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fidelity's stake in technology stocks rose to 10.7 percent of total assets at the end of September from 3.5 percent earlier in the year.  </p>
<p>He warned that technology stocks are riskier investments, &quot;however, given the earnings potential of many technology companies at the end of the period, the fund can ill afford to stay away.&quot;</p>
<p>Several of the fund's top 10 stocks are cyclicals, including General Motors Corp, Chrysler Corp, CSX Corp and Deere &amp; Co which have lagged gains in the broad market this year, &quot;despite generally favorable business prospects.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;I believe this was tied to investor skepticism that earnings for these companies may have already peaked for this economic cycle,&quot; he said. &quot;The market was reluctant to reward these stocks with higher valuations -- despite respectable earnings -- until the companies can prove that their best earnings aren't behind them.&quot;</p>
<p>When asked why the fund has underperformed this year, Stansky laid the blame on Magellan's high stakes in bonds, cash, cyclical stocks and in a few battered companies such as Digital Equipment Corp and AT&amp;T Corp earlier this year.</p>
<p>Without mentioning his predecessor, Jeffrey Vinik, who announced his resignation in May, Stansky said, &quot;that lack of firepower among the fund's largest holdings somewhat limited its returns.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Michael Ellis, Boston bureau (617) 367-4176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
