<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18393" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ford announces new computer-aided design system.</title>
<headline>Ford announces new computer-aided design system.</headline>
<byline>Todd Nissen</byline>
<dateline>DEARBORN, Mich. 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Calling it a crucial change for how it develops new cars and trucks, Ford Motor Co. Wednesday launched a new computer-aided design project based on a computer programme from Structural Dynamics Research Corp..</p>
<p>Ford said the new project, called C3P, will cut prototype costs by up to 50 percent; improve investment efficiency by 20 percent to 30 percent; and eliminate half of costly late development changes.</p>
<p>&quot;The new C3P initiative represents the most fundamental change of the engineering computer infrastructure in Ford's history,&quot; Paul Blumberg, director of product development systems at Ford's Product Development Centre, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Officials did not specify any dollar amount savings. But executives said they fall under previously disclosed product development cost savings. Three new vehicle programmes started this year will use C3P.</p>
<p>Once the programme is fully implemented in 2000, Ford said it will merge computer-aided design, manufacturing and engineering functions into a seamless, unified system encompassing all stages of vehicle and component development.</p>
<p>Ford's decision to team up with Structural Dynamics Research (SDRC) raised eyebrows at competitors. The Milford, Ohio-based firm is a small player in the market of supplying computer aided design and manufacturing systems (CAD/CAM) to the auto industry, according to both competitors and analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;You just don't hear about SDRC,&quot; said Ron Bienkowski, an executive engineer at Chrysler Corp.</p>
<p>Bienkowski also chided Ford for launching a new design programme seven years after Chrysler did.</p>
<p>&quot;We made the decision to go to a single system like C3P back in 1989,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chrysler, as well as several other Japanese and European automakers, use the more popular CATIA programme from Paris-based Dassault Systemes and IBM Corp..</p>
<p>Charles Foundyller, president of market research firm Daratech Inc. in Cambridge, Mass., said the SDRC system is an easy-to-use, powerful system that should serve Ford well.</p>
<p>&quot;All in all, I don't think Ford made a bad decision,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ford made the C3P announcement as part of a half-day presentation to reporters touting the No. 2 U.S. automaker's computer capabilities. Among other news items announced Wednesday, Ford:</p>
<p>-- plans to eliminate 90 percent of its physical prototypes by 2000 in favour of electronic versions. Physical prototypes now constitute about 40 percent to 50 percent today;</p>
<p>-- will be able to conduct a computer-simulated frontal crash for $10 in 2000, compared to the $200 it currently costs;</p>
<p>-- will introduce a production car in Europe in 1997 that was designed almost completely using computer technology.</p>
<p>Ford executives were hard-pressed to assign dollar amounts to all of the new computer design and prototype initiatives.</p>
<p>But Claude Lobo, director of advanced design at Ford, said the new systems dramatically improve quality and free designers and engineers to take more risks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DEARBORN, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
