<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186975" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - A. Brown details Informix downgrade.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - A. Brown details Informix downgrade.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Joining several other Wall Street analysts who have recently reduced their earnings outlooks on Informix Corp, Alex. Brown analyst Jim Moore said he cut his current quarter and upcoming year estimates on the database software maker.</p>
<p>-- Moore also confirmed he downgraded the stock to buy from strong buy.</p>
<p>-- Citing concerns about certain near-term risks and an ongoing product transition, Moore said he cut his earnings estimate for the current fourth quarter to $0.22 per share from $0.26 per share previously.  </p>
<p>-- &quot;The main reason for lowering the numbers is fourth quarter risk,&quot; Moore said, pointing in particular to the expected negative growth in the company's software tools business, which accounts for roughly 15 percent of revenues.</p>
<p>-- He also expressed concerns about Informix's Japan and Federal Systems businesses in the current quarter, &quot;given that the company is not giving (analysts) any information on that.&quot;</p>
<p>-- &quot;There is just too much risk on the quarter,&quot; he said to continue to maintain a strong buy rating on the company. &quot;We were just cleaning up our rating today.&quot;</p>
<p>-- However, Moore said he believed the company's next generation multimedia database product, known as the Universal Server, &quot;is very much on track,&quot; and added, &quot;That will help the stock in the long term.&quot;</p>
<p>-- The Alex. Brown analyst joined analysts from Montgomery Securities and Donaldson Lufkin who cut their earnings estimates on Informix on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- However, Salomon analyst Neil Herman confirmed on Wednesday that he had upgraded Informix to buy from hold. He declined to comment further.</p>
<p>-- The stock was up 1-11/16 at 19-5/16 in heavy trading.</p>
<p>-- E. Auchard, Wall Street bureau, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
