<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189986" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Novelist Tom Clancy targets online game audience.</title>
<headline>Novelist Tom Clancy targets online game audience.</headline>
<byline>Franklin Paul</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Best-selling author Tom Clancy and software developer Virtus Corp. hope to blast their way into the online gaming arena with the formation of Red Storm Entertainment, the author said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Red Storm, a partnership owned equally by Clancy and Virtus, plans to offer interactive computer games, with a focus on the new generation of multiplayer games, which allow players to match wits against each over via online networks.</p>
<p>The games will be based on the sort of military and geopolitical storylines that have made Clancy one of America's most popular authors.</p>
<p>&quot;Using the computer, we can set up multiplayer games ... that will create a degree of realism that never really existed outside of the professional communities,&quot; said Clancy, who is also Red Storm's chairman and whose best-sellers include the novel &quot;Red Storm Rising.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to turn out games that are more realistic than naval officers play for a living,&quot; he said in an interview.</p>
<p>Online interactive gaming allows multiple users in remote locations simultaneously to play games linked by modems over the Internet.</p>
<p>The emerging field generated $50 million in sales last year and is expected to grow to a $1.6 billion business by the year 2000, according to market research firm Jupiter Communications.</p>
<p>Existing online gaming firms like Mpath Interactive's Mplayer or Total Entertainment Network allow players, for a fee, to play games primarily based on strategic conquest.</p>
<p>&quot;The dream that (we) have is that in not too many year's time we will have thousands of people playing one of our games worldwide at the same time,&quot; Doug Littlejohns, Red Storm president, said in an interview.</p>
<p>The games will be sold on compact disc, and will be available over the Internet as they are developed. Cary, N.C.-based Red Storm expects to introduce its first two products in the fall of 1997, with two more to follow in 1998. Expansion into other entertainment media is also in the works.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at a broad franchise of games plus derivatives; books, maybe movies, TV series, toys, you name it,&quot; Littlejohns said.</p>
<p>Littlejohns is a retired Royal Navy captain and friend of Clancy, the author said in a message to visitors to the new company's Web site. Computer users can find details on Red Storm at http://www.redstorm.com.</p>
<p>&quot;Tom Clancy SSN,&quot; a computer game developed by Clancy and Virtus and released in the United States on Tuesday, is a precursor to the alliance. Future releases will be distributed in Europe by Virgin Interactive, a division of Viacom Inc., a Virtus executive said.</p>
<p>Putnam Books will publish the hardcover novel of &quot;Tom Clancy SSN.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
