<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190497" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Copyright loss may spark more problems for Aztech.</title>
<headline>Copyright loss may spark more problems for Aztech.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in multimedia company Aztech Systems' were hammered on Thursday after the company's defeat in a copyright battle, and analysts warned it could face a cash-flow crunch that may hinder operations.</p>
<p>Aztech's share price plunged more than 18 percent in early trade to a low of S$0.43 (US$0.30) and last traded at S$0.485 at mid-morning before trading was suspended at the company's request pending an announcement. Its share price had fallen from a high of S$0.97 early this year.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the Court of Appeal in Singapore ruled Aztech had infringed the copyright of Creative Technology's eight-bit Sound Blaster sound card software code.</p>
<p>That overturned an earlier High Court decision in October 1995 to dismiss Creative's claims of copyright infringement against Aztech.</p>
<p>&quot;Aztech's share price is unlikely to perform in the near term given the lawsuit prospects. Creative can go ahead and bring an additional lawsuit for the 16-bit sound card and make Aztech's prospects even more cloudy,&quot; Stephen Chan, senior analyst at Kay Hian James Capel, told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Share analysts said they expected Aztech to trade closer to S$0.40, around two times its revised book value of about S$0.20.</p>
<p>They said Aztech had a weak balance sheet and feared Aztech could face a cash-flow hurdle that could hamper its operations.</p>
<p>Officials at Aztech and Creative could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Aztech had shareholders' funds of about S$120 million and debt of about S$110 milion as of June 1996.</p>
<p>Gregory Yap, investment analyst at J.M. Sassoon &amp; Co, said he estimated Aztech's damages from the lawsuit to be about S$28 million, excluding legal costs.</p>
<p>&quot;If Creative does intend to push for a lump sum payable, then Aztech would be in trouble,&quot; said Yap.</p>
<p>He said Aztech might not be able to go ahead with an intended Euro convertible bond issue to raise capital to refinance its debt.</p>
<p>Patrick Yau, analyst at Schroders Securities, said Aztech could be left with only half of its shareholders funds after taking into account the copyright damages and its interim losses -- S$17.7 million in net loss and an extraordinary charge of S$15 million for its investment in U.S.-based Reveal Computers Products Inc.  </p>
<p>Yap said Aztech's cash-flow crunch might be felt from the second half of 1997 as he expected the legal process to drag out.</p>
<p>He said the most critical period for Aztech would be until June next year. The company would have problems if it did not have enough working capital to fulfil increased orders for Christmas and other big orders in the months ahead.</p>
<p>Analysts said that if Creative also decided to sue Aztech for software code infringements for 16-bit and 32-bit sound cards, the real impact might not be felt for at least two years. Prospects would be gloomy during that period, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
