<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198978" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TALKING POINT - Health care information seen growing.</title>
<headline>TALKING POINT - Health care information seen growing.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street's rumbling bull market has left health care information technology stocks in the dust, but the group could be poised for recovery.</p>
<p>While the broad U.S. stock market has surged to record highs, health care information technology stocks have been hammered by a spate of profit warnings that began in the summer, leading battered investors to turn their backs on the once high-flying shares.</p>
<p>&quot;People are nervous and I don't blame them for being nervous,&quot; said UBS Securities analyst Anthony Vendetti.</p>
<p>But analysts covering the industry, which is in the business of automating doctors' and hospitals' paperwork, said the stocks should rise out of their sick bed, driven by the growth of the U.S. managed care industry.</p>
<p>Since July investors have been rocked by warnings of earnings shortfalls from companies including Cerner Corp, Medaphis Corp, HCIA Inc, and Health Management Systems Inc.</p>
<p>From their market highs in May, health care information stocks declined a mean of 32 percent through the end of October, according to brokerage Punk, Ziegel and Knoell.</p>
<p>Meanwhile price/earnings multiples over 1997 projected earnings have tumbled 29 percent, according to the firm, which which tracked a list of 26 stocks in the group.</p>
<p>But Wall Street analysts following the industry are sticking to their buy ratings.</p>
<p>However, they favor the health information technology companies with large customer bases that will enable them to avoid having their quarterly earnings thrown out of whack by a single delayed contract, the source of some of the group's recent woes.</p>
<p>&quot;In this environment you want to go with the established companies,&quot; Vendetti said.</p>
<p>He listed among his buy recommendations as HBO &amp; Co and Medic Computer System.</p>
<p>The analysts say they continue to expect the companies to profit from increased spending by hospitals and health maintenance organizations on computers and software needed to cut paper work and provide medical information and records over expanding health care networks.</p>
<p>Market pressures driving doctors to join larger physician networks as well as so-called capitation programs, in which doctors are paid by managed care groups a pre-determined, fix amount per patient, will also benefit the group, analysts said.</p>
<p>Punk Ziegel and Knoell analyst David Francis said he expected the health care information technology industry to grow by 35 to 40 percent through the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;Managed care is not going away, capitation is not going away,&quot; Francis said. </p>
<p>His recommendations include &quot;aggressive buys&quot; on HBO &amp; Co, Medic Computers, IMNET Systems Inc, and Physician Support Systems Inc.</p>
<p>Sally Yanchus, initiated coverage of health care information stocks at Oppenheimer and Co on Tuesday, calling the beaten-down valuations in the group &quot;a tremendous opportunity.&quot;</p>
<p>Yanchus put buy ratings on HBO &amp; Co, with a 12-month price target of 75, Medic Computer, with a target of 45, Phamis Inc, with a target of 25, IMNET, with a target of 40 and  and Sunquest Information Inc, with a target of 25.</p>
<p>On Tuesday afternoon trading HBO &amp; Co was up 1/2 at 53, Medic Computer was flat at 29-1/4, IMNET gained 2-1/8 to 16-1/4, Sunquest eased 1/4 at 15, Cerner was off 5/8 at 11 and Phamis rose 3/8 at 11-1/2.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
