<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20000" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bill Gates predicts computer future at conference.</title>
<headline>Bill Gates predicts computer future at conference.</headline>
<dateline>NEW ORLEANS 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computers will visually identify their users, recognize their voices and talk back probably within the next decade, Microsoft's Bill Gates told a computer conference Tuesday night.</p>
<p>Speaking at the Computer Associates International Inc 20th annual users conference, Gates said, &quot;Microsoft is taking the long-term approach ... spending $2 billion a year on research and development.</p>
<p>&quot;We're working on things like speech recognition, speech synthesization and visual recognition. In the next decade, today's interfaces will be obsolete,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Computers will listen, talk, see, learn and even screen our mail. And we'll be able to see the response of someone when they read our mail to them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier Tuesday CA and Microsoft announced an agreement to integrate Microsoft's Internet Explorer browser with CA's Unicenter TNG systems management software.</p>
<p>The two companies said they agreed to work together on systems for managing enterprise applications, including those on the Internet's World Wide Web.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, CA will distribute Internet Explorer 3.0 with its Unicenter TNG software developers kit. Microsoft's ActiveX Controls and &quot;Wolfpack&quot; clustering technology also will be integrated with Unicenter TNG.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW ORLEANS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
