<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203129" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CompuServe seen dissolving Wow! service.</title>
<headline>CompuServe seen dissolving Wow! service.</headline>
<byline>Therese Poletti</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CompuServe Corp is expected to announce on Thursday that it is dissolving its Wow! consumer online service as it gives up on the consumer market and refocuses on the corporate market, industry sources said.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Columbus, Ohio based company declined to comment, saying he could not comment in advance of a &quot;strategic announcement&quot; CompuServe plans early Thursday.</p>
<p>The struggling online services company has been under more pressure in recent months from America Online Inc, the Microsoft Corp Network and Internet access providers.</p>
<p>The company plans to halt its marketing aimed at consumers and it will expand its emphasis on corporate customers in the U.S. and Europe. CompuServe will try to convert its 100,000 Wow! users to its core CompuServe Information Service and it will not abandon its current consumer users, sources said.</p>
<p>But it will not make the consumer business a key focus, as it cedes to the dominant America Online, which is growing its subscriber base again, after a hiccup in growth this summer.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts said that such a move could entail some layoffs at CompuServe, and possibly a restructuring charge to cover Wow! employees who cannot be reassigned.  </p>
<p>CompuServe's move comes on the heels of some recent aggressive actions by AOL to stay on top with its plans to shut down its GNN direct Internet access and its announcement to cut its workforce by 300 employees and take a $75 million charge in its second fiscal quarter.</p>
<p>AOL also announced flat-rate pricing of $19.95 a month for unlimited access, bowing to the competition from Internet access providers and their flat monthly rates of $19.95.</p>
<p>CompuServe's Wow! service is a flat-rate service, for $17.95 a month, but it could not be learned if CompuServe will change the pricing of its core CIS service as it dissolves Wow.  </p>
<p>CompuServe hopes to move all its Wow! subscribers over to its core service by the end of January.</p>
<p>&quot;They have a separate productions staff, separate marketing, etc,&quot; said Abhishek Gami, an analyst at Nesbitt Burns Securities, adding however that CompuServe has tried to keep Wow! extremely lean and some employees will likely be moved to the main service or to SPRYNET, its Internet service.</p>
<p>Since CompuServe went public in April, its prospects have dimmed, with its stock tumbling from its initial offering price of $30 a share. Its shares now trade at around $11-5/8, since it has announced losses and a drop in subscribers.  </p>
<p>&quot;They have had a whole lot of problems since they went public,&quot; said one industry source. &quot;They need to reposition the company.&quot;</p>
<p>CompuServe is the second largest online service after America Online.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
