<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209783" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: APEC not plugging into U.S. info-tech plan.</title>
<headline>APEC not plugging into U.S. info-tech plan.</headline>
<byline>Bill Tarrant</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. plan to free global trade in computers and telecommunications at the turn of the century appeared to be floundering on Friday at an annual conference of Asia-Pacific nations.</p>
<p>Washington had hoped the 18-member Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum would give a ringing endorsement to its plan to cut tariffs to zero by the year 2000 on a broad range of information technology products.</p>
<p>Instead, trade and foreign ministers, meeting ahead of APEC's summit on Monday, would probably issue a vague statement welcoming ongoing negotiations in Geneva on such a pact, delegates said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've worked out language that's acceptable,&quot; said a senior representative from a Latin American delegation. &quot;It will say that efforts in Geneva to conclude an ITA (information Technology Agreement) are endorsed by APEC.</p>
<p>&quot;But we don't want to prejudge the outcome in Geneva by having negotiations about it here (at APEC),&quot; the delegate said.</p>
<p>The stakes are high. Washington says the information technology business is worth $1.8 trillion and the United States accounts for 60 percent of it.</p>
<p>The United States wanted APEC to endorse the ITA to give the pact a head start when it is submitted at next month's inaugural World Trade Organisation meeting in Singapore.</p>
<p>U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky told a conference of APEC business leaders that information technology products were the infrastructure of the 21st Century.</p>
<p>&quot;They are and will be to that century what roads and bridges were in the 19th century, &quot; Barshefsky said.</p>
<p>Japan's Trade Minister Shinji Sato told Reuters on Friday that while Tokyo and Washington were enthusiastic, &quot;we should not push it too strongly here, because we might invite the suspicion of other members&quot;.</p>
<p>Washington put a brave face on the pact's fate at APEC.</p>
<p>&quot;I won't be able to give you box score right now because (negotiations) are going on even as we sit here,&quot; said Ambassador John Wolf, the American coordinator for APEC.</p>
<p>U.S. State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said: &quot;I can tell you progress has been made today, but we're not at the end of this process.&quot;</p>
<p>Malaysia and some other developing countries object to the tariff targets and timeframes in the pact, saying it undermines the essential volunteerism of the diverse group.</p>
<p>&quot;There must be assurances that flexibilities are given to such countries that need flexibility in the area of the timeframe and in product coverage,&quot; Malaysia's Minister of International Trade and Industry told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>Asked if she thought the WTO meeting in Singapore could endorse the ITA agreement in its current form, Rafidah Aziz said: &quot;As it stands I doubt it very much.&quot;</p>
<p>The European Union accused the United States this week of undermining the ITA by trying to exclude important categories of goods, which U.S. trade officials denied.</p>
<p>APEC decisions are based on consensus, which means crafting language that is acceptable to all members.</p>
<p>Rodolfo Severino, the undersecretary in the Philippine Foreign Ministry, said ministers would reach a consensus on the accord.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that some formula will be arrived at with the approval of all ministers, which will take into account members' concerns,&quot; Severino said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
