<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216240" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Novell not for sale.</title>
<headline>Novell not for sale.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novell Inc, the giant software company is not for sale and sees its future course as an independent one, Chief Financial Officer Jim Tolonen said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We see ourselves as an independent entity,&quot; Tolonen told Reuters in a telephone interview after the company released fourth quarter earnings.</p>
<p>He said Novell chairman John Young told analysts on a conference call immediately following the release that Novell belives the best way to provide value for customers and shareholders is to follow an independent course.  </p>
<p>Tolonen also said Novell is comfortable with analysts' estimates that it will earn in fiscal 1997 between $0.80 and $0.90 a share. For the fiscal year ended October 31, Novell earned $0.35 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;We're well positioned to show great earnings growth,&quot; Tolonen said. &quot;We have turned the company around.&quot;</p>
<p>But it has been a rocky road in recent months. The Orem, Utah-based company sold some assets, including WordPerfect -- a company many analysts said should never have been bought in the first place. Chief Financial Officer Bob Frankenberg resigned in late summer.  </p>
<p>Tolonen said revenues in the fourth quarter for software for intranets -- a key product -- rose $50 million from the third quarter.</p>
<p>Tolonen said Novell was still focusing on finding strategic partners for a variety of projects.</p>
<p>The company's recent difficulties has kept alive speculation that Novell might be the object of a takeover attempt. But with its capitalization at about $3.8 billion, there are not many companies that could accomplish such a feat, Tolonen said.</p>
<p>Novell shares closed up 1/8 at 10-7/8, compared with its 52-week low of 8-3/4.</p>
<p>--Judith Crosson 303-820-3900</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
