<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217276" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Softbank to raise funds for broadcasting business.</title>
<headline>Softbank to raise funds for broadcasting business.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's aggressively expanding Softbank Corp said on Tuesday it would raise 54 billion yen ($482 million) in Japan's stock and bond markets to fund its latest business target -- digital satellite broadcasting.</p>
<p>Softbank, already absorbing large amounts of funds to support a series of bold investments, said it would issue 4.7 million new shares and float convertible bonds worth 10 billion yen ($89.2 million).</p>
<p>Talk that Softbank would tap deep into the markets depressed the company's share price. It tumbled by its daily limit on the over-the-counter market in heavy trade, and was quoted at 8,990 yen in the early afternoon on Tuesday, down 1,000 yen ($8).</p>
<p>Traders said the expectation fuelled fears of an oversupply of Softbank shares.</p>
<p>Last November, Softbank raised 66.5 billion yen ($593 million) from the stock market by issuing 2.8 million new shares.</p>
<p>This was in addition to aggressive borrowing from the bond market -- 90 billion yen ($803 million) through straight bond issues and 70 billion yen ($625 million) in convertible bond issues last business year alone.</p>
<p>Softbank, which has become world's largest computer-related magazine and book publisher through a string of bold buyouts, said the new funds would be used for the launch of a new digital satellite television service, J-SkyB.</p>
<p>Softbank launched the joint venture in the summer with international media tycoon Rupert Murdoch's News Corp.</p>
<p>The two bought 21.4 percent of Japan's nationwide television network Asahi National Broadcasting in June.</p>
<p>Softbank president Masayoshi Son said earlier this month that digital satellite broadcasting would be Softbank's business focus for the next year or two.</p>
<p>Analysts expect more than 100 billion yen ($892 million) will be required to launch the satellite broadcasting business.</p>
<p>Softbank has said Son's comments marked at least a temporary halt to a buying spree which culminated in the purchase in September of an 80 percent stake in Kingston Technology Corp, a leading supplier of memory modules, for cash and stock worth some $1.5 billion.</p>
<p>Within the past year, Softbank has completed $2.1 billion acquisition of Ziff-Davis Publishing, and last year spent some $800 million for the Interface Group, whose trade show portfolio includes Comdex, the largest U.S. computer trade show.</p>
<p>The expansion drive, as well as issues of new shares to finance the buyouts, have worried some investors, who think the speed of growth too fast.</p>
<p>Softbank has forecast a parent current profit of 19 billion yen ($170 million) for the year to March 1997.</p>
<p>($1=112 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
