<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217751" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Easdaq trade kicks off Wednesday with Dr Solomons.</title>
<headline>Easdaq trade kicks off Wednesday with Dr Solomons.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.K.-based anti-virus software developer Dr Solomons Group Plc has won the race to be the first stock listed on Europe's new exchange for growth stocks, Easdaq, and begins trading Wednesday, the exchange said.</p>
<p>&quot;Dr Solomons launches today on Nasdaq and is due to start trading on Easdaq on Wednesday,&quot; Easdaq spokesman Chris Pickles told Reuters on Tuesday. He was unable to give a listing price.</p>
<p>Easdaq said in a statement that Dr Solomon's planned to raise about $96 million to reach total market capitalisation of about $300 million. Goldman Sachs is acting as lead manager.  </p>
<p>Its initial market makers on Easdaq will be Hambrecht &amp; Quist Saint Dominique in Paris and Beeson Gregory in London.</p>
<p>By 1725 GMT the stock was trading on the U.S. growth stocks market Nasdaq at $17, down from an opening level of $17-5/8.</p>
<p>Pipped to the post by Dr Solomon's, Belgian biotechnology firm Innogenetics  INNX.ED is due to start trading on Easdaq on Thursday after an initial public offering.</p>
<p>It hopes to raise $78 million to achieve a market capitalisation of about $246 million.</p>
<p>French &quot;smart card&quot; maker ActivCard SA and Belgian software firm Artwork Systems aim to list on Easdaq in early December.  </p>
<p>The pan-European exchange, which is modelled on Nasdaq, became technically operational on September 30.</p>
<p>It expects to see the shares of a dozen companies traded by the end of January and up to 50 by the end of 1997 with a target of 500 companies listed in the next five years.</p>
<p>These would include some of the 79 European companies already listed on Nasdaq, which are seeking a dual listing.</p>
<p>&quot;Dr Solomon's, Innogenetics, ActivCard and Artwork Systems are exactly the kind of entrepreneurial growth companies that Easdaq is aiming for,&quot; Easdaq chief executive officer Jacques Putzeys said in the statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;A large number of similar companies have applied for admission and are currently in various stages of discussion with the market authority. There is a clear need for Easdaq, and now that quotations have actually started we expect the number of applications to accelerate,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>To be admitted, firms must be supported by at least two Easdaq-registered market makers. They must have total assets of 3.5 million Ecus and capital and reserves of two million Ecus.</p>
<p>The Easdaq project originated from contacts between the European Venture Capital Association, the European Commission and various market players.</p>
<p>Nasdaq is one of Easdaq's 91 shareholders which brought about 370 million Belgian francs together to finance its launch.</p>
<p>Trading on the Brussels based exchange is between 0930 and 1630 Belgian time (0830 and 1530 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Lorrayne Smith, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6812, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
