<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218801" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks finish higher, towed by blue chips.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks finish higher, towed by blue chips.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo stocks ended higher on Tuesday, supported by a booming New York stock market and towed by blue-chip issues, brokers said. They said market participants were eager to see the Bank of Japan's (BOJ) &quot;tankan&quot; business sentiment survey to be released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>At the end of the session, the Nikkei 225 was up 124.68 points or 0.59 percent at 21,418.25. Its December futures were 60 points higher at 21,360.</p>
<p>&quot;International issues which are seen doing well stole the limelight once again today as investors eagerly snapped up the shares,&quot; said Nomura Securities strategist Masaaki Higashida.  </p>
<p>Some regional banks on the other hand were battered. Tokuyo City Bank Ltd   8547.T shed 28 to 191 yen, the largest</p>
<p>percentage loser on the the Tokyo Exchange first section, due to margin transaction linked selling as well sales inspired by worries over its financial health. Bank of Kansai Ltd shares were down 30 yen at 610 on the Osaka bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;Ever since the Finance Ministry suspended some of Hanwa Bank Ltd's business operations, investors have become sensitive about regional banks,&quot; a second-tier broker said.</p>
<p>In over-the-counter shares, Softbank Corp plunged to a new low for the year by late trade, down 970 at 9,020 yen.  </p>
<p>Traders said the fall was brought about by fears of an oversupply of Softbank shares.</p>
<p>The OTC index stood at 1,420.65, down 7.59 points or 0.53 percent in late afternoon.</p>
<p>The gaining sectors were led by precision instruments, miscellaneous manufacturers, retailers, fisheries, rubber and machinery. The retreaters were headed by iron/steel, real estate, mining, oil and construction.</p>
<p>-- Masako Iijima, Tokyo Equities Desk +81-3-3432-9052</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
