<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219358" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS - High-tech issues stay chipper.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS - High-tech issues stay chipper.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Persistent bullishness in technology issues kept call options for the sector well bid amid generally slow trading in the broader market ahead of the Thanksgiving Day holiday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think buyers are feeling really comfortable,&quot; said a brokerage trader. &quot;But trying to pick a top just hasn't worked.&quot;</p>
<p>Intel Corp, America Online Inc and Bay Networks Inc calls were among the most actively traded options today, with underlying shares rising on relatively large volume.  </p>
<p>Most of the large option trades in other sectors, such as Wal-Mart Stores Inc and Merck &amp; Co, were vertical spreads and rollovers by institutions, traders said.</p>
<p>The broader stock market was flat to softer, with caution about overbought conditions keeping implied volatilities aloft despite time-decay concerns ahead of the Thanksgiving Day holiday on Thursday.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 100 index was up 0.82 point at 732.17 at 1258 CST/1858 GMT. The Chicago Board Options Exchange volatility index, which reflects implied volatilities for OEX options, was up 0.14 point to 18.47.  </p>
<p>Traders said the market was cautious because stocks tend to be choppy around this time of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;Friday is a half-day, (but) we usually do stuff on that day,&quot; said a trader in the OEX pit at CBOE. But he added that traders were &quot;clearing out&quot; by late morning today.</p>
<p>Tim Ord of the Ord Oracle said today's small losses were just minor consolidation and expected further gains in the OEX and S&amp;P 500 futures in the very near term.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though the Dow (Industrials) is down 30, we're not having a crash or anything,&quot; Ord said. &quot;This isn't really a correction, it's a flat market.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said put/call ratios for individual equity options and index options had both been very high lately and were again at lofty levels around 2.0 this morning.</p>
<p>Contrarians in the market see higher turnover in puts relative to calls as a sign stocks have more room to gain.</p>
<p>Ord also noted that the New York Stock Exchange tick index .TIC.N marked a hefty downtick reading of 905 on Tuesday, a level often associated with a short-term bottom.</p>
<p>Five-minute and 15-minute charts for S&amp;P futures also seemed to be forming triangles, which were likely to be continuation patterns, he added.  </p>
<p>Still, he cautioned that the market had a lot of dangerous elements in the longer term.</p>
<p>Bill Yates of DYR Associates said tech stocks were overbought and toppish, just as they were in mid-1995 before shedding most of the gains they had made in preceding months.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like a repeat of what happened in '95,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another sector that looked toppish near term was airline issues, he added. The American Stock Exchange airline index .XAL was down 3.12 at 407.33 and the Philadelphia Stock Exchange airline index .PLN was off 3.56 at 419.67.</p>
<p>-- Chicago Derivatives Desk (312) 408-8750</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
