<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220489" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Clean sweep for UK virus killer at Easdaq start.</title>
<headline>Clean sweep for UK virus killer at Easdaq start.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's newest stock market, Easdaq, on Wednesday finally went live as shares in the first company to be listed on it, a British-based anti-virus software developer, began trading.</p>
<p>Dr Solomon's Group Plc won the race to kick off the screen-based action on the pan-European growth stocks exchange, modelled on the Nasdaq in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been satisfactory for a first day,&quot; Easdaq spokesman Chris Pickles said. &quot;The system has held up and prices (for Dr Solomon's) stayed stable.&quot;</p>
<p>Easdaq -- the European Association of Securities Dealers Automated Quotations System -- expects to see a dozen shares traded by the end of January and up to 50 by the end of 1997 with a target of 500 companies listed in the next five years.</p>
<p>Easdaq became technically operational on September 30, but the rules were not published until late October.</p>
<p>Dr Solomon's stock opened at $17, saw some action between $17-1/8 and $16-7/8, and stood at $17 again at the close. Volume had reached 17,775 shares by then.</p>
<p>Easdaq's trading hours are 9:30 a.m. (0830 GMT) to 4:30 p.m. 1530 GMT). The exchange has offices in Brussels and London.</p>
<p>Dr Solomon's is also listed on Nasdaq in the United States, as are other candidate stocks. On Nasdaq the stock was also quoted at $17 on Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Dr Solomon's planned to raise about $96 million to reach total market capitalisation of about $300 million.</p>
<p>Pickles said the stock had seen trade throughout the European Union. &quot;As expected trades were done across borders.&quot;</p>
<p>The hi-tech company is one of many entrepreneurial growth companies that Easdaq is aiming for.</p>
<p>Pipped to the post by Dr Solomon's, Belgian biotechnology firm Innogenetics is due to start trading on Easdaq on Thursday after an initial public offering.</p>
<p>It hopes to raise $78 million to achieve a market capitalisation of about $246 million. Shares in its initial public offering, five times oversubscribed, are priced at $12.</p>
<p>French &quot;smart card&quot; maker  ActivCard SA and Belgian printers software firm  Artwork Systems aim to list on Easdaq in early December.</p>
<p>Another candidate emerged on Wednesday. French low-cost flat screen technology firm PixTech, already listed on Nasdaq, said it aimed to raise 100 million French francs via Easdaq at the beginning of December.</p>
<p>Easdaq is a rival of the Euro NM exchange for small- and medium-sized companies. The Nouveau Marche project involves the Brussels, Frankfurt, Paris and Amsterdam bourses.</p>
<p>Easdaq's Pickles highlighted the differences between the two projects. &quot;We don't see it as a competitor, (Euro NM) is not pan-European, it is (a market) for companies from those countries within those countries.&quot;</p>
<p>Easdaq, by contrast, was aimed at international investors and for internationally oriented companies, he said.</p>
<p>The Easdaq project originated from contacts between the European Venture Capital Association, the European Commission and various market players.</p>
<p>Nasdaq is one of Easdaq's 91 shareholders which brought about 370 million Belgian francs together to finance its launch.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
