<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223343" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel's Pilat to make offering on London's AIM.</title>
<headline>Israel's Pilat to make offering on London's AIM.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pilat Technologies International Ltd, an Israeli software and human resources management consulting firm, plans to raise up to 3.5 million sterling on London's Alternative Investment Market (AIM) next month.</p>
<p>Pilat chairman Michael Zukerman said on Thursday that the company would raise between 2.65 million and 3.5 million sterling, representing 18-23 percent of the company.</p>
<p>Pilat will issue a prospectus on December 3 and offers must be submitted by December 6. Admission date to AIM is December 10.</p>
<p>Zukerman said the company opted for London because &quot;we went to the market that knows us&quot;.</p>
<p>Clients of Pilat's British subsidiary include British Airways, Wellcome, British Telecom and Sky.</p>
<p>&quot;We are known in England. A good part of our earnings are from England. And in Israel there is no (new issues) market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other Israeli companies such as plastics parts maker Plasson have faced difficulties raising funds in London in the past few months due to the stalled Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;We are concerned,&quot; Zukerman said but added he hoped its recognition in Britain would overcome doubts.</p>
<p>The company, which derives 75 percent of its pretax profit from abroad, also sells in Hong Kong, Australia, South Africa and Malaysia.</p>
<p>Most of the proceeds from the offering will be used to buy Mardoni Associates Inc., a U.S. maker of software for the human resources market, similar to Pilat's products.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to buy a U.S. company to have an outlet in the U.S. market,&quot; Zukerman said.</p>
<p>He said Pilat expects to complete the acquisition by the end of the year, adding there was a price cap on the purchase of $4 million in cash.</p>
<p>Pilat is expected to post a net profit in 1996 of one million sterling, including Mardoni's results, while turnover of the two companies combined should reach 17 million sterling, including 15 million sterling from Pilat.</p>
<p>Zukerman noted that any company issuing shares on the AIM cannot make an offering in North America.</p>
<p>- Tova Cohen, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
