<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226075" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Sausage says to meet forecasts.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Sausage says to meet forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newly-listed Internet software developer Sausage Software Ltd said on Friday it expects to meet prospectus forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;We are yet to announce our first set of results and I am confident that our prospectus forecasts for full year sales will be met,&quot; managing director Steve Outtrim told shareholders at the annual meeting.</p>
<p>Sausage, which started trading in June 1995 and turned over A$3.0 million in its first year of operations, has forecast revenue of A$8.0 million in its second year of business.  </p>
<p>Sausage, which listed on October 14, hit a high of A$1.50 shortly after its sharemarket debut, but is currently trading around its record lows, which prompted a query from the Australian Stock Exchange on Thursday.</p>
<p>At 12.10 p.m. (0110 GMT), Sausage shares were steady at 39 cents after hitting a low of 30 cents on Thursday.</p>
<p>Outtrim said there had been some concern expressed about the current share price, however, it is important to put this matter in some perspective.  </p>
<p>He said the company has only been listed for a few weeks and it is therefore much too early to judge the company's performance.</p>
<p>Outtrim said it is important to note that Sausage Software is the first stock of its type to list on the Australian Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;By its very nature, it will take some time for the market to fully understand the way companies like ours operate, the markets they operate in and the great opportunities that exist for them,&quot; Outtrim said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
