<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227183" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Markets await 'bookend' data.</title>
<headline>WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Markets await 'bookend' data.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Benkoe</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Wall Street bull is expected to continue its post-election stampede this week, although traders will be watching two pieces of data due on Monday and Friday that could sent the market stumbling.</p>
<p>&quot;(The bull market) is not over,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd.  &quot;Everybody is trying to get that little correction.  But we are in the throw-in-the-towel mode for bears.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;A lot of numbers are going to be important next week,&quot; said Hugh Johnson at First Albany. &quot;At the top of the list are bookends, the Monday report from the NAPM, and the November payrolls on Friday.&quot;</p>
<p>On Monday, the National Association of Purchasing Management's November data will be released at 1000 EDT/1500 GMT. The November forecast is 50.8 versus 50.2 in October.</p>
<p>On Friday, the U.S. Labor Department issues unemployment amd payroll data for November at 0830 EST/1330 GMT. The payroll forecast is 179,000 versus 210,000 in October. The November unemployment rate is seen unchanged at 5.2 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Both of those numbers are likely to set the tone for the bond market, and the bond market has been very important to the stock market recently,&quot; Johnson said.</p>
<p>Analysts will be watching two components of the purchasing manager report: Vendor deliveries and the percent of purchasing managers that report paying higher prices. The data are key indicators of the temperature of the economy and inflation and are watched carefully by the Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>&quot;If (the numbers) come in as expected, the bond market is likely to continue to move up, and stock prices are also likely to move up,&quot; Johnson said.  </p>
<p>Analysts are increasingly certain the bull market will continue unimpeded in the near term.  &quot;We're in the midst of a parabolic move,&quot; Bleier said.  &quot;There's no question we're in the midst of an extremely emotional move in the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Since U.S. Election Day, the Dow Industrials index has gained about 450 points, or seven percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody knows how expensive we are, yet it doesn't matter,&quot; Bleier continued. &quot;Money flow keeps coming fast and furious from funds...The question for the week ahead is how high can this parabolic move take us?&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;There's no reason for anyone to sell,&quot; he said. &quot;What would you buy as a substitute?&quot;</p>
<p>Metz predicted a rise in the next few weeks of secondary stocks and in &quot;rumor stocks&quot; -- those affected by talk of takeovers and restructurings. He mentioned Quaker Oats Co and SmithKline Beecham Plc.</p>
<p>Another piece of data due Monday is construction spending for October. The U.S. Commerce Department will issue the data at 1000 EST/1500 GMT.  The forecast is a decline of 1.0 percent, versus September's rise of 1.9 percent.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Conference Board will issue its data on leading indicators for October at 0830 EST/1330 GMT.  The forecast is for unchanged versus up 0.1 percent in September.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the Labor Department will announce revised third quarter productivity and costs at 1000 EST/1500 GMT. The forecast is for a drop of 0.1 percent versus a gain of 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>Also on Friday, at 1000 EST/1500 GMT, the Commerce Department will issue numbers on factory orders for October. The forecast is for a gain of 0.2 percent versus September's rise of 2.7 percent.  </p>
<p>Strategists pointed to the hefty rises in some well-known issues such as General Electric Co, Citicorp, Intel Corp and Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>But some strategists worried that the rising market was due to the lack of supply in fairly valued stocks.</p>
<p>Michael Metz at Oppenheimer &amp; Co said the market was facing a &quot;supply vacuum&quot; as portfolio managers were reluctant to give up well-performing blue-chip stocks.</p>
<p>If managers sold the stock, they would have to hold onto the cash, or buy a stock that is not doing as well as the equity they sold.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
