<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227593" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spyglass implements Internet device plan.</title>
<headline>Spyglass implements Internet device plan.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spyglass Inc is moving full speed ahead on its business strategy focusing on technology to connect everyday products from telephones to televisions to the Internet.</p>
<p>But while the Internet and the World Wide Web hold promise, analysts say Spyglass' strategy is not without risk as many major players have yet to commit formally to the technology.</p>
<p>&quot;I would call it an accelerated focus on the device market and the infrastructure required to support devices on the Internet,&quot; said Doug Colbeth, chief executive of Spyglass.  </p>
<p>&quot;We see the opportunity there,&quot; he added in an interview.</p>
<p>Today, Spyglass unveiled various new products that implement its strategy to focus on software and infrastucture to connect devices other than personal computers (PCs) to the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;I sincerely believe everything will be Web-enabled at some point,&quot; said Nesbitt Burns Securities analyst Abhishek Gami. However, &quot;their new strategy is very high risk.&quot;</p>
<p>Gami said Spyglass has a six- to 12- month lead on other companies in the device market, but needs more firm orders. Spyglass's current clients include Microware Systems Corp,  WebTV Networks and WorldGate Communications.  </p>
<p>&quot;The key here is how fast Spyglass can sign up customers,&quot; Gami said. &quot;So far they have a handful, but not enough to say they are going to be a sure winner.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite the risk, the potential in the device market is huge, and Spyglass is leading the way at this point.</p>
<p>Nebitt Burns' Gami said he estimates potential market size at about one billion &quot;units&quot; which could be Web-enabled today -- i.e.televisions, pagers and cell phones.  </p>
<p>Gami said he has not placed a dollar value on the market and doesn't know of one.</p>
<p>&quot;(I)t's very difficult for a lot of people to get a grasp of it. It's very futuristic,&quot; said Steve Harmon, an analyst for Mecklermedia's iWorld, an Internet-based business analysis source. &quot;They (Spyglass) really have done their homework and they have a vision.&quot;</p>
<p>Colbeth said he expects millions of Web-enabled devices to sell in the 1997 holiday season and tens of millions the following year. This season, he said hundreds of thousands of products are likely to sell.  </p>
<p>&quot;I believe by the year 2000 there will be an equal number of non-PC devices connected to the Internet as PCs,&quot; Colbeth said, adding that will be 150 million to 200 million of each.</p>
<p>Among the new products Spyglass announced today is Prism, expected to be available in the second quarter of 1997. Among Prism's uses is to convert Internet content, such as Web pages, to be seen on a television.</p>
<p>Spyglass also said it has content collection technology, which sends &quot;agents&quot; to the Internet to automatically find information on a regular basis.</p>
<p>The company said it will also launch WebNotes Mail, which allows users to access electronic mail from non-PC devices.</p>
<p>((--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
