<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232040" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spyglass sees revs from device software.</title>
<headline>Spyglass sees revs from device software.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spyglass Chief Financial Officer Gary Vilchick said Monday he expects the company's new device software business to contribute dramatically more of total revenues in the second half of its fiscal year.</p>
<p>&quot;Last quarter, (device revenue) was close to 13-14 percent. I think you will see a very dramatic shift if you look at Q1 and Q2,&quot; Vilchick told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The company's 1997 fiscal year began in October.  </p>
<p>&quot;You will see a very significant shift with the revenues coming out of the device market becoming a predominant piece of our business (in the) third and fourth quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Spyglass shares rose 2-5/16 to close at 12-5/8 in Nasdaq trade Monday, after the company outlined its strategy to make products that will enable a whole new range of devices gain access to information available through the World Wide Web.</p>
<p>During the transition to the devices market, revenue growth will slow to around 50 percent in the fiscal year to the end of September, 1997, from its blistering pace of more than doubling in previous years, Vilchick said.  </p>
<p>For fiscal 1997, revenues are expected to be in the $33 million to $35 million range, up from $22.3 million in fiscal 1996, Vilchick said, adding that 1998 revenues should climb into the $50 million to $60 million range.</p>
<p>&quot;We've indicated that in 1998 we would expect to see our margins return to more of a historical pattern, including operating margins in the 15- to 20- percent range,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;From our end what we're doing on this investment model is really a front-ended model to introduce a whole series of products that will impact our 1997 numbers but we don't see that as a long-term issue,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Vilchick also noted the company has around $35 million in cash and no debt. &quot;In fact, we've been generating cash on an operating basis, so this is a chance for us to do the right thing from a long-term shareholder's investment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Under technology deals with Microsoft Corp in December 1994 and a year later in December 1995, Spyglass expects a revenue stream from royalties of around $4 million to $5 million a year, or 10 to 15 percent of revenues.</p>
<p>Those agreements currently expire at the end of 1998.  </p>
<p>Spyglass has sought to differentiate its offering by partnering with major makers of computers and other devices, including Bandai Co. Ltd., which is producing Apple Computer Inc's Pippin device, as well as with companies making small, robust real-time operating systems. Spyglass Chief Executive Doug Colbeth told Reuters in an interview earlier today he expects the number of devices connected to the Internet that are not personal computers to match the number of Internet-connected PCs by the year 2000, with 150 million to 200 million expected of each.  </p>
<p>Spyglass executives said the market will include not only devices which can be used as a human interface, like handheld devices or Internet boxes for television such as its deals with WebTV Networks and PowerTV, but also devices which primarily use the Internet to communicate with each other.</p>
<p>Such devices may be able to automate functions in the home, or let you control them from the road, for example.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be the Dolby of the Internet,&quot; Freidland said of the audio technology company which has come to be a standard for high fidelity sound. &quot;We feel like we have literally about a two-year time advantage (over rivals).&quot;  </p>
<p>Vilchick said the heavy investment in the new technology in the first half of this year would result in research and development rising to 37-38 percent of sales, up from 30 percent in fiscal 1996.</p>
<p>As part of its effort to build on partnerships with customers, like real time operating system provider Microware Systems Corp, Spyglass said it would more than double its existing staff of 19 in its Partners Services division.</p>
<p>The company has traditionally built its business on the basis of upfront licensing fees, of say $200,000 to gain access to its source code, with follow-up charges to help build products, and incremental revenues from royalties.</p>
<p>The executives said that while licenses have often attracted revenues on the order of $1.20 to $1.50 per seat under such arrangements, the company is also considering an annual subscription model, creating more stable cash flows.</p>
<p>-- sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau +1 415 846 5400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
