<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237384" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Report says many U.S. electronic games too violent.</title>
<headline>Report says many U.S. electronic games too violent.</headline>
<byline>Robert Green</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The video and computer game industries are doing a good job of rating their products but many of the games are still too violent for children, a watchdog group told Congress on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Too many games now on the market this holiday season are more violent, more antisocial and generally more disgusting than ever. The gift these products give is to communicate the unadulterated message that killing is cool and viciousness is a virture,&quot; Sen. Joseph Lieberman, D-Connecticut, said.</p>
<p>He spoke at a news conference where the National Institute on Media and the Family released a report on electronic games and the rating system used by their manufacturers.</p>
<p>Lieberman said manufacturers often try to promote the games by stressing how violent they are. He cited an ad for the computer game Duke Nukem, made by GT Interactive Software, which said, &quot;Smell steaming entrails as Duke's new microwave cannon fries and explodes those alien bastards.&quot;</p>
<p>The report said most companies were using a uniform rating system for all games. But it said many retail outlets sold or rented games to anyone regardless of the ratings and many clerks did not understand the system.</p>
<p>The report cited a dozen video games -- Doom, Fighting Vipers, Killer Instinct, Krazy Ivan, Mighty Morphin Power Rangers, Mortal Kombat, Primal Rage, Resident Evil, Revolution Z, Street Fighter 11, Virtual Cop and Virtual Fighter 2 -- which it said contained excessive violence and other questionable content.</p>
<p>It also listed 10 violent computer games popular with children: ATF, Crusader No Regret, Daggerfall, Doom, Duke Nukem, Mech Warrior 2, Mortal Kombat, Pray for Death, Quake and Warcraft 2.</p>
<p>Video games in arcades are largely unregulated, the report said, with arcade operators letting children play whatever games they wanted unless parents objected.</p>
<p>The report urged parents and others to use the ratings when buying games for children. Ratings designate games that are suitable for young children, preteen-agers, teenagers up to and over the age of 17 and adults only.</p>
<p>The video and computer game industry adopted the voluntary rating systems after Lieberman and Sen. Herb Kohl, a Wisconsin Democrat, introduced a bill that would have imposed government ratings.</p>
<p>Douglas Lowenstein, president of the interactive Digital Software Association, said the rating system allowed buyers to choose the games they wanted for themselves and their children from a broad range of interests and tastes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
