<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238726" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: BMC Software of the U.S. charts Asia growth.</title>
<headline>BMC Software of the U.S. charts Asia growth.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. database management products company BMC Software plans a vigorous Asian expansion after opening a series of offices in the past 18 months, Hugh Sutherland, BMC managing director for Asia, said on Thursday.</p>
<p>He told Reuters in an interview that along with the new offices BMC had opened a research and development centre in Singapore and extended partnerships to boost regional business.</p>
<p>For the fiscal year ending March 1997, BMC aimed to double its Asian contribution to worldwide revenue to 15 percent from seven percent, he said.</p>
<p>Based on corporate projections of a 25 percent increase in global revenue to about US$535 million for fiscal 1997, Asian revenue could be around US$80 million.</p>
<p>&quot;BMC's goal is to replicate our success in the U.S. and Europe, to be the premier provider of systems management products,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sutherland said the company's shift over the past two or three years into a broad provider of management tools from a pure seller of mainframe products had made it vital to have stronger relationships with key Asian organisations.</p>
<p>Otherwise, opportunities in Asia -- which for BMC excludes Japan, Australia and New Zealand -- could be missed.</p>
<p>BMC now has offices in Singapore, Korea and Hong Kong and is opening an office in Malaysia in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>It uses Hong Kong a base for tapping China's market and has a distributor in Beijing which aims to operate across the country.</p>
<p>BMC also capitalises on its partnerships with big players such as Hewlett-Packard Co, Digitial Equipment Corp, Oracle Corp and Sybase Inc to extend its reach, Sutherland said.</p>
<p>About 60 percent of BMC's Asian business is mainframe-based and should move to 50-50 with open systems in the next two years, he said.</p>
<p>He said the mainframe computer business was not a sunset sector, adding that it brought in 85 percent of BMC's licensing revenue of US$269 million for the fiscal year ended March 1996.</p>
<p>In Asia, markets such as South Korea and China, along with a stream of maintenance revenue, would keep the mainframe business buoyant at least over the next two years, he said.</p>
<p>BMC's Asian open systems growth mirrored hefty growth experienced on a global basis in the second quarter ended September 1996, he said.</p>
<p>BMC set up a Singapore R&amp;D centre in July which aimed to develop open systems products in Asian languages.</p>
<p>&quot;We view that it is essential for us to have internationalised products to effectively address the North Asian markets,&quot; Sutherland said.</p>
<p>The first such products, expected by the end of March, will be for Japan and Korea, followed by products for Taiwan and China by mid-1997. Sutherland declined to say how much he expected to ship.</p>
<p>He said BMC expected these Asian-customised products to make &quot;positive contributions&quot; to earnings within two years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
