<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242133" id="root" date="1996-12-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US IPO VIEW - Few pockets of strength in weak market.</title>
<headline>US IPO VIEW - Few pockets of strength in weak market.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A calendar of largely poor quality issues has driven Wall Street away from the initial public offering market for the moment, leaving the landscape littered with postponements -- and more could be on the horizon.</p>
<p>&quot;(Underwriters) are going to have to push back and cancel or cut back quite a few deals between now and January,&quot; said Henry Hermann, chief investment officer of Waddell &amp; Read, which manages about $25 billion in funds.</p>
<p>&quot;This is usually the busiest time of year, but the calendar is slacking off. It's because quality has been very, very bad,&quot; said Manish Shah, editor of the IPO Maven.</p>
<p>Last week, Internet advertising agency Poppe Tyson Inc., Southern California Physicians Insurance Exchange, and Access TV Network pulled planned initial public offerings. Many are on &quot;to-be-announced status&quot;, including four deals by Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette, two by Goldman Sachs, two by Merrill Lynch and three by Montgomery Securities.</p>
<p>But IPO experts said quality deals could still sparkle, aided by still-strong inflows of money into small-cap aggressive mutual funds.</p>
<p>Vivid Technologies Inc. could rise 75 cents to $1 on its first day of trading this week, according to firms that forecast opening premiums for IPOs.</p>
<p>Vivid develops systems that inspect airline baggage for plastic and other explosives. Its systems have been installed in airports in Europe. Its closest rival, InVision Technologies Inc., went public in April at $11 a share and now trades near $22.</p>
<p>John Fitzgibbon of the IPO Aftermarket said computer network software company Versatility Inc. by Merrill Lynch could jump $2 to $3 at its opening.</p>
<p>Two companies with Internet affiliations are also planning to go public. One is TMP Worldwide Inc., the world's largest yellow pages advertising agency and a recruitment advertising agency. The company also runs Web sites for recruitment purposes, including the &quot;Monster Board&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a quality issue but it's overpriced. They have too much debt and are growing through acquisitions. Their internal growth rate is only about 4 percent and its priced at something like 25 to 30 times earnings. But the stock could go higher,&quot; said Shah. Fitzgibbon said the deal could rise about 75 cents on its first day.</p>
<p>San Francisco-based First Virtual Inc. also plans an offering. Its VirtualPIN software allows users to make secure financial transactions over the Internet using a personal identification number, without exposing their credit card numbers. The company currently has about 2,650 merchants and 180,000 consumers registered.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very overpriced. They still don't have the critical mass yet, and the trouble is, by the time they do, other companies might also,&quot; said Shah.</p>
<p>Some international companies are also tapping the U.S. markets for cash, including Singapore-based Asia Pacific Wire &amp; Cable and Hong Kong's APT Satellite Holdings Ltd., which plans a large IPO of 105 million shares for $16 to $20 each.</p>
<p>The hottest global deal this week could be ECSoft Group Plc, which Fitzgibbon reckons could rise $1. The British company provides information technology consulting services.</p>
<p>Colt Telecom Group Plc is also going public. The U.K. company provides competitive phone access in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of deregulation, they could do quite well in the future,&quot; said Shah. &quot;But don't expect any profitability or significant value in earnings for the next several years. But they could become a good takover candidate somethime in 1998.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
