<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243408" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>Japan: Softbank taking 35 percent stake in U.S. software firm.</title>
<headline>Softbank taking 35 percent stake in U.S. software firm.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Softbank Corp., the world's largest computer magazine and book publisher, said Monday it will take a 35 percent stake in California anti-virus software firm TrendMicro for 3.5 billion yen ($31 million).</p>
<p>The company said payment to TrendMicro would be made by Dec. 27.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to expand business, our group will strive to back up TrendMicro's Internet-related business,&quot; Softbank President Masayoshi Son told a news conference.</p>
<p>Softbank will try to persuade some 50 computer hardware makers worldwide to use Cupertino, Calif.-based TrendMicro's software in their systems and ask other makers to integrate the software in their memory boards, he said.</p>
<p>Son said his company will continue to actively invest in Internet-related businesses but not necessarily with any large-scale purchases.</p>
<p>Softbank plans to use part of the money to be raised through a new share issue to finance its investment in TrendMicro. Softbank is traded over-the-counter in Tokyo.</p>
<p>A Softbank source said that TrendMicro has already moved its headquarters to Tokyo as part of its plan to list its shares on Japan's over-the-counter market as early as 1998.</p>
<p>Softbank has become the world's largest computer-related magazine and book publisher through a string of buyouts.</p>
<p>In the summer, it also launched a joint digital satellite television service, known as J-SkyB, with Australian media tycoon Rupert Murdoch's News Corp.</p>
<p>In June, the two bought 21.4 percent of national television network Asahi National Broadcasting of Japan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
