<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245297" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Autodesk, Softdesk in merger pact.</title>
<headline>Autodesk, Softdesk in merger pact.</headline>
<dateline>HENNIKER, N.H. 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Autodesk Inc and Softdesk Inc said on Tuesday they signed a definitive merger agreement, in a deal valued at about $72 million or $12 per share for Softdesk shareholders.</p>
<p>Autodesk said it would issue about 0.44 shares of its common stock for each outstanding Softdesk share, and that it expected to take a one-time charge of about $10 to $12 million when the deal closed. The merger was expected to close the first quarter of Autodesk's fiscal year, the companies said.  </p>
<p>In connection with the deal, Softdesk said it also granted Autodesk an option to acquire 19.9 percent of Softdesk stock under certain circumstances.</p>
<p>The deal was worth $72 million based on closing stock prices on December 9, the companies said.</p>
<p>Autodesk, based in San Rafael, Calif., supplies PC design software, and Softdesk supplies AutoCAD-based application software for architecture, engineering and construction (AEC).  </p>
<p>A Softdesk spokesman said Autodesk had the option to buy 19.9 percent of the company if another party launched a separate bid for Softdesk.</p>
<p>Softdesk would be integrated into Autodesk's AEC market group, headquartered in Henniker and managed by David Arnold, formerly Softdesk chief executive officer. Arnold would become vice president of Autodesk's architecture, engineering and construction market group, the companies said.  </p>
<p>Softdesk has been one of Autodesk's largest independent software developers, with revenues of $26.5 million for the nine month period which ended September 30, they said.</p>
<p>The merger would accelerate Autodesk's strategy to deliver AEC vertical market applications and base technology to customers and independent software developers, based on regional market conditions, the company said.</p>
<p>The merger was subject to approval by Softdesk shareholders and would be accounted for as a pooling of interests, the companies said.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HENNIKER, N.H."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
