<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248236" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall St rumors reflect investor jitters.</title>
<headline>Wall St rumors reflect investor jitters.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>After having feasted on record gains in 1996, Wall Street is beginning to fall prey to rumors that the banquet may be ending.</p>
<p>Financial markets are famous sources of rumors of all sorts, but analysts said the markets' volatility in the face of the latest wave of tongue wagging is a reflection of investors' nervousness over profits.  </p>
<p>At the end of the year, with market players holding large profits &quot;there tends to be a susceptibility among investors to shoot first and ask questions later,&quot; said Phil Orlando, chief investment officer of Value Line's Asset Management division.</p>
<p>&quot;In a situation like this, it's better to lock the profit in and come back and buy later if it turns out they sold prematurely,&quot; Orlando said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday U.S. stocks were hit by a string of unsubstantiated talk that included rumors that market engine International Business Machines Corp might issue a profit warning.  </p>
<p>Other rumors included talk the U.S. might bomb Iran in January, and that Japanese investors were shedding U.S. bond holdings.</p>
<p>&quot;The rumor mill is churning at full speed now,&quot; said Guy Truicko, portfolio manager, Unity Management.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials finished off 71 points, or one percent, at 6403 after being down 130 points at the day's low.</p>
<p>Stocks were undercut by Treasuries, which were particularily hit by talk of Japanese selling, analysts said. The benchmark 30-year bond ended down 1-26/32, its yield jumping to 6.63 percent from Tuesday's close at 6.49 percent.  </p>
<p>One stock sector that has come storming back from a July selloff is the high technology group. IBM is trading at its highest levels since before the 1987 market crash and others including Intel Corp, Microsoft Corp and Dell Computer Corp have produced eye-popping gains.</p>
<p>Given their gains, the group is particularily vulnerable to negative talk, such as Wednesday's IBM rumor, analysts said. IBM declined to comment on the market talk and said it had no plans to issue a news release on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;After the tremendous run we've had the market is definitely a little nervous, knowing that there's always something that can come out of left field,&quot; Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter.</p>
<p>Defying the day's downdraft, Intel jumped 7-3/4 to 136-7/8 after positive comments from brokerage Merrill Lynch. Intel's gains helped limit the Nasdaq composite to a loss of three points, closing at 1309.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1733</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
