<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249330" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 'Q' Steals the show in 'Star Trek: Borg' CD-ROM.</title>
<headline>'Q' Steals the show in 'Star Trek: Borg' CD-ROM.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I. 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>When you slip &quot;Star Trek: Borg&quot; into your CD-ROM drive, you get this friendly message: &quot;Welcome human to the Star Trek: Borg installation programme. Choose 1 to assimilate Borg into your hard drive. Resistance is futile. Choosing 0 is futile.&quot;</p>
<p>But who would want to resist?</p>
<p>For nearly two years, &quot;Star Trek: The Next Generation&quot; was a series in search of a villain. The Klingons were allies, the Ferengi were more comical than ominous and the worm-eating parasites that took over the bodies of Starfleet officers were never heard from again after a suspenseful first-season episode.</p>
<p>Then came the Borg. Originally conceived as a race of insects, this cybernetic species that &quot;assimilates&quot; outsiders by turning them into mechanical automatons in their own image quickly became the Federation's favourite nemesis. The Borg are a big reason the film &quot;Star Trek: First Contact&quot; scored so well so quickly when it made its debut in theatres last month. Fans couldn't wait to bring them back for a new battle.</p>
<p>Although &quot;Star Trek: Borg&quot; (Simon &amp; Schuster Interactive, Windows/Macintosh, $50) involves time travel and the Borg, it has nothing to do with the hit movie.</p>
<p>Players assume the role of Cadet Qaylan Furlong, whose father was killed 10 years earlier in a battle with a Borg ship at Wolf 359, an actual star 7.6 light years away. Now the Borg have returned, and Furlong, visiting the Starship Cheyenne, is anxious for revenge. But the Cheyenne's captain has decided to remove him and other non-essential personnel just before the attack.</p>
<p>Up pops Q, the obnoxious omnipotent entity played with great relish by John deLancie.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps I should introduce myself,&quot; deLancie announces with a flourish at the beginning of the game. &quot;I imagine you've heard of me, though -- Q. It's short for Q.&quot;</p>
<p>Q, apparently enamoured by the first letter of the cadet's first name, takes Furlong 10 years into the past aboard his father's ship, the Righteous. He shows Furlong that his father died because the Righteous' original security officer, Lt. Sprint, was killed four hours earlier and the unseasoned ensign who assumed the post couldn't handle the job.</p>
<p>&quot;If Lt. Sprint were still alive, he might be able to save the ship. But he's been dead for four hours. No wonder they don't want him on the bridge,&quot; deadpans deLancie.</p>
<p>Q lets Furlong possess the body of Lt. Sprint, promising that if Furlong makes all the right decisions over the next four hours, he might be able to save the Righteous and his father.</p>
<p>&quot;Star Trek: Borg&quot; isn't a traditional computerized role-playing game. Players won't get bogged down with puzzles and minutia for 50 or 60 hours.</p>
<p>Like it's predecessor, &quot;Star Trek: Klingon,&quot; &quot;Star Trek: Borg&quot; is more of a live-action interactive movie, filmed using the props, personnel, and sets used for the various &quot;Trek&quot; series and movies. The player must make decisions at key points along the plot. Those choices determine whether the player lives, dies or gets turned into a Borg using a device that sounds suspiciously like a dentist's drill.</p>
<p>If you make a fatal blunder (and what mortal won't?), Q sends you back to the previous decision point in hopes that you'll make a better choice, or you'll first check your tricorder so you'll know how to work the security controls, adjust your phaser or learn a Borg code.</p>
<p>DeLancie doesn't just appear in &quot;Star Trek: Borg,&quot; he takes it over. He has mastered this condescending character to the point where he can make you laugh and shudder at the same moment. He'll taunt you when you've made a mistake that will lead to your father's death, and harangue you when he has to keep sending you back to the same spot in the story because you can't figure out what you're supposed to do.</p>
<p>&quot;You think I do these things just to be perverse? Well, yes, I suppose I do,&quot; he admits. &quot;Try to get it right this time. I'm tired of replaying this moment.&quot;</p>
<p>Although &quot;Star Trek: Borg&quot; boasts two hours of video on its three disks, the movie (if you do everything right) lasts 45 minutes. But half the fun is discovering what happens if you make a wrong turn and seeing history play out differently.</p>
<p>The game has some problems. The video became jerky for a while each time I saved my place, the manual doesn't tell you how to skip past the video sequences you've seen for the 10th time (just between us, the password is OBEY), the text on the tricorder was almost impossible to read (fortunately, Q narrates the entries for you), and the game promises an added feature called &quot;The Picard Dossier,&quot; but I couldn't find it anywhere on the three disks.</p>
<p>But those are annoyances, not fatal flaws.</p>
<p>For fans wondering whether &quot;Star Trek: Borg&quot; is a game they can resist playing, the Borg are right. Resistance IS futile.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
