<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255425" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Nasdaq stock exchange seeks more German listings.</title>
<headline>Nasdaq stock exchange seeks more German listings.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. stock exchange Nasdaq said at a roadshow on Friday that it hoped more German companies would eventually join the exchange, but that disclosure was still a problem for many German companies.</p>
<p>&quot;The big problem with German companies has been disclosure, with German companies finding difficulty reconciling their accounts with systems like Generally Agreed Accounting Principles (GAAP),&quot; said Charles Balfour, vice president of the Nasdaq Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Nasdaq was founded in 1971 and currently has 5,300 companies listed. The company said its composite Nasdaq index grew by 40 percent last year and 20 percent so far this year.</p>
<p>Among its star performers are Microsoft and Intel, which have a market capitalisation of $78 billion and $77.8 billion respectively. Its daily share volume to the end of September 1996 was $541 million.</p>
<p>&quot;It will take time for German companies to change. There is a definite change as German companies wish to compete for U.S. institutions' dollars and access cheaper markets and capital,&quot; said Balfour.</p>
<p>&quot;What has helped Germany up to now has been the strength of its currency, but with Germany hell-bent on European Monetary Union, that could change,&quot; said Balfour.</p>
<p>Balfour said that Nasdaq had worked with the German bourse operating company Deutsche Boerse in upgrading systems and information sharing.</p>
<p>&quot;Having companies listed on the NASDAQ and other stock exchanges helps global liquidity. You can be sure that transactions follow liquidity as surely as night follows day,&quot; said Balfour.</p>
<p>Balfour said that the new European growth stocks index, EASDAQ, which went live on November 27, was no threat at all.</p>
<p>&quot;There are interesting companies listing on Easdaq and the other growth stock exchanges, but mostly these are companies who are too small and couldn't afford the management time to come to the U.S. market,&quot; said Balfour.</p>
<p>&quot;The listings on these exchanges allow these companies to raise their heads above the parapets, from where they can then come to the U.S.,&quot; said Balfour.</p>
<p>Balfour said that Nasdaq had helped Easdaq in setting up, supplying it with software and advice and Balfour said that Nasdaq would like to see the smaller European innovation bourses thrive.</p>
<p>&quot;We have put a small amount of seed money into Easdaq to help it get going. Our interest is to help companies access the U.S. capital pool,&quot; said Balfour.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
