<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255858" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel's Pilat completes London offering.</title>
<headline>Israel's Pilat completes London offering.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's Pilat Technologies International Ltd completed a 2.65 million pound sterling offering in the United Kingdom on Friday, its adviser and broker Raphael Zorn Hemsley said.</p>
<p>The offering for 3.868 million shares for 18 percent of the company at 68.5 pence per share was at the bottom end of what Pilat had hoped to raise. The shares will be listed on the London Alternative Investment Market (AIM).</p>
<p>Plasson Ltd, another Israeli company that tried floating shares for trading on AIM in October, failed because of what management said were political concerns about Israeli companies on the part of European investors.</p>
<p>But Michael Rosenberg, Raphael's chairman, told Reuters that political factors were not the major reason for Pilat's failure to raise the full amount it had hoped. The company, which provides software and consultancy services in human resources, had expected to raise as much as 3.5 million pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;The political factor has an impact, but it's mostly a book-balancing problem,&quot; Rosenberg said.</p>
<p>&quot;(Pilat) will be the sixth Israeli company in the market out of 225 AIM-listed companies,&quot; Rosenberg said. &quot;That's three percent of the market.&quot;</p>
<p>He said most fund managers saw three percent was the ceiling for an Israel weighting in AIM and for now would hesitate to buy into new Israeli issues. As a result, Rosenberg said, it would difficult for smaller Israeli companies to go public on AIM for the next three to four months.</p>
<p>Bigger Israeli companies -- with a capitalization of $50 to 60 million and substantial international business -- could still be floated, he added.</p>
<p>Pilat will be using the proceeeds of the offering to complete its acquisition of a U.S. company Nardoni Associates. The acquisition is expected to boost Pilat's net profit for 1996 to one million pounds.</p>
<p>- David Rosenberg, Jerusalem newsroom, 972-2-537-0502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
