<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255981" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SEC expands suit against Systems of Excellence.</title>
<headline>SEC expands suit against Systems of Excellence.</headline>
<byline>Gene Ramos</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Regulators are seeking to recover about $8.33 million from 21 individuals and companies who allegedly received illegal stock profits from Charles Huttoe, former chairman of Systems of Excellence Inc., the Securities and Exchange Commission said Thursday.</p>
<p>The 21, who are not charged with any wrongdoing, were named relief defendants in an expanded civil complaint filed by the SEC, which charged Huttoe and others in November with massive stock manipulation.</p>
<p>Systems of Excellence is a maker of video teleconferencing equipment based in McLean, Va. It previously was based in Coral Gables, Fla.</p>
<p>The SEC charged Huttoe, 49, and a Miami resident, with making about $12 million in illegal profits from the secret distribution of millions of Systems of Excellence shares to members of his family and his firm's and his sale of company stock.</p>
<p>The SEC originally alleged that Huttoe had made about $10 million illegally, but since filing the case, it had uncovered $2.4 million more of profits he had amassed, the agency said.</p>
<p>Also named in the original complaint were six companies, including stock promoter SGA Goldstar Research Inc., Huttoe's wife, his mother and a niece. The charges followed SEC's suspension of Systems of Excellence's trading for 10 days in October.</p>
<p>John Fedders, a lawyer representing Huttoe, his wife and his mother, had no immediate comment.</p>
<p>Mitchell Cohen, counsel for SGA Goldstar, said he had not seen the amended complaint but said &quot;we intend to defend the case vigorously.&quot;</p>
<p>Systems of Excellence, which is under new management, said in a statement that it applauded the SEC's action. It said it was continuing its own review of the past management's activities and that none of those named in the amended complaint are associated with current management.</p>
<p>Among the relief defendants named were Barclay Davis and his wife, who allegedly controlled illegal proceeds made by Huttoe in a joint bank account.</p>
<p>The SEC alleged that Huttoe manipulated the market by issuing false, favourable information about Systems of Excellence and then selling his shares after the price had artificially risen.</p>
<p>SGA Goldstar and its affiliates were allegedly bribed with Systems of Excellence stock to recommend the company to subscribers to the SGA Goldstar Whisper Stock report, a tout sheet available on the Internet, the SEC said. The group also took advantage of the inflated market for Systems of Excellence that they created, dumping their own stock on unwitting investors, the SEC alleged.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
