<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264649" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Software group SAP watched for sale slowdown signs.</title>
<headline>Software group SAP watched for sale slowdown signs.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software developer SAP AG will be watched closely even through the normally quiet end-year holiday period for any further indications of sales problems at the once buoyant company, analysts said.</p>
<p>SAP shares lost a quarter of their value in October after its third-quarter sales growth showed an unexpected slowdown.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking for any sign of what year-end numbers will come out in January,&quot; said Brian Wilkinson, who follows the company for HSBC James Capel in London. &quot;SAP really has got to be as good as it's ever been to make its sales target.&quot;</p>
<p>SAP, whose R/3 software is used by businesses to keep track of accounting, purchasing, manufacturing and sales data, said in October it expected sales for the year to reach 3.5 billion marks ($2.3 billion) -- eight percent less than its previous forecast of 3.8 billion marks.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, SAP shares closed floor trading down 70 pfennigs at 204.5 marks. They were trading above 270 marks before SAP revised its sales estimates.</p>
<p>A disappointing fourth quarter could push the stock below the key support level of 200 marks, analysts said.</p>
<p>Also eagerly awaited is SAP's breakdown of sales, Wilkinson said. &quot;The split of maintenance revenue versus new product fees will tell you how well R/3 is selling against competing products,&quot; he explained.</p>
<p>In September R/3 sales were 130 million marks below the level of June, a result which SAP officials have attributed to sluggish economies in Germany and a few other countries.</p>
<p>Yet sales of business software competitors PeopleSoft Inc. and Baan Co NV have soared without interruption, Wilkinson noted.</p>
<p>For the first nine months of 1996, SAP sales rose 33 percent to 2.4 billion marks ($1.55 billion). In the same period PeopleSoft saw total sales rise 95 percent to $296.5 million. Baan's nine-month revnues climbed 88 percent to $264 million, boosted by a doubling of product sales.</p>
<p>&quot;A weak quarter for SAP coincided with good quarters for the competition,&quot; Wilkinson said. &quot;The market is becoming tougher for them.&quot;</p>
<p>The eagerly awited fourth-quarter results will cap a trying year for SAP. Earlier this week co-founder Hans-Werner Hector quit his supervisory board post over differences with chief executive Dietmar Hopp.</p>
<p>Hector, who had been criticised by Hopp earlier this year for transferring some of his shares into a trust, said the supervisory board was ineffective against a management board dominated by Hopp.</p>
<p>Management boards of top executives handle the daily operations of German companies while outside supervisors oversee the development of the company and its management.</p>
<p>SAP also suffered a shock to its stock in April when U.S. consulting firm Forrester Research Inc said R/3 sales would peak in 1997 because SAP had not moved quickly enough to adapt it to the Internet.</p>
<p>The German firm plans to roll out its Internet version in the first quarter of 1997, later than many of its competitors.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49 228 260 97150 ($1=1.5474 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
