<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273817" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: First management change by AT&amp;T CEO-to-be.</title>
<headline>First management change by AT&amp;T CEO-to-be.</headline>
<byline>Gilles Castonguay</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>John Walter, the future leader of AT&amp;T Corp., made his first mark on the largest U.S. telecommunications company Sunday with a management change.</p>
<p>Walter, who is to become chief executive officer of AT&amp;T on Jan. 1, 1998, replaced Joseph Nacchio, a 26-year veteran of the company and an architect of AT&amp;T's failed attempt to recover its share of the consumer long-distance market.</p>
<p>He named Gail McGovern in Nacchio's place as executive vice president of the New York-based company's consumer and small business division.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to make a lot of decisions on many fronts, and this is one of them,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>McGovern, who served as executive vice president of the business markets division, said in an earlier interview that she would focus on &quot;top-line revenue growth&quot; on assuming her new post.</p>
<p>Walter, whose appointment last October was not well received on Wall Street due to his inexperience in the telecommunications industry, declined to say if he planned to make more changes at the senior executive level.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm comfortable with the level of management that we have now,&quot; said Walter, who had been chief executive of the commercial printer R.R. Donnelley &amp; Sons Co.</p>
<p>Walter has been working alongside Robert Allen, AT&amp;T's outgoing chief executive officer, to get acquainted with the company since his appointment in October.</p>
<p>Nacchio later said in an interview that he decided to leave AT&amp;T over the weekend after getting an &quot;offer I couldn't refuse&quot; from Qwest Communications Corp., a small telecommunications company in Denver.</p>
<p>Nacchio, who joined AT&amp;T in March 1970, will become president and chief executive officer of Qwest, which designs and builds fiber optic networks and manages a national long-distance network.</p>
<p>&quot;I've always wanted to be a chief executive officer,&quot; he said, adding that he had been talking with Qwest Chairman Philip Anschutz during the last three months about the possibility of working for the company.</p>
<p>Nacchio said he obtained a &quot;great financial package,&quot; including an interest in the company.</p>
<p>As a &quot;carrier's carrier,&quot; Qwest provides network services to such companies as Sprint Corp., MCI Communications Corp. and AT&amp;T.</p>
<p>During his first year at the job, Nacchio said he would help the company handle its rapid growth, obtain resources and develop a strategy.</p>
<p>His resignation from AT&amp;T was the latest in a series of departures from the country's leading long-distance company.</p>
<p>In August, Alex Mandl, who had been deemed a likely successor to Allen, left his post as president and chief operating officer to join a wireless communications venture called Associated Group Inc..</p>
<p>Jim Barksdale quit as chief executive of AT&amp;T Wireless in January 1995 to become president and chief executive of the Netscape Communications Corp. Internet software company.</p>
<p>Jeffrey Kagan of Atlanta research company Kagan Telecom said Nacchio's departure could be interpreted by some industry observers as yet another setback for the company.</p>
<p>&quot;It's another pothole in the road to (AT&amp;T'S) recovery,&quot; he said. &quot;They (the company) have had a year of these, one after another.&quot;</p>
<p>The company has seen its market share in the $80-billion-a-year long-distance market dwindle from a near-monopoly since its breakup in 1984 to around 55 percent today, according to analysts' estimates.</p>
<p>In addition to MCI and Sprint, AT&amp;T has faced competition from a host of small but agressive resellers of long-distance service.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
