<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278194" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tech stocks to feel pressure from CA forecast.</title>
<headline>Tech stocks to feel pressure from CA forecast.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Technology stocks will feel pressure Friday from software giant Computer Associates Inc's dismal third quarter revenue forecast, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to assume that CA will spill over to the other techs. You have to expect that the big cap technology companies will trade lower,&quot; said Frank Calta, director of trading at Anvil Institutional Services.</p>
<p>Computer Associates fell sharply in pre-open trading, free falling to 54-3/8 from 61-3/4.  </p>
<p>One trader cautioned that Computer Associates fell on slim trading of only a few hundred shares and may recovered throughout the day.</p>
<p>After the market closed on Thursday, Computer Associates said that due to weakness in the European market, it expects third quarter revenues to fall below Wall Street estimates. Despite the revenue shortfall, the company said its earnings may still be able to reach consensus estimates of $0.75 a share for the quarter.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley on Friday downgraded Computer Associates to outperform from strong buy.  </p>
<p>Computer Associates' warning may have only a short-lived effect on other technology stocks, which have showed strength in year-end trading, some traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;This may filter over into other stocks, but after the first 15 minutes (of trading), it won't hurt the rest of the group. Investors will disregard this news and it will just hurt Computer Associates,&quot; said Kenneth Ducey, vice president, director of trading, BT Brokerage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
