<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285560" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Techs surge in rally led by Intel.</title>
<headline>Techs surge in rally led by Intel.</headline>
<byline>Jessica Hall</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bullish comments on Intel Corp sparked a technology rally and pushed the tech-laden Nasdaq Composite Index to its highest level in two weeks.</p>
<p>Technology stocks surged Friday after Salomon Brothers analyst Erika Klauer upgraded Intel to strong buy from hold and predicted better-than-expected personal computer unit growth for 1997.</p>
<p>The momemtum continued as Merrill Lynch analyst Thomas Kurlak restated his forecast for a quick recovery for the U.S. semiconductor industry in 1997.  </p>
<p>&quot;Intel got the major push, but that trickled over to everyone else,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Intel Corp surged 4-2/8 to 134-3/8. International Business Machines gained 3-7/8 to 156-7/8. Compaq Computer Corp jumped 2-1/4 to 74-5/8. Microsoft Corp increased 1-3/4 to 83-3/8  </p>
<p>Friday's optimism follows a weak showing for technology stocks on Thursday. Techs slid after computer retailer CompUSA Inc posted disappointing December same-store sales.</p>
<p>&quot;The technology sector is very sensitive -- susceptible to these mood swings,&quot; said Kenneth Ducey, director of trading at BT Brokerage, a subsidiary of Bankers Trust.</p>
<p>&quot;Two days of trading into the new year, we're seeing eratic market swings. Investors have to get used to these types of mood changes - it should continue like this for the rest of the year,&quot; Ducey said.  </p>
<p>Traders expect the pendulum to swing back after Friday's gains.</p>
<p>&quot;We could see some profit taking by the end of the day or on Monday. Some companies may hold on to these gains, but it's likely there will be some easing,&quot; said Bob McCready a trader with A.G. Edwards and Sons.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite Index rose 20.58 to 1301.28 at midday Friday, the first time the index has stood above 1300 since December 20.</p>
<p>The Philadelphia Stock Exchange semiconductor index gained 6.89 to 245.50. The American Stock Exchange Internet index gained 5.52 to 247.37 and the Morgan Stanley high tech index rose 9.34 to 346.74.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials rose 62 points, led by a solid rally from IBM. The broader market also got a boost from the bond market, which started to stabilize after yesterday's sharp drop.</p>
<p>Some other technology gainers included Cisco Systems Inc, which increased 1-3/8 to 64-1/4, and Micron Technology Inc, which jumped 1 to 30-5/8. Oracle Corp gained 1-7/8, and Sun Microsystems Inc increased 1 to 27-3/4.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
