<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286705" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Software vendors &quot;police&quot; Singapore shopping mall.</title>
<headline>Software vendors &quot;police&quot; Singapore shopping mall.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Wong</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new computer shop hopes to help police fight fake software sales in a Singapore shopping centre that is a favourite of computer fans.</p>
<p>U.S. software giant Microsoft Corp has staked out a visible presence next to rows of computer shops in Sim Lim Square, a well-trodden outlet for software programmes and games.</p>
<p>Some traders sell counterfeit software for a fraction of what it costs to buy the real thing.</p>
<p>Microsoft hopes its presence will deter culprits, especially since it has joined a software piracy group and police to uncover underground sales of copied software.</p>
<p>&quot;We conduct our own raids and have increased the number of raids in coming months against shops selling illegal CD-ROMs,&quot; said Christopher Austin, Microsoft's corporate attorney for Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>He said that unless Microsoft put money into enforcement and worked with local authorities to track down illegal sales, shops selling real software &quot;won't have a fighting chance&quot;.</p>
<p>FULL-TIME INVESTIGATOR</p>
<p>Austin's new position with Microsoft, in addition to its use of a full-time investigator and more paralegal resources, reflects the company's intention to wage combat with software thieves.</p>
<p>Working with Singapore police this year, Microsoft's efforts helped to lead to the seizure of 5,800 CD-ROMs from two vans distributing to re-sellers within the shopping centre, Austin said.</p>
<p>The CD-ROMs had a retail value of U.S. $1.5 million.</p>
<p>Investigators uncovered a complex system of lookouts and runners who distributed the counterfeit CD-ROMs to waiting clients from vans parked some distance from the shops.</p>
<p>This month, Seattle-based Microsoft took a more active role in retailing by providing marketing support to a local partner to sell its software.</p>
<p>The first Microsoft store in the world was opened three months ago at Funan Centre, a nearby shopping complex where counterfeit software was found at some outlets.</p>
<p>One government official said Funan Centre has been &quot;cleaned up&quot;, and the same will be done for Sim Lim.</p>
<p>&quot;(Shops) have probably hidden away all their (fake) goods because they see too many business suits around,&quot; said Paul Lovell, managing director of Microsoft in Singapore while opening the second Microsoft store in Sim Lim Square.</p>
<p>&quot;Come back on a Saturday, and they will be at it again,&quot; he added, referring to replica products that are sold alongside the real thing.</p>
<p>Software developers now realise that unless they spend money educating the public, and back up small stores selling their copyrighted computer games, more revenue will be lost.</p>
<p>DEVELOPERS DETERRED</p>
<p>Singapore software developers also complain that piracy takes aways incentives to put money in research and developement.</p>
<p>&quot;Piracy affects local developers. It's hard to pump in money on multi-million dollar R&amp;D (research and development) investments when we can't protect the software,&quot; Richard Yen, managing director of Ednovation, said at the Microsoft store opening.</p>
<p>Software publishers also try to stop retailers from selling hardware with free software, unless they have contracts to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't support original software dealers with this sort of action, basically they can't win,&quot; Austin said.</p>
<p>&quot;They can't compete because right next door, right upstairs, you have a dealer selling hardware with free software.&quot;</p>
<p>The Business Software Alliance (BSA), representing leading software publishers, reported that about 58 percent of software used in Singapore in 1994 was pirated.</p>
<p>This accounted for US$45 million in lost revenue, BSA said.</p>
<p>Overall, software theft in Asia exceeded US$4.3 billion in 1994, some 29 percent of the US$15.2 billion lost worldwide.</p>
<p>Although the piracy rate in Singapore has fallen, revenue losses have climbed, partly due to higher business activity.</p>
<p>But software vendors are taking heart from Singapore's Copyright Act of 1987, coupled with bilateral agreements with the United States, Britain and Australia, which makes it easier to pursue and prosecute offenders.</p>
<p>The Singapore government views software theft as a serious offence and courts have started to hand down heavier penalities.</p>
<p>So far, retailers convicted of piracy have been fined as much as $45,000 and jailed for up to 30 months.</p>
<p>($1 = S$1.4)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
