<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292751" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: System Software sees quick return to profitability.</title>
<headline>System Software sees quick return to profitability.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>System Software Associates Inc said Wednesday that despite posting a fourth quarter loss, the company is bouncing back and expects &quot;a quick return&quot; to profitability.</p>
<p>&quot;We think starting in the quarter we are in now we'll see year-over-year revenue growth, and we should see a quick return to profitability in the business,&quot; Roger Covey, chairman and chief executive of the company, told analysts and reporters on a conference call.  </p>
<p>The Chicago-based business software company on Tuesday reported a fourth quarter net loss of $0.13 a share versus a profit of $0.35 last year. Revenues were $109.4 million, down from $122.7 in 1995.</p>
<p>All 1995 data was restated due to a change in the company's accounting method. Covey said the company will now recognize revenue from resellers only after the product has been sold to the end user.  </p>
<p>Covey said System Software's recent release of its BPCS Client/Server version 6.0 was difficult for the company, but positive results are now showing up. He said, for example, software licensing fee revenues rose 81 percent from third quarter to $81.6 million.</p>
<p>&quot;This really dramatic increase was driven by market place acceptance of our new software,&quot; Covey said. &quot;We think we've gone through what turned out to be a long and difficult product launch.&quot;  </p>
<p>Covey said the company also expects to post improved results in its European operations after a rough 1996. Covey said the profits from Europe dropped by about $60 million from 1995 to 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to have a strong first quarter, the quarter we're in now, in Europe and particularly in the U.K.,&quot; Covey said.</p>
<p>Covey said the company replaced the entire management team in Britain and made various management changes in Spain and Scandinavia as well. In addition, the company has put more emphasis on training and education, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We know that '97 will be a lot better year for us than '96 was in Europe,&quot; Covey said. &quot;To tell you the truth, we moved much too slowly on this. There are things we probably should have done a year ago and didn't.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
