<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292822" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Netscape shares tumble after downgrade.</title>
<headline>Netscape shares tumble after downgrade.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Netscape Communications Corp plummeted on Wednesday, shedding nearly 18 percent of its value after a Wall Street analyst lowered his rating, citing factors that could slow growth and dent the market's valuation of the Internet software pioneer.</p>
<p>By 3:45 p.m. EDT, the share was off 10-3/8 at 48-3/8 in volume of more than 13.5 million shares, the third most actively traded share on the Nasdaq market.</p>
<p>Analysts and traders attributed the decline to a research note issued by Deutsche Morgan Grenfell Inc analyst William Gurley saying the stock closed Monday near his price target.  </p>
<p>A colleague at Gurley's office in nearby Menlo Park said the analyst was not commenting publicly on the research report, in which traders said he downgraded the stock to an &quot;accumulate&quot; rating from a buy.</p>
<p>The sharp decline was a further demonstration of investor's jitters over the highly volatile Internet market, where many see huge opportunities, but the rapid pace of change is forcing frequent changes in business plans.</p>
<p>Netscape, which since its high-flying August 1995 initial stock offering has assumed the mantle of a bellwether for the nascent sector, is also in the throes of a shifting strategy.  </p>
<p>Since last summer's &quot;browser war&quot; showdown with Microsoft Corp, which has pledged to give away its Internet Explorer software and thereby essentially eliminated the market for sales of Netscape's initial Navigator product, Netscape has been forced to overhaul its business plan.</p>
<p>The Mountain View, Calif. company is now concentrated on corporate intranets, or private computer networks that utilize cheaper and more flexible Internet technologies to improve distribution of information to employees and customers.</p>
<p>Just before Christmas, Netscape released a public test version of its new, feature-rich Communicator software.  </p>
<p>The preview of the Communicator suite has received solid critical review and Netscape said Wednesday that it had helped boost the number of users of Netscape's electronic mail to 12 million, making it the market's fastest-growing e-mail.</p>
<p>But analysts have raised concerns the new business model requires longer lead-times to produce customer sales and this could provide serious transition challenges.</p>
<p>Gurley's note cited just such &quot;a lengthening sales cycle, a new pricing model and a major product transition,&quot; as being among the reasons for his downgrade, market-makers said.  </p>
<p>The analyst's report concluded that &quot;the fundamentals remain intact, though there is near-term uncertainty,&quot; they said, adding that Tuesday's market close of $58-3/4 was near the analyst's price target of $60.</p>
<p>Among the factors raised by the analyst was also an expectation that Netscape may not be able to manage to produce the positive upside surprise in its fourth quarter 1996 results as it has in recent quarters.</p>
<p>First Call's survey of Wall Street estimates, which analysts are expecting to be issued on January 28, shows a consensus estimate of $0.10, up from $0.03 a year ago.  </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Netscape said the company had issued no news that would account for the share activity.</p>
<p>Some market sources said another factor in the stock's decline was talk that Chrysler Corp may have chosen International Business Machines Corp's Lotus Development Corp unit over Netscape.</p>
<p>But Chrysler spokeswoman Lori McTavish said the carmaker has contracts with both Lotus, for electronic mail and with Netscape, for its intranet software requirements.</p>
<p>&quot;We have contracts with both Lotus and with Netscape. We have not dropped Netscape for Lotus,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau, +1 415 846 5400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
