<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302440" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Corel and Netscape set software alliance.</title>
<headline>Corel and Netscape set software alliance.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Corel Corp. and Netscape Communications Corp., seeking to steal some thunder from Microsoft Corp., announced on Monday an alliance to meld office productivity software with enhanced Internet capabilities.</p>
<p>Corel said it licensed Netscape Communicator -- Netscape's new e-mail and browser software -- with the aim of integrating it with Corel's WordPerfect Suite 8 and Corel Office Professional 8. Terms of the deal were not disclosed.</p>
<p>The announcement was also designed to take some of the limelight off Microsoft's planned glitzy unveiling of its Office 97 software package on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the timing of the announcement) was not an accident,&quot; one Netscape official confirmed.</p>
<p>The marriage of Netscape's Internet software suite and Corel's word processor and other software tools is part of a growing marketing trend in which Internet browsing and communications are brought together with other computer applications in a seamless package.</p>
<p>Ottawa-based Corel, along with Lotus software from IBM Corp., has made inroads against Microsoft in the all-important corporate  market for so-called productivity software, which includes word processing, spreadd sheets, e-mail and Internet capabilities.</p>
<p>Corel and Mountain View, Calif.-based Netcscape said they would jointly develop the new products, which they hoped to ship later this year. The companies would also undertake joint marketing of the software package.</p>
<p>&quot;Our combined efforts will produce the only desktop productivity suite that is completely open and standards-based, a concept in sharp contrast to the competition,&quot; Corel President Michael Cowpland said in a statement.</p>
<p>Corel and has been working with Netscape for some time, offering Netscape Navigator with the WordPerfect Suite and Office Professional since early 1996.</p>
<p>Corel's Cowpland made it clear he was looking for further joint projects with the Internet startup firm Netscape.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we are very keen to be working with Netscape so we will explore all possibilities,&quot; Cowpland said in a conference call with journalists and analysts on Monday.</p>
<p>Netscape, which has turned its focus to the corporate &quot;intranet&quot; market, hoped with the Corel deal to capitalize on Corel's success in penetrating Microsoft's hold on the software market, Netscape Vice President Bob  Lisbonne said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
