<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304957" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Netscape off after Merrill cautions on Q4.</title>
<headline>Netscape off after Merrill cautions on Q4.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Merrill Lynch analyst Bruce Smith said in a research note that Netscape Communications Corp's fourth quarter was &quot;severely back-end loaded&quot; and this could hurt its current first quarter.</p>
<p>Shares of the Internet software company were down 3-3/4 at 43 at midday on volume of more than 3.3 million shares.</p>
<p>Smith said he expects Netscape's fourth quarter results, due to be reported January 28, to be in line with Wall Street estimates. But for the first time, the company had to stretch to reach its target, he said.  </p>
<p>According to First Call, analysts' consensus estimate for Netscape's fourth quarter earnings is $0.10 per share.</p>
<p>Merrill estimates Netscape's fourth quarter revenues will come in at $118 million, and earnings at $0.12 a share.</p>
<p>Smith said he retains his 'hold' rating on the stock.</p>
<p>However, he said the scramble to meet fourth quarter numbers did not bode well for Netscape's performance in the current first quarter, which he notes is historically weak for software companies.</p>
<p>Smith noted the stock has declined 20 percent over the past week following a downgrade by Deutsche Morgan Grenfell analyst William Gurley. Traders said Gurley cut the stock to accumulate from buy. Gurkey was quoted as saying there was very little upside to published fourth quarter revenue estimates of $110-$120 million.  </p>
<p>Smith said first quarter results may be flat with, and perhaps even down from, the fourth quarter, which would be well short of his current estimate of a 6.0 percent rise in revenue to $125.4 million and earnings per share of $0.13.</p>
<p>Speaking of the fourth quarter, he told Reuters, &quot;Basically, the quarter was severely back-end loaded.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people have said the quarter was just back-end loaded. I'm saying it was severely back-end loaded. They closed a significant amount of business on December 31 just to make the quarter, which they've never had to do before.&quot;</p>
<p>In his research note, Smith said the unlikelihood of an upside surprise for the company this quarter &quot;is significant because Netscape has made a habit of greatly exceeding expectations since they came public in August 1995.&quot;</p>
<p>He said his 1997 revenue estimate of $534 million and earnings per share estimate of $0.57 could be too high.</p>
<p>Smith also said that when he downgraded Netscape in September he foresaw &quot;significant risk&quot; to the company's 1997 revenues and earnings due to its reliance on browser sales for 60 percent of its revenues, especially in light of Microsoft Corp's aggressive push into this area.</p>
<p>&quot;Subsequent to our downgrade, Netscape made a bold attempt to enter the e-mail and groupware market currently dominated primarily by Lotus Development and, to a lesser extent, Microsoft,&quot; he said in the note. Lotus is a unit of International Business Machines Corp.</p>
<p>Netscape executives last week estimated that 12 million people have begun using Netscape's products for sending and receiving electronic mail. They said this compares favorably with the estimated 15-16 million users of rivals' e-mail systems.</p>
<p>But Smith said Lotus appears to have a lead of three to five years in the area with its Notes product, adding that because the market is already well-penetrated, he believes it will be difficult for Netscape to displace the incumbent.</p>
<p>Netscape argues that it will succeed by introducing e-mail that complies more broadly with cheaper Internet standards.</p>
<p>But Smith said his earlier assessment that Netscape could maintain its momentum through 1996 and into the first half of 1997 &quot;appears to have been optimistic as the slowdown in momentum is happening in the fourth quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have heard of two major deals that were closed on December 31, one of which apparently closed late in the evening,&quot; said Smith.</p>
<p>He said his research note was based on checks with several industry sources.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we had anticipated major problems when we downgraded the stock in September, we are surprised by the speed that business conditions have slowed for Netscape,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Smith said he expects the stock to remain under pressure for the foreseeable future. He said he will review his 1997 estimates after fourth quarter results are reported on January 28.</p>
<p>((--sam.perry@reuter.com, Palo Alto Bureau, 415 846 5400))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
