<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30903" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: FEATURE - Japan venture businesses slow to take off.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Japan venture businesses slow to take off.</headline>
<byline>Ayumi Moriyama</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yoshito Hori likens the young Japanese entrepreneur trying to take off to a trainee pilot bumping along the runway.</p>
<p>&quot;If a divine wind blows, he will take off and fly. If not, he is doomed.&quot; says Hori, president of Globis Corp.</p>
<p>Globis is one of only a few firms that support venture businesses in Japan through funding and education and Hori has taken a lead, feeling that Japan lags far behind the United States in the field.</p>
<p>The Japanese government would like venture businesses to flourish amid the economic slump to generate more jobs, as Microsoft Corp and Apple Computer Inc have done in the United States, but so far has not succeeded in getting many off the ground.</p>
<p>Young Japanese still prefer to work for the Mitsubishis, Mitsuis, Sumitomos and other large corporations, even though Japan's unemployment is now at its highest level ever.</p>
<p>The Ministry of International Trade and Industry (MITI) has been supporting entrepreneurs by organising seminars and study sessions, as well as some access to funding.</p>
<p>&quot;If more people learn about the positive attitude the government is showing towards entrepreneurs, the general mentality towards ventures should change as well,&quot; Hori says.</p>
<p>He believes practical education is vital to prevent dangerous kamikaze-style ventures.</p>
<p>At Globis's management school, Hori organised a programme where students can obtain an MBA degree through a tie-up with Leicester University in central England.</p>
<p>&quot;The curriculum consists of the essential factors in management including conceptual skills such as problem finding, problem solving, and strategic thinking, which are difficult to acquire in knowledge-based Japanese education based on memorisation,&quot; Hori said.</p>
<p>Tomoyo Kazumi, in a book on Japanese entrepreneurship, says Japan's new venture-friendly atmosphere compares with that of the United States in the 1970s and 80s.</p>
<p>What triggered venture business in the U.S. was the faltering economy after the Vietnam War, while that in Japan comes from the burst of the bubble economy in the late 1980s, she says.</p>
<p>There is no clear documentation of business startups, but a survey by People's Finance Corporation Research Institute showed the creation of new businesses has started to rise again after hitting a recent bottom in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>Toshihiko Ichida, researcher at the New Business Research Institute says: &quot;You can't say it's a venture business boom when you look at the statistics. It's rather a support boom.&quot;</p>
<p>The support is coming from the government and private sector but a dramatic increase in new businesses is lacking, he adds.</p>
<p>Venture businesses have featured well in the media, through articles depicting young entrepreneurs amid a society of traditional values such as lifetime employment, consensus decision making and seniority based salaries.</p>
<p>&quot;But it will take time to educate the entrepreneurs, and it will take time for financial institutions to be able to tell which companies are worth investing in and which are not,&quot; Ichida says.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a painful learning period that Japan has to go through,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Hori said it would take about 10 more years for venture businesses to finally become part of mainstream Japanese society, as they have done in the United States.</p>
<p>The prospects are bright, but until then, Japan's fledgling entrepreneurs will have to undergo a difficult period of trial and error, he says.</p>
<p>One of the most successful Japanese venture businesses is Softbank Corp, the country's biggest software retailer.</p>
<p>The company has recently engaged in massive, high-profile acquisitions in Japan and overseas.</p>
<p>Its president, Masayoshi Son, who is often likened to Microsoft's Bill Gates, uses an aggressive and controversial management style which constantly challenges Japanese business taboos.</p>
<p>His style has induced admiration from some and phobia from others.</p>
<p>Softbank's acquisitions include Ziff-Davis, a major U.S. computer magazine publisher, and Kingston Technology Co, the world's biggest producer and supplier of computer memory boards.</p>
<p>Despite the scarcity of venture capital businesses, there are a number of private funds looking for potential investment.</p>
<p>Among those are the Japan Associated Finance Co Ltd (JAFCO), a group company of Nomura Securities Co Ltd, which operates a 152.3 billion yen ($1.40 billion) fund and provides help in Initial Public Offerings.</p>
<p>Most of the funds support companies in their developing stage, but a few have been established to help companies that are still in the incubation period.</p>
<p>For an investor, there is less risk in putting money into a company that is closer to bringing in a profit from the new idea.</p>
<p>Hori says his aim is to ensure more fledgling entrepeneurs get off the ground and glide upward. ($1=109.0 Yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
