<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312186" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Helping that Nye guy save Earth.</title>
<headline>Helping that Nye guy save Earth.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Bill Nye the Science Guy: Stop the Rock!&quot; from Pacific Interactive (Windows/Macintosh, $40) starts off with both good news and bad news.</p>
<p>The bad news: A giant meteoroid will strike Earth in five days.</p>
<p>The good news: Mankind has just built a computerized Meteoroid And Asteroid Xploder, or MAAX, which should be able to blow it apart.</p>
<p>The really bad news: MAAX has gone mad. The computer has decided that witnessing a cataclysmic event like the one that apparently wiped out the dinosaurs is too good an opportunity to miss.</p>
<p>&quot;You humans will have to prove that preserving humanity is more interesting,&quot; MAAX announces. To do that, the folks at Nye Labs must answer seven riddles before the meteoroid hits. &quot;If you beat the clock, I'll hijack that rock.&quot;</p>
<p>Designed for ages 9 and older and scheduled to be released Jan. 21, &quot;Stop the Rock!&quot; is based on the Emmy-winning Disney show that explores science concepts for youngsters. It features scientist/comedian/author Bill Nye, whose whacked-out presentations keeps sometimes-dry science topics lively.</p>
<p>The game's demented nature shows up in little ways. Press the buzzer at the door of Nye Labs and it produces a knocking sound. Inside the lab, on the board that outlines this week's production schedule, there's a note that says &quot;Location shoot on Friday unless planet destroyed.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Let's pause and reflect for a moment,&quot; the TV newsman says as he picks up a hand mirror to check his makeup. Such silly jokes are everywhere.</p>
<p>Also along for the ride are other scientists, such as Capt. Swell Whitecap, the chief of marine operations who fancies himself a pirate, atmospheric researcher Connie Vection, geologist Sam Andreas and oceanographer Sue Nami.</p>
<p>Most of the time players will wander around Nye's laboratory/museum checking out his machines, gathering hints, exploring, and hoping to find pictures or objects that constitute the answers to riddles such as &quot;When you can't stand the heat, when you can't take the pressure, prove there's a spot where life grows in great measure.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the time it's fun and informative. But &quot;Stop the Rock!&quot; has a few annoying quirks.</p>
<p>In most computer games, the cursor changes shape or colour when you're touching a &quot;hot spot,&quot; such as an object you can manipulate. The system for &quot;Stop the Rock!&quot; is unnecessarily complicated, sometimes requiring you to open a computer and remove a probe that you have to drag around.</p>
<p>Also, it's not always clear how you're supposed to solve the riddles. Even when you've pinpointed the answer, you may have to do other inconsequential things before the solution becomes acceptable.</p>
<p>And &quot;Stop the Rock!&quot; doesn't make it clear that if you choose &quot;Hang out&quot; instead of &quot;Join Nye Labs&quot; at the beginning of the game, you won't be able to solve any of the riddles or hear about the meteoroid. You might think something's wrong with the game.</p>
<p>Finally, Sue Nami's admonitions to stop drifting around like driftwood (even when players know what they're doing) quickly become condescending. Just ignore the bratty geek and have fun exploring the lab. You're bound to learn something interesting.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>A recent column on computerized pinball games produced a lot of e-mail. Some of it correctly noted that Sierra's &quot;3-D Ultra Pinball: Creep Night&quot; is available for Macintosh machines, not just Windows. A Mac version of &quot;Full Tilt! 2 Pinball&quot; is due sometime this year.</p>
<p>One writer objected to my observation that real-life pinball seems to be a dying game. The &quot;mad keen Pinball player&quot; from Britain advised that &quot;Pinball is very much alive and kicking over here -- we're starting to see a backlash against video games.&quot;</p>
<p>Another avid pinball player, an owner of a 1993 Twilight Zone machine, complained that I had been unfair to &quot;Pro Pinball&quot; because it is the only CD-ROM game where the flipper action and ball motion are &quot;virtually identical to that of a real machine.&quot; The other games &quot;are either too easy, too repetitive&quot; or have an unrealistic feel that makes &quot;the shots ridiculously difficult to hit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A December column that explained how the registration screen in &quot;FX Fighter Turbo&quot; pops up unannounced every 14 days no matter what you're doing, and how the problem isn't eliminated by uninstalling the game, produced another wave of e-mail.</p>
<p>Most of it was from consumers expressing frustration at the various techniques used by companies to dun consumers into registering.</p>
<p>The manufacturer, GTE Entertainment, expressed the fear that by using the word &quot;virus&quot; when I characterised the unwanted &quot;reminder&quot; programme, consumers would believe that &quot;FX Fighter Turbo&quot; would wipe out their hard drive, as many malevolent viruses do. In this case, that won't happen. The registration reminder is simply an unwanted and unnecessary annoyance.</p>
<p>As a few e-mail correspondents noted, the registration reminder is, in the vernacular of computer viruses, a Trojan horse or simply a Trojan. Although it may do unwanted or unpleasant things, a Trojan cannot make copies of itself and cannot, by itself, infect another computer.</p>
<p>Like the legendary Trojan horse, which was welcomed inside the walled city by the unwitting leaders of Troy, a Trojan is brought into a computer by a customer who doesn't realise that he's getting an extra &quot;surprise&quot; in the software package he wants to load.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
