<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317920" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/First USA pops on takeover.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/First USA pops on takeover.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Options on shares of First USA Inc were not particularly busy Monday, but they posted some of the sharpest gains among equity options as the stock soared.</p>
<p>First USA shares were up nine at 45-3/4 by 1345 CST/1945 GMT after news Banc One Corp said it agreed to pay about $52.61 for each First USA share.  Nearly 12 million First USA shares changed hands.</p>
<p>&quot;The options that are up the most are First USA,&quot; said one trader at the American Stock Exchange, where the options trade. &quot;But they're not very busy.&quot;  </p>
<p>The most active First USA option was the May 40 call, which traded about 850 contracts.</p>
<p>The option, which had open interest of 679, including an addition of 45 contracts last Friday, rose 5-7/16, or more than 400 percent, to 6-3/4.</p>
<p>The most active option in the February series was the 35 strike call, with volume of nearly 500 contracts.</p>
<p>It had open interest of 2,155 through Friday, when 106 contracts were closed out.</p>
<p>That option rose 8-1/8, or nearly 350 percent, to 10-1/2.  </p>
<p>The most active First USA put was the February 45, with volume of 525. The option was new and had no open interest. It was trading at 13/16, off its high of 1-1/8.</p>
<p>Banc One shares lost ground, falling 3-1/2 points to 41-5/8 on total volume of more than 7.4 million shares.</p>
<p>But in a sign investors appeared to view the buyout as positive news, Banc One calls drew heavy interest and traders said much of it was additions.</p>
<p>The Banc One February 30 call traded nearly 13,200 contracts, the February 32-1/2 call traded 3,075 and the February 35 call traded roughly 1,265.  </p>
<p>The Banc One February 30 calls fell 3-3/4 to 11-1/2 but had open interest of only eight contracts through Friday.</p>
<p>One trader said bullish investors could be buying those options, betting on the stock to recover and bounce higher, while some investors may be going short the calls, expecting them to continue to decline with the stock.</p>
<p>The most active Banc One put was the February 40, which traded about 940 contracts. It rose 1/4 to 1/2.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Microsoft Corp options were busy as the stock rallied on heavy volume.</p>
<p>Microsoft shares were up 3-3/8 at 90-1/2 in late trade.  </p>
<p>Microsoft shares, with volume of more than 16 million making them the most active on Nasdaq, had reached an all-time high of 92-7/8.</p>
<p>The stock rallied after reporting strong second quarter earnings Friday despite the company's warning of slowing growth in fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>Among the Microsoft options, the February 90 call was most active, with volume of about 6,680 contracts. The February 95 call traded more than 3,900. On the put side, the February 85 was most active, with volume of 3,375 contracts. ((--G.Crawford, 312 408 8750/E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150108">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
