<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="320732" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Remedy jumps after Goldman Sachs rating.</title>
<headline>Remedy jumps after Goldman Sachs rating.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Remedy Corp shares jumped as much as 15 percent Tuesday after a closely watched analyst at Goldman, Sachs &amp; Co placed the software stock on its &quot;recommended list.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares of Remedy rose six to 46-1/4 in early afternoon Nasdaq trading. Earlier, the shares traded as high as 46-3/8.</p>
<p>Rick Sherlund, the Goldman analyst, placed Remedy on the recommended list because of the software company's estimated 45 percent growth rate, distribution strengths and capable management, he wrote in a research report released Tuesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;We estimate revenue and earnings growth of 95 percent and 85 percent respectively for 1996,&quot; when the company reports its year-end results next week, Sherlund wrote. &quot;Our estimates for 1997 are for revenue and earnings growth of about 65 percent and 60 percent respectively.&quot;</p>
<p>Remedy, based in Mountain View, Calif., writes computer programs for the customer service departments of large companies. Its customers, which include some of the world's biggest retailers and service companies, use its software to keep track of complicated customer requests.  </p>
<p>The help-desk software niche is one of the fastest growing segments of the computer industry. Remedy's share of the market is about one-fifth.</p>
<p>Shares of Remedy's competitors also rose. Vantive Corp shares rose 3/4 to 27-3/4 while Clarify Inc jumped 2-1/4 to 34-1/2. Scopus Technology Inc was up 3-3/4 to 45.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
