<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="320779" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tandem sees seasonal uptick in fiscal Q2.</title>
<headline>Tandem sees seasonal uptick in fiscal Q2.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tandem Computers Inc said that it expects the normal seasonal uptick in business from its fiscal first quarter to its fiscal second quarter and it also expects continued modest pressure on product gross margins.</p>
<p>Tandem executives, speaking to analysts on a conference call, also said that they plan to continue cutting their expenses to offset any future margin declines.</p>
<p>Earlier, Tandem reported better-than-expected first quarter earnings of $0.10 a share including a real estate gain. The First Call consensus estimate was $0.04 a share.  </p>
<p>&quot;We expect a fairly normal seasonal improvement over first quarter,&quot; Roel Pieper, Tandem chief executive, told a conference call. Executives declined to be more specific on the expected seasonal uptick.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe there is continued modest pressure on product gross margins,&quot; Pieper added, citing continued competitiveness in the industry and Tandem's new lower-margin products based on Microsoft Corp's Windows NT operating system.</p>
<p>Executives said that in the first quarter some of its expenses were non-recurring due to Tandem's product launch in the quarter. Expenses will decline in the second quarter.  </p>
<p>Tandem introduced its S-Series of its Himalaya servers in the first quarter and Enrico Pesatori, the newly appointed president and chief operating officer said that Tandem shipped 16 S-Series systems in the quarter.</p>
<p>Executives also said that they saw some impact from the stronger dollar in Japan and that the net impact on the first quarter versus the year ago period was a negative impact of $5 million on revenues, from currency fluctuations.</p>
<p>The company also said it expects a lower tax rate in fiscal 1998, due to an agreement with Japan, through its sale of some of its assets in Japan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
