<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321639" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Leading US tech stocks expected to rise for months.</title>
<headline>Leading US tech stocks expected to rise for months.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks of bellwether computer, software and networking companies are likely to rise for at least three more months as customers carry on with their spending spree on technology, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In the past two weeks, most of the pillars of the computer industry -- International Business Machines Corp, Microsoft Corp and Intel Corp -- have reported earnings that were better than Wall Street expected, easing concerns about slowing demand for personal computers.  </p>
<p>&quot;So far, all the big technology companies' earnings have been way ahead of expectations,&quot; said Daniel Ries, an analyst at Nomura Securities in New York. &quot;Business activity looks like it's strong.&quot;</p>
<p>On Tuesday, IBM, the world's biggest computer maker, reported better-than-expected fourth-quarter earnings of $2.02 billion, or $3.93 a share, up from $1.71 billion, or $3.09, share in the year-ago period. Wall Street had expected Big Blue to earn $3.88 a share, according to First Call.</p>
<p>Revenues rose six percent to $23.14 billion.  </p>
<p>Last week, Intel and Microsoft also reported earnings that exceeded most forecasts.</p>
<p>The strong earnings has led some fund managers to buy even more technology shares, even though industry leaders such as Microsoft, Intel, IBM and Cisco Systems Inc are trading near record highs.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm buying Intel and Cisco, especially Intel,&quot; said Bill Schaff, who manages $250 million at Bay Isle Financial in San Francisco. Schaff said he expected those stocks to continue to outperform the market in coming months.  </p>
<p>Fueling the stock price increases is optimism that companies will continue to spend lavishly on personal computers in 1997, reflecting demand for faster PCs that can run a new generation of business software and that can handle transactions through the Internet.</p>
<p>According to a recent report by Montgomery Securities in San Francisco, corporate spending on technology is expected to increase 20 percent this year from $950 billion spent in 1996.  </p>
<p>To be sure, analysts warned that not all technology stocks would fare well in coming months. Microsoft, Intel, Compaq and Cisco -- the biggest companies in software, semiconductor, PCs and networking, respectively -- appear to be shoving aside their smaller competitors.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the largest stocks that did the best,&quot; said Steve Dube, an analyst at investment bank Wasserstein Perella in New York. &quot;I expect that to continue.&quot;</p>
<p>The smaller technology companies, for the most part, did not have impressive earnings in the recent quarter.  </p>
<p>Digital Equipment Corp, for example, said last week net income fell 79 percent in its fiscal second quarter to $31.9 million.</p>
<p>Apple Computer Inc, which reported a loss of $120 million last week, also warned investors it did not expect to report a profit until September, six months later than it originally forecast.</p>
<p>Some investors also are finally starting to pay attention to warnings of slower growth from technology companies, they said.</p>
<p>Until now, most investors have shrugged when the chief financial officers of bellwether companies have tried to damp expectations with predictions of slower growth.</p>
<p>&quot;When I see problems at computer retailers, it makes me worry about final demand for this stuff,&quot; said Jim Crabbe, principal of Portland money management firm Crabbe Huson Group, which manages $4.5 billion.</p>
<p>The rising dollar could also spell trouble for technology companies trying to sell in hot markets, such as Asia, Crabbe said.</p>
<p>((Kourosh Karimkhany, in Palo Alto, +1 415 846-5401))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
