<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="322665" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu, Arafat to attend Davos forum - officials.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu, Arafat to attend Davos forum - officials.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat, their Hebron deal signed, will attend the World Economic Forum in the Swiss resort of Davos next week, Forum officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Forum founder Klaus Schwab told reporters in Geneva that Netanyahu, Arafat and Egypt's President Hosni Mubarak would be together on the Davos conference platform for a discussion on the Middle East on Sunday February 2.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Netanyahu said no meeting had yet been set between the prime minister and the Palestinian president.</p>
<p>But with Israel's handover of most of the West Bank city of Hebron complete, Netanyahu is likely to focus more on drumming up business for the Jewish state now that he has wrapped up his first peace deal with the PLO.</p>
<p>Differences with the PLO and Egypt over a Hebron accord kept Netanyahu away from a Forum-sponsored Middle East and North Africa economic conference last November in Cairo, an event at which Israel was largely sidelined.</p>
<p>Officials of the Geneva-based Forum said final arrangements for the appearance of Netanyahu, Arafat and Mubarak had not yet been completed, but they would be staying in Davos for between 36 and 48 hours.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope they will agree to sit together on Sunday at a plenary session and answer questions,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>Schwab said he was not aiming to arrange talks between the three or any combination of them.</p>
<p>&quot;At the Forum, we leave it to the people involved to organise such meetings if they wish,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>The Jerusalem Post published on Tuesday a list of top international business executives it said Netanyahu wanted to invite to Israel this year to discuss expanding their interests in the country.</p>
<p>The list included Microsoft Corp president Bill Gates, Itochu Corp chief executive officer Minoru Murofushi, General Motors Corp CEO John Smith, Siemens AG chairman Heinrich von Pierer and General Electric Co chairman John Welch.</p>
<p>Asked about the newspaper report, Netanyahu's spokesman said only: &quot;He is always interested in meeting business people to advance Israel's economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Arafat is likely to present the Forum with a picture of a Palestinian economy struggling to recover from Israeli closures that have prevented thousands of Arab workers from reaching jobs in Israel.</p>
<p>Donor countries that had pledged $2.4 billion after the landmark 1993 Israeli-PLO self-rule deal have so far delivered a total of $985 million, far below the losses incurred by the Palestinian economy in 1996 due to the closures, the Palestinian Monetary Authority said this month.</p>
<p>Real Palestinian gross domestic product fell to $1.633 billion in 1996 from $2.161 billion in 1995, it said.</p>
<p>Israel clamped a blanket closure on the West Bank and Gaza Strip in February 1996 following the first of four suicide bombings by Islamic militants that killed 59 in Israel. The closure, which was gradually eased, was imposed again in September after fresh clashes between Israeli and PLO security forces claimed the lives of 60 Palestinians and 15 Israelis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
