<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="323865" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spyglass sees Q2 results similar to Q1.</title>
<headline>Spyglass sees Q2 results similar to Q1.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spyglass Inc said Wednesday it expects second quarter expenses and revenues, excluding those due from Microsoft Corp, to be close to those of the first quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We would expect Q2 to look very similar for us, this is obviously excluding the Microsoft arrangement...in terms of revenue and expense levels,&quot; Gary Vilchick, chief financial officer, told analysts in a telephone conference call.</p>
<p>&quot;That's the guidance I would want to give you at this point,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Spyglass second quarter began January 1.  </p>
<p>Spyglass today reported a loss for the first quarter of $0.12 a share. Revenues were $3.89 million, and operating expenses were $6.36 million.</p>
<p>Spyglass said it had agreed with Microsoft for a full buyout of royalties owed to Spyglass for its Mosaic browser technology in Microsoft's Internet Explorer.</p>
<p>The buyout includes a one-time $8 million payment, including $7.5 million in cash. Spyglass said it will recognize the funds in its fiscal second quarter.  </p>
<p>Spyglass, which provides embedded software, is in the midst of a product transition to what has been dubbed the device market. The company develops software to link everyday products like cellular phones and televisions to the Internet.</p>
<p>The company has a long list of customers who have agreed to use Spyglass's software and services, which will lead to multiple revenue streams, and claims a significant time-to-market advantage. But, Spyglass expects it will take another few quarters before it sees the real impact in its results.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are still seeing 6- to 12-month lead times between when we form a relationship with the company and when we see deployment of those products,&quot; said Doug Colbeth, president and chief executive officer of Spyglass.</p>
<p>&quot;While we think this market is very real, we think the major deployments, which is where we would see the major run-time royalties...is a late 1997, (early) '98 type of phenomenon,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Vilchick said at that point he would expect the company to return to &quot;historical&quot; profitability.</p>
<p>In addition to investing in the device market, Spyglass said it is continuing to increase the size of its professional services group.</p>
<p>The group, which customizes and integrates Spyglass' technology into customer's products, totalled 25 at the end of December. It was half that size in October, the company said.</p>
<p>Colbeth said a typical initial software agreement means $200,000 to $250,000 in revenues for Spyglass and in about half of the initial transactions customers ask for professional services.</p>
<p>&quot;Professional services can actually equal the size of the initial transaction,&quot; Colbeth said.</p>
<p>((--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
