<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326119" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish IT share rally could be nearing its end.</title>
<headline>Swedish IT share rally could be nearing its end.</headline>
<byline>Birgitta Forsberg</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A rally in Swedish information technology (IT) shares could be nearing an end, even though the pace of new IT companies entering the bourse is continuing at a frantic rate, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment in the Nordic market is euphoric and shares are more than fully valued,&quot; an analyst said. &quot;I get frightened when I see how much shares have risen in the past month.&quot;</p>
<p>Although there is no index showing how much the sector has risen, analysts estimate it has outperformed the general index's 5.79 percent advance since the start of the year.</p>
<p>Last year, IT shares doubled in value, analysts said, outdoing a general index jump of 38 percent.</p>
<p>Now analysts say the sector could be overheating. Some expect the whole sector to slide, while others see investors becoming more selective.</p>
<p>With only a few IT shares on the bourse, investors hoping for substantial growth have been scrambling to lay their hands on them, pushing prices higher.</p>
<p>&quot;They are investing for the future when traditional computing will merge with media and television,&quot; Karl-Mikael Syding, analyst at Swedish bank Swedbank, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Last year 10 IT companies were listed on the bourse and another eight have said they are in the starting blocks.</p>
<p>Three of them, Alfaskop Partners AB, Office AB and Entra Data AB, announced on Tuesday they would seek listings.</p>
<p>A fourth, computer consulting company Sigma AB, will present a prospectus on Thursday for its February 21 introduction, an analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is understandable that the companies take the chance to introduce themselves on the bourse because they can get as much money that way as they could earn over 20 years,&quot; Syding said.</p>
<p>He said many IT companies had a price/earnings (p/e) ratio of 20. Syding was fairly optimistic about current price levels, but was cautious about further increases.</p>
<p>&quot;A bubble (which will burst) will be created sooner or later, but not yet,&quot; Syding said.</p>
<p>&quot;Those looking at the sector have lost the sense of correct valuation and they do not know when a bubble starts to build.&quot;</p>
<p>Regarding the newcomers, Entra looks almost fully valued with a p/e of 20 on 1997 profits, while posting a 12 percent profit margin in 1995, Syding said.</p>
<p>Alfaskop seems cheap at a p/e of about 12 but Office will be listed without the best bits.</p>
<p>Of the companies already listed, some analysts say they believe in WM-Data, which offers computer network building, software, eduction and support. But others said it was overvalued.</p>
<p>&quot;WM-Data's share should be 40 percent lower,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Other share prices should be cut by 50 percent, analysts said. Among this group is Verimation AB, a company making products which enable different computer brands to communicate, according to Syding.</p>
<p>He said, however, rival Frontec was too cheap.</p>
<p>&quot;While Verimation markets its product on its technical abilities, Frontec offers to solve a problem for companies with its product,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
