<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332298" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Sony in talks with Murdoch on satellite venture.</title>
<headline>Sony in talks with Murdoch on satellite venture.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sony Corp said on Friday it was in talks on joining Rupert Murdoch's Japanese satellite TV alliance, a move that analysts say would remake the electronics giant into an integrated multimedia company.</p>
<p>They said Sony would also give Murdoch's new broadcast venture an edge over its two rivals in what promises to be a heated battle in the Japanese media market.</p>
<p>&quot;Sony has long been seeking a chance to create synergies between hardware and software,&quot; said Takatoshi Yamamoto, analyst at Morgan Stanley Japan Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;Satellite broadcasting is one of the few areas which allow Sony to integrate its businesses, such as content -- films, music and videogames -- studio-use broadcasting equipment and home-use set-top boxes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sony, an entertainment and consumer electronics giant, said it was in talks with media tycoon Rupert Murdoch's News Corp and Softbank Corp to invest in their jointly owned venture Japan Sky Broadcasting Co, or JSkyB.</p>
<p>&quot;It is true that we consider JSkyB a possible investment target and are continuing negotiations on this,&quot; Sony said in a statement, adding that no final decision had been made.</p>
<p>A Softbank spokesman said the three are considering bringing Sony in as a shareholder in the venture as well as a content provider and a supplier of broadcasting equipment.</p>
<p>Softbank Corp is a computer software and publishing firm.</p>
<p>According to Nihon Keizai Shimbun reports on Friday, Sony hopes to take a one-third stake in JSkyB.</p>
<p>Sony has tried repeatedly to venture into satellite broadcasting in Japan and the United States, in order to secure distribution routes for its films, music and game software, but failed to obtain licenses due to regulatory barriers.</p>
<p>Sony, traditionally strong in broadcasting equipment technology and manufacturing, said earlier this week it would establish a new group company to pull together its broadcasting-related businesses.</p>
<p>Satellite broadcasting has become the hottest sector for consumer electronics manufacturers.</p>
<p>Matsushita Electric Industrial Co last year also approached Murdoch to discuss investments in JSkyB, an industry official said. Matsushita now owns a 15 percent stake in DirecTV, a company in the Hughes Electronics Corp group and a major rival of Murdoch's JSkyB.</p>
<p>Sony's participation in JSkyB would give the group an edge over rival operators, analysts say, when Japan's three multichannel satellite broadcasters begin battling head-to-head for viewers this spring.</p>
<p>JSkyB will start beaming 12 channels in April, increasing that number to 150 channels by April 1998.</p>
<p>Rival PerfecTV, a venture led by a consortium of leading Japanese trade houses, launched its service in October 1996 and has already acquired more than 100,000 subscribers. It will expand the service to 100 channels this spring from 62 at present.</p>
<p>And DirecTV, which brings together Matsushita, the powerful Mitsubishi conglomerate and Hughes, will start beaming 100 channels this autumn.</p>
<p>&quot;Sony is very good at dealing with content producers. With Sony's strong brand name, JSkyB will have an advantage over the others,&quot; said Tadashi Nishi, analyst at Sakura Institute of Research.</p>
<p>JSkyB and PerfecTV have agreed to use the same receiver and are considered to have a head start over DirecTV in the race for subscribers.</p>
<p>But some analysts believe the impact of Sony's participation in the race will be limited, as it is unlikely to stop supplying broadcasting content to JSkyB's rivals.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't think Sony's joining JSkyB would make it difficult for us to acquire content from Sony's entertainment units,&quot; said a spokesman at DirecTV.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
