<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333639" id="root" date="1997-01-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apple mulls closer Intel, Microsoft ties - paper.</title>
<headline>Apple mulls closer Intel, Microsoft ties - paper.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Struggling computer maker Apple Computer Co. is considering closer ties with semiconductor power Intel Corp and software giant Microsoft Corp., The New York Times reported Sunday.</p>
<p>Company executives told the newspaper Apple was weighing making a line of machines that run on Intel microprocessors. Apple computers now run on microprocessors made by Motorola Inc.</p>
<p>In addition, Microsoft Chairman Bill Gates visited Apple headquarters in Cupertino, Calif., in mid-January. The hourlong session was attended by Gates; Apple Chairman Gilbert Amelio; Steven Jobs, Apple's co-founder and head of NeXT Software Corp,., recently bought by Apple; and Ellen Hancock, Apple's chief technology officer.</p>
<p>The meeting covered other matters, but the subject of closer cooperation in the years ahead was on the agenda.</p>
<p>The Times, quoting people familiar with the meeting, said one item was a discussion of the possibility of Apple's licensing Windows NT, Microsoft's industrial-strength operating system for the corporate market.</p>
<p>Amelio was not directly quoted about possible alliances with Microsoft and Intel, Apple's longtime rivals.</p>
<p>However, he told the Times that within two or three years, &quot;I would like to have the most compatible personal computer in the industry, able to run more software than anyone -- period.&quot;</p>
<p>Amelio added, &quot;We're not in a world by ourselves. We have to be able to support the commodity technology standard.&quot;</p>
<p>Personal computers with Intel microprocessors and running on Microsoft operating systems overwhelmingly dominate the worldwide PC market.</p>
<p>Apple has been hit by declining sales, mounting losses and a falling stock price. The company on Jan 15 reported a loss of $120 million, or 96 cents a share, in its fiscal first quarter.</p>
<p>Apple predicts a return to profitability in the fiscal fourth quarter, which ends in September 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
