<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334005" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IBM's Lotus sees 18 mln users in '97. [CORRECTED 23:59 GMT]</title>
<headline>IBM's Lotus sees 18 mln users in '97. [CORRECTED 23:59 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>LAKE BUENA VISTA, Fla. 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top executives at Lotus Development Corp said that they expect the number of seats, or users, of its core Lotus Notes groupware software to grow to 18 million in 1997, up from a total of 9.5 million seats from 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;That's another 8.5 million incremental seats in 1997,&quot; said Mike Zisman, executive vice president of strategy for Lotus.  </p>
<p>The prediction, made at a conference here called Lotusphere, represents a substantial rise in the growth IBM is forecasting for its Lotus Notes franchise (corrects from &quot;....is scaled back from previous predictions made by Lotus and International Business Machines Corp executives, who predicted at the time of the IBM/Lotus merger that Lotus will have 20 million Notes seats by the end of 1997&quot;). </p>
<p>&quot;By contrast, a Lotus spokeswoman said it had sold nine million Notes seats by the end of 1996 and 12 million users of its of its cc:Mail electronic mail program, a simpler form of electronic mail often sold in conjunction with Notes.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The new 1997 estimate from IBM Lotus represents absolute growth of 8.5 million Notes seats by the end of 1997, excluding any additional cc:Mail users.&quot;</p>
<p>Still, Lotus executives and IBM chairman and chief executive officer Louis Gerstner, said that Lotus now has even more momentum, fueled in part by the positive customer reception to its new server software for Lotus Notes, called Domino, which was written entirely in Internet standards, to embrace the Internet.  </p>
<p>&quot;At this time last year, we were beginning to see some encouraging evidence that the merger was working,&quot; said Gerstner, referring to IBM's $3.5 billion acquisition of Lotus in 1995. &quot;Now a year later, I think the evidence is irrefutable...Notes seats have doubled again.&quot; Gerstner referred to Domino as the &quot;crown jewel&quot; in IBM's Internet strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;While some people in the press cannot get it straight, we are the world's largest software company.&quot;  </p>
<p>Lotus also announced many new products and previewed more pieces in its overall strategy to make Lotus Notes completely compatible with the Internet, including software called Domino.Broadcast, which will let corporate users of Lotus Notes deliver news headlines from PointCast, and corporate news, straight to a user's desktop, in the new model of &quot;pushing&quot; information to a user.</p>
<p>The company also previewed new software being developed for networked computers that was developed entirely in Sun Microsystems Inc's Java language, code-named Kona. Lotus also previewed what it said is code-named a Kona Desktop, a suite of applications, such as calendar, spreadsheet, and other applications, for a network computer, running on IBM's Network Station.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAKE BUENA VISTA, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
