<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="336194" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW-Sterling Software eyes Asia.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Sterling Software eyes Asia.</headline>
<byline>Angela Tan</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S-based Sterling Software sees Asia's contribution to its total revenue growing to 20-25 percent in the next three to five years against 17 percent presently, the group's Asia Pacific president said on Monday.</p>
<p>Sterling, ranked as one the largest software companies in the world, expects electronic commerce to propel its growth, James Johnson told Reuters after a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Asia currently contributes about 17 percent of the group's revenue. Over the next three to five years, we see rapid growth from outside the United States,&quot; Johnson said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are anticipating 20-25 percent growth from this region,&quot; Johnson said.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of this will come from the electronic commerce part. Right now, it is the fastest growing sector,&quot; he said, adding that electronic commerce presently contributes about 10 percent of the group's revenue in Asia Pacific.</p>
<p>The company, which also provides highly technical services for the U.S. federal government, posted US$400 million in revenue for the fiscal year ended September 30, 1996. This excluded earnings from Sterling Commerce, which was spun-off last year.  </p>
<p>Electronic commerce, where the internet is used to conduct business between companies, is seen growing at 38-40 percent in the United States and 68 percent in the international markets last year, Johonson said. Actual market worth was not available, company officials said.</p>
<p>Johnson was here to launch Sterling Software's electronic commerce operations in Singapore, its regional headquarters.</p>
<p>Acquisitions are the company's main growth strategy, Johnson said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking for companies to fit with our strategy.. Most of the growth will be through acquisitions,&quot; he said.??  </p>
<p>In Singapore and Malaysia, Sterling would develop electronic commerce through its new business partner, Network Integration Systems.</p>
<p>To date, the company has invested US$300,000-$400,000 in Singapore and was looking at a project with the National Computer Board which would add another US$400,000 in investments, said Ruth Connolly, Sterling's Asia Pacific vice president.  </p>
<p>The group, which derives about 25 percent of its business from U.S. government agencies, was unfazed by annual squeezes from cutbacks in U.S. defence spending, Johnson said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the slowest growing business for the group. Each year the federal government squeezes our margins a little bit but it is the business that has a lot of follow-on businesses,&quot; Johnson said.  </p>
<p>In Malaysia, the group is engaged in two projects with a large government organisation while in South Korea, it is involved in Korea Trade Network, a government project funded by the Korea Trade Association.</p>
<p>Plans in China and Hong Kong remain vague due to uncertainty over China's takeover of Hong Kong in July. But according to Sun Whye Mun, the group's regional manager for electronic commerce, Sterling &quot;is going into the markets with some partners but plans are not finalised yet&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703083)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
