<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33692" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Internet travel service launches new ticketing site.</title>
<headline>Internet travel service launches new ticketing site.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The full-service Internet travel agency Premier Travel said it will launch a new site on the World Wide Web on Wednesday to make it easy to surf the Internet for airline tickets.</p>
<p>Ken Orton, president of Preview Travel, said in an interview the company has already sold more than $5 million worth of airline tickets and vacation packages through its services on American Online Inc since May this year.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a utility built for consumers,&quot; Orton told Reuters, noting that the service aims to provide the travelling public with &quot;an unbiased look at what's available&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;People are voting with their credit cards,&quot; he added. &quot;People who know they want to buy an airway ticket want to go the shortest distance (to obtain it).&quot;</p>
<p>Up to now, Premier Travel has offered vacation packages and tickets through America Online, itself an investor in Premier with a stake of less than 20 percent of the travel agency, and on its Web site at  http://www.vacations.com.</p>
<p>The new service, at  http://www.reservations.com, enables customers to design their own travel plan, order tickets using their credit cards, and have them delivered within two days.</p>
<p>Orton noted this service largely revolved around specific details, such as fares and schedules, while its other holiday package-oriented businesses are geared to use multimedia capabilities to sell entire vacation deals.</p>
<p>The airline ticketing system will enable travellers to book tickets 24 hours a day, seven days a week, and enable them to store up to five different profiles with preferences, such as seating priorities, class of service and meal requests.</p>
<p>Individuals can keep separate profiles for business trips and for use with family members or when traveling alone.</p>
<p>Preview Travel said it has invested heavily in research and development to introduce the service both on the Web and on America Online, where it is available under the keyword &quot;reservations.&quot;</p>
<p>Orton said that as of September 18, it will become America Online's primary airline ticketing service, displacing EasySaabre, the electronic ticketing service pioneered by AMR Corp's American Airlines.</p>
<p>Orton said the company's existing online travel service has been averaging $50,000 to $100,000 in tickets daily, with great peaks in usage during last month's fare wars.</p>
<p>&quot;During the fare wars we did very large numbers,&quot; he said, noting the rush to buy tickets had aparently flooded airlines' own reservation agents with inquiries.</p>
<p>Although the company has online competition and is a long way from matching the size of sales by EasySaabre, which according to industry executives last year sold in excess of one million tickets worth an estimated $300 million, Orton said its technology has the capacity to exceed that amount.</p>
<p>&quot;We could get bigger than EasySaabre using our present architecture,&quot; Orton said, adding the company is also engaged in a co-promotional deal with Netscape Communications Corp to appear on Netscape's &quot;destinations&quot; button.</p>
<p>The Netscape home page is the most heavily-trafficked site on the World Wide Web multimedia section of the Internet.</p>
<p>Preview Travel is a 12-year-old company which has specialised in travel-related television programming and which began offering services on the Internet in 1995.</p>
<p>Investors in  the privately-held company include America Online, Landmark Communications, US West Corp's US WEST Interactive Services group and the Menlo Park-based venture capital firm Kleiner Perkins Caufield &amp; Byers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
