<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341067" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Strange ride through 'Obsidian' is anything but rocky.</title>
<headline>Strange ride through 'Obsidian' is anything but rocky.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Obsidian&quot; (SegaSoft, Windows, $60) is sold with the slogan &quot;the rules do not apply here.&quot; That's for sure. Not many games will let you walk up and down walls in your quest to save the planet.</p>
<p>That's only one of the delightful surprises in this fantasy adventure, which has lush artwork, creative puzzles and an engaging, nonviolent storyline.</p>
<p>A lot of other games have been marketed with the promise that it plays like the immensely popular &quot;Myst.&quot; &quot;Obsidian&quot; delivers.</p>
<p>The setting is the year 2066, an era when the world has nearly become polluted beyond habitation. You and your partner have developed a method for creating microscopic robots that are rapidly cleaning up the atmosphere. The protective ozone layer, for example, has been restored to 95 percent of its original levels in just two months.</p>
<p>While on vacation in a newly-cleaned forest, you discover a small chunk of obsidian that seems to have taken on a life of its own. The rock is growing at a fantastic rate, becoming a towering 50-foot black crystal cathedral in just three days.</p>
<p>While exploring the phenomenon, you and your partner are sucked inside the rock and sent to a world where bureaucracy isn't everything -- it's the only thing.</p>
<p>Soulless bureaucrats have been replaced by soulless robots with television screens for heads. The faces of the human bureaucrats simply appear on each screen, handing out largely useless information. &quot;I've taken the bureaucratic oath,&quot; one explains.</p>
<p>Your initial job is to arrange the repair of the ramp that the Bureau Chief tried to extend to welcome you. But before you can do that, you have to find the right form, get it pre-approved, and then get it approved by the Office of Immediate Action, where you're warned that they're a little behind in the work.</p>
<p>&quot;Come back in a year,&quot; the office director tells you. &quot;We'll take immediate action then.&quot;</p>
<p>It is a world reminiscent of Terry Gilliam's classic and bizarre 1985 movie &quot;Brazil.&quot;</p>
<p>That's just the beginning. There are three other fantastic worlds to explore -- one cold and mechanical, the second based in a huge junkyard, the final one light and expansive. In addition, the puzzles you have to solve to get through the game are set in their own surreal landscapes.</p>
<p>In one case, you're transported to a place where the surface is covered with strange cannon balls; you can shoot them at a distant tornado.</p>
<p>In another, you land on a world where the flexible limbs of a tree keep dipping down to touch glowing stakes in the ground. And there's the beach, where the size of the sand castle depends on how you approach it and the waves travel out of synch, which is a problem the player must correct.</p>
<p>You have to figure out what everything is, what you're supposed to do, and how to manipulate the environment to solve the puzzle. Some are maddeningly difficult. The good ones allow the answer to dawn on you as you play around.</p>
<p>You'll need a lot of computing power to enjoy this game. A Pentium 90 processor, at least 16 megabytes of RAM, a 4x-speed CD-ROM drive, 2 megabytes of VRAM, 16-bit video and audio cards and AWE32 are all strongly recommended. (The Macintosh version, due in a few months, requires a Power Mac 7100 with System 7.0.)</p>
<p>Ultimately, &quot;Obsidian&quot; becomes another cautionary tale about humans giving away too much power to their machines. The theme is old and worn. But the surreal ride through &quot;Obsidian&quot; is so much fun, you probably won't care.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Arthur's Reading Race&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $30) -- Living Book's third interactive storybook starring Arthur the aardvark has him challenging his little sister to a reading contest as they walk around town. Sis turns out to be a lot better than he expects. It's for ages 3 to 7.</p>
<p>&quot;Discworld II: Mortality Bytes!&quot; (Psygnosis, DOS/Windows95, $50) features the voice of Monty Python's Eric Idle and lets you play the role of Rincewind, the incompetent wizard who must bring back Death, who has disappeared and left everyone immortal. It's rated for ages 13 and older.</p>
<p>&quot;M.A.X.: Mechanized Assault &amp; Exploration&quot; (Interplay, DOS, $50) -- A battle strategy game where you have to colonise a planet and crush competing colonists. You can play as one of eight factions and use any of 50 pieces of equipment. It's for ages 13 and older. A Pentium 90 is recommended.</p>
<p>&quot;Orly's Draw-A-Story&quot; (Broderbund, Windows/Macintosh, $30) -- Designed for budding artists and writers age 5 to 10, this products has four stories and features pictures that talk to you when you colour them in. The coloured images then become part of the story.</p>
<p>&quot;SkyNet&quot; (Bethesda Softworks, DOS, $40) -- Join the resistance in a post-apocalyptic world where Terminator-style robots are the enemy. It features 17 weapons and over 20 robot enemies. It's rated for ages 17 and older.</p>
<p>&quot;SPQR: The Empire's Darkest Hour&quot; (GT Interactive, Windows95, $50) -- A role-playing game where you must determine who is plotting to destroy Rome. The game claims to provide insight into how Rome worked -- mechanically, economically, culturally and politically.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
