<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341136" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP shares fall ahead of 96 results. [CORRECTED 20:25 GMT]</title>
<headline>SAP shares fall ahead of 96 results. [CORRECTED 20:25 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Software developer SAP AG, once the darling of German technology shares, had analysts holding their breath on Wednesday as its shares tumbled six percent amid concerns about its year-end earnings report.</p>
<p>The report, due on Friday, would give investors their first look at SAP since it said in October that profit and sales growth unexpectedly slowed in the third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all waiting for the numbers in suspense,&quot; said Juergen Hackenberg, a Deutsche Morgen Grenfell analyst in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>SAP shares were the biggest decliners on the blue chip DAX index, with its actively-traded preference shares ending bourse trade down nine marks at 217.50 marks, while the broader market rose 0.33 percent.</p>
<p>SAP's preference shares weakened further in afternoon electronic dealings, falling 14.90 marks, or around six percent, to 217 marks. The company's common stock also fell six percent to 213 marks.</p>
<p>The Walldorf-based company, whose R/3 software is used by companies to keep track of accounting, purchasing, production and sales data, in October slashed its expectations for 1996 profit growth to 30 percent from previous 40 percent forecast.</p>
<p>The company was unable to explain the unexpected slowdown in growth and industry analysts began to wonder whether SAP's bubble had burst, slamming the shares which lost more than a quarter of their value in one day.</p>
<p>DG Bank (corrects from Hackenberg) forecast SAP's 1996 net income would rise to just under 500 million marks from 405 million marks in 1995 -- indicating even slower growth than the 30 percent rate SAP predicted.</p>
<p>Hackenberg forecast net income of 537 million marks, just over the 30 percent outlook, but other analysts shared the DG Bank view (corrects Hackenberg forecast). Many were revising their forecasts, saying it was unclear how SAP fared in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm insecure about it,&quot; said one London-based analyst who follows SAP. &quot;I'm not entirely happy with what the company might say.&quot;</p>
<p>The market for so-called &quot;client/server&quot; software such as R/3 is still growing rapidly, driven by the use of Internet technology in company communications networks, and SAP still holds a &quot;considerable&quot; lead over its competitors, Hackenberg said.</p>
<p>But some smaller client/server developers such as PeopleSoft Inc. of the United States and Baan Co NV of the Netherlands were now growing much faster than SAP and providing investors with greater opportunities.</p>
<p>Baan on Wednesday said 1996 sales leaped 79 percent to $387.96 million while net income soared 137 percent to $36.33 million. Baan should continue to grow substantially in 1997 and 1998, a recent Salomon Brothers report said.</p>
<p>PeopleSoft, whose sales rose 95 percent in the first three quarters of 1996, was expected to release year-end results in the next several days.</p>
<p>Analysts said they were also concerned Baan and PeopleSoft had narrowed SAP's technological lead, especially since SAP has been slow to add features that let companies offer information over the Internet.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
