<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341970" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Netscape counts on user upgrades in 1997.</title>
<headline>Netscape counts on user upgrades in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Netscape Communications Corp executives said they have seeded the market with some 50 million browser users and aim to attract these customers to upgrade to new products in 1997.</p>
<p>Mike Homer, Netscape's vice president of marketing, said in a conference call the company is targeting &quot;a very big opportunity that we've seeded that we can now harvest&quot; by getting customers to upgrade to its newest products this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the market opportunity is enormous,&quot; Netscape President and CEO James Barksdale said after the company reported 1996 results in-line with analyst estimates.</p>
<p>The executives said they expect to encourage their installed base of Internet browser software users to upgrade to the Communicator product which is now in beta testing and will formally begin selling in the second quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>The company also plans further server software upgrades.</p>
<p>In addition to bootstrapping into the new business from their dominant browser position, Netscape's Homer also noted the company has already &quot;slingshot&quot; itself past International Business Machines Corp's Lotus Development Corp in supplying electronic mail capabilities.</p>
<p>Homer said Netscape's estimate that it has 12 million users of its electronic mail feature on Netscape Navigator was already beyond an estimated nine million for Lotus.</p>
<p>Netscape CFO Peter Currie said while the company does not make financial projections, he acknowledged that &quot;it's harder to grow the same percentage growth rates as we showed early in 1996, just because the base of business has grown.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Do we think we're going to grow? Yes,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>For all of 1996, the company's revenues grew by more than four-fold from the previous year, to $346.3 million.</p>
<p>Currie said it was difficult for Netscape, which completed its initial offering in August 1995, to achieve financial predictability at this point in its life because it is &quot;still a relatively new company with a relatively new product line creating a new segment of the industry.&quot;</p>
<p>Nevertheless, he repeated market predictions that industry sales of Internet-related products and services will rise to somewhere on the order of $10 billion in the year 2000 and said Netscape was &quot;well positioned&quot; in this market.</p>
<p>Barksdale said Netscape must continue to concentrate on weaknesses such as support for developers and its sales channel and building more indirect sales in the U.S. market -- this figure was relatively flat in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Homer said Netscape still estimates it has &quot;better than 75 percent&quot; of the browser market, despite stiff competition on Windows 95 and Windows NT by Microsoft Corp  MSFT.O.</p>
<p>The Netscape executives said a study by Zona Research and released before Netscape's results on Tuesday was skewed in favor of rival Microsoft because it contained a disproportionate number of Windows 95 users.</p>
<p>That study found Netscape's share of users for whom it is the primary browser had slipped to 70 percent from 83 percent in August, while Microsoft's Internet Explorer gained in share to 28 prcent compared with 8 percent in August.</p>
<p>Homer said Netscape's Web home page at the end of the fourth quarter was receiving some 120 million hits a day, some six times more than earlier in the year and one continued sign of interest in its products.</p>
<p>Goldman Sachs analyst Michael Parekh said Netscape's fourth quarter result should bring &quot;a sigh of relief&quot; to investors who had expected a negative bombshell, and he expects a strong product portfolio in the second half.</p>
<p>Currie said concerns raised earlier this month by one analyst that Netscape may have completed up to five percent of last quarter's business on New Year's Eve was overstated.</p>
<p>&quot;The business is back-end loaded in the quarter...and I think it has been for all enterprise software companies.&quot; he said. But he said only one deal was completed on the last day of 1996, representing about one percent of fourth quarter sales.</p>
<p>-- Palo Alto Bureau +1 415 846 5400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
