<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34676" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Murdoch seeks to tie up with PerfecTV in Japan.</title>
<headline>Murdoch seeks to tie up with PerfecTV in Japan.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's News Corp, planning a multi-channel digital satellite broadcasting service in Japan to start next year, hopes to tie up with Japanese rival PerfecTV, a News spokeswoman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>She quoted visiting media tycoon Rupert Murdoch, chairman of News Corp, as saying he hoped to allow Japanese viewers to access both providers' satellite services through a single receiver and dish.</p>
<p>Murdoch revealed the plan in press interviews, she said.</p>
<p>News plans to offer a 150-channel JSkyB service in Japan through a joint venture with Softbank Corp.</p>
<p>The joint venture is expected to be granted a licence for a TV service using the JCSAT-3 satellite this autumn. The service is expected to start late next year.</p>
<p>The PerfecTV group, headed by Itochu Corp, will launch Japan's first digital satellite broadcasting service in October. It plans to offer a 60-channel service and aims to acquire 300,000 subscribers in the initial year.</p>
<p>A PerfecTV spokeswoman said the company had not yet received such a request from News, but added that the proposed tie-up was not impossible.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is no official request yet. But the (tie-up) would benefit our subscribers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Analysts say News is seeking to link up with PerfecTV because of the large number of existing terrestrial TV channels in Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is a bit crowded and demand for pay-per-view satellite TVs may be slow for a while,&quot; said an industry official.</p>
<p>JSkyB will be followed by DirecTV, a unit of Hughes Electronics Corp, which plans to launch 100-channel digital satellite broadcasting in Japan in 1997.</p>
<p>The media tycoon's entry into Japan's broadcasting and media market has stirred controversy in the industry, normally immune to realignments and foreign offensives.</p>
<p>Murdoch earlier this week sought to appoint John McBride, head of News Corp's Japan unit, as an executive of its affiliate Asahi National Broadcasting.</p>
<p>But the request was reportedly rejected on the grounds that Japanese law forbids foreigners from assuming executive posts at Japanese broadcasting companies.  </p>
<p>News and Softbank jointly acquired Japanese media company Obunsha Media for 41.75 billion yen ($383 million). Obunsha has a 21.4 percent stake in Asahi National Broadcasting Co, known as TV Asahi.</p>
<p>The Asahi Shimbun group is the largest shareholder in TV Asahi, holding a 38.3 percent stake in the broadcaster. ($1=109 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
