<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348966" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP stock soars on 1996 earnings surprise.</title>
<headline>SAP stock soars on 1996 earnings surprise.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in German software developer SAP AG leapt more than 13 percent in early trading on Friday after the company revealed higher-than-expected results for 1996.</p>
<p>SAP preferred shares, which last year joined the DAX-30 index, were up some 13 percent at 251.90 marks at 0840 GMT, outstripping by far the IBIS DAX index, which was up 0.6 percent at 3,036.76 points.</p>
<p>Its common stock was up 12 percent at 245.20 marks.</p>
<p>&quot;Those were tremendous figures,&quot; said a Munich trader. &quot;They gave the market a wonderful boost this morning.&quot;</p>
<p>SAP reported a 40 percent rise in its 1996 net profit to 567 million marks and said sales rose 38 percent to 3.72 billion marks, surpassing its own forecast for 30 percent sales growth.</p>
<p>Analysts said the company probably gained on the dollar's recent strength and redoubled sales efforts in the fourth quarter after lowering its forecasts in October.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar is certainly a key point because their sales are strong overseas,&quot; said Peter Thilo Hasler, a Vereinsbank Research analyst in Munich.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure they did everything they could in the fourth quarter to increase results, too.&quot;</p>
<p>SAP shares had come under heavy pressure earlier this week amid fears that the company would not even meet its own sales forecasts for 1996.</p>
<p>Hasler said he recently cut his recommendation on SAP to below average from market neutral and said he planned to keep that recommendation.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
