<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="352754" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Nintendo says no impact in software shift.</title>
<headline>Nintendo says no impact in software shift.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nintendo Co Ltd has seen virtually no impact on its business from a shift in which makers of two popular games for its video game machines are providing the games to rival Sony Corp for its PlayStation, Nintendo president Hiroshi Yamauchi told a news conference on Monday.</p>
<p>He also said shipments of the Nintendo 64 player in Japan amounted to 1.85 million units from its launch in June until January, and an estimated 130,000 to 140,000 units remained at retailers in Japan.</p>
<p>He said actual sales in Japan therefore amounted to 1.7 million units as of the end of the Christmas season.  </p>
<p>The 64-bit Nintendo machine was sold out in the U.S. market, where the company had shipped 2.14 million units since its launch at the end of September.</p>
<p>Asked if there was any impact on its business from a shift by software makers to make best-selling games compatible with Sony's rival PlayStation players, Yamauchi said there was &quot;virtually no impact on Nintendo's business&quot; from the moves.</p>
<p>The games are &quot;Dragon Quest&quot;, made by Enix Corp, and &quot;Final Fantasy&quot;, made by Square Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Although the maker of Dragon Quest said it would start selling the new version of the game in spring 1999, nobody was sure when the software would actually be launched or whether the new version would prove more popular than existing ones, Yamauchi said.</p>
<p>He predicted there would be &quot;an important turning point&quot; next year for 32-bit players using CD-ROMs. Such machines had already shown their limitations when it came to development of new ideas for games, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
