<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354547" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Microsoft's Gates &quot;confused&quot; by Apple strategy. [CORRECTED 22:30 GMT]</title>
<headline>Microsoft's Gates &quot;confused&quot; by Apple strategy. [CORRECTED 22:30 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Mark John</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft chairman Bill Gates on Tuesday said he wanted to maintain existing ties with struggling Apple Computer but said he was confused by its strategy for its core computer technology.</p>
<p>Gates, in Germany for a new product launch, moreover said he was not devoting time to considering how the two companies might collaborate more closely, thus appearing to pour cold water on recent speculation of closer links between the two.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very interested in continuing to work with Apple as we have done through history. But I am confused by the Apple operating system strategy...and have decided not to worry about the future (in this respect),&quot; Gates said.</p>
<p>Last week the New York Times reported that Apple, which in January (corrects from &quot;earlier this month&quot;) reported a $120 million first-quarter loss, was considering forging closer ties with the software giant and its semiconductor-maker ally, Intel Corp.</p>
<p>It said that Gates had visited Apple headquarters in Cupertino, California, earlier this month and had held an hour-long meeting with Apple chairman Gilbert Amelio, and Apple co-founder Steven Jobs.</p>
<p>Gates confirmed that he had met Jobs since the recent purchase by Apple of Jobs' NeXT Software Corp firm, but did not say what had been discussed at any meetings.</p>
<p>He said that a recent deal between Microsoft and Apple under which Microsoft's Office software product was sold in Europe as a package with Apple's Macintosh computers had produced &quot;sales beyond expectations&quot;.</p>
<p>But he said that the situation facing Apple, struggling to maintain sales against the domination of the Microsoft-Intel standard in the world personal computer market, was now &quot;very challenging&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;People like Apple, and would like them to succeed. But that doesn't mean they will succeed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Apple's Amelio was quoted in the New York Times as saying he wanted Apple to be producing &quot;the most compatible personal computer in the industry&quot; within two to three years, supporting what he called the &quot;commodity technology standard&quot;.</p>
<p>Such a goal is in direct contrast to Apple's former aim of providing an alternative to the so-called &quot;WinTel&quot; combination of Microsoft Windows software on Intel-based computers.</p>
<p>Speculation has been mounting that Apple will announce a major shake-up of its business, with sources close to the company saying that could entail a major round of job cuts and a concentration on a core businesses.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal on Monday said people within the company believe Apple could sell key units, including its Newton hand-held computer unit and some of its software development operations.</p>
<p>Gates was in Frankfurt to present the newly-launched release 5.0 version of its Exchange Server messaging system for computers.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
