<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35486" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Microsoft in alliance with India's TCS.</title>
<headline>Microsoft in alliance with India's TCS.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. on Thursday announced a strategic alliance with India's Tata Consultancy Services (TCS), making TCS its premier consulting partner.</p>
<p>&quot;TCS will be one of the prime engines of Microsoft products,&quot; Sanjay Parthasarathy, Microsoft's regional director for the Indian subcontinent, told reporters.</p>
<p>Microsoft Corporation India Pvt. Ltd is a fully-owned subsidiary of the US-based Microsoft Corporation.</p>
<p>&quot;India has the potential to be a worldwide leader in software development and value added services,&quot; Parthasarathy said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very excited about our partnership with Microsoft,&quot; said S. Ramadorai, TCS's chief executive officer.</p>
<p>TCS is India's largest information technology consulting organisation. TCS will establish a consulting group to focus on Microsoft technologies and products, officials said.</p>
<p>Microsoft in turn will provide TCS Consultants with extensive training and early access to Microsoft products still in the testing stage.</p>
<p>&quot;In short, what we mean by this alliance is leveraging mutual strengths for customer products,&quot; TCS's Ramadorai said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
