<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355326" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP down as new share placement begins.</title>
<headline>SAP down as new share placement begins.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in German computer software maker SAP AG slipped about three percent on Tuesday as a consortium announced details for a controversial share placement valued at nearly 900 million marks ($548.5 million).</p>
<p>Union Bank of Switzerland and Morgan Stanley said they were offering 3.54 million ordinary shares in SAP -- one of the world's five top software groups - that were once held by SAP co-founder Hans-Werner Hector, who resigned in late 1996.</p>
<p>The banks announced the book-building period for the offering began on Monday and will end on Thursday, putting pressure on SAP shares which ended bourse trade down 7.30 marks at 243.20 marks.</p>
<p>The offering is scheduled to include three million shares, with the balance of 540,000 shares held for oversubscription. They represent about 5.7 percent of the 61 million ordinary shares in SAP, which also has 42 million preference shares.</p>
<p>The shares to be offered are currently held by the Eugenia Trust, which are among the shares bought from Hector in early 1996.</p>
<p>Hector sold his 11.2 percent stake in SAP last year to the trust fund and quit the supervisory board in December after a long-running dispute with SAP Chairman Dietmar Hopp.</p>
<p>Hector accused Hopp of not listening to dissenting opinions, prompting him to sell the stake despite criticism of the move by top SAP officials.</p>
<p>The share transfer and sale has been viewed by SAP as threatening the grip the four remaining founders of SAP have by bringing joint ownership below a 74 percent floor specified in a agreement in which their voting rights were pooled.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.640 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
