<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356602" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Microsoft opens two new offices in Africa.</title>
<headline>Microsoft opens two new offices in Africa.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp said on Wednesday it had opened two new offices in east and west Africa as part of its expansion drive on the continent.</p>
<p>The offices were opened in December and January in Abidjan, Ivory Coast and Nairobi, Kenya and Microsoft Regional Africa managing director Rob Katz said it had cost &quot;hundreds of thousands of rands&quot;.</p>
<p>Katz said it was Microsoft policy not to reveal figures for individual subsidiaries.</p>
<p>&quot;We have opened two new offices in Abidjan and Nairobi. This shows that Microsoft is not a short-term organisation but is committed to the region,&quot; Katz told a news conference.</p>
<p>Kenya and Ivory Coast were two of the most developed countries in terms of infrastructure, Katz said.</p>
<p>He said it was hoped that the offices would grow into full subsidiaries with time, offering the full level of product support services.</p>
<p>&quot;Africa is the last developing region in the world. We hope to have 10 to 20 new sales offices in Africa by the year 2000,&quot; business manager for Regional Africa Phil Allcock said.</p>
<p>Revenue generated in Regional Africa -- Africa south of the Sahara desert excluding South Africa and including the Indian Ocean Islands -- grew to 20 percent of total Africa revenue in 1996 from one percent in 1993.</p>
<p>Total revenue from Regional Africa represented less than one percent of total Microsoft revenue, Katz said.</p>
<p>Microsoft opened its South Africa office in 1992 with a view to using it as a base to expand into Africa south of the Sahara.</p>
<p>Allcock said part of the problems experienced in entering Africa were high excise duties ranging from 15 to 40 percent leading to pirating of software and poor communication infrastructure.</p>
<p>Katz said they saw Africa in the same league in 10 years with east Asian countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We are expecting Africa to be our next big market. The business opportunities there are untapped and require 'hands on' management to understand the market dynamics of each country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Charles Phahlane, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
