<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357504" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - D.Telekom, Netscape target German businesses.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - D.Telekom, Netscape target German businesses.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Telekom AG, broadening its relationship with Internet software maker Netscape Communications Corp, plans to expand access to the global computer network and develop new services for businesses, company officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Expanding an existing agreement to distribute Netscape's popular &quot;browser&quot; for the World Wide Web, the graphical part of the Internet, Deutsche Telekom said it would adopt the entire range of Netscape products to develop corporate networks based on Internet technology, also known as intranets.</p>
<p>&quot;Through the cooperation with Netscape we are expanding the spectrum of our offering in the area of the Internet and intranets and ensure that all our business customers receive solutions tailored to their needs,&quot; said Herbert May, Deutsche Telekom board member in charge of enterprise customers.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom has distributed over 10 million copies of Netscape's popular Navigator browser in succeeding versions to the 1.4 million subscribers of its online service T-Online, the largest in Germany.</p>
<p>Under the new agreement, Telekom would offer the entire range of Netscape software products both for those viewing content on the Internet or a company's intranet and Internet publishing software for servers.</p>
<p>T-Online subscribers will now be given the new 4.0 version of Netscape's browser, now called Communicator becasue it adds applications to enhance communcating over computer networks. Telekom will also use Netscape SuiteSpot server and local area network products.</p>
<p>Netscape has similar agreements, though it says not as far-reaching, with around 19 European telecommunications companies. It generates around 22 percent of its worldwide sales in Europe.</p>
<p>Jim Clark, chairman and founder of Netscape, said the company commands around 70 percent of the browser market and 30 percent of the Internet server market.</p>
<p>After the Internet explosion of the past two years, the next phase of development of the global network will be enhanced communication over computer networks between companies and their customers and suppliers.</p>
<p>&quot;Netscape's strategy is to develop the networked enterprise as a primary force in 1997,&quot; he said. &quot;We think companies like Deutsche Telekom are the best-placed to offer these services because they own the networks.&quot;</p>
<p>While German businesses have been slow to adopt Internet technology and use e-mail, recently-listed Deutsche Telekom has begun aggressively pursuing an Internet strategy and is now targeting over 1,000 companies that use its T-Online for their internal communications to transform these to intranets.</p>
<p>&quot;Telekom is the biggest and most aggressive telco offering Internet services and has grasped this more quickly than many telecoms companies in the world,&quot; said Netscape's Clark.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom's relationship with Netscape, while not intended to involve any capital investment, could deepen further in the coming months.</p>
<p>Netscape is not only providing software. It will also assist Telekom to develop Internet applications for businesses and T-Online is developing a new version of its software that will be tightly integrated with Netscape software.</p>
<p>&quot;Could we just use the Netscape browser? It is not decided yet just how the new software version will look,&quot; said T-Online managing director Wolfgang Keuntje.</p>
<p>Keuntje said the company would install a second high-speed Internet connection to the United States in the next few months and said the service aimed to have two million subscribers by the end of the year.</p>
<p>He would not comment on T-Online earnings, saying only: &quot;We are not making a loss.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
