<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370285" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apple, Reebok top CalPERS' list of underperformers.</title>
<headline>Apple, Reebok top CalPERS' list of underperformers.</headline>
<dateline>SACRAMENTO, Calif. 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Apple Computer Inc and Reebok International Ltd topped the California Public Employees' Retirement System's closely watched list of financial laggards released Tuesday.</p>
<p>CalPERS, the nation's largest public  pension fund, vowed that the boards of the 10 companies appearing on its 1997 list could face a fight for re-election in proxy fights if they do not significantly improve their performance.</p>
<p>&quot;We are prepared to vote against a corporation's entire board and sponsor proxy proposals if needed changes aren't made,&quot; said Kayla Gillan, general counsel for CalPERS, which manages $108 billion in assets.</p>
<p>In recent years, companies appearing on CalPERS' list have been targets of fierce corporate governance fights and board shakeups. CalPERS' shareholder activism often has led to better stock performance by the targeted companies, recent studies have found.</p>
<p>CalPERS said Tuesday it believes Apple's top management &quot;lacks experience in the personal computer business,&quot; and is paid too much in light of huge financial losses and layoffs.</p>
<p>Reebok, the nation's second-largest sneaker maker, made the list because of a &quot;financial freefall.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Despite a recent upswing in the company's stock price, CalPERS is concerned that Reebok's management has operated with insufficient accountability to the board...,&quot; CalPERS said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear that these companies have lost their competitive edge and without intervening could emerge as financial deadweight compared to their industry peers,&quot; William Crist, president of the CalPERS board of administration, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Other companies appearing on the list this year include: software companies Novell Inc and Sybase Inc ; Stride Rite Corp ; Bassett Furniture Industries Inc; grocery distributor Fleming Cos Inc ; Rollins Environmental Services Inc ; Summit Technology Inc; and Sensormatic Electronic Corp.</p>
<p>Last week, CalPERS voted against Apple's board of directors at its shareholder meeting. CalPERS said two or more of Apple's directors sit on four or more boards and personal stock ownership is significantly low among most directors.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been in discussions with CalPERS and we plan to meet with them to discuss their concerns,&quot; said Nancy Paxton, Apple's corporate spokeswoman. She declined to comment further.</p>
<p>Stride Rite, Bassett Furniture and Rollins Environmental are on the poor performers' list for the second year in a row. CalPERS has requested meetings with each of the company's independent directors to discuss their performance, the fund said.</p>
<p>If the companies fail to cooperate, the retirement system said it would use &quot;aggressive means&quot; to improve performance, such as voting against directors and filing shareholder proposals.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I46700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SACRAMENTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
