<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370676" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Dassault Systemes rallies on results.</title>
<headline>Dassault Systemes rallies on results.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Dassault Systemes rose more than 10 percent on Tuesday after the specialist in computer assisted design and manufacturing reported a 55 percent jump in net income to 342.5 million francs for 1996.</p>
<p>The stock was up 25 francs at 335 at 1400 GMT, and analysts said the rally was justified given the improvement expected in Dassault Systemes' operating margins.</p>
<p>Several analysts said they expected to raise their 1997 and 1998 earnings estimates for the group after an analysts' meeting held on Tuesday morning.  </p>
<p>&quot;When it first listed shares on the bourse, the company set a target of between 33 and 36 percent for its operating margin in the medium term, compared with 30.3 percent in 1995. This objective was reached in 1996. The company has raised its objectives again, and is thinking in the medium term of heading toward 50 percent,&quot; brokerage Oddo said.</p>
<p>Oddo raised its earnings per share (EPS) estimates for Dassault Systemes to 8.20 francs for 1997, from 7.50 francs previously, and to 9.90 francs for 1998 from 9.20.</p>
<p>&quot;The currently evalution is not euphoric. It's close to that of a company like Microsoft and that's fully justified,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Analyst Pascal Mathieu at CCF Elysees Bourse said he expected to raise his earnings estimates for Dassault Systemes. &quot;The tone is very optimistic. The forecasts are very positive both for sales growth and margins. It's a good share,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another analyst, however, said he was remaining neutral on the share, which he said was trading at 27 times 1998 earnings estimates.</p>
<p>&quot;The firm has a 75 percent premium relative to the market and is as expensive, if not more, than its U.S. rival Parametric Technology corp,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
