<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371090" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: FEATURE - Kids spark computer sale boom in China.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Kids spark computer sale boom in China.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese parents, notoriously indulgent of the one child that they are allowed, have sparked a boom in the sales of home computers to both educate and amuse their &quot;little emperors&quot;.</p>
<p>Computer retailers in Shanghai say sales have doubled over the past year thanks to falling costs, the rapidly rising incomes of middle class couples and the increasingly easy-to-use and Chinese language-friendly software available.</p>
<p>&quot;We bought a personal computer recently because it's the trend, but also for him,&quot; said a shopper at a computer plaza in Shanghai's city centre, pointing a thumb at his young teenage son.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a skill for when he enters the work world,&quot; the man added.</p>
<p>A MUST-HAVE SKILL</p>
<p>Doting parents buy the expensive machines with a sense that computers are the future and that their children must know how to use one to succeed, said Qiu Debin, the sales manager for Legend computers, China's largest PC manufacturer.</p>
<p>&quot;People believe there are two must-have skills in the job market -- foreign languages and computers,&quot; Qiu said. &quot;Many people think: 'I must work a little harder for my child, because if he doesn't know how to use computers, he's going to have a difficult time in the future.'&quot;</p>
<p>Sales of PCs in China are estimated to have totalled around 1.8 million last year, according to official estimates.</p>
<p>Microsoft Corp founder Bill Gates on a visit to Shanghai last year said China was possibly already the seventh biggest market for computers in the world and growing fast.</p>
<p>&quot;This sudden growth doesn't come from professionals, it comes from regular families,&quot; said Qian Junyong, Shanghai sales manager for Compaq</p>
<p>The boom is possible because of rapidly increasing personal incomes in China.</p>
<p>Annual wages in Shanghai averaged 28.3 percent growth per year between 1991 and 1995, according to official statistics. A white-collar office worker now earns around 5,000 yuan ($600) a month.</p>
<p>So the 10,000 yuan price for a name-brand PC &quot;is no longer an astronomical figure for many families,&quot; said Qiu.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that people have only one child, parents are paying more attention to what's going on in their children's heads,&quot; said Zheng Xunhua, an engineer at a PC shop.</p>
<p>The growing variety of Chinese software -- about 98 percent of it pirated, according to U.S. estimates -- is also making computers more accessible to beginners, Zheng said.</p>
<p>Most of the computers sold in China are pre-loaded with the Chinese version of Microsoft's Windows 95 operating system, launched in March 1996.</p>
<p>WHITE-HOT COMPETITION</p>
<p>Zheng said PC sales started to really take off in the second half of last year, and that the battle between domestic and foreign computer makers had become very fierce.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition is white-hot,&quot; said Legend's Qiu. &quot;We want to grab as much market share as possible while the market is still developing by holding down profits.&quot;</p>
<p>Xinhua news agency reported recently that Legend lowered its prices four times in 1996, forcing Compaq to follow suit.</p>
<p>Domestic producers have the upper hand in the battle for the China home computer market, industry people say.</p>
<p>&quot;The technology has become so public and transparent that domestic computers are now not much worse than imported ones,&quot; said Legend's sales manager Qiu.</p>
<p>Domestically made computers accounted for 56 percent of the China market in 1996, up from 35 percent in 1995, according to the official media.</p>
<p>&quot;People no longer take IBM as the standard,&quot; said Qiu. &quot;In the past, if you mentioned personal computers, people would say 'Oh, IBM.' They don't have this idea any more.&quot;</p>
<p>Compaq's Qian gave three reasons why locally made computers had an advantage: &quot;First, their prices are lower. Second, their performance is adequate for family users, Third, their distribution can outreach Compaq.&quot;</p>
<p>ROOM TO EXPAND</p>
<p>Shanghai, with its relatively high incomes and education levels, is leading China's home computer revolution, but retailers expect it to spread to other parts of the country quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still a lot of room to expand in the next two or three years. said Legend's Qiu. &quot;Ownership is still low compared to other countries.&quot;</p>
<p>Compaq's Qian also predicted long-term growth.</p>
<p>&quot;This trend will definitely continue, and not just for one or two more years, but a long time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
