<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371424" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Telmex busy as stock rallies.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Telmex busy as stock rallies.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telfonos de Mexico (Telmex) February 40 calls highlighted individual equity option trading Wednesday, attracting heavy volume as the shares broke through that strike price.</p>
<p>By 1400 CST/2000 GMT, the Telmex February 40 call traded a total of 13,610 contracts, the bulk of which crossed on the American Stock Exchange (AMEX).</p>
<p>Telmex options trade on the AMEX and the Chicago Board Options Exchange.</p>
<p>Telmex shares, extending Tuesday's rebound, were ahead 1-1/2 at 40-1/2, their session high.  </p>
<p>On the New York Stock Exchange, Telmex was the most active issue, with more than 4.9 million shares changing hands. Consolidated volume topped 5.4 million.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Telmex shares fell nearly a point before rebounding to close a point higher at 39.</p>
<p>The stock was up despite reporting disappointing earnings on Tuesday, American Depositary Receipt (ADR) traders said.</p>
<p>Harrison Roth, senior options strategist at Cowen &amp; Co, said the stock's ability to crack the 40 strike price contributed to the heavy options volume at that strike.  </p>
<p>The Telmex February 40 call had open interest of 24,537 contracts. More than 4,200 positions were closed on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;They've been liquidating those (positions) over the past four days, but there's still such a huge amount that it still was a concern,&quot; Joseph Sunderman, an analyst at Investment Research Institute in Cincinnati, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Now the stock's been able to penetrate through that level, which is a healthy sign for the stock,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that a key will be to see how much of Wednesday's volume is from positions being closed out as opposed to new positions being opened.  </p>
<p>Sunderman said the Telmex February 40 calls continue to have one of the lowest volatilities among other Telmex options, which suggests most investors were exiting positions.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at other strikes, the March 40 (call) has a lot of volume and slightly higher implied volatility than the February 40,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're also seeing a lot more trades going off near the ask, so that looks like new positions being opened.&quot;</p>
<p>The March 40 calls traded a total of 3,420 contracts.</p>
<p>In other action, an investor bought back DuPont Co July 90 calls and sold the January 1998 80 calls, Roth said.  </p>
<p>Each of those two options traded 3,820 contracts. The investor bought back the July 90 calls at 22-1/4 and sold the LEAP (long term equity anticipation securities) January 80 call at 32-7/8.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the Learning Co Inc February 15 put traded about 2,600 contracts and the March 12-1/2 traded about 2,860.</p>
<p>Roth said it appeared an investor bought the February 15 puts and sold the March 12-1/2s. The February 15s were trading at 4-7/8 and the March 12-1/2s at 2-1/2.</p>
<p>((-- G. Crawford, 312 408-8750/Email: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
