<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376651" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Geoworks to acquire UK's Eden for $30 mln.</title>
<headline>Geoworks to acquire UK's Eden for $30 mln.</headline>
<dateline>ALAMEDA, Calif. 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mobile telecoms software provider Geoworks said it will buy the privately-held U.K. mobile communications systems company Eden Group Ltd. in an all-stock transaction valued at around $30 million.</p>
<p>Geoworks said in conjunction with the deal it will issue 1.28 million new shares of common stock, a roughly 9 percent increase in its shares outstanding to 15.4 million shares.</p>
<p>Geoworks Chief Executive Gordon Mayer told Reuters the deal will be accretive to earnings in 12 to 18 months, and that the company will continue to weigh further acquisition prospects.  </p>
<p>&quot;The reason we're doing this is we believe it accelerates our business model as we look out 12 months from now,&quot; he said in an interview embargoed for completion of the deal, which he said would be accretive to earnings &quot;in four to six quarters.&quot;</p>
<p>Manchester-based Eden, which was founded in 1989 and now has 33 employees, develops software for handheld consumer appliances, with a special focus on compactness and low memory, requirements which are key to mobile communications.</p>
<p>Geoworks has been pushing to design software for smart phone systems both for use on handsets, where Eden's products are positioned, and on the server side of the market.</p>
<p>Mayer said Eden's software would firm up its handset market position when the companies' product lines were combined.</p>
<p>&quot;We will incorporate (Eden's operating system) into our offering,&quot; Mayer said. &quot;This does a good job of solidifying and accelerating our software for the handset manufacturers.&quot;</p>
<p>Geoworks has licensed its GEOS operating system to Nokia, Ericsson Telefonaktiebolog, NEC NEC Corp, Toshiba Corp, Hewlett-Packard Co, Brother International Corp, and Canon Inc's Canon Business Machines.</p>
<p>Eden's founder, David Crisp, will be appointed to the newly created position of vice president and general manager of Geoworks Europe, which will be a wholly-owned subsidiary.</p>
<p>Geoworks said it expected the deal to close in the current quarter, ended March 31. Geoworks shares closed down 50 cents to 22-1/2 in trading on the Nasdaq market on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It gives us an immediate European presence,&quot; said Mayer. &quot;We want more European partners. Secondly, our (existing) European partners are working on more designs.&quot;</p>
<p>Geoworks' current European partnerships had been on the handset side, he said, and Geoworks also wanted to expand operating relationships on the network management side.</p>
<p>Mayer said Eden gave it closer physical access to the world's largest installed base of digital cellular phones, in Europe, and the UK company also had major Japanese equipment makers as customers. He declined to identify these, however.</p>
<p>But he said the company would continue to look at acquisitions, including ones that would concentrate on management of the network, or so-called server products for managing the systems on which smart phones operate.</p>
<p>&quot;I think because we had the opportunity to supply content and services through cellular operators to people that own these handsets, we think there may be other opportunities, acquisition opportunities, on the server side,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mayer cited industry estimates predicting more than 150 million smart phone units by 2001, compared with just 50 million conventional cellular phones. This compares with 90 million projected for 1997, primarily voice phones, up from 60 million last year.</p>
<p>Smart phones, like the Nokia 9000 Communicator already on the market in Europe, integrate a variety of communications features like e-mail, paging, facsimile, and Web access.</p>
<p>The market research firm Mobile Insights projects a $2 billion worldwide market for smart phones by the year 2000, Geoworks noted. Digital cellular networks are due to be launched in the United States as well later this year.</p>
<p>--sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau +1 415 846 5400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALAMEDA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
