<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377334" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: NTT Data pares losses after M'bishi pinball denial.</title>
<headline>NTT Data pares losses after M'bishi pinball denial.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in NTT Data Corp erased some of their earlier losses on Thursday after Mitsubishi Corp denied it was planning to withdraw from the prepaid &quot;pachinko&quot; card business.</p>
<p>NTT Data shares fell sharply on Thursday morning after a Japanese business daily reported that Mitsubishi was aiming to sell its stake in a pachinko card firm in which NTT owns shares. But Mitsubishi later denied it had any such plan, allowing NTT Data shares to recover some lost ground.</p>
<p>NTT Data shares were down 80,000 yen at 3.13 million yen at 0135 GMT.</p>
<p>Earlier in the session, the shares had topped the list of percentage losers on the Tokyo Stock Exchange&quot;s first section, standing 160,000 yen down at 3.05 million yen at 0049 GMT.</p>
<p>The Nihon Keizai Shimbun reported on Thursday that Mitsubishi was looking for buyers for shares in the venture, Japan Leisure Card System Co, among companies in the pachinko industry. Pachinko is a Japanese form of pinball.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Corp said it had no plan to sell its stake in Japan Leisure and would support the company along with NTT Data.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
