<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="385385" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FUND VIEW - Dreyfus Third Century.</title>
<headline>FUND VIEW - Dreyfus Third Century.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Benkoe</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The nearly 40 so-called &quot;socially responsible&quot; mutual funds in the United States often operate under a different set of pressures.</p>
<p>Before a fund buys a stock, it must pass muster with a set of &quot;socially responsible&quot; criteria as well as the traditional investment requirements.</p>
<p>Who prevails when the &quot;socially responsible&quot; criteria conflict with the investment issues?   When push comes to shove</p>
<p>at the 25-year-old Dreyfus Third Century, its managers said, the socially responsible element prevails.  </p>
<p>&quot;If there is ever a question concerning a (socially conscious) problem with a company, and I feel that it would preclude their inclusion in the fund, then I would make that decision,&quot; said Eric Steedman, the co-portfolio manager who oversees research in social issues.</p>
<p>Steedman said at a recent briefing for reporters that the fund uses four criteria to measure social responsibility: Environmental performance, worker health and safety, and diversity, such as whether a company's senior management and the board of directors includes minorities and women.  </p>
<p>The fourth criteria is consumer protection and product &quot;purity,&quot; a standard under which the company avoids investments in companies whose products and services are harmful to consumers.</p>
<p>Based on these yardsticks, THE fund has not invested in tobacco, alcohol, gaming and most defense stocks.</p>
<p>Steedman and and co-manager Stephon Jackson said they generally find energy equities and stocks in the smokestack industry troublesome due to environmental issues.</p>
<p>The fund considers &quot;socially responsible&quot; issues after it weighs the financial fundamentals. Jackson said the fund seeks companies that offer &quot;growth at a reasonable price.&quot;  </p>
<p>Jackson seeks stocks with reasonable price/earnings, that have superior earnings growth compared to the rest of the sector, and has surprised Wall Street with its earnings estimates.  It employs the usual method of talking to management.</p>
<p>After Jackson selects a stock, he confers with Steedman to see if the stock can pass the other set of requirements.</p>
<p>Jackson and Steedman acknowledge that the fund can't be all things to all &quot;socially-responsible&quot; investors, and won't adopt every social issue.  </p>
<p>But the managers said they won't hesitate to unload what they considered a badly behaving stock.  The fund sold shares of Briggs &amp; Stratton Corp after the company sued the National Catholic Reporter for libel.  The U.S. publication had criticized the company over its layoff practices.</p>
<p>The $580 million fund currently has 59 holdings, with most issues comprising about 3.5 percent of the portfolio.</p>
<p>Top holdings include Intel Corp, Microsoft Corp, Citicorp, BankAmerica Corp, Fannie Mae, Johnson and Johnson, and Merck and Co Inc.  </p>
<p>The fund has returned 5.1 percent year to date through February 6, 24.33 percent in all of 1996, and 10.89 percent annualized over the last five years, according to Lipper.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
