<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388317" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: &quot;Discworld&quot; fails to overcome the prattle problem.</title>
<headline>&quot;Discworld&quot; fails to overcome the prattle problem.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>If you know and appreciate the humour of Monty Python, then &quot;Discorld II: Mortality Bytes!&quot; is for you.</p>
<p>The British group was known for bleakly bizarre humour such as the routine involving a travel agent and an obnoxious customer who refused to stop talking.</p>
<p>&quot;If you don't shut up, I'm going to have to shoot you,&quot; the frantic travel agent eventually threatened as the customer kept complaining about countries that can't make a proper cup of tea, hotel swimming pools full of fat businessmen pretending to be acrobats and the way Campbell's cream of mushroom soup is regarded as the first item on menus of international cuisine.</p>
<p>You can guess what the travel agent did.</p>
<p>There are several moments in &quot;Discworld II: Mortality Bytes!&quot; (Psygnosis, DOS/Windows95, $50) when I could empathize with that travel agent.</p>
<p>The characters in this CD-ROM role playing game prattle; oh boy, do they prattle. The blather was intended to be funny, but between jokes you get enough time to balance your checkbook, bathe your cat, or take those accordion lessons you've always wanted.</p>
<p>It's a shame because &quot;Discworld&quot; has plenty of comedic potential.</p>
<p>Discworld is named after a flat 10,000-mile-wide world that sits on the back of four giant elephants. They, in turn, stand on the shell of a turtle who obviously hasn't realised that if he swam upside down and scraped his shell against a rock, he could get on with his life.</p>
<p>In the Discworld city of Ankh-Morpork, best known for a smell that has kept invaders at bay for centuries, the locals have discovered that the natural order of things has become disordered. People are dying (their hearts have stopped beating, anyway) but their bodies are still moving. Death, it seems, has taken a holiday .</p>
<p>&quot;He LOOKS dead,&quot; says one mourner who can't understand why the beloved Windell is still moving. &quot;He SMELLS dead,&quot; says another, &quot;but, of course, he always did.&quot;</p>
<p>Windell, who isn't pleased about being undead, is ordered into the street by his mourners. &quot;Compose yourself, Windell,&quot; one says. &quot;You can't decompose here.&quot;</p>
<p>Ultimately, it's up to the incompetent wizard Rincewind, whose voice is provided by Monty Python's Eric Idle, to bring back Death so the Grim Reaper (a.k.a. the Thief of Years, Harvester of Mankind, Assassin Against Whom No Lock Will Hold, etc., etc.) can collect the spirits and bring things back to normal on Discworld.</p>
<p>Along the way, Rincewind meets plenty of strange folk. There's Gimlet, whose restaurant specialises in &quot;rodents hygienically prepared&quot; (which means he washes his hands after he makes the mouse burgers), a vampire with false teeth who has to subsist on Bloody Marys because he stalks his victims with a flashlight, and Casanunda, the world's second-greatest lover, who has to bring along a stepladder when he wants to kiss a pretty woman.</p>
<p>It's cute, it's clever, it's very long-winded.</p>
<p>And when the developers simply steal the &quot;Bring out your dead&quot; gag from the movie &quot;Monty Python and the Holy Grail,&quot; it looks like they are stretching for laughs.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, I'm sure Eric Idle fans will love it. They'll want to send me e-mail and drone on and on about the subtle inside jokes laced throughout the game.</p>
<p>Please don't bother. If you prattle on too long, I may send you to my &quot;favorite&quot; travel agent.</p>
<p>-  -  -  -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Banzaibug&quot; (Grolier Interactive, Windows 95, $45) -- Billed as &quot;the flight sim with an attitude,&quot; this flight simulator from an insect's point of view lets you play a bug trapped in an exterminator's house. Your job: overthrow the human occupants while avoiding clouds of toxic bug spray. One &quot;mission&quot; lets you dive-bomb Mom's hair to drive her out of the kitchen.</p>
<p>&quot;Magic: The Gathering -- Battlemage&quot; (Acclaim, Windows 95, $45) lets players battle wizards on the world of Corondor in this multiplayer action and strategy game. It's for ages 13 and older.</p>
<p>&quot;Stars!&quot; (Empire Interactive, Windows 95, $43) -- A space strategy game designed to let players discover new life forms and new planets, and to control fleets of spaceships and space stations.</p>
<p>-  -  -  -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
