<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390114" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FULL TEXT - Borland restructuring.</title>
<headline>FULL TEXT - Borland restructuring.</headline>
<text>
<p>SCOTTS VALLEY, Calif., Feb. 20 (Reuter)  Borland International Thursday announced plans to cut 300 jobs as part of a worldwide restructuring. The following is a copy of the company's statement.</p>
<p>----------------- NEWS RELEASE ----------------------</p>
<p>SCOTTS VALLEY, Calif., Feb. 20 /PRNewswire/ -- Borland International Inc., (Nasdaq: BORL) today announced a worldwide restructuring plan aimed at returning the company to profitability in its 1998 fiscal year, which begins April 1, 1997.  The restructuring plan involves significant reductions in operational expenses as well as the implementation of new programs aimed at growing the company's revenues. Only selective restructuring was conducted in Borland's international operations, which continue to show strong results.</p>
<p>Delbert W. Yocam, who joined Borland on December 2, 1996, as the company's Chairman and CEO said, &quot;This restructuring is the beginning of a plan to grow Borland into a thriving company known for the value it provides to organizations building client/server and Internet/intranet applications.  We plan to leverage Borland's rich heritage of high-quality and high-performance software development tools to expand our business into new markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Involved in the restructuring plan are significant reductions in operating costs, including a reduction in employees and contractors of approximately 300 personnel worldwide, or a reduction of approximately 30 percent.  After this restructuring, Borland will employ approximately 700 full-time equivalent employees worldwide.  Borland also aims to achieve cost reductions through new marketing and support programs that will replace programs that no longer fit Borland's core business or strategic focus.  This restructuring plan is anticipated to produce annual operating cost savings in excess of $30 million, and product restructuring savings in excess of $30 million.</p>
<p>Consistent with the company's Golden Gate strategy, Borland continues to aggressively pursue the corporate IT marketplace through the delivery of new application development tools. Golden Gate is a strategy that focuses on providing tools to IT developers that allow them to combine the best of the client/server and Internet architectures for departmental and enterprise application development.  Borland development tools allow open and scaleable solutions.  They allow customers to extend their investments in application development by providing bridges between legacy systems and client/server architectures to the Internet, and between decentral and central IT. Furthermore, Borland's  Golden Gate strategy provides interoperability between competing technology standards, such as the Internet platforms from Microsoft Corp., Netscape Communications Corp. and Sun Microsystems Inc., thereby reducing the risk involved in platform selection.</p>
<p>Today, only Borland provides an interoperable family of tools that are designed to meet development needs from the desktop to the enterprise. Borland's family of tools are renowned for their performance, productivity, scalability and reliability, and continue to out-rank the competition in technological excellence.</p>
<p>Following are some of the additional steps involved in Borland's restructuring program:</p>
<p>New Product Development</p>
<p>* As previously announced, a high priority will be placed on new product development.  Research &amp; Development programs at Borland are now aimed at delivering at least one major product release each quarter.  This practice is intended to help customers keep pace with the rapid changes in technology and to provide Borland with a consistent revenue stream.  New client/server and Internet/intranet product releases scheduled for the coming quarters include Borland C++Builder, Delphi 97 and Jbuilder, Borland's upcoming Java development tool.  In addition, Borland continues to work on developing new Internet products.  </p>
<p>* The first new product release scheduled to ship in calendar year 1997 is Borland C++Builder.  It is currently in manufacturing and is scheduled to be generally available early next month.  Borland C++Builder is a completely new visual rapid application development tool that combines the power and control of the C++ programming language with the rapid application development productivity of Borland's award-winning Delphi(TM) product line.</p>
<p>Increasing Alliances with Corporate IT Leaders</p>
<p>* Borland is continuing to make progress in forming strategic alliances with other IT leaders as part of the company's plan to reach new markets and expand its customer base.</p>
<p>* Earlier this month, Borland announced a non-exclusive, worldwide license agreement with Oracle Corp.  Under the terms of the agreement, Oracle will integrate and distribute the Borland C++Builder and JBuilder technologies for use with a number of Oracle's existing and future products, including Sedona, Developer/2000 and Designer/2000.</p>
<p>* Borland is now preparing to release the first version of its new Delphi AS/400 product line this quarter.  Delphi AS/400 will enable developers to build open, scaleable client/server applications using Delphi Client/Server Suite to access IBM AS/400 systems.</p>
<p>* Borland is continuing its strategic alliance programs with Netscape Communications Corp., Sun Microsystems, Inc. and Microsoft Corp. as part of its Golden Gate strategy.  Borland's products are based on an open architecture, enabling the company to support the industry's leading Internet platforms.</p>
<p>New, Cost-Effective Technical Support, Sales &amp; Marketing Programs</p>
<p>* In anticipation of expanding the company's enterprise business, Borland is implementing several new fee-based technical support programs.  Separate technical support programs will be provided for departmental and enterprise customers in order to better meet customer's support needs. Additionally, Borland is increasing the technical support provided on its web site.</p>
<p>* As part of the company's plan to increase more business delivered through VARs and system integrators, Borland is developing new marketing programs to support the efforts of these channel partners who are steadily increasing the company's revenues in the client/server market.</p>
<p>* As the retail channel continues to contribute a significant percentage of revenues, Borland will continue to market to this well-established channel while also increasing support for its direct sales and partner channels.</p>
<p>* The Borland web site is consistently ranked among the world's top 50 commercial web sites.  Borland plans to further invest in its web site marketing program, since it is today successfully generating leads, building corporate awareness, and answering customer questions.</p>
<p>* In order to reduce costs for its Open Environment division, Borland is downsizing its Boston operations, and relocating key technical personnel now based in Boston to the company's headquarters in Scotts Valley, Calif.</p>
<p>* With the intention of extending its reach into corporate IT, Borland and its Open Environment division will form one, integrated sales team, enabling Borland to leverage the expertise of Open Environment in supporting enterprise customers.  </p>
<p>* This restructuring plan serves as the foundation for Borland's new business organization.  A strategic business plan will be presented this summer by Del Yocam at Borland's eighth annual developer conference in Nashville, TN.</p>
<p>Borland: Making Development Easier</p>
<p>Borland International Inc. is a leading provider of high-quality software products for software application developers worldwide.  Borland is distinguished for its award-winning family of rapid application development tools and scalable middleware technology  for desktop, client/server, intranet/Internet, and enterprise systems.  The Company's products are supported through comprehensive corporate and independent developer programs, value added resellers and systems integrators.  Founded in 1983, Borland is headquartered in  Scotts Valley, California.  For more information on Borland, customers can visit Borland Online at http://www.borland.com.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
