<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391213" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Borland to cut 300 jobs in worldwide restructuring.</title>
<headline>Borland to cut 300 jobs in worldwide restructuring.</headline>
<dateline>SCOTTS VALLEY, Calif. 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Borland International Inc. said Thursday it planned to cut 300 jobs, nearly 30 percent of its work force, as part of a global restructuring programme aimed at restoring the company to profitability in fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>In a statement, the computer software firm said the restructuring plan involved significant reductions in operational expenses, as well as the implementation of new programmes aimed at raising the company's revenues.</p>
<p>&quot;This restructuring is the beginning of a plan to grow Borland into a thriving company known for the value it provides to organisations building client/server and Internet/intranet applications,&quot; said Borland Chairman Delbert Yocam.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to leverage Borland's rich heritage of high-quality and high-performance software development tools to expand our business into new markets.&quot;</p>
<p>After the restructuring, Borland will employ about 700 full-time employees worldwide.</p>
<p>Borland will take a $24 million to $30 million charge in its current fiscal 1997 fourth quarter to account for the restructuring. The charge will cover severance payments, expenses for closing the Boston office of its Open Environment unit, and the relocation of developers to headquarters in Scotts Valley, Calif., Chief Financial Officer Paul Emery said during a telephone conference call with reporters.</p>
<p>Scotts Valley, Calif.-based Borland said it also aimed to achieve cost reductions through new marketing and support programmes that will replace programmes that no longer fit its core business or strategic focus.</p>
<p>The company said the restructuring plan is expected to produce annual operating cost savings in excess of $30 million, and product restructuring savings in excess of $30 million.</p>
<p>For the nine months ended Dec. 31, Borland posted a loss of $65.5 million, compared with a profit of $7.8 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Borland's stock gained 87.5 cents to $7 on Nasdaq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SCOTTS VALLEY, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
