<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404553" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CD-ROMs feature Jamaican tales and Koala Karma.</title>
<headline>CD-ROMs feature Jamaican tales and Koala Karma.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's tough being a frog when you have a friend like Orly.</p>
<p>Just when a juicy bug comes within range of your tongue, the imaginative little Jamaican girl starts wondering if your would-be snack should have its life spared. Her reason: the insect might be an intrepid bug explorer, or a kind-hearted creature from outer space who has bravely landed on Earth to warn us that an armada of cruel alien monsters is about to invade our planet.</p>
<p>Orly not only knows how to make a frog feel guilty about his choice of entree, she also knows how to put fun into the art of teaching illustration and writing skills to children ages 5 to 10.</p>
<p>&quot;Orly's Draw-A-Story&quot; (Broderbund, Windows/Macintosh, $30) is a delightful CD-ROM that shows youngsters how to make stories come alive.</p>
<p>Once a child picks a tale, Orly sends players to an easy-to-use art programme, where they can draw the characters and objects that Orly needs for each story.</p>
<p>If they have trouble imagining something, they can open a window (the real kind, not a Microsoft kind) and select from one of the pre-made drawings. Next, they can paint it with a large palette of colours or special patterns (the programme conveniently keeps the colours within the lines).</p>
<p>But &quot;Orly's&quot; is more than a computer painting programme. When you're working on a character where the eyes and mouth have already been provided by the programme, the eyes follow you around as you draw or paint on the picture.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the characters make small talk as you're drawing them. &quot;I got lots of ideas, you know,&quot; one dull-witted bird with a Cockney accent remarks as you paint him. &quot;I just can't think of what they are, that's all.&quot; There's also a bubblegum-chewing bug who talks like a Valley Girl.</p>
<p>When you're finished, all of the drawings are incorporated into Orly's stories. And if you get bored with one of her four stories, you can create your own.</p>
<p>&quot;Orly's&quot; has great features. The method for teaching children to use the art programme is elegantly simple. The characters are engaging, including her frog friend Lancelot, who, true to his roots, croaks &quot;ribbit-mon.&quot;</p>
<p>But the real star is Orly, the dreadlocked little girl with the overactive imagination and an infectiously upbeat attitude. Most of the credit for her goes to Alreca Whyte, a 23-year-old college student from Jamaica, whose voice has been electronically altered to make her sound younger. She gives Orly real personality.</p>
<p>My only concern is that younger children may have trouble understanding Orly's Jamaican accent. But that's a minor problem. Youngsters tend to adapt quickly to dialects and they'll find that &quot;Orly's Draw-A-Story&quot; is, as Orly herself might say, &quot;da mos' amazin' ting!&quot;</p>
<p>    -    -    -    -</p>
<p>Don't you just hate it when you get a terrible ache in the pit of your stomach and you can't tell whether it's indigestion or a catastrophic shift in the balance of the universe?</p>
<p>Me too.</p>
<p>But get used to it. It's just one of the conundrums to be faced if you play &quot;Koala Lumpur: Journey to the Edge,&quot; a CD-ROM game, also from Broderbund (Windows, $39), where the fate of the cartoon cosmos is in your hands.</p>
<p>Billed as &quot;a comic adventure with an attitude,&quot; this is the story of a mystic koala bear who travels on a flying meditation mat, talks like Gandhi, and finds himself teleported to a huge room with two big doors.</p>
<p>Behind Door No. 1, the evil Macho de Nada is trying to break through so he can unleash a Comedy Apocalypse on the universe.</p>
<p>Behind Door No. 2 is the sweet-voiced Ella Mental, Supreme Being of the Cartoon Universe, who doesn't quite live up to her job description. She's not supreme enough to stop Macho de Nada, and can't tell Koala where he can find the pieces of the fabled Lost Scroll of Cartoon Prophesies that will stop the Macho Man.</p>
<p>So Koala, his doggedly determined canine companion (Dr. Dingo Tu-far), and you (a fly) must find the missing pieces and restore order in the universe or, in the words of Ms. Mental, &quot;kiss your chakras goodbye.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Koala Lumpur&quot; ranks pretty high on the weirdness meter. It takes players to a theme park for people who need therapy, a space station run by a 6-year-old, and the Land of Lost Things, where all your missing keys, socks and spare change go.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, it doesn't move the laughter meter as far as you might think. Some sections are mildly amusing, such as when Dr. Dingo develops haemotomaphobia (a fear of hickies) after he sticks a vacuum cleaner hose on his neck and his girlfriend thinks he's been cheating on her, but others fall flat.</p>
<p>Although it's a cartoon, &quot;Koala Lumpur&quot; is rated for ages 13 and older, which you might expect from a game with neutering jokes, where the package depicts a koala as road kill, and players can explore (from a dog's point of view) the hazards of high-voltage fire hydrants.</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
