<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40532" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Broderbund warns of lower profits.</title>
<headline>Broderbund warns of lower profits.</headline>
<byline>Bob Tourtellotte</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Broderbund Software Inc., with sales of its popular software game Myst declining sharply, said Monday it expected fourth-quarter results to fall short of analysts' estimates.</p>
<p>The company said revenues were expected to be between 85 percent and 90 percent of the $37.1 million of sales in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Earnings for the company's fourth fiscal quarter ended Aug. 31 are expected to be below analysts' estimates of 27 cents a share, according to investment research network First Call. In last year's fourth quarter, Broderbund earned $7.2 million, or 33 cents a share.</p>
<p>The news sent Broderbund's shares skidding $4.375 to $23.25 on the Nasdaq system.</p>
<p>&quot;The software industry is facing a glut of supply (of products), and Broderbund has not been as robust as others at beefing up their supply,&quot; said Keith Benjamin, analyst at San Francisco-based brokerage, Robertson Stephens and Co.</p>
<p>For the past three years Broderbund, which creates computer software for use in homes, schools and small businesses, has relied on the perennial best-seller game Myst to boost sales.</p>
<p>First launched in 1993, the mystery adventure game has surprised industry experts by continually posting strong quarterly sales, but analysts said it appears the wind has finally blown out of Myst's sails.</p>
<p>A Broderbund spokesman said sales of Myst were off about 50 percent from year ago levels. Sales of the once-popular Carmen Sandiego children's series have also declined.</p>
<p>The company also noted the lower revenues and earnings were due to disappointing sales of its affiliated label products such as the joint venture it has with Random House to produce Living Books educational software for children.</p>
<p>Newer competitors like Walt Disney Co.'s Disney Interactive wing have cut into Broderbund's market share.</p>
<p>The company spokesman said on some Living Books products, Broderbund has had to lower prices from $29 or $39, down to the popular $19.99 level.</p>
<p>The spokesman said other top titles, such as its Print Shop Deluxe line of productivity software, continue to perform well at retail levels. But there, too, analysts said bruising competition has put Broderbund on the defensive.</p>
<p>&quot;It's no more Mr. Nice Guy for Broderbund, that's a franchise they want to keep,&quot; said Vince Turzo, analyst at Jefferies and Co.</p>
<p>Analysts said Broderbund won't likely put earnings back on track until next year when a sequel to Myst, as well as other new and exciting products, need to hit retail shelves.</p>
<p>Fortunately, they note Broderbund is well-liked by retailers, has a strong track record of earnings and plenty of cash to stand the gap between now and next year.</p>
<p>For the educational and entertainment software industry as a whole, of which Broderbund is a market leader, analysts said Broderbund's woes should not spell added trouble.</p>
<p>Many of them said competition remains hot and shelf space tight, but as is usually the case, companies with the strongest and newest titles will see sales growth in the high-teens.</p>
<p>Broderbund's results for the fourth quarter and fiscal year ending Aug. 31 are expected to be released on Oct. 9.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
