<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405414" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: NTT Data says to guarantee pinball card unit loan.</title>
<headline>NTT Data says to guarantee pinball card unit loan.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>NTT Data Corp said on Wednesday that it will guarantee loans taken out by its pinball card unit.</p>
<p>The loan guarantee is valid from the end of February to the end of May and will only cover up to 15 billion yen worth of the unit's loans.  </p>
<p>NTT Data said in a statement that it and Mitsubishi Corp would guarantee loans taken out by pinball card company Nippon Leisure Card-System Co and the amount would depend on the stakes NTT Data and Mitsubishi hold in the unit.</p>
<p>NTT Data has a 10.05 percent stake and Mitsubishi has a 18.85 percent stake in the company, which makes prepaid cards for &quot;pachinko&quot; pinball gaming machines.</p>
<p>Separately, a Mitsubishi Corp spokesman told Reuters that Mitsubishi would guarantee loans of up to 28 billion yen taken out by the unit. He added that Mitsubishi will continue to support the ailing unit, which is suffering losses as a result of incidences of forgery involving its pre-paid pinball cards.  </p>
<p>Mitsubishi officials have said that the pinball card company's liabilities exceeded its assets by 46 billion yen as of September 30, 1996. They also said the unit lost 18 billion yen due to cases of forgery of its pre-paid pinball cards in the period from April to September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
