<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408281" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Oracle sees up to $1 bln Egypt IT market.</title>
<headline>Oracle sees up to $1 bln Egypt IT market.</headline>
<byline>Christine Hauser</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt's market for information technology has the capacity to more than triple in the next five years as population grows and the government privatises, industry executives said on Thursday.</p>
<p>At a news conference to announce the opening of a subsidiary in Egypt, executives from the U.S. software firm Oracle Corp said they forecast the market would grow three to five times.</p>
<p>&quot;Egypt has got the potential in three to five years to have an over $1 billion market in hardware, software and services,&quot; Hans Jarnick, Oracle vice president for East and Central Europe, Middle East and Africa told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said that Oracle's market share in Egypt was about $3 million. &quot;We have made a very conscious decision to make a substantial investment in Egypt.&quot;</p>
<p>Egyptian businessman Naguib Sawiris, who is working on an import agreement deal with Oracle, told the news conference the current market was about $250 million a year. &quot;It could be $750 million, maybe in the next three to four years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said that low government spending on computerisation, and the still-nascent buying power in Egypt as the country continues with economic reform were among the reasons why the figure for the Arab world's most populous country were relatively low.</p>
<p>With $28 billion market capitalisation, Oracle Corp. is the world's second largest software firm after Microsoft.</p>
<p>Oracle plans to open its wholly-owned subsidiary Oracle Egypt Ltd by June, adding to its Middle East presence in the United Arab Emirates, Saudi Arabia, Bahrain and Kuwait, officials said.</p>
<p>They said Oracle is targeting the government, public, private, defence, oil and gas, and banking sectors, and first year operating costs are expected to be $4 million.</p>
<p>Egypt has embarked on a reform programme including privatisation to transform its economy and attract foreign investment. Wilfreid Schoefer, Oracle Near and Middle East managing director, said the reform plans attracted Oracle.</p>
<p>&quot;International companies are now ready to invest in Egypt. It was a logical decision to strengthen involvement and investment,&quot; he said. &quot;Egypt is one of the most important information technology markets in the Middle East.&quot;</p>
<p>But Sawiris said copyright infringement in Egypt was &quot;a serious point for Oracle, too.&quot;</p>
<p>The Business Software Alliance, a lobbying group financed mainly by the big software producers, said in October that it had identified about 100 firms using pirated software in Egypt.</p>
<p>The group said it believed at least 80 percent of software in Egypt is pirated, meaning about $80 million a year in losses.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom 20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
