<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408413" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft Network plans to revamp program lineup.</title>
<headline>Microsoft Network plans to revamp program lineup.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp plans to cancel about half the 20 &quot;shows&quot; it launched on its online Microsoft Network with great fanfare four months ago in a programming overhaul that will affect nearly 200 contract workers, company executives said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Larry Cohen, group product manager for the Microsoft Network, said the affected workers, in jobs ranging from production and marketing to software development, would not see their contracts renewed, although the online service continues to seek creative talent to develop new shows.</p>
<p>He said no permanent Microsoft employees would be laid off.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a set of shows that won't be renewed,&quot; Cohen said. &quot;When we rolled out the network back in October, we said some would be renewed and some wouldn't be renewed. We're also adding shows as well.&quot;</p>
<p>When the Microsoft Network was relaunched last year after 14 months of operation, executives modeled the Internet online service after television, with separate &quot;channels&quot; aimed at different demographic groups and weekly or daily serial entertainment programs.</p>
<p>Microsoft spokesman John Pinette said the shows that are getting canceled have been unable to attract sufficient advertising or &quot;hit rates.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We think it's good for the network in the same way that television shows get replaced midseason,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cohen declined to identify the shows that are being canceled, but a report in the Los Angeles Times said they included the comedy, &quot;15 Seconds of Fame,&quot; and &quot;475 Madison Avenue,&quot; a soap opera.</p>
<p>Bob Bejan, who heads content development for MSN, told the newspaper the shows will be replaced by 14 new ones. He said the job cutbacks are part of the company's effort to adopt Hollywood's practice of hiring and firing as production needs change.</p>
<p>&quot;The role of labor in media is accordion in nature,&quot; Bejan said. &quot;You gear up when you need people. Then you gear down. Finally, we are doing that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
