<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="409520" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sony expected to slash PlayStation prices Monday.</title>
<headline>Sony expected to slash PlayStation prices Monday.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sony Corp. is expected on Monday to cut the price of its PlayStation video game machine by as much as 25 percent, a move that would steal attention from rival Nintendo Corp.</p>
<p>Sony could cut PlayStation's suggested retail price to between $149 and $179, down from $199 currently, industry analysts and executives said. The Nintendo 64, a hot-selling rival machine, sells for $199.</p>
<p>&quot;Nintendo is getting tremendous publicity right now and Sony is trying to steal some of that,&quot; said Lee Isgur, video game industry analyst at Corporate Counselors, a market research firm.</p>
<p>With the weaker Japanese yen, Sony can afford to cut its prices in the United States. The consumer electronics company has already reduced PlayStation prices in Japan. Sony also is looking to preserve the PlayStation's momentum, which slowed a bit when the Nintendo 64 came out last fall.</p>
<p>Analysts and video game software executives have expected Sony to cut prices for some time, but not so early in the year nor as dramatically. The move also could force Nintendo and Sega Enterprises Ltd. to join the price war.</p>
<p>&quot;They have to follow,&quot; said David Farina, analyst at William Blair &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Sony officials declined to comment, but said they will make a &quot;major business announcement&quot; on Monday. A spokeswoman at Nintendo said they expect Sony to cut prices, but declined to comment until Sony makes the announcement. Sega officials also declined to comment.</p>
<p>A hardware price war would be a boon for the video game software industry. Most software vendors have had a difficult time in the past two years while the industry rolled out a new generation of consoles.</p>
<p>Software sales took off this Christmas with the Nintendo 64's introduction and price cuts from Sony and Sega. Bobby Kotick, chairman of video game software vendor Activision Inc., said last week he expects a booming year this year as hardware prices continue to fall.</p>
<p>Kotick said he expects Sony to cut PlayStation prices to as low as $99 in the United States by Christmas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
