<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413647" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Legg Mason manager likes cable, utilities - Barron's.</title>
<headline>Legg Mason manager likes cable, utilities - Barron's.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A mutual fund manager for Baltimore's Legg Mason told the weekly financial tabloid Barron's that he was interested in cable companies like Tele-Communications Inc because they stood to gain from the rise in Internet use.</p>
<p>William Miller told the tabloid in an interview in its March 3 issue that he also thought that power utilities and online service providers like America Online were a good investment, however unattractive they might seem.  </p>
<p>&quot;Cable offers a better chance of finding values,&quot; he was quoted as saying. &quot;Tele-Communications Inc, for instance. It's underperformed forever. They poured capital into a lot of questionable ventures. But they've become more focused on generating free cash.&quot;</p>
<p>Miller said he did not find the potential threat from satellite television to be very daunting. &quot;(Their) growth is slowing.&quot;</p>
<p>Miller said cable companies could fend for themselves.  </p>
<p>&quot;They have big infrastructure in place,&quot; he said. &quot;And there's a shortage of bandwidth, which is placing tremendous demands on the Internet service providers.&quot;</p>
<p>Miller said power utilities were becoming attractive as their sector was becoming deregulated.</p>
<p>He said utilities were not likely to hold onto inefficient plants that would cost them money in the new, competitive market.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks to me like the high-cost generating facilities will be taken off the utilities' hands, which will give them a wad of cash,&quot; he said. &quot;They'll become cash-rich and free-cash-flow-rich. And we follow the cash.</p>
<p>&quot;UniCom, the old Commonwealth Edison, is down to the low 20s, from 28 a few weeks ago, and has a seven (percent) yield,&quot; he said. &quot;New York State Electric and Gas has a yield pushing 6 (percent). Illinova pays out close to 5 (percent), and has been raising its dividend 11 (percent) a year. Eastern Utilities has almost a 9 (percent) dividend.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if these stocks stall for the rest of the year, they should offer competitive returns with the overall market,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Miller also said Wall Street had not realized how much cash America Online could generate.</p>
<p>He said it had no problems with receivables because membership fees were paid by credit card and it did not have to finance any inventory.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
