<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413656" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IPO VIEW - Market edgy, looking for direction.</title>
<headline>IPO VIEW - Market edgy, looking for direction.</headline>
<byline>Kamalakshi Mehta</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The market for initial public offerings will reflect the edginess of other financial markets as jittery investors look for signs of a correction.</p>
<p>&quot;They're looking for comfort in case of a correction,&quot; Steve Zenker, portfolio manager at McCabe Capital Managers, said, referring to investors' current predilection, amid an uncertain environment, for large, liquid stocks.</p>
<p>The uncertainty was fueled by Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's comments during the first leg of his semiannual testimony to Congress last Wednesday, where he raised questions about the rapid rise of stock prices and hinted at a possible preemptive interest rate increase.</p>
<p>However, if the Fed decides to leave interest rates unchanged and the rate of growth continues at a comfortable pace, investors could start gravitating back to small-cap stocks, Zenker said, because the &quot;divergence in valuations (between large and small caps) was so great.&quot;</p>
<p>This would be good news for IPOs, which have a greater presence in the small-cap sector.</p>
<p>Some analysts even said that a general stock sell-off may not be bad news for the IPO market.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's get it over with,&quot; said David Menlow, president of Springfield, N.J.-based IPO Financial Network Corp. &quot;And when we do, we'll end up in a much better position.&quot;</p>
<p>The fate of IPOs was mixed last week, with some issues, like IONA Technologies Plc and General Cigar Holdings, surprising analysts with the strength of their openings, and some, like NACT Telecommunications Inc., coming in below expectations.</p>
<p>More than a couple of deals broke issue, or fell below their IPO price, on the first day of trading.</p>
<p>But strong showings like General Cigar and Ciena Corp. -- which went public in early February at $23 and closed on Friday at $39.25 -- should help attract investors' interest, analysts said.</p>
<p>A further boost will come from Ford Motor Co.'s planned IPO of its Hertz unit, which was announced on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Big names like Hertz bring attention to the IPO market,&quot; said Ken Fleming, an analyst at Renaissance Capital Corp., an IPO research firm based in Greenwich, Conn.</p>
<p>This week's roster boasts few such names, however, and analysts see minimal fireworks.</p>
<p>The pick of the week, according to several analysts, is Nationwide Financial Services Inc. NFS.N, a provider of long-term savings and retirement products to retail and institutional investors in the United States.</p>
<p>Nationwide, the largest deal of the week, is offering 20.5 million shares globally, with 16.4 million shares slated for North America. The price range is $21 to $23 per share.</p>
<p>Vincent Slavin, who tracks IPOs for Cantor Fitzgerald, said he sees that price going up by at least $1 in that deal, which is being lead-managed by CS First Boston.</p>
<p>Complete Business Solutions Inc. could see a similar jump at its debut, analysts said.  Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette is lead underwriter on the 3.7-million-share deal, which has a price range of between $13 and $15 a share.</p>
<p>The company provides information technology services to large and mid-size organizations.</p>
<p>AmeriTrade Holding Corp., which is offering 2.35 million shares between $14 and $16 a share, could pick up between 75 cents and $1, some analysts said. The company provides internet brokerage services.</p>
<p>Storage Dimensions Inc., SPR Inc. and Kos Pharmaceuticals Inc. could also garner premiums, analysts said.</p>
<p>Many analysts said that while the IPO market looked less euphoric than last year, it was more rational.</p>
<p>Shorn of the hype, valuations are more realistic, which &quot;gives the whole world the opportunity to get into the market,&quot; said John Fitzgibbon, editor of the IPO Aftermarket.</p>
<p>Investors are taking a company-by-company approach so that &quot;it's not group action, but individual action,&quot; that characterizes the market, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
