<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413732" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India awaits Gates to open windows of opportunity.</title>
<headline>India awaits Gates to open windows of opportunity.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Is he coming to buy? Or is he coming to sell?</p>
<p>Opinions vary, but there is no doubt that Bill Gates, among the world's richest men and chairman of Microsoft Corp, the world's biggest computer software company, will be welcomed in India with the kind of hype usually reserved for pop stars.</p>
<p>Gates was scheduled to arrive in New Delhi on Monday on a four-day visit to India during which he will meet Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda, address corporate leaders and encounter his fans, some who admire his wealth and others his vision.</p>
<p>Two of India's leading newsmagazines, &quot;Outlook&quot; and &quot;The Week,&quot; have already published cover stories on Gates, detailing his skills, wealth and tastes.</p>
<p>Gates' stake in Microsoft was worth $23.5 billion at the end of 1996. His personal net worth was estimated at $18.5 billion last September by Forbes Magazine.</p>
<p>&quot;First of all, he wants to get a first hand experience of the country. Meeting with customers, partners and policy makers will give him this experience,&quot; a Microsoft spokesman said in a written response to questions from Reuters on Gates' visit.</p>
<p>For India, home to thousands of skilled software engineers, 41-year-old Gates is a shining example to emulate in its dream of becoming a leader in high-growth information technology.</p>
<p>Gates would visit Bombay, but did not have the time to visit Bangalore, called India's Silicon Valley, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Microsoft is a software development company and the huge pool of immensely talented software engineers in India makes the country a particularly interesting place for Bill Gates visit,&quot; the Microsoft spokesman said.</p>
<p>Last year, Gates won Indian hearts when he lobbied successfully with the Bill Clinton administration against a proposed U.S. immigration law that would have adversely affected Indian engineers.</p>
<p>&quot;He argued that America requires the services of Indian software companies for a win-win situation,&quot; The Week quoted Dewang Mehta, executive director of India's National Association of Service and Software Companies (Nasscom), as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;It is great news that India is high on Gates' radar screen. His visit reflects the value he places on the Indian software industry,&quot; Nandan Nilekani, deputy managing director of software firm Infosys Technologies Ltd, told &quot;Outlook.&quot;</p>
<p>Gates' Indian visit is also seen by many as an opportunity for Microsoft to boost its products.</p>
<p>&quot;India has reached the two-million mark in personal computers, which Gates may be interpreting as what is often referred to as the 'firecracker point' -- the temperature at which the market explodes,&quot; said &quot;Outlook&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The Indian subcontinent is an important market for Microsoft and the company has been increasing its investments in the region,&quot; the Microsoft spokesman said.</p>
<p>On Friday, Finance Minister P. Chidambaram proposed to abolish all customs duties on software and slashed tariffs on computer parts in his budget for 1997/98 (April-March).</p>
<p>The spokesman said Gates would hold private business meetings on Monday. On Tuesday, he was scheduled to address three gatherings in New Delhi.</p>
<p>He was scheduled on Wednesday to fly to Bombay where he would hold private meetings, meet chief executives of 500 Indian computer companies and address a session on the social aspects of information technology attended by Prime Minister Deve Gowda.</p>
<p>Gates first met Deve Gowda last month during the annual World Economic Forum meeting at Davos in Switzerland.</p>
<p>Gates is scheduled to leave for South Africa on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
