<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414988" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Cytrix, Conrail highlight slow day.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Cytrix, Conrail highlight slow day.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>With Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan set for more Congressional testimony Wednesday and a key economic report scheduled for Friday, options investors moved to the sidelines Monday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's dead,&quot; one options trader based in Chicago said. &quot;Everyone is waiting around for Greenspan and the numbers.&quot;</p>
<p>Last week, Greenspan's comments sent the market into a tailspin and investors are wary of what he may say this week.</p>
<p>On Friday, the all-important employment report for February is due before the stock market opens.  </p>
<p>Some special situations did attract options investors, however, with Citrix Systems Inc being one.</p>
<p>Citrix shares, which fell sharply last week after the company said its core products may face competition from Microsoft Corp, rebounded slightly.</p>
<p>Traders said last week that investors were buying and selling Citrix calls, but call buyers appeared to have the upper hand Monday.</p>
<p>The Citrix March 15 call was the most active option at the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE), with volume of 4,800 at about 1345 CST/1945 GMT.  </p>
<p>The March 20 call traded 2,720 and the April 15 call traded about 630 contracts, rounding out the most active Citrix options.</p>
<p>The stock, which fell from the 40 area last week, was up 2-5/8 at 15-1/4. Volume topped 4.1 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like small retail buyers are nibbling at this thing,&quot; Michael Schwartz, a managing director at Oppenheimer &amp; Co, said. &quot;There are some spreads in there but not large ones.&quot;</p>
<p>He noted that open interest in the Citrix March 15 call was only 1,277 going into today.  </p>
<p>&quot;It does look like speculation by the public, which will probably result in an increase in open interest,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Conrail Inc options were fairly active as the stock rallied on widespread reports that a four-month takeover battle for control of the railroad may soon be settled.</p>
<p>Conrail was up 6-1/4 at 110-3/4 on more than 1.2 million shares by afternoon.</p>
<p>The agreement would reportedly split up Conrail assets between rival bidders CSX Corp and Norfolk Southern Corp.  </p>
<p>Conrail said it would hold a board meeting Monday to consider options relating to its proposed merger with CSX, but a spokesman declined to elaborate.</p>
<p>Among the Conrail options, the March 110 call was most active, with volume of about 2,910 contracts. The March 105 call traded 2,420 and the March 115 call traded 1,425. The April 110 call traded nearly 2,600.</p>
<p>Schwartz said the call activity &quot;represents a lot of optimism this deal is going to be finalized in a couple of weeks.&quot; ((--G.Crawford, 312 408 8750/Email: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
