<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421504" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Gates says India potential &quot;software superpower&quot;.</title>
<headline>Gates says India potential &quot;software superpower&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp chairman Bill Gates was quoted on Wednesday as saying India could become a global software superpower and was a more attractive investment target for his firm than China.</p>
<p>&quot;India has the momentum to become a software superpower. It has the necessary potential. All that India needs is a few examples of successful companies,&quot; Gates said in an interview published in the Economic Times.</p>
<p>&quot;The importance of India as a software country and a place we've decided to invest in is greater than China. I am impressed with the talent India has. The world can draw from this enormous pool of talent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gates, who has won front-page headlines during his four-day visit that began on Monday, said he was impressed by India's success in halting software piracy and by government efforts to encourage the growth of information technology.</p>
<p>&quot;My trip is a milestone in terms of my understanding of what kind of partnerships we can have (with India), where the market is, and I think we are getting quite a warm reception,&quot; Gates told the daily.</p>
<p>The 41-year-old Microsoft chief said he was optimistic that the firm would develop &quot;talking computers&quot; within the next five years.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an area (in which) we have done a lot of advanced research. We have the higher speed chips that are extremely helpful. The thing that's tough is that speech is somewhat ambiguous,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gates, one of the richest men in the world with a 25 percent stake in Microsoft estimated at some $23 billion, said computer-induced changes had profoundly changed the way people think about education, democracy and markets.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a sort of ultimate tool of capitalism -- to be able to reach out to see everybody who wants to sell a product or services, everybody who wants to buy that product or services, and let them collaborate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gates was due to launch a new product and address a seminar in Bombay on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
