<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421533" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Deutsche Telekom talks with AOL continue.</title>
<headline>Deutsche Telekom talks with AOL continue.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Telekom AG said on Wednesday it is still in discussions with the German media group Bertelsmann AG and the U.S. online service provider America Online about a possible alliance.</p>
<p>The alliance would involve Telekom's online services T-Online and AOL Europe, a spokesman for Telekom told Reuters, who denied an earlier magazine report that Telekom wanted to ally T-Online to software group Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;The discussions are continuing,&quot; the Telekom spokesman said, but would give no details as to what stage the discussions were at.</p>
<p>Telekom said that it would be announcing a cooperation agreement with Microsoft in coming weeks at the CeBIT computer fair in Hanover, but said the announcement had no relevance on competition grounds.</p>
<p>In November 1995 Telekom and Bertelsmann announced a agreement on principle to ally their online services, which would include some form of exchange of mutual holdings.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Bertelsmann group in Guetersloh said that its negotiations with Telekom were experiencing problems on competition grounds.</p>
<p>Bertelsmann said that German cartel authorities had indicated there could be problems if market leaders T-Online and AOL Europe, which is a operated by Bertelsmann and AOL, sought to forge an alliance.</p>
<p>One of the points of issue is how much of a stake Telekom is allowed to take in the alliance. Telekom has sought around 30 percent.</p>
<p>The German Federal Cartel Office said that its president, Dieter Wolf, said some time ago that it would examine any proposed cooperation between T-Online and AOL.</p>
<p>The watchdog said that it had received no further concrete plans from the parties involved.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
