<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429029" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IPO VIEW - Skittish investors favor big deals.</title>
<headline>IPO VIEW - Skittish investors favor big deals.</headline>
<byline>Kamalakshi Mehta</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>A few IPOs have had stellar debuts in the past couple of weeks, but the consensus among analysts is that the market remains finicky and investors will continue to favor big deals while letting small issues fall by the wayside.</p>
<p>According to Manish Shah, editor and publisher of the IPO Maven, &quot;people have made a kind of fundamental shift in attitude that if it is a large company we will pay for it even at a higher multiple. If it is a small company we just don't want to pay for it&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's money with places to go so some (IPOs) will be successful,&quot; said Vincent Slavin, who tracks IPOs for Cantor Fitzgerald. &quot;The bigger ones have the best chance&quot;. A few, like Hertz, were &quot;definites&quot;, he said, &quot;but it's a crazy market.&quot;</p>
<p>Last week saw substantial gains for some of the larger issues - Nationwide Financial Services Inc rose nearly 15 percent at its market debut, and AmeriTrade Holding Corp not only saw first day gains of 4-1/2 over its IPO price of $15, but held on to the gains to end the week at $21 a share.  </p>
<p>But as a reminder that the IPO market still had surprises in store, Kos Pharmaceuticals, a development stage company with no revenues from products sales, bucked the trend favoring companies with track records and solid earnings and zoomed up $7 from its offering price of $15.</p>
<p>Other deals were less fortunate: shares of Complete Business Solutions Inc priced below their estimated price range and then slipped further at their debut, Riviera Tool shares also broke issue or dipped lower than the IPO price, and SPR Inc slashed its IPO terms for the second time.  </p>
<p>According to Securities Data Co, over 100 IPOs are set to be priced in March and some analysts said that the full pipeline was adding to the market's woes. &quot;Because it's crowded and because people are trying to get a tone for the market.... deals are difficult to do these days,&quot; said Michael Essex, syndicate manager at McDonald &amp; Co Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The backlog of deals weighs on the overall IPO market when we've got an environment like we're in which is somewhat uncertain and frankly biased towards large-caps,&quot; said Matt Considine, analyst at Phoenix Duff &amp; Phelps.  </p>
<p>But deals will continue to get done, and this week's calendar looks fairly busy, with analysts expecting a good showing from a few companies.</p>
<p>NeoMagic Corp is &quot;one of the best of the week,&quot; and could be up a point at the open, said John Fitzgibbon, editor of the IPO Aftermarket. The Santa Clara, Calif.-based company, which develops multimedia accelerators for sale to notebook PC manufacturers, is offering three million shares between $7 and $9 each. Morgan Stanley is lead underwriter.  </p>
<p>Colonial Downs Holdings Inc, a company formed to pursue horse racing and pari-mutuel wagering in Virginia, could see a premium anywhere from 1/4 to one point at its debut, according to Fitzgibbon.  The 4.25 million share deal, expected to fetch a price of between $9 to $11 a share, has Friedman, Billings, Ramsey &amp; Co as lead underwriter.  </p>
<p>Activewear manufacturer Pluma Inc's offering of 3.1 million shares, lead-managed by J.P. Morgan, is also expected to garner a premium, though analysts don't see any fireworks. &quot;Don't expect it to go through the roof,&quot; said Shah of IPO Maven. &quot;It's a fair company at a fair price.&quot; The shares are expected to price in a range of $12 to $14.</p>
<p>Other deals expected to do well include Kinetics Group Inc and Ramco Energy Plc's American Depositary Share issue.</p>
<p>The trend in the IPO market -- if one could be definitively identified -- which was rewarding bigger deals and passing over smaller deals, would only change, said Shah, &quot;when investors' appetite for the large caps is satiated simply because of the high P/E (price to earnings) multiples there&quot;. However, he said, it didn't look like this was about to happen anytime soon.</p>
<p>((---New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
