<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430954" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Navarre to acquire balance of NetRadio.</title>
<headline>Navarre to acquire balance of NetRadio.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Navarre Corp, a national distributor of music and computer software, said Monday it agreed to acquire the remaining 50-percent ownership of NetRadio Corp, operator of NetRadio Network, an entertainment site on the Internet.</p>
<p>Concurrent with Navarre's acquisition of NetRadio, ValueVision International Inc said it agreed to acquire a 15-percent interest in Navarre's new NetRadio subsidiary for about $3 million.</p>
<p>Navarre acquired an initial 50-percent ownership of NetRadio in May 1996 for $1.5 million.  </p>
<p>Under terms of Navarre's purchase of the remaining 50 percent stake in NetRadio, Navarre will initially issue 125,000 shares of Navarre common stock to NetRadio shareholders and the merge NetRadio into a unit of Navarre.</p>
<p>Based on the financial performance of NetRadio through March 1999, NetRadio shareholders could receive up to an additional 1,975,000 shares of Navarre common stock.  </p>
<p>Eric Paulson, Navarre's chairman and chief executive officer, said, &quot;We have structured this acquisition to provide a solid link between NetRadio's future performance and payout. We are convinced that this linkage will maximize the long-term benefits to Navarre shareholders while enabling Navarre, through the new NetRadio subsidiary, to become a significant participant in electronic commerce on the Internet.&quot;</p>
<p>Navarre said it expects the transaction to close during the week of March 17.</p>
<p>ValueVision operates the nation's third-largest television home- shopping network and following the acquisition, the audio feed of ValueVision's shopping network will be carried by NetRadio.</p>
<p>The purchase price of the 15 percent stake is composed of $1 million in cash and an additional $2 million in advertising time to increase NetRadio's visibility among cable subscribers. Additionally, ValueVision will be granted exclusive rights for most merchandise categories to be made available in NetRadio's programming.</p>
<p>	     ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
