<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433980" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: D.Telekom, MSN cooperate online.</title>
<headline>D.Telekom, MSN cooperate online.</headline>
<dateline>HANOVER, Germany 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>German telecommunications group Deutsche Telekom AG said on Tuesday that the 1.4 million subscribers to its online service T-Online would in future have access to the Microsoft Network.</p>
<p>In an extension of a cooperation agreement between Telekom and the U.S. software group, content -- online magazines and so-called chat forums -- from Microsoft Network (MSN) will be integrated in T-Online.</p>
<p>&quot;Microsoft is an ideal expansion of T-Online with its software competence and know-how in the area of content,&quot; Telekom chairman Ron Sommer told a news conference ahead of the CeBIT information technology trade fair in Hanover.</p>
<p>Sommer said that with the next version of T-Online software, to be made available this week at CeBIT, subscribers to the service would be able to call up MSN content without first leaving T-Online and dialling up MSN.</p>
<p>The number of T-Online subscribers rose 40 percent last year to 1.4 million at the end of 1996. Most of the subscribers access the service over Telekom's high-speed Integrated Digital Services Network (ISDN).</p>
<p>Telekom board member in charge of residential customers said a total of 4.6 million ISDN channels have been sold in Germany, of which 1.6 million were accounted for by residential users.</p>
<p>ISDN allows online users to access the Internet at speeds of as much as three to four times that of conventional analogue modems.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very happy about the promising partnership between Microsoft and Deutsche Telekom - the leading online provider in Europe,&quot; said Microsoft chief Bill Gates in a written statement distributed at the news conference.</p>
<p>T-Online has until now provided its subscribers with software for viewing pages on the World Wide Web -- a so-called browser -- from Microsoft competitor Netscape Communications.</p>
<p>It was not immediately apparent if T-Online would now make Microsoft's browser, the Internet Explorer, available to its subscribers.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49 228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOVER, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
