<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436439" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Internet World ushers in flood of new, improved products.</title>
<headline>Internet World ushers in flood of new, improved products.</headline>
<byline>Michelle V. Rafter</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's Internet convention time again, which means the usual river of new product and strategic alliance announcements from industry players is rising to flood stage.</p>
<p>In anticipation of Spring Internet World, which runs March 10-14 in Los Angeles, companies are taking the wraps off new or improved Web browsers, &quot;push&quot; technologies, e-mail services, electronic-commerce software, multi-player online games, Web-based chat services, corporate intranet systems, modems, Web programming tools and a slew of other goods and services.</p>
<p>Internet conventions have become as commonplace as Hollywood awards shows -- and sometimes just as vapid. But Spring Internet World continues to be regarded as one of the biggest and best of the bunch, mainly because it remains something of a bellwether for the Internet products consumers and corporate computer users will see during the remainder of the year.</p>
<p>More than 600 companies are expected to exhibit during the five-day confab, which is run by Mecklermedia, publisher of Internet World and other industry magazines.</p>
<p>Some highlights include:</p>
<p>-- Browsers -- Both Netscape and Microsoft will offer peeks at new Web browsers, which are gradually outgrowing their names to become do-it-all Internet or desktop operating systems. Microsoft's Internet Explorer version 4.0 will incorporate a Web browser and features of the company's Windows operating system, including functions that let users search for files on their personal computer.</p>
<p>Netscape is also piling features onto its Navigator Web browser, including an e-mail filter, the ability to handle mini-applications written in Java, and &quot;push&quot; features that send news and other information to a user's desktop rather than making them hunt for it online. Neither programme is expected to be commercially available until late this year or 1998.</p>
<p>-- Push technologies -- PointCast, which made its debut at the 1996 Spring Internet World, pioneered the push concept and continues to set a blistering pace for the raft of competitors that have since entered the market. Earlier this week, PointCast added the Wall Street Journal and Ziff-Davis Publishing Co. to its list of publisher partners.</p>
<p>Among its rivals, newcomer Astound introduced push software for small Web sites that's relatively cheap -- $195 for the company's WebCast Personal Edition compared with tens of thousands of dollars for software from Marimba and BackWeb. But analysts see trouble ahead. There's not enough room for all the push players that have emerged, and by year's end, only a handful will remain, predicts a just-released report from International Data Corp.</p>
<p>-- Electronic commerce -- Companies are still trying to figure out how to make a buck online, and once they've landed a paying customer, how to handle net-based financial transactions. At Internet World, Digital Equipment Corp. will weigh in with its solution, an e-commerce software systems called &quot;Millicent&quot; that would allow people to buy and sell information for a fraction of a penny.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, several companies are announcing initiatives to develop smart cards, credit-card sized devices with an embedded computer chip that can store money, data or encryption keys. AT&amp;T is working on a smart-card project with Mondex, and Hewlett-Packard is teaming up with database company Informix and Gemplus, a leading French smart-card manufacturer.</p>
<p>-- Online games -- In the days immediately preceding the convention, Microsoft, MCI and Sony unveiled plans to create online game services or upgrade existing ventures.</p>
<p>Microsoft announced a number of upgrades to its Online Gaming Zone site, including improvements in instant message features and a deal with Hasbro to make available games such as Monopoly and Scrabble. Sony's game site, The Station, will feature games such as Wheel of Fortune as well as games originally built for the company's PlayStation video game console.</p>
<p>MCI will offer British Telecom's Wireplay, which unlike the others is on a private dial-up network, not the Internet.</p>
<p>More than 50,000 people are expected to attend Spring Internet World. That's 10 times the number of people who showed up for the first Internet World convention four years ago in San Jose, Calif., when a mere 45 companies has products on display.</p>
<p>The convention is closed to the public, but daily highlights and other details are available on the following Web sites:</p>
<p>-- Internet World (http://events.iworld.com/spring97/iw/) -- Mecklermedia's official convention guide.</p>
<p>-- News.com (http://www.news.com/) -- cnet's daily technology news service.</p>
<p>-- PC Week (http://www.pcweek.com/sr/sr.html) -- A special Internet World report from the online version of ZDNet's weekly computer newspaper.</p>
<p>-- TechWire (http://www.techweb.com/) -- CMP Media Inc.'s daily technology news service.</p>
<p>(Michelle V. Rafter writes about cyberspace and technology from Los Angeles. Reach her at mvrafter(at)deltanet.com. Opinions expressed in this column are her own).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
