<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436608" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 50 ways to lose your marbles.</title>
<headline>50 ways to lose your marbles.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Marble Drop&quot; (Maxis, Windows, $30) isn't a complicated game to play, but it can be a wonderfully challenging game to win.</p>
<p>Although these puzzles have the look of Leonardo da Vinci sketches, they are really inspired by cartoonist Rube Goldberg, the inventor of fantastic machines.</p>
<p>Your job is to put marbles of various colours into funnels and allow them to roll their way down wire ramps, move up conveyor belts, fly through the air and eventually roll into a trough.</p>
<p>It's tricky. The marble with the correct colour must end up in the correct position in the trough. Because the path the marble takes can activate a series of switches, gates, hammers and other gizmos, predicting the marble's path can be maddening.</p>
<p>In the Ctesibus puzzle, for example, you must use one marble to load a cannon and use another to trip the firing mechanism to shoot the marble across the screen.</p>
<p>In another puzzle (named Apollonius Dyskolos, but a better name would have been Fire and Ice), you must be sure that the marble doesn't pass through two flames or two freezers in a row, otherwise the marble will fry or shatter before it gets to its trough.</p>
<p>In the final puzzle, everything is invisible except for the marble, the funnel and the ramp at the end.</p>
<p>With 50 different levels like this, &quot;Marble Drop&quot; gives you plenty of ways to lose your marbles -- both figuratively and literally. Fortunately, if you run short, you can use some of your points to buy additional marbles.</p>
<p>The only problem with the game is that some of the faded Leonardo-style handwritten screen notations that give information about each level can be difficult to read on low-resolution monitors. (Fortunately, they're not written backwards as Leonardo tended to do.) But otherwise, &quot;Marble Drop&quot; requires virtually no directions and if you get stumped on one level, it lets you go on to the next.</p>
<p>At $30, that's 60 cents per level. The package also includes a free copy of the original &quot;Full Tilt! Pinball&quot; programme. It's cheap fun for someone looking to kill some time with a cute game.</p>
<p>Windows 95 users can try out the first five levels for free by downloading them from the Maxis web site at http://www.maxis.com</p>
<p>    -    -    -    -</p>
<p>&quot;Magic Fairy Tales: Barbie as Rapunzel&quot; (Mattel Media, Windows/Macintosh, $30) offers a new twist on the story of the girl with the extraordinarily long hair: it's the princess who saves the prince so the pair can live happily ever after.</p>
<p>The product, for girls 4 and older, is designed to take advantage of Barbie's popularity. But the only thing that makes this a &quot;Barbie&quot; product is the title, plus the fact that the skinny heroine has blonde hair. There's no Ken and no Skipper. There's no reference to Barbie anywhere in the story.</p>
<p>It's almost as if Mattel took a generic fairy tale game, designed by a company known as Media Station, and slapped the &quot;Barbie&quot; name on it.</p>
<p>&quot;Barbie as Rapunzel&quot; is pretty good even without the Barbie name. Children can let the 16-minute story play by itself, or they can get involved along the way with matching games, a maze game and other diversions.</p>
<p>In this version, Rapunzel is trapped in a rocky tower filled with clothes and a kitchen where the pots and jars are never empty (which explains how she gets her food). One day, when a handsome prince with little rock climbing experience finds the tower, Barbie throws down one end of her hair so he can climb up.</p>
<p>The prince discovers that Rapunzel has wonderful social skills even though her only company has been three birds and a grumpy talking mirror. When the angry witch banishes the prince to a distant land, Rapunzel escapes from the tower by cutting her hair with scissors from her kitchen (one wonders why she didn't try this sooner), and becomes the kingdom's most overdressed traveller.</p>
<p>Eventually, Rapunzel finds the prince and develops a plan to rid the witch of her powers.</p>
<p>It's all very empowering for little girls. Yet the puzzles feature many stereotypical &quot;girl&quot; activities, such as dressing up, cleaning, cake decorating, and matching pieces of gowns.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Classic Rock Guitar, Volume 2&quot; (Windows, $60) -- The second in Ubi Soft's &quot;Learn &amp; Play&quot; series, this CD-ROM teaches guitar techniques for people who already have some basic chord-playing skills. It uses seven John Lennon/Paul McCartney songs for the demonstrations. There are 70 lessons in all.</p>
<p>&quot;Custom House&quot; (Sierra On-Line, Windows, $50) lets a computer owner design every room in a house, either from scratch or using 50 standard room layouts and over 250 specific floor plans. Once done, a three-dimensional walkthrough shows what each room will look like.</p>
<p>&quot;The Treasure Hunt&quot; (OmniMedia, Windows/Macintosh, $30) is for ages 4 to 9 and features a band of pirate mice who have to get their ship, the Barleycorn, to safety. It's based on the Amanda Wood children's story.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
