<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="440285" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Active Voice, Siemens in alliance.</title>
<headline>Active Voice, Siemens in alliance.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA CLARA, Calif. 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Active Voice Corp and Siemens Business Communication Systems said on Thursday they formed a messaging product alliance worth more than $50 million in software revenues for Active Voice over six years.</p>
<p>The companies will work on products that break down the barriers between electronic mail (E-mail), voice mail, facsimiles and mixed media files, using a system based on Microsoft Corp's Windows NT software.</p>
<p>They say the market for such products is expected to be worth $6 billion by 2001.  Siemens Business Communications is part of Siemens AG of Germany.  </p>
<p>&quot;This relationship represents a major commitment by both companies to pool our combined strengths in technology, sales and support,&quot; said Robert Richmond, chairman of Active Voice.</p>
<p>Active Voice specialises in voice processing services.</p>
<p>The plan is to provide a single &quot;in-box&quot; so that an executives can call in and have E-mails read or faxed to them, or can use a computer to access voicemail for example.</p>
<p>A big complaint among busy executives, particularly those who travel frequently, is that there are too many places that separately need to be checked for messages.</p>
<p>Siemens will make the products in its Cherry Hill, N.J., plant, and have exclusive worldwide distribution rights.  The first messaging products are expected to be available later this year. (( Nick Louth, New York Newsroom 212 859 1712))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA CLARA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
