<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441149" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: D.Telekom outlines online deal with Microsoft.</title>
<headline>D.Telekom outlines online deal with Microsoft.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>HANOVER, Germany 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>German phone giant Deutsche Telekom AG on Thursday outlined the details of its online deal with Microsoft Corp and said it planned to expand high-speed telecoms networks and improve home-banking.</p>
<p>While the deal with Microsoft emerged earlier this week appears to conflict with previously announced plans by Deutsche Telekom and Bertelsmann AG to form an alliance with America Online in Europe, officials from both companies sought to play down any dissonance.</p>
<p>When the plans with Bertelsmann were announced last year, the companies held open the option of exchanging stakes between T-Online and the European unit of America Online, the U.S. online service in which Bertelsmann holds a stake.</p>
<p>But the planned tie-up between Telekom and Bertelsmann was being forged on the assumption that Microsoft News (MSN) would steamroller its way through Europe after its launch, but the service has floundered and has fewer than 100,000 subscribers in Germany.</p>
<p>As a result, it is unlikely that regulators would allow any sort of merger or equity swap between T-Online and AOL.</p>
<p>&quot;We never said we wanted to form an alliance against Microsoft and it also is not true that what we are doing today with Microsoft is directed against Bertelsmann,&quot; said Telekom board member Herbert May at the CeBIT technology fair.</p>
<p>He declined to comment further on talks with Bertelsmann, saying only: &quot;Certainly on the basis of anti-trust considerations there will be no exchange of capital.&quot;</p>
<p>Bernd Schiphorst, director of Bertelsmann's online activities, said that with the slow take up of MSN the situation had changed but that talks with Telekom had not collapsed.</p>
<p>&quot;Talks are continuing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The deal between T-Online and Microsoft also appears to be more bark than bite and is restricted to joint distribution of each other's online service and software licencing.</p>
<p>&quot;T-Online is a means of access,&quot; said Knut Foekler, head of MSN in Germany. &quot;It's a distribution deal not unlike what we have agreed with other carriers such as MCI.&quot;</p>
<p>Bernard Vergnes, president of Microsoft Europe, also made clear that T-Online customers were not getting a free lunch from Microsoft. While MSN would be accessible through T-Online, it would only be accessible to paying MSN customers.</p>
<p>&quot;They must be MSN subscribers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wolfgang Keuntje, head of T-Online's parent company, Online Pro Dienste GmbH, confirmed this, saying that T-Online offered itself as a platform and provided certain services such as billing and some customer management for MSN.</p>
<p>&quot;We are providing access to MSN and making its content available for T-Online subscribers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The two companies must still work out the charges to T-Online customers for accessing MSN and what MSN will pay for any subscriber management services provided by Telekom.</p>
<p>&quot;These talks will begin soon. We have not yet discussed price models,&quot; said Foekler.</p>
<p>So what is an alliance at the end of the day?</p>
<p>&quot;Some four million users of Windows 95 in Germany will be able to click and get access to T-Online,&quot; said Vergnes.</p>
<p>The two companies also plan to jointly market Internet and intranet technologies based on Microsoft BackOffice and the Microsoft Commercial Internet System, server technology that is meant to enhance security for electronic commerce.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOVER, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
