<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442701" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Hot techs see some rolling.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Hot techs see some rolling.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some investors were rolling March positions out to April and beyond, particularly in some of the often-active technology stock options, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>March options expire at the end of next week. Among the most active options Friday were Micron Technology Inc on the Pacific Stock Exchange (PSE) andd Oracle Corp on the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE).</p>
<p>Most of the activity in both sets of options was on the call side, with both stocks trading higher.  </p>
<p>In Friday trading, Micron shares closed up three at 45 on turnover of about 10.6 million shares.</p>
<p>Oracle gained 4-7/8 to 41 on 17.2 million shares.</p>
<p>Gruntal repeated a neutral rating on Micron and Oracle reported better-than-expected earnings after the close on Thursday.</p>
<p>Michael Schwartz, a managing director at Oppenheimer &amp; Co, said open interest and volume in some of the Micron options suggested investors had begun closing out March positions and opening new ones in April ahead of next week's expiration.  </p>
<p>&quot;The open interest is quite substantial in the March 40's and March 35's,&quot; he said. &quot;It looks like the beginnings of some rolling.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that a good percentage of the volume in the March 45 call was likely from investors rolling over March positions into April.</p>
<p>The Micron March 45 call had open interest of 6,422 contracts and volume of abou 5,700.</p>
<p>Open interest in the March 40 call was 18,656. It traded 3,475 contracts.</p>
<p>A couple Micron March puts were busy, but Schwartz said it did not appear much was rolled out into April.  </p>
<p>The Micron March 40 put traded nearly 3,600 contracts and the March 42-1/2 put traded 1,655.</p>
<p>&quot;The puts are not being rolled unless they're being rolled up&quot; to higher strike prices, Schwartz said.</p>
<p>In the Oracle options, it appeared some investors were rolling out of March and up in strike price, he said. Most action was on the call side.</p>
<p>The Oracle March 40 call, which had open interest of 12,885 contracts, traded 5,110 contracts, making it the most active in the group. The April 45 call traded 4,680 contracts. Its open interest was just 1,702 contracts.  </p>
<p>&quot;It looks like some rolling going out even further (than April) in some cases,&quot; Schwartz said, noting the strong volume in the Oracle June 45 call, which traded nearly 1,800 contracts.</p>
<p>The most active Oracle put was the March 40, with turnover of around 2,180. Open interest was a strong 10,520.</p>
<p>&quot;There are still some big put positions,&quot; Schwartz said. &quot;I don't see much rolling there. I guess they don't feel the squeeze to have to rush in to push those forward with the stock still above the strike,&quot; he said. ((--G.Crawford, 312 408 8750/Email: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
