<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443067" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German software group, AMD take CeBIT awards.</title>
<headline>German software group, AMD take CeBIT awards.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>HANOVER, Germany 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Software maker Star Division GmbH's &quot;Star Office&quot; was chosen by a leading German computer magazine as winner of both the best German software and best software awards at this year's CeBIT trade fair.</p>
<p>The so-called &quot;CeBIT Oscar&quot; went to Star Division's flagship product, a basic office programme that allows office workers to do all of their basic tasks and is fully integrated with the Internet.</p>
<p>While the award has no official quality, it is respected in CeBIT circles and highlights the fact that as German unemployment hovers at its highest levels since World War Two a growing number of innovative companies are gaining respect.</p>
<p>Marco Boerries, the young founder of Star Division GmbH, gave a boyish grin as he accepted the award, which not only expressed a certain satisfaction, but also seemed to reveal that he recognised how far such a small honour can go.</p>
<p>&quot;This prize has a lot of meaning for me because now with Star Office 4.0 we are in a position to move beyond Germany,&quot; he said at the award ceremony on Friday in Hanover.</p>
<p>Star Division will launch Star Office in the U.S. and seek a listing on the Nasdaq stock exchange this year. Sweeping the awards at Europe's biggest computer fair is just another feather in its bonnet to show U.S. investors.</p>
<p>Launched two weeks ago, the latest version of Star Office is already finding support from computer retailers, including Vobis Microcomputer AG, which will pre-install the software on new its PCs, Boerries told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be lots more. At the first of April a lot of people will start bundling Star Office,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The prize is awarded each year by Chip magazine, one of Germany's most established computer monthlies. In addition to the software awards there is an award for the best hardware innovation and the best communications product.</p>
<p>The best hardware award went to Advanced Micro Devices Inc for its K6 microprocessor for personal computers, which will be officially launched next month to compete with Intel Corp, the market leader, with its popular Pentium chip.</p>
<p>&quot;At CeBIT the successor to the Pentium has not yet been a real issue,&quot; said Michael Ardelt, head of Chip publisher Vogel Computer Verlag. &quot;But behind the scenes the whole CeBIT is talking about it.&quot;</p>
<p>Cornelsen Software, a German eductational software group, won the best communications award for its programme &quot;Master Detectives Hunt Lork,&quot; a programme that combines offline and online elements to teach German to primary school children.</p>
<p>&quot;Almost all the products we considered in this area aimed at improving access to the Internet,&quot; said Rainer Garbowski, chief editor of Chip magazine. &quot;Finally there is a product that seeks to improve the content.&quot;</p>
<p>Garbowski, aware that some might charge the awards were biased in favour of German manufacturers, said the panel of judges sifted through more than 1,500 products and narrowed this to 50 before making a final decision on Thursday.</p>
<p>If one thing has marked this year's CeBIT it has been the absence of announcements of new, ground-breaking products.</p>
<p>While many European companies in the past have used the CeBIT as the launching pad for new products, the accelerated pace of change in the industry has made this nearly impossible so that the majority of the nearly 7,000 exhibitors came with the clear intention of doing business, not making news.</p>
<p>&quot;More than 95 percent of exhibitors do business with each other here,&quot; said Joerg Schomburg, board member of Deutsche Messe AG, which organises CeBIT.</p>
<p>&quot;But this is no longer a place for big announcements. The trend that we observe is that there is increasing pressure to get products to market quickly,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOVER, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
