<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444854" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft, Intel mysteriously absent rejigged Dow.</title>
<headline>Microsoft, Intel mysteriously absent rejigged Dow.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The absence of Microsoft Corp. and Intel Corp. from the stocks picked to join the newly revised &quot;Dow 30&quot; has left many analysts sceptical of how serious Dow Jones &amp; Co. is about making its blue-chip index more reflective of the American economy.</p>
<p>The most world's most widely tracked stock market barometer replaced four lagging stocks with four new ones to become less smokestack-oriented and more technology-related in a bid to closely represent the economy.</p>
<p>Added to the list were computer maker Hewlett-Packard Corp., health care products company Johnson &amp; Johnson, top U.S. retailer Wal-Mart Stores Inc. and insurance company Travelers Group Inc.. Dropped were Bethlehem Steel Corp., Westinghouse Electric Corp., Texaco Inc. and retailer Woolworth Corp..</p>
<p>&quot;Adding Hewlett-Packard brings the Dow closer to true 'high-tech,' but I would have liked to see more. I'm really waiting for Microsoft,&quot; said Bill LeFevre, senior market analyst at Ehrenkrantz King Nussbaum.</p>
<p>Currently, technology is weighted in the 30-stock average through International Business Machines Corp. and United Technologies Corp..</p>
<p>&quot;Hewlett-Packard is a franchise leader. But to exclude Intel and Microsoft? Clearly, that would make the average more representative,&quot; said Richard Cripps, chief market strategist at Legg Mason Wood Walker.</p>
<p>A common misconception on Wall Street is that only New York Stock Exchange-listed companies can join Wall Street's most exclusive corporate club, automatically excluding Microsoft and Intel, which are traded on the Nasdaq market.</p>
<p>Not so, according to a Dow Jones spokesman.</p>
<p>Although historically all companies in the Dow have been listed on the NYSE, &quot;being listed on the Nasdaq is not a disqualifying factor at all,&quot; said Dow Jones spokesman Roger May. He noted that Nasdaq-listed truck company Yellow Corp. is a component of the Dow Jones Transportation Average.</p>
<p>That makes the absence of Microsoft and Intel even more baffling, market analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It really is part of the battle between the Nasdaq and NYSE. I just don't think Microsoft and Intel are serving the public by staying listed on the Nasdaq,&quot; said Frank Calta, director of trading at Anvil Institutional Services.</p>
<p>The changes in the Dow, the first such in six years, create more volatility, analysts said.</p>
<p>A move of one-eighth of a point in Dow stocks has been worth about 0.38 of a point change in the index, known as the divisor. With the new change, it will be worth slightly more than 0.40 of a point. Full details about the new divisor will be released on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;This makes for a much more dangerous Dow,&quot; said Harry Laubscher, market analyst for Tucker Anthony. He said that in the shift, three undervalued stocks will be replaced with three overvalued stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The upshot is the Dow is likely to be hit harder during any major market decines because they lose the undervalued stocks that would provide some support,&quot; Laubscher said.</p>
<p>Texaco, reacting to its removal from the prestigious index, said, &quot;It is the privilege of Dow Jones to revise the index. Oil companies are still represented by Exxon and Chevron. We do not see much of an impact; investors will judge us on our performance.&quot;</p>
<p>Neither Microsoft nor the Nasdaq could be reached for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
