<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449976" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: IBM, Lotus to invest in Malaysia.</title>
<headline>IBM, Lotus to invest in Malaysia.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Business Machines (IBM) and its subsidiary Lotus Development Corp will invest around 10 million ringgit over the next two years in Malaysia.</p>
<p>&quot;Collectively Lotus and IBM will, in the next 24 months, invest something on the order of 10 million ringgit,&quot; in the &quot;Multimedia Super Corridor&quot;, Lotus president Jeff Papows told a news conference on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Papows was on a visit to Malaysia to explore investment opportunities in the 'super corridor,' a 15-km by 50-km zone stretching from Kuala Lumpur south to where a new airport and federal capital are under construction.</p>
<p>He met Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He said Lotus will use Malaysia's diverse ethnic population to develop training courses for the entire Asian region from India to China. The investment will also cover recording labs and original software research, he said.</p>
<p>Malaysia is emphasising its multilingual workforce -- it has Malay, Indian and Chinese communities -- as an attraction for companies marketing products throughout Asia.</p>
<p>Papows said Lotus was interested in two projects in the 'corridor,' &quot;the paperless administration system&quot; of the new federal capital and so-called &quot;smart schools&quot; using internet technololgy that Malaysia is developing.</p>
<p>The Lotus president said revenues from the booming Asia market exceeded that of Europe for the first time last year. Lotus' Asian revenue increased by 128 percent in 1996 over the previous year, he said.</p>
<p>Lotus has decided to make Malaysia the headquarters for its franchise education system called &quot;the Asia Pacific Lotus Authorised Education Centre&quot;, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
