<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453308" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Yahoo! to pay Netscape $5 mln plus ad revs.</title>
<headline>Yahoo! to pay Netscape $5 mln plus ad revs.</headline>
<dateline>MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif. 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yahoo Inc said Wednesday it will pay Netscape Communications Corp a one-time fee of $5 million for use of the Netscape brand name as well as advertising revenue from the new &quot;Netscape Guide by Yahoo!&quot;</p>
<p>Yahoo, which will sell advertising on the new site, has agreed to pay Netscape a minimum $10 million in the first year of the deal and $15 million in the second year from advertising revenues.  </p>
<p>Additional advertising revenue will be split between the two companies, with the majority of those revenues going to Yahoo.  The companies declined to give any advertising revenue projections but Netscape said that if their internal projections panned out, the service would be &quot;a great benefit&quot; to the revenues of both companies.</p>
<p>Netscape said that new sites like &quot;Netscape Guide by Yahoo!&quot; will help the fledgling Internet advertising market to grow from $300 million to $1 billion by helping to attract big consumer advertisers to the medium.  </p>
<p>The new service, a personalized guide to the Internet which will showcase the best sites on the Web, is set to launch during the second quarter of 1997 and users of previous versions of Netscape Navigator will be able to access the site by clicking on the Destinations button of their browsers.</p>
<p>&quot;Netscape Guide by Yahoo!&quot; is a general navigation service targeted at consumers which, among other things, will allow users to configure their own front pages to meet personal tastes as well as customized news feeds.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Yahoo! will be responsible for the programming, production, operations and ad sales of the new service, along with What's New, What's Cool, People and Yellow Pages on Netscape's Internet site.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
