<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453851" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Netscape in deal with four search firms.</title>
<headline>Netscape in deal with four search firms.</headline>
<dateline>MOUNTAIN VIEW, California 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Netscape Communications Corp. said on Tuesday it has struck a fresh deal with the four public internet search companies, and will also announce a separate deal with Yahoo! on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Under the multi-company deal, Netscape has agreed to recognize Excite Inc., Infoseek Corp., Lycos Inc. and Yahoo! Inc as Premier Providers for its new Netscape Search program to start on May 1.</p>
<p>The program would replace one in which the four companies and McKinley Group, which Excite acquired last summer, had each paid roughly $5 million to Netscape for a place on the &quot;search&quot; button on the Netscape home page.</p>
<p>Netscape's home page remains the most heavily-accessed site on the World Wide Web, according to surveys of Internet traffic, in part because its Navigator browser is programmed to start out at the Netscape site.</p>
<p>No information was immediately available about the financial terms of the latest &quot;search&quot; button contract.</p>
<p>Netscape said the four premier providers would be featured on tabs, with rotating prominence between them. It said a fifth tab could be customized by users from a list of Marquee Providers, including Excite's Webcrawler, which it procured from America Online.</p>
<p>The new Search page would also enable users to select one provider to appear as their favorite, enjoying the prominent position whenever Netscape Search is accessed.</p>
<p>As part of the deal, the search providers would continue to be Netscape Flagship partners, displaying a Netscape Now button prominently on their own services and using Netscape client and server software for their sites.</p>
<p>A &quot;button&quot; on a Web page is a graphic image which a user may point at using a computer mouse or other pointing device, and move to another site by clicking on the image.</p>
<p>Netscape and Yahoo! said they would outline terms of a second, essentially unrelated deal on Wednesday morning in a teleconference call. No further details were immediately available, although a Yahoo! spokeswoman said a news release will be issued ahead of Wednesday's market open.</p>
<p>The Netscape-Yahoo! deal would be financially material to Yahoo!, according to the company's spokeswoman.</p>
<p>The C/Net online news service reported late on Tuesday that the latter agreement would be a multimillion dollar contract for Yahoo! to manage Netscape's &quot;destinations&quot; pages on its site. These highlight leading-edge sites.</p>
<p>Both companies declined to provide details.</p>
<p>Search company executives have said Netscape was holding a hotly-contested bidding contest for a company to run its destinations site, which would relieve Netscape from day-to-day operational support responsibilities while likely still providing a significant revenue stream.</p>
<p>-- sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau 415 846 5400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOUNTAIN VIEW, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
