<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="463692" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Reed-Elsevier makes U.S. science deal.</title>
<headline>Reed-Elsevier makes U.S. science deal.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Kelly</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reed Elsevier said on Monday it planned a $320 million public offer for MDL Information Systems Inc. in a deal expected to further strengthen the Anglo-Dutch group's lucrative science publishing business.</p>
<p>Reed Elsevier said its Elsevier Science Inc unit would offer $32 a share for California-based MDL, a supplier of scientific information management systems, under terms unanimously approved by the boards of both companies.</p>
<p>The Anglo-Dutch group said it would use part of its cash balance of more than one billion pounds ($1.6 billion) to pay for MDL.</p>
<p>It said the planned acquisition would bring together the leading provider of scientific information with the leading provider of systems to manage and analyse such data.</p>
<p>MDL's software systems, databases and services help customers in the chemical, pharmaceutical and biotechnology industries to manage, analyse and communicate high volumes of research and development material, it said.</p>
<p>The U.S. company made a pre-tax profit of $11 million in the year to March 31, 1996 on revenues of $62 million.</p>
<p>In February it signed a deal worth several million dollars over three years to supply software and services to British-based Glaxo Wellcome Plc, the world's biggest pharmaceutical company.</p>
<p>Reed Elsevier had revenues of 3.38 billion pounds in 1996 of which 553 million came from science publishing, making it the world's biggest player in this field.</p>
<p>Science publishing is Reed Elsevier's most lucrative business, generating pre-tax profits of 231 million pounds -- a profit margin of 41.8 percent.</p>
<p>Elsevier Science publishes over 1,200 scientific journals and plans to start delivering them through an online database connection this year under the name of Science Direct.</p>
<p>Reed Elsevier co-chairman Herman Bruggink said MDL's products enhanced the productivity and speed of scientific research and were a good strategic fit with Elsevier Science.</p>
<p>&quot;There are considerable opportunities, particularly in an online environment, to add further value to the customers of both MDL and Elsevier Science through the electronic linkage of data,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Board member Paul Vlek told Reuters that MDL would start making a positive contribution to the group's earnings from 1998.</p>
<p>Analysts welcomed the deal, saying MDL would mesh well with Elsevier's existing science publishing business and give an extra push to its plans for electronic distribution.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of multiples of sales and profits the (purchase sum) is pretty substantial...but I think the synergy advantages will justify that,&quot; said Patrick Wollenberg of Rabo Securities.</p>
<p>Jeff Meys of ABN AMRO Hoare Govett said Reed Elsevier planned to pay 32 times MDL's historic earnings before interest and tax which might seem high for a publishing company but was a reasonable multiple in the information technology sector.</p>
<p>He applauded Reed Elsevier's patience in waiting for the right acquisition candidate to come along.</p>
<p>&quot;With the money they were sitting on, any acquisition would have been earnings enhancing...but waiting for the things to come along you really want is good management,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On the Amsterdam bourse Elsevier shares closed 0.10 lower at 28.80 guilders while the main market index fell 1.7 percent.</p>
<p>In London trade Reed International shares fell 23 pence to 10.80 pounds. In morning Nasdaq trade in New York MDL shares were up $13.875 at $31.125 after closing at $17.25 on Friday before the Reed Elsevier bid was announced. ($ = 0.623 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
