<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="472328" id="root" date="1997-03-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apple stock rises as Oracle chairman mulls bid again. [CORRECTED 23:16 GMT]</title>
<headline>Apple stock rises as Oracle chairman mulls bid again. [CORRECTED 23:16 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-03-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>(Corrects by removing last three paragraphs, as Steve Jobs was incorrectedly reported to have recently become a member of the Apple board).</p>
<p>By Kourosh Karimkhany</p>
<p>The stock of Apple Computer Inc.  rose more than 11 percent in heavy trading Thursday on a report that the chairman of software company Oracle Corp.  said once again he was interested in buying the troubled computer maker.</p>
<p>Oracle Chairman Larry Ellison told the San Jose Mercury News Wednesday that he was forming an investor group to raise $1 billion to buy a majority stake in Apple.</p>
<p>Ellison, a flamboyant software billionaire, has said since April 1995 that he would like to buy Apple with his own money, partly to prevent Microsoft Corp.  from dominating the computer industry.</p>
<p>Based on its stock price, Apple is worth $2.17 billion. Ellison's stake in Oracle is worth about $6 billion.</p>
<p>Apple rose $1.875 to close at $18.625, while Oracle fell $1.125 to $39.375 on Nasdaq, where both stocks were among the most active issues.</p>
<p>Late in the day, traders said, a bloc of two million Apple shares was traded by Goldman Sachs at $19 a share.</p>
<p>Ellison told the newspaper he was publicly reasserting his interest in buying Apple partly to gauge investor support in the next few days. Based on the reaction, he will decide soon whether to make a bid.</p>
<p>Previously, he has said he approached unidentified big investors about a joint bid. He also has mulled the idea with his friend Steve Jobs, the Apple co-founder who was kicked out of the company in 1985 and returned in December as a part-time adviser to Apple Chairman Gilbert Amelio.</p>
<p>Ellison could not be reached for comment. Katie Cotton, Apple spokeswoman, said the Cupertino, Calif.-based company had no comments about Ellison.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts said they doubted Ellison actually would attempt to buy Apple because he has not taken any concrete steps in the two years that he has expressed an interest.</p>
<p>&quot;The deal doesn't make sense for (any outside investor) to take him up on it,&quot; said David Wu, analyst at investment bank ABN Ambro Chicago Corp.</p>
<p>Still, Ellison's comments should not be dismissed, some analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a mistake to analyze this as a pure business issue, as there is substantial ego involved,&quot; said Paul Saffo, a tracker of Apple and Ellison and a research fellow at Institute for the Future, a Silicon Valley think tank.</p>
<p>Ellison, the third-richest software tycoon behind Microsoft co-founders Bill Gates and Paul Allen, is intent on slowing Microsoft's dominance of the software industry, he has said in recent interviews. Apple, with its huge following of Macintosh fans, could be a key weapon.</p>
<p>Saffo also said Jobs, since returning to Apple late last year, has been very influential in trimming the company and could be &quot;sprucing up&quot; Apple for an acquisition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
