<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="475390" id="root" date="1997-03-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apple CEO says bid talk will not distract him - paper.</title>
<headline>Apple CEO says bid talk will not distract him - paper.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-03-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Apple Computer Inc. Chairman and CEO Gil Amelio said in a newspaper interview published Saturday he will not be distracted by prospects of a potential takeover bid.</p>
<p>Amelio, speaking out for the first time about the possibility of a hostile bid from an investor group led by Oracle Corp CEO Larry Ellison, told the editorial board of the San Francisco Chronicle that he does not believe a takeover bid is actually in the cards.</p>
<p>&quot;I just cannot let this be a big distraction,&quot; he was quoted as saying. &quot;I will not get into a mode reacting to Larry Ellison.&quot;</p>
<p>Ellison confirmed his interest Thursday in making a bid for a controlling interest in the struggling computer maker, saying he and an unspecified investor group had set up an electronic mailbox to seek comments from investors, employees, customers and others interested in Apple.</p>
<p>The Chronicle said Amelio had said he doubted a bid was truly in the offing, pledging to remain personally above the fray, but it said Apple attorneys were dusting off its shareholder rights plan just in case.</p>
<p>Shareholder rights plans, otherwise known as a poison pill, enable a company to defend itself against a hostile bid by issuing new shares to existing holders at lower prices, diluting any stake a bidder might acquire.</p>
<p>&quot;If shareholders decide they want to do something different, it's their company,&quot; Amelio told the Chronicle, but he also said there were &quot;no obvious candidates at this time&quot; to play the role of a white knight for Apple.</p>
<p>Ellison said in an interview published Thursday in the San Jose Mercury News that he would sack Amelio and other top managers if he were to succeed in his bid.</p>
<p>Ellison said any bid would be independent of Oracle, and told the Mercury News he was seeking to raise about $1 billion so he could offer current shareholders 60 percent cash and 40 percent equity in the new Apple.</p>
<p>Apple shares rose in heavy trading Thursday, the last day of trading before the Easter break, closing up $1.875 at $18.625 in Nasdaq trading.</p>
<p>But analysts and industry insiders have noted this is not Ellison's first public overture towards Apple, noting he had talked of taking over the computer maker as long ago as April 1995.</p>
<p>Some analysts also said there was little incentive for investors to agree to the deal so long as Ellison seemed determined not to offer a price above current levels.</p>
<p>Amelio said he had tried to contact Ellison after his statements, but without success.</p>
<p>Steve Jobs, the co-founder of Apple who came back aboard as an adviser this winter after Apple agreed to acquire Jobs' Next Software Inc., was also quoted by the Chronicle as distancing himself from Ellison's bid plans.</p>
<p>&quot;Larry's my best friend,&quot; Jobs told the newspaper.</p>
<p>But Jobs said he was focusing his attention on advising Amelio and putting together a top management team at Apple, saying &quot;I don't know about this takeover bid. I have nothing to do with it.&quot;</p>
<p>Ellison, the third-richest software tycoon behind Microsoft Corp co-founders Bill Gates and Paul Allen, is intent on slowing Microsoft's dominance of the software industry, he has said in recent interviews.</p>
<p>Apple, with its huge following of Macintosh fans, could be a key weapon in that battle.</p>
<p>Apple has suffered declining market share for its famous brand of easy-to-use computers and endured several rounds of restructuring in recent years while its shares have been languishing just above their 10-year lows.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
