<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="478022" id="root" date="1997-04-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Strong large-cap tech profits may end sector slump.</title>
<headline>Strong large-cap tech profits may end sector slump.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong earnings by bellwether technology companies could serve as a catalyst to boost the broader technology sector out of its slump, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to see a couple of good companies put out some good numbers. Then maybe this concern in the market will ease,&quot; said Phil Orlando, chief investment officer of Value Line Asset Management.  </p>
<p>If industry giants such as International Business Machines Corp and Microsoft Corp report solid earnings, as expected, the recent decline in technology stocks could come to a quick halt. But investors will probably have to wait until the second half of the year to see significant gains, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite index has fallen about 13 percent from its peak of 1388 on January 22, pressured in the past two days by a slew of dismal earnings warnings from companies such as FORE Systems Inc, Shiva Corp, Cascade Communications Corp and Informix Corp.  </p>
<p>But investor confidence seems to shift almost daily.</p>
<p>Technology stocks got a slight boost last week amid optimism that major computer, software and chip companies will report solid first-quarter earnings. But this week, earnings warnings from several networking companies erased those gains.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a jumpy market. Investors are reacting or overreacting to everything. Everything is seen as a sign. People are just really nervous. The real direction will come when the big boys report their earnings,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Investors have been unforgiving with companies that are expected to fall short of Wall Street earnings expectations. Quickturn Design Systems Inc, which produces system level verification software used in the design of integrated circuits, fell 7-7/8 to 8-1/16 in the wake of its earnigs warning. Informix Corp and FORE Systems Inc also stumbled on earnings forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not the kind of market where you want to disappoint. When you do, they just pull you apart,&quot; said Brett Discher, vice president of equity trading at Dain Bosworth.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's the cockroach theory on Wall Street that says if you see one, there's probably more. There's a lot of concern about the quarter,&quot; Orlando said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the reality is that it is a vibrant industry with about five years of tremendous growth ahead. They will rally in the back nine months of the year,&quot; Orlando said.</p>
<p>Orlando expects technology stocks to rebound later in the year, erasing the recent slump and hitting new highs.</p>
<p>SoundView Financial Group Inc analyst Mark Specker said believes personal computer makers could benefit from a sooner-than-expected increase in spending.</p>
<p>The acceleration in spending could give computer makers a boost starting in the second quarter and into the third quarter, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
