<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="481884" id="root" date="1997-04-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FileNet sees Q1 loss due to weak orders.</title>
<headline>FileNet sees Q1 loss due to weak orders.</headline>
<dateline>COSTA MESA, Calif. 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>FileNet Corp said it expects to report a first quarter net loss of about $9.0 million or $0.60 per share on revenues of $47 million due to weak orders in domestic and international markets.</p>
<p>In the first quarter last year, FileNet posted a net loss of $11.8 million or $0.79 a share, including a one-time, after-tax charge of $16 million, on revenues of $66.7 million.</p>
<p>FileNet dropped 4-3/4 to 11-1/8 and was one of the most active Nasdaq issues in late morning trade.  </p>
<p>&quot;New orders were unexpectedly weak for the quarter,&quot; said FileNet Chief Executive Ted Smith. &quot;The weakness was experienced in both our domestic and international markets. In particular, several large orders solicited by our European and North American sales organizations did not come through.&quot;</p>
<p>FileNet, which makes integrated image, data processing systems using optical disk technology, also said it expects to take a second quarter charge of between $2.5 million and $3.0 million to consolidate its imaging product development groups.</p>
<p>The imaging product activities will be relocated to Costa Mesa, Calif. from its current facilites in Burlington, Mass.  </p>
<p>FileNet also said it will begin cutting an unspecified number of jobs and reduce hiring during the second quarter in an effort to &quot;adjust its expense levels.&quot;</p>
<p>The company said it will post restructuring charges related to these changes in the second quarter of 1997, but the extent of the charge cannot be determined until a restructuring plan is completed.</p>
<p>Prudential Securities said Wednesday it downgraded FileNet to hold from buy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COSTA MESA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
