<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485189" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Skeptics question AOL-CompuServe match.</title>
<headline>Skeptics question AOL-CompuServe match.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street analysts grew more skeptical Thursday about America Online Inc possibly buying rival online computer service CompuServe Corp, while both companies kept quiet.</p>
<p>Repeating earlier comments, CompuServe said it and parent H&amp;R Block Inc were &quot;in external discussions regarding a possible business combination involving CompuServe.&quot;</p>
<p>Discussions with AOL have taken place, and may still be going on, analysts agreed. But several added that they viewed an AOL-CompuServe merger as ill-advised and improbable.  </p>
<p>&quot;An AOL-CompuServe deal is highly unlikely. We just don't think it's going to happen. Anyone who suggests it will should check their sources,&quot; said Cowen &amp; Co analyst Scott Reamer.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (CompuServe) has talked to AOL in the past, but I think there's a lot of other people they could be talking to,&quot; said Nesbitt Burns analyst Abhishek Gami.</p>
<p>Whispered by analysts as additional possible CompuServe suitors were AT&amp;T Corp, Microsoft Corp, MCI Communications Corp, Sprint Corp, British Telecommunications Plc and the Baby Bells, as well as former CompuServe managers joined in a venture capital firm.  </p>
<p>The giants may be wary of online services due to the problems that International Business Machines Corp and Sears Roebuck and Co had with Prodigy before selling it last year, said Widmann Siff analyst Ernest Widmann.</p>
<p>But analysts also said larger players would be much better placed than AOL to pay cash for CompuServe, which is 80 percent owned by Kansas City, Mo.-based Block and could fetch as much as $2 billion. &quot;Microsoft and AT&amp;T could pay more,&quot; said Brean Murray analyst Barbara Chacour.</p>
<p>Still, Block has been trying so long to break away from CompuServe that it might bite at an AOL offer, analysts said.  </p>
<p>AOL's balance sheet would not easily permit a cash deal. &quot;I suppose there's some way an investment banking firm might structure something,&quot; said Dean Witter analyst Paul Mackey.</p>
<p>More likely, however, would be an offer comprised largely of AOL stock. &quot;If Block took stock in AOL, it would only make their situation worse, not better,&quot; Mackey said.  </p>
<p>An AOL spokesman declined to comment. Block repeated CompuServe's statement. Shares in Dulles, Va.-based AOL, the No. 1 online service, were up 3/4 to 45-1/2 in late trading Thursday. Shares in Columbus, Ohio-based CompuServe, the No. 2 online service, were off 1/8 to 12-1/2.</p>
<p>Even if a deal could be done, analysts questioned its wisdom and workability. &quot;It would be a tough merger because these companies have hated each other,&quot; Chacour said.</p>
<p>A CompuServe acquisition would add about 1.6 million North American subscribers and more than 850,000 European subscribers to AOL's existing base of eight million members.</p>
<p>&quot;However, we believe a stock swap merger at $14 would cause a roughly 30-percent dilution for America Online stockholders,&quot; said Everen Securities analyst Anthony Blenk.</p>
<p>AOL has had so much success gaining customers on its own that buying CompuServe would add little value, Reamer said.</p>
<p>At the same time, some analysts said it might be smart of AOL to scoop up CompuServe. &quot;I'd be surprised if they came together, but who knows,&quot; Widmann said.</p>
<p>((--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
