<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485635" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi prince confident Apple will do better.</title>
<headline>Saudi prince confident Apple will do better.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-04-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diana Abdallah</p>
<p>Saudi billionaire Prince al-Waleed bin Talal said on Thursday he had bought five percent of Apple Computer because he was confident the California-based computer maker would overcome its troubles.</p>
<p>&quot;I bought these shares alone...I've been looking at the technology sector for more than a year. Apple is a great opportunity and they are going through difficult times but they will pull through,&quot; he told Reuters from his office in Riyadh.</p>
<p>&quot;There is incredible potential to do better,&quot; the prince said, a day after announcing he had bought the Apple shares on the open market over the last weeks for $115 million.</p>
<p>The prince declined to say if he planned to buy more Apple shares: &quot;I am keeping all my options wide open.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he knew software billionaire Larry Ellison, CEO of Oracle Corp. Ellison had expressed interest in making a bid for the struggling computer maker and had formed an investor group to gauge interest in taking over Apple.</p>
<p>&quot;I will listen to Mr Ellison, to Apple management or anybody who will help shareholders' value and will decide if more moves are needed,&quot; the billionaire neohew of Saudi King Fahd said.</p>
<p>Asked if he was in the Ellison group, the prince -- who has made his fortune by investing in troubled companies then helping them to recover -- said he has not discussed Apple with Ellison.</p>
<p>&quot;I respect him a lot and I will listen to what he has to say. Again I am keeping all the options open,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The New York Times said on Thursday Apple was looking for a friendly merger partner and was in talks with Sun Microsystems. Apple has suffered declining market share and endured several rounds of restructuring in recent years while its shares have been languishing just above their 10-year lows.</p>
<p>The purchase of Apple shares was the latest in a string of high-profile acquisitions by the prince in the past month.</p>
<p>On March 19 he said he had bought about five percent of Trans World Airlines Inc. A week later, he said he was buying five percent of the Norwegian Cruise Lines.</p>
<p>Also in March, he said he was building a $500 million complex in his hometown Riyadh, to house a Four Seasons Hotel, dubbed the largest commercial building in the region.</p>
<p>Sources close to him said last month he was nearing a deal to buy the six hotels in the Princess chain from British conglomerate Lonrho for almost $560 million.</p>
<p>Though not huge compared to the prince's other holdings, the investments in Apple, TWA and NCL are part of a new trend to diversify from real estate and entertainment.</p>
<p>&quot;Geography or sectors don't mean anything to me as long as the price is low and the potential is good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Technology is the future and the more diversification the better,&quot; he added. He said he was looking at Europe, the United States and the Far East.</p>
<p>Prince al-Waleed, who turned 40 on March 7, is a grandson of Saudi Arabia's founder Ibn Saud. People who know him say he started with a relatively small amount of money from his father and is now one of the wealthiest business moguls in the kingdom.</p>
<p>He has shares in Citicorp, retailer Saks Fifth Avenue and the Plaza Hotel, the Euro Disney theme park near Paris and Canary Wharf in London's Docklands. He also has stakes in former Italian prime minister Silvio Berlusconi's television and advertising business Mediaset.</p>
<p>Earlier this year he bought Paris' luxury George V hotel. Last year he signed a deal with popstar Michael Jackson to cooperate on concerts, films, television, fun parks and hotels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
