<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="485780" id="root" date="1997-04-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MSNBC unveils new cyberstudio.</title>
<headline>MSNBC unveils new cyberstudio.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Intindola</byline>
<dateline>SECAUCUS, N.J. 1997-04-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>MSNBC, the joint cable television-Internet news operation of NBC and Microsoft Corp., Wednesday opened a futuristic studio equipped with a remarkable array of technology and a big bet on the prospects for interactive news.</p>
<p>The cost of converting the former Jamesway Corp. warehouse several miles west of New York City into MSNBC's fully digital, 115,000-square-foot headquarters was not revealed, though NBC News President Andrew Lack addressed a recent report that put the cost at between $45 million and $65 million.</p>
<p>&quot;It was closer to $65 million,&quot; Lack said at a preview of the studio.</p>
<p>Microsoft's vice president for news and commentary, Peter Neupert, said, &quot;This facility is the next step in the implementation of our shared vision of how to change the way news is delivered.</p>
<p>&quot;Sometime in the future, personal computers and television will merge. We have put a stake in the ground. That is a medium we want to own,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the new facility, news reporters, writers and producers will work side by side with Internet specialists, permitting a more efficient integration of the various media, including online, cable and broadcast, encompassed by NBC's news operation, the executives said.</p>
<p>The building will formally open April 7 after MSNBC leaves its old studio in Fort Lee, N.J, which, like Secaucus, is across the Hudson River from Manhattan.</p>
<p>In addition to the new cable TV studio, MSNBC has an extensive Internet operation based in Redmond, Wash., where software giant Microsoft is headquartered.</p>
<p>MSNBC's 100-foot-by-150-foot main newsroom is designed to make news production -- long performed off-camera -- part of a high-tech show amid smokestack industry motifs clashing with floor-to-ceiling digital effects and, of course, dozens of computer workstations and televisions.</p>
<p>Exposed warehouse brick, tin ceilings and riveted girders are interspersed with video walls and robotic cameras that zoom about 120 workstations ringing a revolving anchor desk.</p>
<p>A 70-foot-wide glass wall etched with the image of a ciruit board separates the newsroom from an area that is home to the assignment desk that coordinates all NBC news gathering around the world.</p>
<p>Seven satellite dishes sit atop the building, which from the outside resembles the warehouse it once was.</p>
<p>Launched last July, MSNBC reaches 35 million homes, exceeding by 2 million the penetration cable companies forecast for 2000, according to David Zaslav, president of NBC cable distribution.</p>
<p>With that goal surpassed, he said, the cable companies now are guaranteeing a reach of 56 million homes by the end of the century.</p>
<p>As for the cable station's advertising, Mark Harrington vice president and general manager of MSNBC cable, declined to provide specific figures, but said the station now claims 120 national advertisers, up from 70 when the venture was launched last year. NBC is a unit of General Electric Co.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SECAUCUS, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
