<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489698" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Exxon and General Electric top Forbes 500 list.</title>
<headline>Exxon and General Electric top Forbes 500 list.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Exxon Corp and General Electric Co are co-champions this year, topping the Forbes Super 100 list with the distinction of being America's top companies.</p>
<p>The Forbes list of 500 of the country's top corporations ranks them according to sales, profits, assets and market value.</p>
<p>Forbes magazine, in its 29th annual ranking of the Forbes 500, said Exxon, which ranked third last year, vaulted into its first-place tie with GE by setting a new record for net profits -- $7.5 billion in the most recent fiscal year.  </p>
<p>General Motors Corp, which was co-No. 1 on last year's Forbes Super 100, fell to third place this year as its net profits slipped by $2 billion to $4.9 billion.</p>
<p>GE, which was also ranked No. 1 last year, retained its top spot on the 1997 list with net profits of $7.3 billion.</p>
<p>Ford Motor Co, ranked No. 4 last year, moved alongside fellow Big Three auto maker GM into the No. 3 spot, with current year profits of $4.45 billion.  </p>
<p>Ranked No. 5 both last year and this, Philip Morris Cos Inc came in with profits of $6.3 billion. Because its assets were ranked 42nd out of the top 500, Philip Morris was in the fifth slot.</p>
<p>Forbes, in the April 21 edition of the magazine, said computer companies are increasing on the Forbes 500 list. Ten years ago, 22 computer firms made the list. This year, the number has risen to 59, with Microsoft Corp ranked fourth in terms of market value (up from 373 10 years ago) and Intel Corp rated 40th in terms of market value (up from 498th 10 years ago).  </p>
<p>The combined net income on the Forbes Profits 500 list rose 14 percent over last year to $325 billion, matching the performance for the Standard &amp; Poor's 500, the magazine said.</p>
<p>Aside from Exxon and GE, which recorded the highest net profits in the 29 years of the Forbes list, another big gainer was International Business Machines Corp, whose profits rose 30 percent over last year.</p>
<p>Sales among the 500 rose a total of 8.3 percent to $4.8 trillion in the year.</p>
<p>In a separate ranking, Forbes said that New York City is the No. 1 headquarters for Forbes 500 companies, home to 59 firms in 1996, up from 58 in 1995.</p>
<p>Second is Chicago with 47, the same number and ranking as the prior year.</p>
<p>Ranked No. 3 was Houston, with 28 companies, up from the No. 4 slot and 22 companies in 1995.</p>
<p>Los Angeles, however, fell to fourth place in 1996, with 22 companies, down from the No. 3 slot in 1995 and 27 Forbes 500 companies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
