<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="489708" id="root" date="1997-04-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Broadcasters convention to meld media with computers.</title>
<headline>Broadcasters convention to meld media with computers.</headline>
<byline>Lisa Marie Pane</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The lineup at this year's National Association of Broadcasters convention looks more like a computer industry confab than one devoted to the broadcast medium.</p>
<p>The convention long associated with television networks -- ABC, CBS, NBC, and Fox -- now draws the likes of International Business Machines Corp., Compaq Computer Corp. and Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>The melding of the two industries is viewed as inevitable as digital technology transforms television.</p>
<p>&quot;What you're going to see are a lot of computer companies becoming broadcasters,&quot; said Paul Saffo of the Institute for the Future, a Menlo Park, Calif.-based think tank. &quot;Look at MSNBC.&quot;</p>
<p>MSNBC is a new cable network that is a joint venture of Microsoft and General Electric Co's NBC network, offering a &quot;Generation X&quot; style take on the news.</p>
<p>The NAB convention, which is taking place this week in Las Vegas, comes the week after Federal Communications Commission regulators approved rules giving broadcasters free license to provide high-definition digital television.</p>
<p>The FCC rules call for 30 percent of U.S. households to receive the broadcasts of at least three digital TV stations by May 1, 1999.</p>
<p>They may being receiving those stations sooner, however. Nearly two dozen stations in the top 10 markets have committed to being on the air within 18 months.</p>
<p>Digital technology is expected to allow broadcasters to squeeze as many as six channels on a single existing channel, or TV stations could offer a single high-definition channel.</p>
<p>In addition, digital TV is expected to hasten the convergence of TV and computer technologies. For example, sports fans would be able to watch a game and split their screens to receive the latest scores of other games over the Internet.</p>
<p>Those developments are a prime reason why the NAB has the look and feel of a computer convention.</p>
<p>&quot;You will see the presence of the traditional computing companies in a market that has not been dominated by traditional computing companies,&quot; said John Gardner, manager for market development at IBM Video Enabled Solutions.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year, there was a real sea change occurring with the movement from analog to digital and the blend of media and telecom with personal computing,&quot; he said. &quot;The fundamental sea change is this covnerstion to digital from analog. This is a long term transformation, it started last year and it will increase because of the benefits of digital broadasting.&quot;</p>
<p>One of the highlights of the NAB event this year is a news conference to be held Monday by Intel Corp., Compaq and Microsoft where company executives are to discuss how the computer and broadcasting industries can work together on digital TV.</p>
<p>&quot;The broadcasting industry in general is becoming increasingly aware of the opportunities PCs present,&quot; said Ron Whittier, senior vice president of Intel's content group.</p>
<p>Intel's elevated profile at the convention, he said, is in contrast to past years when the company offered only &quot;token representation.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You have to conclude this is the year of the PC at NAB,&quot; Whittier said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
