<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="495285" id="root" date="1997-04-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: New crackdown on unlicenced software starts in HK.</title>
<headline>New crackdown on unlicenced software starts in HK.</headline>
<byline>Brian Rhoads</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-04-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Armed with a telephone tipoff line, menacing advertisements and a legal fund, an alliance of software manufacturing giants on Tuesday launched a 30-day crackdown on Hong Kong companies using unlicensed software.</p>
<p>Ken Henshaw, chairman of the Business Software Alliance (BSA) in Hong Kong, told a news conference on Tuesday that the alliance would crack down on companies improperly copying software for internal use, which he termed &quot;softlifting&quot;.</p>
<p>This occurs when a company buys a single package of licensed software and loads it illegally onto more than one computer.</p>
<p>Hong Kong is already famous as a centre for trade in pirate software -- factory-produced copies packaged for sale.</p>
<p>But softlifting can be more attractive to companies than pirated software -- abundantly available on CD-ROMs in some Hong Kong arcades -- because it begins with legitimate, good quality software that is free from bugs or viruses, explained Henshaw.</p>
<p>&quot;Softlifting in fact circumvents an element of that negative implication of using illegally produced software, as many firms feel it is -- in some strange way -- acceptable to utilise an insufficient number of licensed software,&quot; said Henshaw, Hong Kong sales manager for Adobe Systems Inc.</p>
<p>BSA is an alliance of software companies, including Adobe, Autodesk, Microsoft and others.</p>
<p>The latest tack of BSA's campaign was prompted by complaints from members and by Hong Kong distributors and resellers, who often waste time and money providing technical support for customers that have not legitimately paid, Henshaw said.</p>
<p>More than 60 percent of small- and medium-sized companies in the territory use illegally copied software, at an annual cost to software manufacturers of US$140 million, he said.</p>
<p>Henshaw said worldwide softlifting cost billions of U.S. dollars, although he had no specific figure.</p>
<p>The ad campaign posters highlight the BSA hotline and offer a HK$15,000 (US$1,940) reward for tipsters whose information helps bring a successful case against offending companies.</p>
<p>Other ads warn companies of the price of being caught.</p>
<p>&quot;Would you pay HK$1 million for pirated software? You may have to,&quot; says one, to be posted in English and Chinese.</p>
<p>The BSA has won settlements against more than a dozen firms that it has pursued so far -- with three cases netting about HK$1 million each, Henshaw said. The money goes into BSA's legal fund to help pursue other offenders, he said.</p>
<p>Suspected offenders would be investigated through legal means, checking with members to determine if a company has any licensed software, said Robert Arnold, an attorney for BSA.</p>
<p>Henshaw said private investigators also were used to gather public information.</p>
<p>The programme did not reflect a lack of confidence in the Hong Kong government's efforts against piracy, Henshaw said.</p>
<p>He said BSA is also campaigning against software pirates, and hopes to persuade Hong Kong's government to allow it to legally pursue landlords of shopping arcades where tenants sell illegal software.</p>
<p>(US$1 = HK$7.74)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
