<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497021" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Internet pioneers see obstacles to ringing up cash.</title>
<headline>Internet pioneers see obstacles to ringing up cash.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Internet is still the rage among top merchants -- many put their Web site addresses on advertising in conventional media -- but most are not hearing cash registers jingle from online sales.</p>
<p>A cluster of leading Internet merchandising executives and experts, speaking at a recent Red Herring Web Markets West conference here, said the market will come, but it will not be a slam-dunk for all.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a myth that the Net is a perfect market and it is a myth,&quot; said John Pettitt, an electronics commerce expert who is chief technology officer at Cybersource, an industry association for Internet commerce. He noted that products can often be bought more cheaply by telephone or in the physical world.</p>
<p>Allen Weiner, principal analyst at the market research firm Dataquest, said he expects mainstream companies to begin addressing the commercial potential of the Internet, but the companies would need to embrace the Web intelligently.</p>
<p>&quot;When you go to the Internet, you need to make sure that you offer the same value that you offer in real life,&quot; he told investors and businessmen.</p>
<p>Furthermore, he said, there will likely only be a few brands that will be created for sale on the Internet alone, with most major companies beginning to use Web sites in addition to advertising or promoting on other media.</p>
<p>Like any other business in any other form, Web business needs to bring in more money than it costs to run the site itself. For example, David Friedensohn, chief executive of Web music retailer Sonicnet, said a company can get past the break-even point if it sells $40 to $60 of goods on a repeating basis to a core of 10,000 customers.</p>
<p>However, the idea of the Web as an added outlet for business hasn't caught on in some sectors. Ford Smith, an executive of Cyberslice, which enables people to order pizza over the Internet from a variety of local shops, said he found many other restaurateurs not to be very excited about doing business on the Web.</p>
<p>Restaurateurs in other countries, such as Australia, New Zealand, Japan and Sweden, seem to be well ahead of their American counterparts in embracing the Web.</p>
<p>Pettit said merchants need to make it less difficult to use the Web before the medium will really catch on.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of merchants make it really difficult to do business,&quot; he said, adding that many Web sites discourage use by failing to provide a telephone number and other assurances people can reach a representative from the merchant if something in the transaction goes wrong.</p>
<p>Pettitt said he often shops for travel tickets on the Internet, but he then purchases them through a travel agent where he said he can often get a cheaper price.</p>
<p>Merchandiser Web sites often use banner advertisements to draw attention to their businesses, enabling a viewer to click on the ad to be directed to a company site. But this method, called &quot;click-through,&quot; may not prove to be the best way to attract consumers.</p>
<p>Some experts believe people want to be able to communicate with businesses on the Web, as they can do at the mall or through telephone mail order.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see shopping as a (Internet) market driver,&quot; said Weiner. He said communications -- the ability to communicate and collaborate online -- will drive the Web.</p>
<p>Several panellists said Internet commerce will likely reach mass-market proportions as early as next year, with some companies already exploiting niche opportunities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
