<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="497063" id="root" date="1997-04-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 'Haunting' pleases with improbable fun.</title>
<headline>'Haunting' pleases with improbable fun.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Let's begin with a few multiple choice questions.</p>
<p>Question 1.: It is a dark and stormy night. What's the best thing to bring with you when you visit the home of your father, a preacher, who has just died at his parish in Cornwall, England?</p>
<p>a.) A flashlight.</p>
<p>b.) A cellular telephone.</p>
<p>c.) Just a gun.</p>
<p>Question 2.) As you enter his mansion-like parish, you notice that the wall portrait looks different when the lightning is flashing and the door to the house slams shut behind you. Do you then:</p>
<p>a.) Wonder why you left the door wide open in the first place?</p>
<p>b.) Sense a horrible evil in the house and try to leave as quickly as possible?</p>
<p>c.) Nonchalantly wander through the rooms so you can check out the typewriter that types by itself, the huge subterranean throne designed by Mr. Wizard's evil twin, or the demons that float up through the floor and try to slice you in half with their swords?</p>
<p>If you answered &quot;c&quot; to both questions, you're ready for &quot;Realms of the Haunting&quot; (Interplay, DOS/Windows 95, $49), a CD-ROM game that seems to pack every horror movie cliche ever devised and has great fun doing it.</p>
<p>It's got the ghostly father, hobbled by chains, who complains that his soul is trapped and tormented by the demons that inhabit the house. He warns that the &quot;stakes are far greater than you can possibly imagine,&quot; and can't give you a straight answer when you ask him what to do.</p>
<p>It's got a helpful spirit who talks like he's read too many Dickens novels, speaks in riddles and insists on referring to you as the &quot;linear mortal.&quot;</p>
<p>It's got vials of strange-looking liquid that -- contrary to what your mother always told you about unlabeled bottles -- you're supposed to drink.</p>
<p>It's got snappy dialogue like, &quot;I just had a wonderful conversation with my father -- and he's dead.&quot;</p>
<p>And, naturally, the fate of all humanity is in your gun-toting hands.</p>
<p>&quot;Realms of the Haunting&quot; is an adventure game where you are forever exploring, finding keys to open doors, discovering switches to open secret passageways, and collecting objects that can carry you to alternate realities. (If you need help, the instruction booklet walks you through the first 10 chapters).</p>
<p>It is also a shoot-'em-up game, with nasty creatures everywhere. As a result, you will need to spend a lot of time searching for new weapons and ammunition (boxes of which are inexplicably scattered around the mansion). It's rated for ages 13 and older because of the animated violence, blood and gore.</p>
<p>There were moments in this game when I thought I was playing &quot;Duke Nukem 3D Goes Gothic.&quot; In addition to all the ammunition boxes, &quot;Realms&quot; offers the same freedom of movement you find in games like &quot;Duke,&quot; &quot;Quake,&quot; and &quot;Doom,&quot; allowing you to gaze in virtually any direction, even as you're walking (or running) in a different direction.</p>
<p>&quot;Realms&quot; also lets you choose among various levels of difficulty for the arcade and adventure portions of the game.</p>
<p>The scenery is detailed, the virtual reality environment is seamless, the special effects are first rate, and the video sequences that help the story unfold (and there are lots of them on the four CD-ROMs) are well done.</p>
<p>But I kept wishing for a computer command that would allow me to shake some sense into the hero. For example, I wanted to point out to the hero that something is amiss when he's staring into a mirror and the reflection of the girl who is following him around him can't be seen.</p>
<p>On the other hand, what do you expect from a game where you're supposed to drink every vial of goopy-looking liquid you find?</p>
<p>&quot;Realms of the Haunting&quot; will keep you busy for days, even if it won't give you many lessons in common sense.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Frame-It&quot; (DogByte Development, Windows, $50) lets you create illustrated cardboard frames for pictures, or custom-design photo ornaments, photo album pages and scrapbook pages. The package includes over 2,000 designs.</p>
<p>&quot;HeliCOPS&quot; (7th Level, Windows95, $40) -- A helicopter shoot-'em-up with 20 missions, five choppers and the ability to &quot;annihilate your so-called friends in multiplayer death matches&quot; while flying through the metropolis of NeoToyko. It requires a Pentium 100.</p>
<p>&quot;Magic: The Gathering&quot; (MicroProse, Windows, $55) is the computerized version of the strategy card game in which the cards represent spells, creatures, lands and artifacts. One player pits his deck of cards against another player's, with the winner gaining a random card from the loser's deck. The strategy comes from choosing the order of the cards. It also has a tutorial for novices.</p>
<p>&quot;Theme Hospital&quot; (Bullfrog, DOS/Windows95, $45) lets you design, manage and maintain a hospital. This off-the-wall programme lets you &quot;create epidemics and abuse your patients,&quot; plus cure over 30 weird diseases, including King Complex (where the patient is possessed by the spirit of Elvis), Slack Tongue (where the tongue swells to five times its orginal length) and Transparency (which can make it almost as hard to find the patient as it is to find the cure).</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
