<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="498656" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PC DOCS, Cognos battered on earnings.</title>
<headline>PC DOCS, Cognos battered on earnings.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>High technology firms PC DOCS Group International Inc and Cognos Inc both dropped on Thursday after news surrounding their earnings.</p>
<p>PC DOCS said late Wednesday that it would release weaker than forecast third quarter earnings while Cognos on Thursday reported a record fourth quarter as expected by analysts.</p>
<p>PC DOCS ares lost 1.85 to reach a new 52-week low of 6.90 in light trading while Cognos slipped 0.50 to 38.00 on the Toronto Stock Exchange.  </p>
<p>PC DOCS, maker of intranet and client/server information management systems, said earnings will plunge to C$0.02 a share from a year-earlier C$0.19 due to weaker than expected overseas business, .</p>
<p>Griffiths McBurney Partners analyst Howard Lis said that &quot;it's the second quarter this fiscal year that they pre-released disappointing numbers.&quot;</p>
<p>However, analysts had expected the news since competitors have released poor earnings results as well, Lis added. &quot;This didn't come as a complete surprise.&quot;  </p>
<p>Lis said that trading was light since PC DOCS also announced a normal course issuer bid, prompting many investors to avoid the market in favor of selling stock to the firm.</p>
<p>Analysts said investors would approach the stock with caution, awaiting more positive quarterly earnings before buying. Loewen Ondaatje McCutcheon analyst Mark Lawrence said: &quot;I think a lot of investors will sit on the sidelines for quite a while.&quot;</p>
<p>In other news, Cognos earned US$0.29 a share for the fourth-quarter ended February 28 versus year earlier US$0.16.</p>
<p>Market players sold Cognos was down following a share surge since mid-March.</p>
<p>((lydia.zajc@reuters.com, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8109))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
