<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="501513" id="root" date="1997-04-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW - 3Com sees mergers in network industry.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - 3Com sees mergers in network industry.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The merger of U.S. networking products company 3Com and modem maker U.S. Robotics will change the industry by pushing other firms to combine, 3Com chief Eric Benhamou said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a shakeout. There will be a reaction on the part of smaller players to try and combine to get to a critical mass,&quot; Benhamou told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>3Com, which makes devices that control and link networks and connect personal computers to networks, and U.S. Robotics are merging through a stock deal valued at US$7.3 billion.  </p>
<p>U.S. Robotics is the leading worldwide maker of computer modems for the consumer market. Benhamou said he expected a &quot;small amount&quot; of job losses from the total 13,000 employees as a result of the merger.</p>
<p>Expected to be completed in summer, the deal will result in the industry being dominated by two giants -- the merged 3Com with revenue of more than $5 billion and its main rival Cisco Systems Inc with sales of about US$4 billion.  </p>
<p>Benhamou said there were already signs of an industry reaction, pointing to the announcement in late March by networking company Ascend Communications it would buy Cascade Communications for $3.7 billion.</p>
<p>Analysts say they also expect smaller networking companies like Bay Networks Inc and Shiva Corp to become acquisition targets.</p>
<p>But Benhamou said there was unikely to be another merger on the scale of 3Com and U.S. Robotics. Even with more mergers, companies would have to compete differently, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It really separates us a lot from everyone else. It brings us to the same revenues as Cisco. It gives us more technology coverage and channel coverage than anyone else,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is going to be a visible difference between the top two vendors and the others. This has the effect of changing the landscape and separating us between the broad-based companies, of which we claim there are two, and the more narrowly-based companies who focus on specific segments,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The merger with U.S. Robotics would not only give 3Com &quot;end-to-end&quot; solutions across LANS (local area networks) and WANS (wide area networks) but opportunities to develop unique products, like subsystems for personal computers, Benhamou said.</p>
<p>The merger could also see a greater presence of U.S. Robotics products in Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;One thing we are going to explore is the possibility of building U.S. Robotics products in the Singapore plant,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>3Com has invested $98 million in the first phase of a Singapore plant to manufacture networking products, a logistics centre, regional support and data centre. The plant is expected to start operation in early 1998.</p>
<p>Benhamou said 3Com would make more acquisitions in future if there were new technologies that it preferred to purchase.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (55-870-3080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
