<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503177" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: A rare German success story - SAP turns 25.</title>
<headline>A rare German success story - SAP turns 25.</headline>
<byline>Elisabeth Ramelsberger</byline>
<dateline>MANNHEIM, Germany 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a country reknowned for its engineering prowess but sorely behind in getting ready for the Information Age, German business software group SAP AG celebrated a rare success story on Friday.</p>
<p>For German Chancellor Helmut Kohl, one of the 700 guests attending SAP's 25th anniversary bash, the Walldorf-based firm is the best example of what industry must do if Germany is to overcome its highest unemployment since the 1930s.</p>
<p>&quot;This company is a model example of a successful and innovative enterprise founding in Germany,&quot; Kohl said. &quot;The start-up capital of its founders was their knowledge, exciting idea, and the courage to take a risk.&quot;</p>
<p>While success came early, with the 1992 launch of its R/3 system -- made not for big mainframe computers but for new smaller client/server systems -- business exploded.</p>
<p>Since 1988, when SAP went public, its annual turnover has soared from 245 million marks ($142.4 million) and net profit of 44 million to 3.7 billion marks and profit of 567 million. It expects sales of around 4.8 billion marks this year and net profit exceeding 700 million marks.</p>
<p>In the early 90s SAP was the high-flyer on the Frankfurt bourse. Annual returns have averaged 45 percent.</p>
<p>Last October, SAP investors showed first signs of nervousness. A slight dent in tempestuous growth rates caused a massive sell-off of shares as traders worried the party was over. But shares have recouped those losses and closed at 286 marks on Friday in Frankfurt bourse trade.</p>
<p>SAP remains a rare story in Germany. Many new companies grow frustrated at the lack of start-up financing from German banks and move to the U.S..</p>
<p>Germany has also been slow to adapt the information technology that is expected to drive industry in the next century. Germans have far fewer personal computers than Americans and while 20 percent of U.S. homes are hooked up to the Internet just four percent of German homes are online.</p>
<p>SAP, which makes standard software that controls the basic functions of a company -- accounting, controlling and warehouse management -- was founded by four former IBM employees in 1972.</p>
<p>Of the four original founders Dietmar Hopp and Hasso Plattner share a special relationship that has driven much of SAP's success. Hopp is the cool-headed engineer and management board chairman who keeps the business running day-to-day, while Plattner is more the charismatic visionary.</p>
<p>SAP's good fortune was to have the right product at the right time. It benefited in the 1990s from the globalisation of industry and reorganisation of Fortune 500 companies.</p>
<p>As large enterprises began to enter a wave of downsizing, they were looking for technology solutions to help simplify information and make it available to employees throughout the enterprise.</p>
<p>As the interdependence of the world's economies penetrates further into small and medium-sized businesses, SAP is confident that it can continue to grow as it moves down the industry chain and adapts its R/3 system to the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;The simplification of our systems will lead to a dramatic expansion down the chain of our circle of customers,&quot; Hopp said earlier this week.</p>
<p>As European companies, banks and governments prepare for the launch of a single currency in 1999, SAP is also set to benefit with software integrated into its R/3 system that manages the transition from national currencies to the euro.</p>
<p>The looming &quot;Millenium&quot; bug -- the inability of computers around the world to recognise the year 2000 -- is also a factor driving many companies to phase out old systems and install new software such as R/3.</p>
<p>Europe's biggest software group, SAP has evolved into a global company. Around 38 percent of its turnover now comes from the United States, which has caused it to seriously contemplate a share listing there.</p>
<p>Germany accounts for 25 percent of sales and the rest of Europe for 24 percent of annual sales, while Asia has grown to 12 percent and Africa is beginning to show with two percent.</p>
<p>SAP's main competitors, though most are still much smaller, are Baan NV, PeopleSoft and Oracle.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097 150 ($ = 1.720 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANNHEIM, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
