<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="503739" id="root" date="1997-04-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PC-Quote to sell non-Internet business.</title>
<headline>PC-Quote to sell non-Internet business.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-04-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>PC Quote Inc said Friday it entered into a non-binding letter of intent to sell its non-Internet-based quotation business to Track Data Corp.</p>
<p>PC Quote said the sale is the first of several strategic moves the company will undertake to further emphasize its Internet-based business.</p>
<p>The letter of intent contemplates a sale price of up to 750,000 shares of Track Data common stock and contingent cash payments of up to 50 percent of pre-tax earnings of the acquired business for a period of three years.  </p>
<p>In addition, Track Data will assume certain liabilities connected with the business.  The transaction is subject to board approvals, the satisfactory completion of due diligence and execution of a definitive purchase agreement.</p>
<p>PC Quote said the annual revenues from the business to be sold amounts to $10 million.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the agreement, PC Quote retains the rights to use its HyperFeed digital feeds of stock prices and financial market information available, to power its Internet/Intranet products.</p>
<p>Louis Morgan, PC Quote chairman, said the deal would allow it to focus on reducing costs and enhancing its rapidly growing Internet business.</p>
<p>&quot;We currently have four successful Internet initiatives with more to come,&quot; Morgan said. &quot;At the same time, our traditional business will be in good hands at Track Data Corp, which already has all of the necessary infrastructure in place.&quot;</p>
<p>Track Data provides real-time financial market data, fundamental research, charting and analytical services to both institutional and individual investors.</p>
<p>PC Quote provides on-line stock and market quotes.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
