<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="512216" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow Jones had considered Telerate sale.</title>
<headline>Dow Jones had considered Telerate sale.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dow Jones &amp; Co Inc said it considered a sale, merger or shrinking of Dow Jones Markets -- formerly Telerate -- before it adopted a plan to invest $650 million in its real-time products unit.</p>
<p>Chief executive Peter Kann made the remarks in response to a shareholders question at the company's annual meeting on Wednesday. He said the decision process took six months.</p>
<p>&quot;It is up to us to execute this program in such a way as to reduce the amount of scepticism,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Kann said that Dow Jones had considered various levels of investment in Telerate, an outright sale, a merger or shrinking the size of the business before deciding on the plan to give it a complete overhaul.</p>
<p>&quot;This was not an easy decisions to make...it was not an emotional decision,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kann, facing intense shareholder criticism of the three-to-four year investment plan, said the company was now committed to its plan.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not emotionally attached to it (Dow Jones Markets) as you might expect we are to the Wall Street Journal,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Dow Jones is planning to shift to Internet-based presentation standards using generic industry software and equipment, a move away from its existing proprietary system.</p>
<p>This move will be helped by an alliance announced this month with Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>Kann said Dow Jones would cover information for all markets from equities, bonds and currencies to energy and commodities, and build electronic transaction systems to allow automated trade in those markets.  </p>
<p>It plans to provide the databases and analytics that are required by fund managers, one of the fastest growing markets for real time information, and will work harder on improving relationships with its customers, Kann said.</p>
<p>&quot;We think this is a good business and will pay a handsome long term return to shareholders,&quot; said Kann.</p>
<p>Analyst Lanny Baker of Salomon Brothers said the next milestone on the path would be around September, a year after the problems with Telerate first came to light.</p>
<p>&quot;By September they should have some signs of progress, in improved Telerate revenues or new products,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Baker added that at that time the input of the new independent directors would become important, and the investment plan would either be accelerated or slowed.</p>
<p>The three new independent directors are Frank Newman, chief executive of Bankers Trust Co, American Express Co CEO Harvey Golub and William Steere, chairman and chief executive of Pfizer Inc.  </p>
<p>Shareholder critics of the investment plan told Reuters they are putting their faith in the track record for creating shareholder value of the outside executives, who were elected to the 15 member Dow Jones board on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Baker said that one critical element was the Wall Street Journal ability to generate the cash flow to fund the investment.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Wall Street Journal slows down, the breathing space is less comfortable,&quot; he said. Baker said the funding in any case is too tight to be accomplished without some borrowing.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot do this plan and pay the dividend  without borrowing $50 million for each of the first two years,&quot; Baker said.</p>
<p>He said that he expected no benefits to Dow Jones earnings from the investment until 1999.</p>
<p>(( Nick Louth, New York Newsroom 212 859 1712))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
