<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="515219" id="root" date="1997-04-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: New IBM, Lotus software to tap Asian retail.</title>
<headline>New IBM, Lotus software to tap Asian retail.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new Web software offered by IBM and its Lotus Development unit expects to capitalise on a burst in demand by Asian businesses for the internet, software company officials said at a launch on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is massive growth out here. This is the layer of growth we will be able to take advantage of,&quot; Charlie Ill, IBM's general manager of software for Asia Pacific, said.</p>
<p>IBM's revenue from networking and distribution of computing software products grew more than 30 percent last year, due to rising demand for electronic business applications.  </p>
<p>The launch of the product, designed to enable IBM to expand its offerings in the fastest-growing segment of its software business, is occurring at a time when its corporate customers and others are turning to the Web for business opportunities.</p>
<p>&quot;I can tell you that Japan has the highest growth rate in internet servers worldwide,&quot; Ill said, adding that Japan last year overtook Germany in growth rates.</p>
<p>He said Asian business will likely reap rewards similar to those of U.S. companies using internet and intranet for retail and other transactions.  </p>
<p>The single largest concern for internet and intranet users was security, but this problem would be partly resolved by Secure Electronic Transaction (SET) technology, Ill said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an industry standard by MasterCard and Visa where two parties agree to use a bank...it's like a tripartite agreement,&quot; said Patricia Yim, manager for ASEAN-South Asia software.</p>
<p>She said that electronic transfer of funds, such as at many retail outlets and the rise in credit card usuage, were examples of changing habits and modes of business.  </p>
<p>IBM's new Network Computing Framework strategy and launch of new Web server software and other products helps link a company's business and data with the global access of the Web.</p>
<p>It provides for establishing a Web site, supporting message handling on an intranet and managing business over the internet, including electronic transfer of funds, IBM officials said.</p>
<p>--Jacqueline Wong, Singapore newsroom (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
