<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="51550" id="root" date="1996-09-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW-MCI happy with Internet services.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-MCI happy with Internet services.</headline>
<byline>Nick Louth</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>MCI Communications Corp, having launched a blizzard of Internet initiatives during the past two years, said it was satisifed with their progress and expected them to break even three or four years after being introduced.</p>
<p>&quot;All of our initiatives are designed to pay back in three, maybe four years. Some are already home; some may take longer,&quot; Tim Price, chief operating officer of MCI's telecommunications unit told Reuters on Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are doing very well, probably better than anybody else, in Web site creation, Web site hosting and Internet access,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However, a couple of initiatives have done less well. In May, MCI closed its electronic malls a little more than a year after they opened for business.</p>
<p>And 1-800-MUSIC NOW, an electronic and telephone shopping service for music, is not doing as well as it was expected to do when it was launched last November, Price said.  </p>
<p>&quot;No, I'm not satisfied by it,&quot; he said, adding that bypassing the archaic distribution systems used by stores was a bigger problem than anticipated.</p>
<p>Price argues that there are two ways of approaching the Internet. Either a company could wait until it is clear what will succeed commercially but lag behind others entering the market, or it could dive in and experiment, taking the rough with the smooth.</p>
<p>MCI has taken the latter route, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Fortunately we have guessed right more than we have guessed wrong,&quot; Price said.</p>
<p>MCI has sought to spread the risk of being an Internet pioneer by establishing links with Intel Corp and Microsoft Corp, and forming a $2.4 billion entertainment alliance with News Corp.</p>
<p>Still, MCI, which is normally fast to show off its successes, has yet to release details of how many clients it has for its various Internet services.</p>
<p>Price would only say that MCI has reaped $100 million in Internet revenues so far, a figure that includes wholesale business carrying traffic for Internet service providers.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsroom 212 859-1712</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
