<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="517262" id="root" date="1997-04-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Oracle CEO says Apple would be good NC supplier.</title>
<headline>Oracle CEO says Apple would be good NC supplier.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-04-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oracle Corp. Chief Executive Officer Larry Ellison said Thursday that Apple Computer Inc. would be a great supplier of network computers, or NCs.</p>
<p>Ellison, a major promoter of new stripped-down, low-cost network computers (NCs) that can access the Internet, made the comment amid mounting industry speculation that he would soon make a bid for Apple, with the aim of turning it into a network computer manufacturer with the Macintosh brand.</p>
<p>Asked whether he would personally make a bid for Apple, the software billionaire said he did not want to comment, but added, &quot;Apple would be a great supplier of NCs.&quot;</p>
<p>Ellison was speaking at the Oracle OpenWorld 1997 business fair in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Apple on Wednesday reported a $708 million fiscal second-quarter loss, which compared with a net loss of $740 million in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>However, the ailing computer maker said strong sales of speedy, new personal computers and laptops and lower expenses would help it meet its goal of reporting a profit by its fiscal fourth quarter ending in September.</p>
<p>Late last month, Ellison said he had formed an independent investor group to gauge interest in taking over Apple.</p>
<p>Ellison said at that time that he would soon decide whether to make a bid based on the reaction from Apple investors, but he added any bid would be independent of Oracle.</p>
<p>The move, which was not the first time Ellison had raised the possibility of personally leading a bid for Apple, came as the Cupertino, Calif.-based computer maker was struggling to recapture a profitable role in the intensely competitive PC industry.</p>
<p>Ellison has said for two years that he would like to buy Apple with his own money, partly to prevent Microsoft Corp. from dominating the computer industry.</p>
<p>Apple, with its huge following of Macintosh fans, could be a key weapon. Apple has suffered declining market share for its famous brand of easy-to-use computers and endured several rounds of restructuring in recent years.</p>
<p>Redwood City, Calif.-based Oracle was the top vendor in the global database market in 1996 with a 30 percent market share, according to a recent study by Dataquest, a market research firm. Dataquest said Oracle posted 1996 database revenues of $1.70 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
