<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="520629" id="root" date="1997-04-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Avant! executives plead not guilty to conspiracy.</title>
<headline>Avant! executives plead not guilty to conspiracy.</headline>
<dateline>SAN JOSE, Calif. 1997-04-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The president and other top executives of Avant! Corp. pleaded not guilty on Friday to charges alleging they helped steal technology from rival software company Cadence Design Systems Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;They're already back at work,&quot; John Huyett, Avant chief financial officer, said after the arraignment in municipal court in San Jose, Calif. &quot;It's business as usual.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier this week, the Santa Clara, Calif., County district attorney's office filed felony charges of conspiracy and trade secret theft against Avant, its President Gerald Hsu, and other officials.</p>
<p>The district attorney alleged that the executives stole technology from Cadence and based products on it. Avant and Cadence both sell expensive software that helps engineers design the microscopic electronic patterns of computer chips.</p>
<p>All of the Avant executives charged were former employees of Cadence. If convicted, each could receive a sentence of up to seven years in state prison.</p>
<p>Avant executives Hsu, business operations executive Stephen Tzyh-Lih Wuu, vice president of technology Yuh-Zen Liao, director Yun-Chung Eric Cho, and director of business operations Shiaoli Leigh Huang each pleaded not guilty at Friday's municipal court hearing, Huyett said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're confident that we'll win,&quot; Huyett said. &quot;We believe the charges are unfounded. There is no conspiracy.&quot;</p>
<p>Avant and Cadence have been bitter rivals for years. For more than a year, Cadence has been pressing its own civil action against Avant, asking the court to stop Avant from selling its products.</p>
<p>Cadence and the district attorney have alleged that many of Avant's chief products have been based on technology Cadence developed. They allege that Avant, under the direction of Hsu, stole the technology bit by bit using the help of former Cadence employees.</p>
<p>Avant, which has grown substantially in revenue under Hsu, has always denied any wrongdoing and alleges that Cadence is using a smear campaign to drive away customers. Both companies chase after giant chipmakers, such as Intel Corp., Motorola Inc. and Texas Instruments Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;Avant's business momentum has been quite good and customers have voted in a way that validates the strength of their technology,&quot; said Raj Seth, analyst at investment bank Cowen &amp; Co. in Boston. &quot;On the other hand, you can't ignore what's going on.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN JOSE, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
