<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="524262" id="root" date="1997-04-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Microsoft set to expand in Croatia.</title>
<headline>Microsoft set to expand in Croatia.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-04-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp on Monday inaugurated its subsidiary in Croatia and announced business expansion in the country as part of wider plans to expand in central and eastern Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very optimistic about business we can enjoy in Europe and Croatia,&quot; Michel Lacombe, vice president of Microsoft Europe, told a news conference. &quot;We believe we can keep the pace (of growth) going.&quot;</p>
<p>But company officials were vague as to actual investments and planned revenues in Croatia.</p>
<p>Microsoft Hrvatska (Croatia) d.o.o. was set up in January 1997 as the firm's 24th subsidiary in Europe. It has only four staff employees and is 100 percent owned by Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>It aims to supply the market through three main distributors and a network of more than 150 dealers. It also has three Microsoft Authorised Training Centres.</p>
<p>&quot;Investments (in Croatia) are serious and huge, ranging from setting up business, localising products to training local partners,&quot; Goran Radman, general manager of Microsoft Croatia told reporters.</p>
<p>Microsoft's main goals in Croatia are to make it a market standard, localise its products and put an end to software piracy, Radman said.</p>
<p>Microsoft is now readying its first localised product -- Croatian Office 1997, which should be available in September this year.</p>
<p>Radman put total investment so far at roughly five million German marks to develop the main business structure.</p>
<p>Croatia had 200,000 installed personal computers in 1996, and some 35,000 new PCs are bought each year.</p>
<p>But it is among the countries with the highest rates of piracy, with some 94 percent of the software estimated to be illegal.</p>
<p>&quot;We are the most heavily pirated product,&quot; said regional director Robert Clough, adding that piracy made it virtually impossible for the company to set revenue targets for Croatia. -- Laura Lui, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
