<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="532774" id="root" date="1997-04-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: A CD-ROM that knows what's best for you.</title>
<headline>A CD-ROM that knows what's best for you.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I. 1997-04-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Admit it. We all need a little mothering once in a while. But do we really want Mom to retake control of our lives?</p>
<p>Well, dear, if that's what you really want, &quot;CyberMom&quot; (Digital Entertainment, Windows) is here for you.</p>
<p>Available in a package that looks suspiciously like a box of Tide laundry detergent, &quot;CyberMom&quot; claims to be &quot;The Maternal Icon of the CyberGeneration!&quot;</p>
<p>It won't do your laundry, clean your room or babysit for the kids, but it will make lists of things you need to do, give you motherly tips (&quot;Label everything&quot;), clean up your desktop and give you some new screen savers.</p>
<p>It also has a &quot;Nag-O-Meter&quot; to remind you about chores, appointments and birthdays (including the birthday of your other mother) monthly, weekly or twice an hour. (Just don't let your real mother find out about this particular function. She's going to want to know why you're willing to spend $25 for a computer product that incessantly nags you when she's willing to do it for free).</p>
<p>Unfortunately, &quot;CyberMom&quot; has a big drawback. It has no &quot;uninstall&quot; programme and when I tried to take it off my computer, I found files from the programme scattered in no fewer than four locations. The technical support service number listed in the programme was no help. It doesn't work for &quot;CyberMom.&quot;</p>
<p>In other words, once you invite &quot;CyberMom&quot; into your computer, you're going to have a hard time getting rid of her.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>On August 6, 1945, when the first atomic bomb was dropped on Japan, the world was changed forever.</p>
<p>The dangers and benefits of the nuclear age now resonate through science, medicine, international relations and popular culture.</p>
<p>&quot;The Atomic Files&quot; (L3 Interactive, Windows, $35) is an attempt to capture the events that led to the dropping of that first bomb, and explore how the fallout has shaped our lives in ways big and small.</p>
<p>To give some perspective on the use of the atomic bomb to end World War II, the CD-ROM goes all the way back to World War I to explain, appropriately enough, how the second World War came about in the first place. You can't accuse the developers of not giving &quot;The Atomic Files&quot; enough breadth.</p>
<p>It features a history of the Manhattan Project and interviews with Hiroshima survivor Kaz Suyeishi and the father of the hydrogen bomb, Edward Teller.</p>
<p>It recalls the silly instructions from the 1950s and 1960s to &quot;duck and cover&quot; if you saw the flash of a bomb, as if it would protect you. And it reminds us that even the bikini has ties to the nuclear age -- it was named after Bikini Atoll, an island whose centre was vaporised and left radioactive by a nuclear test.</p>
<p>&quot;The Atomic Files&quot; has some oddities and errors, including some silly grammatical mistakes and stupid hyperlinks. In the passing reference to the 1994 post-apocalyptic movie &quot;Tank Girl,&quot; the word &quot;tank&quot; is highlighted so you can click on it to get more information. But instead of getting details about the movie, it gives you a definition of a tank, as if people reading a CD-ROM that discusses warfare and subatomic particles might not know what a tank is.</p>
<p>The same was true in the reference to the 1979 movie &quot;The China Syndrome.&quot; Instead of giving details about the movie or explaining the &quot;China syndrome&quot; concept itself (the idea that the meltdown of a nuclear reactor will burn an ever-deeping hole in the ground, as if it were on its way to China), the CD-ROM tells you about China.</p>
<p>&quot;The Atomic Files&quot; also says that &quot;The China Syndrome&quot; exaggerated and sensationalized the Three Mile Island nuclear accident. Wrong. The Michael Douglas/Jane Fonda film was actually released a few months before the accident, which was sensational enough by itself to effectively kill off the U.S. nuclear industry.</p>
<p>The programme also tries to artificially divide the topics into nine categories (each with three subcategories) so the history of the nuclear age can be depicted as a cube. The system is contrived and detracts from an important topic that shouldn't need a gimmick to be compelling.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Ark of Time&quot; (Koei, DOS, $35) lets you play the role of a reporter searching for a missing professor and (in your spare time) solve the riddles of Atlantis, Easter Island and Stonehenge.</p>
<p>&quot;Fallen Haven&quot; (Interactive Magic, Windows95, $55) -- Earth colonists have landed on the planet New Haven. But the same space probe that discovered the planet for humans has alerted an alien race, the Taurans, to its existance as well. Your job it is to stop them from taking over the planet.</p>
<p>&quot;Wings: London Blitz to Pearl Harbour&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $40) is the continuation of Discovery Channel Multimedia's &quot;Wings&quot; series, billed as &quot;the most comprehensive, authoritative and in-depth journal through aviation history.&quot; This one covers the aircraft and weapons of World War II, with over 720 planes from 26 nations.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
