<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54259" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Making something pretty out of info glut.</title>
<headline>Making something pretty out of info glut.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Someone once described the Internet as an amazing library with just one hitch: All the books have been thrown in in the middle of the room.</p>
<p>So finding anything on this new medium can be either really fun if you are content with finding a few gems amongst much dross or a breathtaking waste of time if tend to be a bit A number of groups have been looking at ways of tackling all this clutter on the World Wide Web and one of the more high profile groups includes the Internet-based PointCast Network of Cupertino, Calif.</p>
<p>PointCast, which launched its first foreign edition with a new service in Canada last Wednesday, has been growing around the world. Company officials said they have more than one million registered users and that number has been growing by 250,000 a month. There are some 50,000 registered users in Canada.</p>
<p>The service looks very much like the interactive television big industry has been promising for some time but has not yet delivered.</p>
<p>&quot;Leave it to a startup to deliver the kind of personalized news broadcast that big media companies have been jawing about for years,&quot; said Michael Martin in a review of the service in a May Fortune magazine article.</p>
<p>PointCast is pretty with colours and a lot of activity, including animated advertisements that blink and agitate in one corner of the screen. Users may shape the service to their own needs, getting favourite stock quotes and sports scores to buzz across the bottom of the screen while reading news from Reuters, New York Times or People magazine on other areas.</p>
<p>To read anything a user just clicks on a headline. As well, it would only be a fast click away to search for anything else on the Web with the Netscape browser that shows up on command.</p>
<p>Why is this service so popular? Well it is free for starters. All you have to do is download a rather large blob of software from their site (www.pointcast.com or in Canada: www.pointcast.ca). You do have to put up with some ingenious advertisements that some have found a tad more distracting than the more traditional Internet banner ads.</p>
<p>Advertisers, as well as content providers, have been flocking rather steadily to the PointCast, which began in February.</p>
<p>The privately-held company started by former Silcon Valley types from Adobe, Oracle and Lotus, said some 30 companies have made commitments to buy ads for the final three months of the year, about double their original expectations. To celebrate this, the company has announced it was raising its ad rates.</p>
<p>Several new &quot;channels&quot; have been added recently, including The New York Times, Minneapolis Star Tribune, The Tampa Tribune, and San Jose Mercury News.</p>
<p>The new PointCast service in Canada is backed by Toronto's Globe and Mail Newspaper under a franchise like arrangement. The service will include domestic corporate wires, information from the Globe and might also soon add French and English content from Canada's venerable CBC network.</p>
<p>PointCast officials said they have been negotiating with potential partners in Europe and Asia to set up other modified domestic services, modelled loosely on the Canadian experience.</p>
<p>Jim Wickett, vice president of worldwide business devlopment for PointCast, said companies have been eager to join up with the online service because of its growing &quot;viewership.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's the unprecdented embracing from the viewing public to our broadcast network,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pointcast believes surfers, about 85 percent from corporations, have been attracted to the service because it brings order to today's informational mayhem on the Web.</p>
<p>&quot;It has taken the whole information glut of the Net and brought some structure to it,&quot; said Bob Geddes, managing director of PointCast Canada.</p>
<p>(To comment on this weekly column, Russell Blinch can be reached at: russell.blinch(at)reuters.com, using the &quot;at&quot; symbol on the keyboard).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
