<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="54333" id="root" date="1996-09-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IPO VIEW - Signs of life in U.S. market after lull.</title>
<headline>IPO VIEW - Signs of life in U.S. market after lull.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. IPO market will show signs of life this week after a long, dry summer, as underwriters test the waters ahead of a heavy fall schedule of initial public offerings.</p>
<p>&quot;The IPO market is starting to heat up. We've got about 20 deals next week, and 100 to 125 deals could price between now and the end of October,&quot; said John Fitzgibbon, editor of the IPO Aftermarket newsletter.</p>
<p>International Network Service, Cymer Inc and Rental Service Corp could prove to be hot issues this week, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;They could all go up a point or more in the aftermarket,&quot; Fitzgibbon said.</p>
<p>David Menlow, president of IPO Financial Network, said: &quot;This is the first week in the past few months the major underwriters are starting to poke their heads up out of the sand.... We'll be trying to find the pulse of the market after the July blow-off.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Dow industrials jumped almost 69 to close at 5841. New investments in stock funds rose sharply in August to $19.0 billion from $4.8 billion in July, according to the Investment Company Institute.  </p>
<p>Both the Dow gain and the stronger flow of investment into stock funds lend a more favorable tone to the IPO market, though at least one analyst voiced concern that underwriters would try to jack up prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's been so hot, we'll probably see some opportunistic pricings,&quot; said Steve Tuen, an analyst at the IPO Value Monitor.</p>
<p>However, Menlow shrugged off fears that a run-up in stocks could overvalue the IPO market.  </p>
<p>&quot;Everyone's still a little too nervous.... The run-up came in the Dow, but the confidence has not come back into the stocks that comprise much of the IPO market. And we're still seeing downward revisions in IPOs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Houston Exploration Co, a unit of Brooklyn Union Gas Co, comes to market at a time when the stock of some similar companies, such as Newfield Exploration Co and Forcenergy Inc, are trading near their year highs.  </p>
<p>&quot;Energy issues have been doing quite well in the IPO market,&quot; Fitzgibbon said. &quot;This has been on the calendar before and was knocked off. Sometime that means a negative bite, but not this time around.&quot;</p>
<p>The deal was originally scheduled for July, but was rescheduled. Houston increased the number of shares to be sold to 6.2 million from 5.7 million. Analysts said the deal could fetch a small premium.</p>
<p>In the biggest deal this week, power plant company Calpine Corp is not expected to generate much interest, analysts said.</p>
<p>But some smaller deals could catch the eye of investors.  </p>
<p>Cymer makes excimer lasers for the deep ultraviolet photolithography systems, which make the very small images used in manufacturing advanced semiconductor chips. The San Diego company will offer 3.34 million shares in a range of $7.50 to $9.50 a share. Morgan Stanley is the lead underwriter.</p>
<p>Menlow said RMH Teleservices Inc, which provides outbound tele-services for insurance and financial services firms, could be hot. It plans to sell off a 26 percent stake or 2.8 million shares to be priced in an estimated range of $11.50 to $13.50 a share, according to a regulatory filing.  </p>
<p>The Bryn Mawr, Pa. company posted operating income of $2.0 million and revenues of $25.5 million in fiscal 1995.</p>
<p>Fitzgibbon said offerings by Applied Analytical Industries Inc, three-dimensional software developer Technology Modeling Associates Inc and Tri-Point Medical Corp could generate strong interest.</p>
<p>Tri-Point, to be underwritten by Lehman Brothers, makes adhesive products used to close and seal wounds.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some real quality issues coming,&quot; said George Novello, manager of Smith Barney special equities fund. &quot;But there are also lots of off-the-wall speculative deals that have been waiting on the sidelines. They think the strong market may be an open window to squeeze through.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wall Street Desk (212) 859-1730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300013">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34350">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I84000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
