<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="545146" id="root" date="1997-04-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW-Adobe awakens to Asian potential.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Adobe awakens to Asian potential.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-04-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. graphics-editing software company Adobe Systems Inc is making a belated move to reap Asia's growth potential, a senior company official said on Monday.</p>
<p>It is aiming to match competitors in the region and push revenues from Asia Pacific and Latin America to US$150 million in 2000, said Graham Freeman, Adobe's vice president and general manager for Asia Pacific and Latin America (APL).  </p>
<p>&quot;Asia Pacific and Latin Amercia are now about three to four percent of total company's revenue,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;By year 2,000, we would like to be about 15 percent of revenue, which would see us getting to about US$150 million across Asia Pacific and Latin America,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Adobe's revenue for fiscal year ended November 29, 1996 was US$786.6 million.</p>
<p>Asia was likely to contribute about half of the projected $150 million revenue, he said, without giving a current revenue figure.  </p>
<p>This would mean annual compounded growth rates of 40-45 percent in APL in the next few years, he added.</p>
<p>Adobe said it was undertaking a &quot;multi-million dollar investment&quot; to set up a regional headquarters in Singapore to would provide management, marketing, sales and technical support in South Asia, South Korea and Greater China.</p>
<p>By year end, Adobe would have about 15 staff in the region.</p>
<p>Freeman said Adobe was experiencing little price pressure as it sold mainly to the professional market of publishers and enterprises.  </p>
<p>But he saw the consumer market contributing more revenue in future in terms of royalties from third-party sellers.</p>
<p>Freeman said Adobe was working on setting up a technical centre in India to undertake some software development.</p>
<p>&quot;We might move some localisation of our products in Asia into Singapore, Malaysia, Hong Kong later on,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Adobe was also active in fighting software piracy.</p>
<p>&quot;In estimates we have done to year 2000, we figure if we can help reduce piracy by 10 percent, we would add US$15-20 million to our (APL) revenue by year 2000,&quot; Freeman said.  </p>
<p>Adobe, which has an venture programme that invests in start-up and firms and companies before they launched intitial public offerings, was looking at a &quot;couple of opportunities in Europe&quot;, Freeman said.</p>
<p>&quot;As we see continuing success in that programme, we would like to make it more global,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Adobe announced its first venture stock dividend last week. It is giving its shareholders one share of Netscape Communications Corp for every 100 Adobe shares held. Those with fewer than 2,500 shares will get paid in cash.  </p>
<p>Freeman said one of the company's key growth areas was in its Internet products like Photoshop and Acrobat.</p>
<p>Its HTML (hypertext markup language) product Pagemill, which links text in Web pages, had been delayed for a year since its announcement but would be shipped internationally from May, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
