<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="546952" id="root" date="1997-04-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Virtual pets from Tiger and Bandai.</title>
<headline>Virtual pets from Tiger and Bandai.</headline>
<byline>Judith Schoolman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>It doesn't shed, soil the carpet, chew on shoes or howl at the moon. It can live forever, but if it should die, voila, it gets reincarnated.</p>
<p>It's like no pet you've ever owned -- it's a virtual pet, Tiger Electronic Inc.'s newest toy, Giga Pets.</p>
<p>With a bow to the Tamagotch hand-held toy by Bandai, which is wildly popular in Japan, Tiger's item is a hand-held computerized game that mimics the lives of one of six pets.</p>
<p>Giga Pet comes in six varieties -- a dog, cat, chimp, bit critter, virtual alien or baby T-Rex, which will be a tie-in with this summer's &quot;Jurassic Park&quot; sequal, &quot;The Lost World.&quot;</p>
<p>A player has to care for the pet in all ways -- feeding, walking, cleaning up after it, taking it to the vet and playing with it. If the player fails to do so, the pet dies.</p>
<p>Each Giga Pet is attached to a key chain, with a one-inch-square LCD screen that shows an animated creature engaging in various activities.</p>
<p>The object of the game is to raise the Giga Pet, play with it, clean up after it, take it to the vet and give it a name. The happier and healthier the pet, the higher the score.</p>
<p>However, if the pet should suffer from neglect -- oops. It turns into an angel and goes to heaven. The game can be restarted any number of times.</p>
<p>Powered by a small button cell battery, the game is designed to teach children ages five and up to respond to a pet's needs and develop a sense of responsibility.</p>
<p>Giga Pets were first introduced in February at the American International Toy Fair in New York.</p>
<p>The toy's technology isn't new. It was first used by Tiger in its Precious Pets Dear Diary, an electronic hand held organiser, which was introduced in March 1996. Aimed at kids aged 12 and older, users of the Dear Diary get to select a cat or dog from the computerized &quot;pet shop&quot; and they can play with their pet every time they use the diary.</p>
<p>Giga Pets, developed in the United States but made in China, will sell for about $9.99 and will debut May 1 in New York. They will be introduced nationwide soon after.</p>
<p>Tomagotch, Bandai America Inc.'s version, made an enigmatic debut Tuesday in national advertisements, including one in The New York Times that read, &quot;What sleeps without a bed?... What loves to play but doesn't shed?... Go and hatcha Tamagotch&quot;.</p>
<p>This hand-held, key-chain video game will sell for $18 and will be introduced at toy retailers nationwide this week.</p>
<p>Michael Goldstein, the chief executive officer of Toys R Us Inc., said that children have learned much about virtual pets by reading about them and discussing them on the Internet.</p>
<p>Tamagotch, or &quot;cute little egg,&quot; begins when an egg hatches on the small video screen and a chicken is born. The owner then helps it grow from chick to adult by following commands to feed, play with and even discipline the pet.</p>
<p>The toy comes in one version and the pet &quot;dies&quot; after 10 days regardless of its care.</p>
<p>Unlike a real Kitty, this virtual pet has many more than nine lives.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
