<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="549320" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US computer network stocks up as outlook brightens.</title>
<headline>US computer network stocks up as outlook brightens.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-04-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computer networking stocks saw another day of strong gains Wednesday, benefiting from broad market strength and rising expectations for the sector ahead of a major industry trade show slated for Las Vegas next week.</p>
<p>Analysts said Cisco Systems Inc, the flagship of the group, and the most active stock of the day, gained 2-1/2 to 52-1/2, reflecting investor confidence ahead of the company's earnings quarterly earnings report, due out Tuesday.</p>
<p>Ascend Communications Inc rose 4-1/16 to 45-1/2, as analysts hailed what they said were agressive cost-cutting plans in its Cascade Communications Corp merger.  </p>
<p>Cascade shares rose 2-7/8 to 31-1/2 and Fore Systems Inc added 3-1/2 points to 15-1/4. Cabletron Systems Inc rose 1-3/4 to 34-1/2 and Bay Networks Inc was up 1-1/4 to 17-3/4.</p>
<p>The American Stock Exchange's Network Index was up 10.03 to 229.48, the second day of double-digit gains for the index, which last week had hit a year low of just above 200. The Dow Jones Industrial Average was up about 47 points in late trading.</p>
<p>Smith Barney analyst Therese Murphy pointed to gains in the broad market, along with anticipation of positive news coming out of the Networld+Interop show in Las Vegas next week.  </p>
<p>Analysts and traders said Cisco had traded under a cloud in recent weeks after earnings disappointments from other companies in the sector and rumors that Cisco was gearing up to pre-announce that earnings would fall short of Wall Street expectations in its latest quarter.</p>
<p>With earnings due out on Tuesday and the window for such pre-announcements closed, analysts said investors are confident that there is no disaster pending in Cisco's upcoming earnings results.  </p>
<p>The current consensus estimate for Cisco's third quarter ended April 30 is $0.52 per share versus $0.37 per share in the April 1996 quarter, according to First Call.</p>
<p>Smith Barney's Murphy said Ascend share price gains reflected optimism among investors that the company was planning a series of cost-cutting moves, including some lay-offs and sales force combinations, with Cascade.</p>
<p>Ascend had said in an U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission filing April 22 that it planned to take a one-time charge of about $42.2 million to cover cost-cutting moves related to the merger.  </p>
<p>Murphy said the $42 million shows that Ascend is serious about its plans to take &quot;some significant costs out&quot; of the combination, and said this could further reduce the dilutive impact of the acquisition on Ascend's future earnings.</p>
<p>She said the substantial merger-related charge boosted confidence that Ascend can produce 1997 results within the guidelines it had announced at the time of the merger.</p>
<p>&quot;That has to make people feel Cascade is not going to be a horrendous drag on Ascend's (results),&quot; Murphy said.  </p>
<p>On March 31, Ascend had said it expected the merger to dilute 1997 earnings between $0.05 to $0.10 per share but for the merger to become additive to earnings in the 1998 year.</p>
<p>The once high-flying network group has had to weather a relentless battering since warnings of slowing growth in late January by 3Com Corp and Cascade, among others, spooked investors in the sector as a whole.</p>
<p>The nervousness sent the sector into a slide that caused it to lose more than a third of its value as measured by group indices between late January and mid-April, making it among the worst performing sectors in the stock market during 1997.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
