<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="550830" id="root" date="1997-04-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lack of excitement mars this &quot;Fable&quot;.</title>
<headline>Lack of excitement mars this &quot;Fable&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's time to spoil the ending of &quot;Fable&quot; (DOS/Windows95, $50) the new CD-ROM game from Sir-tech Software about the quest for four precious stones that will free a distant world from domination by a group of monsters.</p>
<p>Here's what happens: The hero sits in a chair. A periscope-like viewer drops from the ceiling. The hero gets out of the chair. A couple of sparks fritter along the edges of some machinery and along the edges of the octogenarian villain who barely moves (but you hear him scream). The hero knocks at the front door and he goes inside. Tiny hearts float out the window of his girlfriend's room.</p>
<p>The words &quot;exhilarating,&quot; &quot;breathtaking,&quot; and &quot;rewarding&quot; never come to mind.</p>
<p>I had high hopes for this lushly-illustrated game because it started off strong, with an animated prologue about some demons who were created when they tried to betray a race of magical creatures known as the Mecubarz.</p>
<p>The player assumes the role of Quickthorpe, who is told by a village elder to bring back four jewels, kill the demons who guard them, and free the world of the demons' tyranny.</p>
<p>&quot;Why me?&quot; asks the scrawny boy after being ordered on a grand and dangerous quest.</p>
<p>&quot;All the other village people are just too busy or not interested,&quot; the elder explains.</p>
<p>It's this sly sense of humour that gives the game its magic. When Quickthorpe returns through the snow to the village gate before he's completed his mission, his amply-endowed girlfriend greets him from the balcony and sweetly reminds him that it's much warmer upstairs with her.</p>
<p>Quickthorpe, mindful of his quest and apparently devoid of male hormones, patiently explains, &quot;I cannot be distracted.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Oh well. Suit yourself, you little worm,&quot; she responds.</p>
<p>References to the Chernobyl nuclear accident and Armani clothing give &quot;Fable&quot; its offbeat humour. Like most games, you're supposed to take virtually everything that isn't nailed down because you may need it later in the adventure. Only this game tries to make you feel guilty about it.</p>
<p>I also like what happens when you make a wrong move and die. In some instances, instead of dramatically announcing that you're dead, you simply collapse in a heap and the game keeps going on without you, just as in real life.</p>
<p>But the clever bits grow scarce as the game progresses.</p>
<p>Clearly the people behind &quot;Fable&quot; could have done better. At the very least, they should have provided a prologue-style closing sequence that would have wrapped up the story.</p>
<p>Buyers should be warned of one potential technical glitch. Each time I used the Windows 95 autorun feature, the cursor appeared as a fuzzy blob. I resolved the problem by minimising the game (by hitting the &quot;Alt&quot; and &quot;Tab&quot; keys simultaneously), then reopening the game by clicking on the &quot;Fable&quot; button on the taskbar.</p>
<p>The real moral to this &quot;Fable&quot; is: If you're going to put a lot of effort into a game, try devoting some to the ending.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;American Heritage: Lincoln and the Civil War&quot; (DOS/Windows, $40) -- Simon &amp; Schuster Interactive's 90-minute multimedia look at Abraham Lincoln has been combined with its previously-released dual-CD-ROM examination of the Civil War.</p>
<p>&quot;Easy Language: Conversation Skills&quot; from IMSI (Windows/Macintosh, $50, http://www.imsisoft.com) is a CD-ROM for learning Spanish, French, English or German. It has 90 lessons, along with a multilingual word processor, spelling checker and thesaurus.</p>
<p>&quot;Finfin on Teo, the Magic Planet&quot; from Fujitsu Interactive (Windows95, $60, http://www.fujitsu-interactive.com) features a half bird-half dolphin creature that anyone over age 4 can make friends with. Finfin interacts directly with the person operating the computer thanks to a device (which comes with the game and plugs into your computer) that senses your movements and sounds.</p>
<p>&quot;Fragile Allegiance&quot; from Interplay (DOS, $50) -- A strategy space simulation game in which players have to trade, make alliances and go to war with six alien races in the year 2,380. For novice players, it has animated tutorials.</p>
<p>&quot;ICL Builder&quot; from R.I. Soft Systems (Windows95, $20, 800-959-7447, http://www.risoftsystems.com) lets you create your own icons for Windows programmes or pull icons out of existing Windows programmes. It's designed for non-programmers. There's also a $25 version with 500 ready-made icons.</p>
<p>&quot;The Last Express&quot; from Broderbund (Windows/DOS/Macintosh, $39, http://www.lastexpress.com) promises political intrigue, suspense, romance and betrayal in an animated adventure set aboard the Orient Express travelling across Europe in 1914. You play a doctor who &quot;can get himself into trouble in four languages.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;See the World by Train -- UK Edition&quot; from Fujitsu Interactive (Windows95, $30, http://www.fujitsu-interactive.com) is a virtual tour of the United Kingdom, including England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland. It's based on a popular TV series in Japan.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-04-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-04-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
