<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="55099" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CheckFree sees loss widening in FY 1997.</title>
<headline>CheckFree sees loss widening in FY 1997.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>CheckFree Corp said it will lose more money in fiscal 1997 due to its purchase of Intuit Services Corp, but that the acquisition will not delay it from reaching positive cash flow in fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;We will lose more money in current fiscal year 1997,&quot; CheckFree Chairman and Chief Executive officer Peter Kight said in a conference call with media and financial analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that as the analysts get information from us over the next couple of days that...it will not affect our analyst projections that we will be cash-flow positive on an accelerating basis in fiscal 1998,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He added, &quot;As the second half of the integration takes place, we are going to be in a position to be a substantially more profitable company.&quot;</p>
<p>CheckFree earlier said it would buy the electronic bill payment and bank services unit of Intuit Inc in exchange for 12.6 million shares of CheckFree, valued at $227 million at CheckFree's Friday closing price of 18-1/16. Kight said he expects all major banks to move into the electronic market within the next 12 months, and therefore he deliberately decided to integrate the Intuit business over a longer, 18-month period to prevent disruptions to customers.</p>
<p>&quot;We clearly believe that the next 12 months in banking is going to be a very important time for banks to stake their claim in the market, to take their position in terms of electronic services,&quot; he said. &quot;We're going to encourage the banks to, if anything, accelerate their decision-making process in terms of offering electronic banking services.&quot;</p>
<p>The merger will consolidate two key pioneers of the banking electronic back-office under one organization.</p>
<p>CheckFree said it had remained on good terms with Intuit, which was a key partner from its entry into the electronic market, even after Intuit acquired the competing unit in 1994.  </p>
<p>&quot;Intuit did in fact chose in 1994 to buy a competitive company and build a competitive service. However, they never disconnected their link to CheckFree,&quot; Kight said.</p>
<p>He said CheckFree was &quot;deeply committed to utilizing Internet and intranet technology.&quot;</p>
<p>He also said the deal with Intuit would result in an extention of the companies' relationship, with Intuit through its BankNow and other products operating at the front end and CheckFree's combined banking and bill payment processing at the back end, supporting various products.</p>
<p>Kight said the integration of Intuit Services Corp would take account of technology it uses, such as secure information technology supplied by TIBCO, a unit of Reuters Holdings Ltd, the worldwide news and information organization.</p>
<p>&quot;That's a fine technology and it will work with anyone's, and it's probably the best implementation of telecom technology with software-based interfaces,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kight said the TIBCO technology is used to provide a hub-based interface and link between consumers, financial institutions and transaction processors such as CheckFree.</p>
<p>-- sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau 415 846 5400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
