<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="558572" id="root" date="1997-05-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Analysts lift Creative earnings prospects.</title>
<headline>Analysts lift Creative earnings prospects.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong third quarter results for multimedia company Creative Technology, combined with predictions of higher sales and healthy margins into fiscal 1998, have led analysts to revise their earnings projections upwards.</p>
<p>&quot;We have revised earn63.7 million from US$132.6 million,&quot; David Toh, an analyst at ING-Baring Securities, told Reuters at the weekend.</p>
<p>On April 26, Creative announced third quarter profits of US$44.2 million or US$0.48 per share, beating an analyst consensus forecast of US$0.34 per share.</p>
<p>This is the third consecutive quarter of robust results after the company was in the red in the previous fiscal year.</p>
<p>Creative Chief Executive Sim Wong Hoo said after the release of the results that he expected gross margins to stay in the 30 percent range for the next five quarters and sales to grow 10 to 15 percent in fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>Most analysts also see Creative chalking up earnings growth in the mid to high teens for 1998.</p>
<p>They said the company's cost and inventory controls and plans to release a lower-cost version of its latest AWE64 sound card to replace older 16-bit sound cards augured well for earnings into fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>The AWE64 card allows the playing of 64 instruments simultaneously.</p>
<p>&quot;They are putting energy into what they are good at -- the sound cards,&quot; said Ng Eng Hou, an analyst at Keppel Securities who raised Creative's 1997 net profit to Singapore $210.2 million (US$146 million) from S$189.8 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The AWE64 Value card is targeted at replacing the upgrade market and it should boost earnings,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The AWE64 Value card will be launched in the next few weeks at US$99, half the price of the current AWE64 costing US$199.</p>
<p>The AWE64 not only has the potential to grab a market of 40 million Sound Blaster customers upgrading from the 16-bit card, but also a slice of the original equipment market (OEM) market, analysts said.</p>
<p>Moving the standard for PC audio to the low-cost AWE64 from the 16-bit card will make it difficult for various competitors, many of whom have satrick Yau, analyst at Schroders Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Creative is trying to change the market towards appreciating high-end sound cards. They are trying to convince people of the need to go beyond the basic sound card,&quot; Toh said.</p>
<p>This could also be seen as a defensive move against Intel's MMX chip, which offers basic sound capabilities, analysts said.</p>
<p>Based on 1998 price earnings ratio of 10 times, analysts said Creative was a buy up to S$26-S$31.</p>
<p>At Friday's close in Singapore, the stock was at S$20.40.</p>
<p>Analysts were, however, unexcited about Creative's move into DVD (digital Video disk) drives.</p>
<p>Creative said it had been shipping first generation DVD drives for a month.</p>
<p>Ng said he did not see DVD drives making any impact on Creative's earnings until at least fiscal 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;They just want to show they have the technology and they are ready. Currently there is not much software or games titles for DVD. There are also a lot of issues not ironed out in DVD,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>US$1 = S$1.44</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
