<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56014" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CheckFree acquires Intuit's bill, bank services.</title>
<headline>CheckFree acquires Intuit's bill, bank services.</headline>
<dateline>COLUMBUS, Ohio</dateline>
<text>
<p>CheckFree Corp. will acquire Intuit Services Corp., the electronic bill payment and bank services unit of Intuit Corp., in a stock deal worth about $258.3 million, the companies said Monday.</p>
<p>At the same time, Intuit will buy a stake of about 23 percent in CheckFree, a leading provider of check processing services.</p>
<p>The acquisition will expand CheckFree's customers for home banking and bill payment services to over 180 financial institutions and more than one million consumers.</p>
<p>Intuit said the sale allows it to reallocate management and focus on its core software and growing Internet businesses.</p>
<p>Columbus, Ohio-based CheckFree said it will offer 12.6 million shares of its common stock for Intuit Services. CheckFree's stock rose $2.5625, while Intuit climbed $2.125 to $32.25 on Nasdaq in late morning trading. Intuit said it plans to sell about 2 million CheckFree shares acquired in the transaction.</p>
<p>Intuit has agreed to pay CheckFree any shortfall if its unit's revenues for the year ending July 31, 1997 fall below $46 million. Intuit Service accounted for less than 3 percent of Intuit's revenues in fiscal 1996.</p>
<p>CheckFree said it will merge the unit's operations into its existing processing systems.</p>
<p>The deal is expected to close before Dec. 31, subject to regulatory and stockholder approval.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition makes us the go-to service company for electronic commerce, and with the shift from paper to electronic commerce clearly underway, that's a good position to be in,&quot; said Peter Kight, chairman and CEO of CheckFree.</p>
<p>&quot;This combination does what the financial institutions have asked for -- it creates an open, completely invisible transaction processing architecture for them to use that supports all leading interfaces.&quot;</p>
<p>CheckFree said its open processing architecture allows financial institutions to deliver home banking and bill payment through personal computers, touch-tone phones and the Internet. Additionally, CheckFree's processing architecture allows financial institutions to offer multiple software interfaces for PC-based home banking and bill payment, including Intuit's Quicken and BankNOW, Microsoft Money, Managing Your Money, HomeATM and other bank-branded software.</p>
<p>Knight said the overall acceleration of growth at CheckFree resulting from the acquisition of Intuit Service would result in more jobs at the company.</p>
<p>Separately, Intuit said its losses widened to $22.0 million, or 48 cents a share, in the quarter ended July 31 from $1.4 million, or 3 cents a share, in the year-ago period. Revenues rose 26 percent to $91.1 million from $72.4 million.</p>
<p>The latest results include an $8 million acquisition charge, increased spending in customer service and technical support, and start-up expenses in bill payment processing at Intuit Services.</p>
<p>Intuit said it typically expects to report operating losses for the July and October quarters because of operating expenses to develop the updated versions of tax and other products.</p>
<p>Mountain View, Calif.-based Intuit produces TurboTax, the best-selling tax preparation software; and QuickBooks, the most popular small business accounting software. Its Quicken programme is the leading personal finance software.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBUS, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
