<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="56504" id="root" date="1996-09-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FULL TEXT-Intuit swaps for Checkfree stake.</title>
<headline>FULL TEXT-Intuit swaps for Checkfree stake.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intuit Inc said it will swap its online banking and bill payment processing unit for a significant equity stake in Checkfree Corp. Intuit will own about 23 percent of Checkfree as a result of the $227 million transaction.</p>
<p>---PRESS RELEASE------------------------------------</p>
<p>Intuit Swaps Online Banking and Bill Payment Processing Unit For Significant Equity Stake in CheckFree Corp.; Intuit's OpenExchange Specifications to Expand Quicken Connectivity</p>
<p>MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif.--(BUSINESS WIRE)--Sept. 16, 1996-- Leveraging a two-year-old investment that ignited the recent explosion in consumer use of online banking and bill payment, Intuit Inc. (NASDAQ: INTU) today announced that it will receive a significant equity stake in CheckFree Corp. (NASDAQ:CKFR), the nation's leading home banking and bill payment processor, in exchange for ownership of Intuit's bill payment processing subsidiary, Intuit Services Corp. (ISC).</p>
<p>In the transaction, Intuit will receive 12.6 million shares of newly issued CheckFree common stock.  Of the resulting 54 million CheckFree shares outstanding, Intuit will own roughly 23 percent. Based on Friday's closing price of 18 1/16 for CheckFree, the transaction is valued at $227.6 million, a substantial return on Intuit's investment in ISC.</p>
<p>CheckFree is the country's leading home banking and electronic bill payment processor and Intuit is the leading developer of personal and small business finance software and Web-based financial services.  This new relationship will provide financial institutions the combined power of Intuit's front-end software and CheckFree's back-end processing, creating comprehensive &quot;best-of-breed&quot; solutions for electronic banking.</p>
<p>&quot;Two years ago, financial institutions preferred a secure, private network to reach customers electronically.  The proof is in the results: Quicken Banking through ISC helped to turn electronic banking into a barn-burner in the last year,&quot;  said Scott D. Cook, Intuit chairman and co-founder.  &quot;Today, the Internet provides sufficient security and reliability to allow a safe migration to public networks.  CheckFree can continue to provide the banking and bill payment processing that financial institutions and other financial service providers will still need.  With this and other moves Intuit is announcing today, we are focusing squarely on the Internet to capitalize on opportunities for our users and financial service providers.&quot;</p>
<p>At the same time, financial institutions will have complete freedom-of-choice: they can use CheckFree's back-end processing with Quicken or other front-end software, or they can use Quicken and other Intuit software and services with CheckFree or other back-end processing services.  To accomplish this, Intuit also announced that it will this fall publish OpenExchange, an integrated framework of easy-to-use specifications and protocols for exchanging data electronically to and from Intuit products for consumers, small businesses, financial service providers and government agencies. Quicken will have a complete banking and bill payment implementation of OpenExchange with the Fall 1997 release; OpenExchange for Quicken investment data will be available this spring.</p>
<p>In connection with the transaction, CheckFree and Intuit also will enter into certain license and service agreements to connect financial institutions to Quicken and to assist in the integration of ISC's operations into CheckFree.</p>
<p>Intuit acquired Intuit Services Corp. in July 1994.  Then known as National Payment Clearinghouse Inc., it processed online banking transactions for customers of four banks offering services to users of Microsoft Money.  Intuit significantly expanded ISC's operations, including construction of the network hub, capable of routing multiple simultaneous connections to different services available through ISC, and added security features which authenticate users with a high degree of confidence before granting them access to bank data.</p>
<p>In November 1995, Intuit launched online banking and bill payment via Quicken using ISC to accomplish the connections between users and financial institutions.  The service is now offered by 35 of the nation's leading banks, charge card companies and brokerage firms, and the customer base has increased more than 15-fold since the NPCI acquisition.  In addition to Quicken, ISC processes transactions for users who bank with BankNOW on America Online, a service Intuit jointly developed with AOL and participating financial institutions. ISC recently renewed a contract to continue processing banking and bill payment transactions for users of Microsoft Money.  </p>
<p>Intuit Inc., a financial software and Web-based services company, develops and markets Quicken, the leading personal finance software; TurboTax, the best-selling tax preparation software; and QuickBooks, the most popular small business accounting software.  Intuit's Quicken Financial Network (http://www.qfn.com) offers a variety of news, information and market spaces including the No. 1 mutual fund Web site, NETworth.com, and the most dynamic personal insurance Web site, Quicken InsureMarket.com.  Intuit's products and services enable individuals, small businesses and financial professionals to better manage their financial lives and businesses.  In addition, Intuit's systems and solutions provide many of the nation's leading financial service providers with communication, sales and marketing opportunities that deliver new customers, better serve existing customers and lower costs. -0-</p>
<p>Note to Editors:  Intuit, Quicken, QuickBooks, TurboTax and MacInTax are registered trademarks of Intuit Inc.  Quicken Family Lawyer, Quicken Financial Planner, Quicken InsureMarket, Pocket Quicken, ProSeries, Quicken Home Inventory, Quicken Quotes, QuickFill, QuickBooks Pro, QuickPay, ExpensAble, Intuit Marketplace, Investor Insight and OpenExchange are trademarks of Intuit Inc. NETworth is a registered trademark of GALT Technologies, Inc.  All other trademarks are property of their respective owners.</p>
<p>For more information on today's announcements, see news release entitled &quot;Intuit Unveils Internet Initiative to Further Revolutionize Finances for Individuals and Small Businesses,&quot;  and Intuit's white paper entitled &quot;OpenExchange Framework: For Electronic Exchange of Financial Data, Transactions and Communications Between Individuals, Small Businesses, Financial Advisors and Financial Services Providers.&quot;  For information on the sale of ISC to CheckFree, see news release entitled &quot;Intuit Swaps Bill Payment Processing Subsidary for Significant Equity Stake in CheckFree Corp.&quot;  These documents are all available on Intuit's Web site, QFN, at http://www.intuit.com.</p>
<p>CONTACT:  Virginia L. Miller, Treasurer</p>
<p>		  415/944-3507</p>
<p>		  James J. Heeger, Chief Financial Officer</p>
<p>		  415/944-6996</p>
<p>		  Intuit PR</p>
<p>		  Jeff Larsen, 415/944-5628</p>
<p>		  http://www.intuit.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
