<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566564" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: A surreal CD-ROM adventure loses its way.</title>
<headline>A surreal CD-ROM adventure loses its way.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's easy to become lost when you play &quot;The City of Lost Children&quot; (Psygnosis, DOS/Playstation, $50, http://www.psygnosis.com), but it's not because the game is so captivating. The plot of this story is so scant, scattershot and, at times, silly that you'll have trouble figuring out what you're doing or why.</p>
<p>Based on a French art-house film that has just come out on video, it's supposed to be the story of a scientist who kidnaps children so he can steal their dreams.</p>
<p>But you never see the scientist, you never get any indication of how he's going to carry out his plan, and although the cyberpuppets in this game are animated in three dimensions, their roles couldn't be flatter.</p>
<p>The tale centres around an orphan named Miette, who is either 10 or 12 (the box and instruction booklet can't agree on her age). The crooked headmistress of her orphanage (actually Siamese twins who speak simultaneously) keeps sending Miette on robbery jobs. After two robberies, which take up most of the game, Miette stumbles onto the plan to kidnap the children.</p>
<p>&quot;City&quot; also features a circus strongman whose younger brother has been abducted and a diver who lives in a cave under the ocean. With colourful characters like these, the game had plenty of potential.</p>
<p>Technically, some elements of &quot;City&quot; are breathtaking. Miette moves smoothly through deliciously-detailed, multi-level sets. The developers use overhead camera angles to give the game a movie-like quality.</p>
<p>But other elements are all wrong.</p>
<p>In many cases, the objects that you'll need to get through the game aren't even visible on the screen. You have to send Miette into an alcove or behind a stack of boxes before an icon appears indicating there's something for her to pick up.</p>
<p>Also, the game requires frustrating precision. In one case, when Miette was supposed to bend down to hide behind some crates, she refused to bend down unless you put her in precisely the right spot AND had her facing in a specific direction.</p>
<p>The lush soundtrack is too loud, its volume can't be controlled (you can only turn it on or off), and the music crescendos at inappropriate times.</p>
<p>After you've gotten a compass by killing the flea trainer with his own fleas (honest, I'm not making any of this up), you learn from a talking camera that the diver (whom you've never met) has killed off the scientist (whom you've never met) and the total number of children who need to be rescued from this city of lost children is four. (Apparently this is a city with a VERY low birthrate).</p>
<p>If you rent the movie first, more of this will make sense. But games, even a surreal one like this, should stand on their own, especially when they're derived from a film few people have seen. It's sad to see so much work put into a game, only to discover that it's the developers who are lost when it comes to telling a complete, coherent story.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>&quot;Life in the Universe&quot; from MetaTools (Windows/Macintosh, $40, http://www.metatools.com) features a lecture on extraterrestrial intelligence and related topics by British physicist Stephen Hawking, an expert on black holes whose brilliant mind is encased in a barely-movable body afflicted with Lou Gehrig's disease.</p>
<p>This CD-ROM features Hawking's fascinating observations about the future of humanity (he thinks mankind must genetically re-engineer itself to survive its aggressive instincts), faster-than-light space travel (he believes it's impossible because we don't see tourists from the future), and artificial life (which, he argues, we've already created in the form of computer viruses).</p>
<p>You can also check on related topics such as black holes, life on Mars, and the evolution of Earth that are illustrated with 200 animations and 50 videos.</p>
<p>But &quot;Life in the Universe&quot; comes with too few directions (sort of like the universe itself) and it requires a little fumbling around to figure out how to make things work properly (also like the universe itself).</p>
<p>And, as you can tell from some charts that don't fit properly on the screen and from hyperlinks that don't directly take you where you need to go, the CD-ROM's design is far from perfect (sort of like life itself).</p>
<p>In ways both good and bad, it's easy to get lost in this &quot;Universe.&quot;</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;British Open Championship Golf&quot; -- a golf simulation that recreates two of Scotland's oldest and most challenging courses and offers commentary from sportscaster Jim McKay. There's also an interactive, animated caddie. It's from Looking Glass Technologies (Windows95, $50).</p>
<p>&quot;Outlaws&quot; -- Noting that &quot;Nothing warms the heart of a cold-blooded killer like hot lead,&quot; this game lets you assume the role of Marshall James Anderson. Your job: gun down the varmints in a dusty town, an abandoned mine and other locales. You can play it as a Spaghetti Western adventure or a single- or multi-player shoot-em-up. It's from LucasArts Entertainment (Windows95, $55, http://www.lucasarts.com).</p>
<p>&quot;Ringling Bros. and Barnum &amp; Bailey: The 12 Circus Rings&quot; is supposed to help youngsters age three to six develop math and problem-solving skills under the pretense of a visit to the circus. It has three levels of difficulty. There are also sections on circus lore and memorabilia, and a screen saver. It's from Byron Preiss Multimedia (Windows, $25).</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
