<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="566720" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-SAP counters insider charges.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-SAP counters insider charges.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>MANNHEIM, Germany 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software developer SAP AG, trying to limit damage from an insider trading probe, said on Wednesday that its top managers and other key employees had not engaged in any illegal dealings.</p>
<p>Employees including board members who knew that last year's third quarter results would show weakened growth had sworn they did not engage in share trading based on that information, supervisory board chairman Bernd Thiemann told the company's annual general meeting.</p>
<p>SAP admitted that the insider probe had already hurt, but it set a goal of increasing revenue by one billion marks ($580 million) this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The unbelievable uproar over this process is likely to have caused major financial damage,&quot; chief executive Dietmar Hopp told the meeting</p>
<p>Management would help investigators to bring the affair to a speedy end and any employees found to have engaged in insider trading would bear the consequences, he said.</p>
<p>Frankfurt prosecutors would take note of the sworn declarations, their spokesman Job Tilmann told Reuters. But they still believed insider trading had been committed, both by company insiders and by others who got information from them.</p>
<p>SAP employees would be questioned as part of the investigation, but the examination of 100 employees' telephone records would take more time, Tilmann said.</p>
<p>The BAWe securities trading regulatory authority said that the suspicious dealings involved put options as well as SAP shares.</p>
<p>Put options, a type of financial derivative, give buyers the right to sell shares at a certain price and then buy them back for a profit later if the underlying value falls.</p>
<p>Managing board member Henning Kagermann told Reuters that SAP was unlikely to face fines resulting from the probe. &quot;It is unlikely SAP would have to pay a fine,&quot; he said. The probe &quot;is not against the firm. It is against individuals&quot;.</p>
<p>Heinz Steffen, a Kleinwort Benson analyst in Frankfurt, said SAP was likely to suffer until media coverage died down. &quot;They will get through this,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;It's clear it hurts them, but it is short-term negative effects.&quot;</p>
<p>SAP shareholders asked a series of questions about how well the company controlled insider information among top executives.</p>
<p>&quot;This problem of insiders at SAP will be very difficult to get under control,&quot; said Annaliese Hieke, a representative of a small shareholder group.</p>
<p>Hopp and members of the supervisory and management boards had signed documents asserting that they &quot;at no time dealt in SAP shares or derivatives in violation of insider trading rules&quot;, Thiemann said.</p>
<p>Managers had not passed on any relevant information to third parties where this was not necessary, he added.</p>
<p>Other employees who had access to critical data have also sworn they did not engage in insider trading.</p>
<p>Hopp, answering a shareholder question, said 71 employees, including 51 at the SAP headquarters, knew by October 18 that third quarter results would fall below expectations.</p>
<p>Prosecutors have launched an investigation into trades by over 100 people in both SAP shares and derivatives after sharp price movements in October last year.</p>
<p>SAP stock plunged by a quarter after the October 22 release of weaker than expected third quarter profits, prompting an investigation by Frankfurt bourse supervisors.</p>
<p>Hopp said the stock price had crashed after a 10-week, 75-mark rise which occurred without apparent reason or positive news from the company.</p>
<p>The combination of rising expectations and the unforeseeable weakening of third quarter growth resulted in the crash in the stock price, Hopp said.</p>
<p>Since last autumn, SAP shares have climbed to near 320 marks, and closed bourse trade on Wednesday at 314 marks, down 3.0.</p>
<p>Hopp said strong first quarter earnings should not encourage the view that the company's business forecast was too cautious. But he added that if the mark remained weak this year, earnings could exceed management expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is a revenue increase of one billion marks,&quot; from last year's 3.722 billion marks, he said, &quot;with a cost increase of less than that.&quot;</p>
<p>SAP sought to land 300 new customers in Germany this year, and he forecast a boom in 1998 when companies accelerated upgrades to SAP R/3 software modified to accommodate the change to dates in the year 2000.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150 ($1 = 1.723 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANNHEIM, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
