<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="567093" id="root" date="1997-05-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cisco cautious on Q4 growth, stock seen weak.</title>
<headline>Cisco cautious on Q4 growth, stock seen weak.</headline>
<byline>Eric Auchard</byline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1997-05-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cisco Systems Inc matched Wall Street's diminished expectations for its April quarter, but analysts warned the stock could trade lower on Wednesday after cautious comments made by Cisco executives.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the stock is going to trade down tomorrow,&quot; said an analyst who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>The company late on Tuesday reported earnings for the third fiscal quarter ended in April of $0.52 per share -- matching the consensus analyst estimate for the quarter according to First Call. The company reported earnings of $0.37 per share in the comparable period of 1996.</p>
<p>Cisco shares slipped to 56 in after-hours trading on Tuesday from an earlier close of 57-3/4, before the release of the April earnings report and the conference call with analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;April basically made the quarter for them,&quot; A.G. Edwards analyst Peter Andrew said after listening to the conference call. &quot;The big question is whether this is a trend that will continue into the current quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>During a conference call, John Chambers, Cisco's president and chief executive, spoke with a mixture of cautious optimism and what he called &quot;normal paranoia.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Though this quarter was more back-end loaded than we would have liked, April was very solid in terms of bookings and linearity,&quot; he said, comparing April to February and March, which Cisco had warned earlier in the spring had showed signs of sluggishness.</p>
<p>&quot;While we are cautiously optimistic, we need to see how the next few months go before we can determine if what occurred in April is a trend.&quot;</p>
<p>Referring to the current quarter ended in July, Chambers said: &quot;Q4 has historically been a good quarter for Cisco, however in the past high backlogs and longer lead times provided a buffer between the variable order growth and reasonable, steady revenue growth.&quot;</p>
<p>But he warned that Cisco was seeing ever shorter order lead times.</p>
<p>&quot;Even in good quarters, we won't know until the last couple of weeks of the quarter whether we will close at, above or below expectations,&quot; Chambers said.</p>
<p>When asked if April's growth rate and seasonal strength typically seen in the current quarter could produce double-digit growth over the April quarter, Chambers said: &quot;I would think that would be a little too optimistic.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We tend to be very conservative on the financial positioning,&quot; he went on. &quot;We would look for single-digit this quarter in terms of the growth projections,&quot; adding that Cisco was planning its expenses accordingly.</p>
<p>Days Sales Outstanding (DSOs), a carefully watched measure of the time it takes to collect accounts receivable increased to 63 days from 59 days, Chief Financial Officer Larry Carter said during the call.</p>
<p>&quot;The rise was primarily due to non-linearity of shipments in the quarter,&quot; Carter said, referring to the April uptick in bookings. But if current conditions hold up, Cisco expects DSOs to improve in the July quarter, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Geographically, growth remained solid except where there is lower capital spending overall and therefore reduced network spending,&quot; he said of industry growth overall, adding: &quot;We see this in such areas as Japan, Germany and France.&quot;</p>
<p>While Japan and Germany may be bottoming out, Chambers said, &quot;France continues to see very, very sluggish and we saw a little bit of sluggishness in Korea as well.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Cisco's telephone carrier sales business was soft, worldwide, even though its Stratacom unit's April quarter revenues were 30 percent above any previous quarter.</p>
<p>A.G. Edward's analyst Andrew said that although Cisco posted year-over-year revenue growth in the April quarter of 52 percent, revenues grew a tepid three percent from the January 1997 quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the first quarter in recent memory that they grew in the single-digits,&quot; Andrew said.</p>
<p>Seeking to play down weak sequential quarterly growth, Chambers said on the call: &quot;Analysts believe and we agree that underlying industry drivers (of growth) have not changed.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The growth projections from industry sources continue to estimate industry growth between 30 to 50 percent, subject to fluctuations from quarter to quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cisco's growth of more than 50 percent year-on-year beat the aggregate growth of Cisco's top eight competitors, which had a combined rate of 30 percent in the most recent quarter, Chambers noted.</p>
<p>&quot;Gross margins of 55.3 percent - flat from last quarter - was a good achievement,&quot; Chambers said. Cisco had previously voiced concern that its historically high profit margins could decline during the quarter.</p>
<p>Echoing their previous long-term guidance, Cisco officials repeated that the company's gross margins were expected to continue to decline, despite periodic quarters where improvement or no change occurs.</p>
<p>Chambers said Cisco's goal over the next 12 to 24 months was to grow at or above industry growth rates of 30 to 50 percent, but he cautioned that Cisco's size makes growing faster than the industry increasingly difficult to sustain.</p>
<p>He said Cisco's partnerships with industry heavyweights such as already announced relationships with Microsoft Corp, Intel Corp, Hewlett-Packard and GTE Corp will play a more prominent strategic role than acquisitions in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe strategic partnerships will be as important in the next three years as acquisitions were in the last three years,&quot; the executive said. This wlll allow Cisco to offer more complete end-to-end systems that reduce the difficulties of managing large, far-flung networks.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that acquisitions will continue going forward,&quot; Chambers added. &quot;We will probably acquire eight to 12 companies this year, for example,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
