<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571078" id="root" date="1997-05-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore software piracy rate rises in 1996-survey.</title>
<headline>Singapore software piracy rate rises in 1996-survey.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-05-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore's software piracy rate rose six percentage points to 59 percent in 1996, according to latest survey figures released by the Business Software Alliance (BSA) on Thursday.</p>
<p>The BSA, a watchdog body for the software industry, said in a statement this represented more than a 10 percent rise in the rate of increase over 1995.</p>
<p>A similar survey showed Singapore's piracy rate had declined by eight percent in 1995.  </p>
<p>&quot;These statistics suggest that more than half of software used on personal computers in Singapore are unlicensed,&quot; Stuart Ong, vice president of BSA said in the statement.</p>
<p>The BSA said one of the more common infringements among businesses was the installation of software on more than one computer within a company after the purchase of one legitimate copy.</p>
<p>It said it was offering a Singapore $20,000 (US$ 14,000) reward for leads on companies using pirated software.</p>
<p>Despite the setback in 1996, Singapore still has the second lowest piracy rate in Asia, the BSA said.  </p>
<p>The survey showed the piracy rate rose three points in Malaysia to 80 percent, two points to 64 percent in Hong Kong and by one point in the Philippines to 92 percent.</p>
<p>Piracy rates fell two points in Thailand to 80 percent, one point in Indonesia to 97 percent, six points to 70 percent in South Korea and four points in Taiwan to 66 percent, the survey said.</p>
<p>US$1 =S$1.44</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
