<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="571940" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Autodesk ships new release of AutoCAD.</title>
<headline>Autodesk ships new release of AutoCAD.</headline>
<dateline>SAN RAFAEL, Calif. 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Autodesk Inc said on Friday it began shipping AutoCAD Release 14, a new version of its flagship design software product.</p>
<p>The new version of AutoCAD -- which helps architects and engineers design the guts of buildings and machines -- draws and calculates designs much faster than the previous version, the company said. It is also easier to use, according to trade magazines that have tested it.  </p>
<p>The new release of AutoCAD also could encourage many of the Autodesk's 1.6 million existing customers to upgrade, which would bolster revenue, said Christine Tsingos, Autodesk vice president and treasurer.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly it's an important factor this year&quot; to the company's growth, Tsingos said. It is the centerpiece of a recent reorganization at the company and the most important release among a slew of new products this year, she said.  </p>
<p>Autodesk, based in San Rafael, Calif., got about 70 percent of its $496.7 million revenue last fiscal year from AutoCAD sales and related products. The company depends heavily on new versions of AutoCAD for growth.</p>
<p>Revenue declined seven percent last fiscal year, ended January 31, because AutoCAD Release 13 did not sell well. The previous version had been plagued by some performance problems and was not well received by the technical press.  </p>
<p>About half of the company's 1.6 million customers are still using AutoCAD Release 12, Tsingos said. Release 14, with better performance and ease-of-use, could encourage customers to upgrade, she said.</p>
<p>Investors have been awaiting the new product eagerly. Goldman Sachs &amp; Co, a prominent Wall Street investment bank, upgraded its rating on Autodesk's stock to &quot;trading buy&quot; in April partly based on the prospect of the new product.</p>
<p>Autodesk shares have jumped in recent weeks in anticipation of the launch. The stock rose 5/8 to 39-1/8.</p>
<p>((--Kourosh Karimkhany, in Palo Alto, 415 846 5401))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN RAFAEL, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
