<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="572295" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JSkyB says in talks with Fuji TV on capital tie-up.</title>
<headline>JSkyB says in talks with Fuji TV on capital tie-up.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan Sky Broadcasting Corp (JSkyB) is in talks with Japanese terrestrial broadcasting company Fuji Television on its possible capital participation in JSkyB, a JSkyB spokesman told Reuters on Friday.  </p>
<p>JSkyB is also talking with Walt Disney Co and several Japanese terrestrial broadcasters other than Fuji TV on content supply and possible capital participation in JSkyB, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;But Fuji TV in particular has a strong interest in taking a stake in JSkyB,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>JSkyB is a satellite broadcasting venture already linking Softbank Corp, News Corp Ltd and Sony Corp.</p>
<p>JSkyB hopes to complete talks with Fuji TV as early as possible, or at least during News Corp chairman Rupert Murdoch's visit to Japan next week, he said.</p>
<p>Murdoch is to visit Japan on May 14 to make a keynote speech at the World Congress of the International Federation of the Periodical Press on May 15.</p>
<p>Murdoch is expected to stay in Japan for two or three days, he said.  </p>
<p>Fuji Television is to go public on the Tokyo Stock Exchange this autumn.</p>
<p>JSkyB will start test-beaming in Japan this spring and aims to offer 150 channels in spring 1998.</p>
<p>Although Softbank president Masayoshi Son has said Softbank News Corp Sony will own equal stakes in JSkyB, an announcement has been delayed.</p>
<p>The talks with terrestrial broadcasters are in line with media tycoon Murdoch's policy of providing local-language content in its satellite broadcasting programmes, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>But media reports said Murdoch had difficulties convincing Japanese broadcasters to supply content to JSkyB until Sony early this year announced its participation in JSkyB.</p>
<p>Tough competition for subscribers is expected this autumn when Hughes Electronics Corp group's DirecTV plans to start a 100-channel service. Japan's PerfecTV started a multi-channel satellite broadcasting service last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
