<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="573404" id="root" date="1997-05-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JSkyB says in talks with Fuji TV on capital tie-up.</title>
<headline>JSkyB says in talks with Fuji TV on capital tie-up.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Media giant News Corp's Japanese satellite broadcasting venture, Japan Sky Broadcasting Corp (JSkyB), is seeking to recruit a strong ally from the powerful Japanese terrestrial broadcasting camp.</p>
<p>A JSkyB spokesman told Reuters on Friday that it was in talks with Japan's Fuji Television Network, which is known for the variety of its programme content libraries, on possible capital participation in JSkyB.</p>
<p>A Fuji TV official confirmed that the two firms were discussing conditions of equity participation and details of cooperation in the JSkyB venture.</p>
<p>The JSkyB spokesman also said it was also talking with Walt Disney Co and several Japanese terrestrial broadcasters other than Fuji TV on content supply and possible capital participation.</p>
<p>&quot;But Fuji TV in particular has a strong interest in taking a stake,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>JSkyB is a satellite broadcasting venture linking News Corp, Sony Corp and computer software publishing and exhibition company Softbank Corp.</p>
<p>JSkyB hopes to complete talks with Fuji TV as early as possible, or at least during News Corp chairman's Rupert Murdoch's visit to Japan next week, he said.</p>
<p>Industry watchers said Murdoch, who is visiting Japan on May 14 and plans to stay two or three days, plans a news conference on May 14.</p>
<p>Hisashi Hieda, president of Fuji TV, has repeatedly expressed interest in joining one of the satellite broadcasters.</p>
<p>Fuji, which is going public this autumn, has recently refurbished its studios and headquarters in preparation for its entry into digital television.</p>
<p>JSkyB will start test-beaming in Japan this spring and aims to offer 150 channels in spring 1998.</p>
<p>The talks with terrestrial broadcasters are in line with Murdoch's policy of providing local-language content in satellite broadcasting programmes, the JSkyB spokesman said.</p>
<p>But media reports said Murdoch had difficulties convincing Japanese broadcasters to supply content to JSkyB until Sony early this year announced its participation in the project.</p>
<p>Tough competition for subscribers is expected this autumn when Hughes Electronics Corp group's DirecTV plans to start a 100-channel service. Japan's PerfecTV started a multi-channel satellite broadcasting service last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
