<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="581117" id="root" date="1997-05-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Sony, News Corp, Softbank, Fuji to be JSkyB partners.</title>
<headline>Sony, News Corp, Softbank, Fuji to be JSkyB partners.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-05-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fuji Television Network, Sony Corp, News Corp and Softbank Corp will become equal partners in the Japanese satellite broadcasting venture Japan Sky Broadcasting Corp (JSkyB), a Fuji spokesman said on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>The Fuji spokesman did not indicate the size of the stake each of the four partners would hold in JSkyB but he said that some other investors would be minor shareholders.</p>
<p>The four major partners will hold a news conference at 3 p.m. (0600 GMT) on Wednesday to announce the alliance, the Fuji spokesman said.</p>
<p>The spokesman did not say who would take the minor stakes in JSkyB, but industry sources said they might include a unit of Walt Disney Co and Japanese trading house Marubeni Corp.  </p>
<p>&quot;The four investors will cooperate and work hard for the success of JSkyB,&quot; the Fuji spokesman said.</p>
<p>JSkyB was originally set up by News Corp and Softbank, a computer software distribution and publishing company.</p>
<p>JSkyB will start test broadcasts in Japan this spring and aims to offer 150 channels in the spring of 1998.</p>
<p>Fuji, which is one of Japan's major terrestrial broadcasters, will provide programme content, personnel and various technologies to JSkyB, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Jiji news agency said on Tuesday that JSkyB's four major partners would have about a 20 percent stake each in the venture.</p>
<p>Last week, a JSkyB spokesman said the company was talking with Walt Disney Co about possible capital participation.</p>
<p>But on Tuesday, the Japanese business daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun said Disney had not agreed to invest in JSkyB, without making it clear whether talks were continuing or not.</p>
<p>Nihon Keizai said last week that Marubeni was considering whether to take a stake in the satellite broadcasting venture.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
