<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="584359" id="root" date="1997-05-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: LA Dodgers whack News Corp shares lower.</title>
<headline>LA Dodgers whack News Corp shares lower.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-05-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Rupert Murdoch's News Corp Ltd were hit lower on Wednesday on concerns over its plans to buy the Los Angeles Dodgers baseball team and U.S. cable TV group International Family Entertainment Corp.</p>
<p>However, this was partially offset by positive reaction to News Corp's securing respected partners to its Japanese satellite broadcasting venture JSkyB in Tokyo today.</p>
<p>Over A$400 million was wiped off News Corp share value, when the stock price ended the day 21 cents or 3.54 percent down at A$5.72 with nearly seven million shares traded.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think News Corp has a lot of balls in the air and that (LA Dodgers) is one more,&quot; said one Sydney media analyst, who did not want to be named.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Los Angeles Dodgers sought permission to sell the baseball team to Fox Sports, a unit of News Corp. The sale is reported to be worth up to US$350 million and would be Murdoch's first move to directly own a professional sport team.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people are looking at the LA Dodgers deal and saying 'oh God what are they doing?'&quot; said a Melbourne-based media analyst, who added that at this level, News Corp shares were undervalued.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the market was still wary of big acquisitions by News Corp, adding the reports that Murdoch's plans to buy International Family Entertainment, the owner of cable channel the Family Channel were not positive.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a billion dollar deal, but where is the strategy?,&quot; another Sydney-based media analyst said.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal reported on Wednesday that News Corp is closer to buying the Family Channel owner, but the deal may hit snags over demands by the Robertson family, which controls International Family Entertainment.  </p>
<p>Murdoch, who is currently in Tokyo to launch JSkyB, said he is in talks to buy the L.A. Dodgers, one of America's most famous sports franchises.</p>
<p>Analysts said the JSkyB venture was the one bit of positive news to come from News Corp recently. News Corp will jointly own JSkyB with Fuji Television Network, Sony Corp and Softbank.</p>
<p>&quot;JSkyB is very good news,&quot; said the Melbourne analyst. JSkyB aims to offer 150 channels from around April 1998.</p>
<p>However, analysts said there was still disappointment with News Corp U.S. satellite television broadcasting plans.  </p>
<p>News faces legal action in the U.S. from its would-be satellite partner EchoStar Communications Corp  DISH.O as the $1.0 billion deal signed in February appeared to unravel.</p>
<p>Murdoch was to use EchoStar, a maker and distributor of satellite TV products, to form a major part of its planned U.S. satellite TV plans under the ASkyB banner, but the partnership as been hit a series of snags from technical to legal issues.</p>
<p>&quot;Who knows what is going to happen with AskyB?&quot; said a third Sydney-based media analyst. News Corp ordinary and preference shares soared after the EchoStar deal was signed three months ago, but analysts said this was now priced out of the stock.  </p>
<p>News Corp preference shares also fell sharply on Wednesday, by 18 cents or 3.67 percent to A$4.72, which is about 22 percent below the level hit after the Echostar deal in February, the ordinary shares have fallen 20 percent over the same time.</p>
<p>Analysts are also concerned over News Corp's 1997/98 profits which are in danger of being holed by the disaster movie &quot;Titanic&quot;, which is estimated to have cost more than US$200 million to make.</p>
<p>&quot;All this is not making investors feel comfortable in the short term,&quot; the Melbourne analyst said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
