<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="593867" id="root" date="1997-05-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Post-expiry, pre-FOMC lethargy.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Post-expiry, pre-FOMC lethargy.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-05-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Activity in U.S. equity options was very lean as the market was enveloped in lethargy after Friday's May option expiration and ahead of Tuesday's Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting, traders said.</p>
<p>Apart from a few large institutional spread deals that had a somewhat hedge-oriented bias and perennial speculative trading in some technology stocks, volume was very thin.</p>
<p>&quot;I should say it's a slow Monday after the expiration,&quot; said Andrew Schwarz, a senior partner of AGS Specialist Partners. &quot;And ahead of the FOMC meeting, of course.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders were evenly divided on whether the Federal Reserve would raise interest rates. But even those who expected a rate hike said the market was likely to resume its bull trend after perhaps a brief selloff.</p>
<p>&quot;It will sell off on that, but that will be a good buying spot,&quot; said Jay Shartsis, director of options trading at R.F. Lafferty &amp; Co.</p>
<p>In fact, even as most of the market awaited the FOMC, low-delta calls on the battered Hewlett-Packard Co shares attracted bottom-fishing bids, said Rod Jamieson, vice president of option strategies at EVEREN Securities.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think they're just playing it for a trading bounce,&quot; he said. &quot;You might have some people who are a little nervous going into the FOMC, but with some of these tech stocks they don't really care.&quot;</p>
<p>Hewlett shares, which were sold off last week after a subpar earnings report, were up 1/8 at 52-1/2.</p>
<p>June 55 calls with volume of 3,338 contracts were among the busiest options on the Chicago Board Options Exchange, while June 60 calls traded 1,079 contracts.</p>
<p>On the Pacific Stock Exchange, 10,000 contracts each of Adobe Systems Inc January 40 and 35 puts traded.  </p>
<p>The stock was off 3/4 at 44 in early afternoon trade.</p>
<p>&quot;They're buying the Jan 40s and selling the Jan 35s, so they're very bearish,&quot; Harrison Roth, first vice president of Cowen &amp; Co, said of the vertical spread by an institution.</p>
<p>On the American Stock Exchange (AMEX), Seagate Technology Inc June 30 calls and 30 puts had turnover of 4,640 and 3,600 contracts respectively, while June 45 puts traded 2,395 contracts. The stock was down 2-1/2 at 46.</p>
<p>Most of the selling in the deep in-the-money 30 calls and buying in the out-of-the-money 30 puts were done in a conversion trade against a stock position, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;A lot of the trades today were a conversion on the June 30 line,&quot; Schwarz said. &quot;But outside of that, there was one institutional customer who was buying a lot of puts.&quot;</p>
<p>He noted that the big put purchases fueled concern about the stock, which had been declining steadily since early May from just below 55.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been a rather substantial increase in volatility,&quot; Schwarz said. Implied volatility for at-the-money July 45 puts stood at about 58 percent, slightly above the stock's historical one-month volatility of about 50 percent.</p>
<p>-- Chicago Derivatives Desk ((312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
