<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="602051" id="root" date="1997-05-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: More murder on the Orient Express.</title>
<headline>More murder on the Orient Express.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Robert Cath, 29, is a physician and a ladies man who has a reputation for being able to get into trouble in four languages. His interest in esoteric forms of medicine has gotten him banned from practice in America. He's wanted by British police for a murder he didn't commit.</p>
<p>And when his old friend Tyler Whitney invites him on a trip aboard the Orient Express in 1914, he discovers that Whitney has been stabbed to death in their compartment. Whitney's trunk, designed to hold a foot-long egg-shaped object, is empty.</p>
<p>So Cath dumps Whitney's body out of the moving train, assumes Whitney's identity, and finds himself locked in a web of international intrigue, where more than a few people want to slit his throat for reasons he can't begin to understand.</p>
<p>Confused? You're supposed to be. But making sense of everything is part of the fun of playing &quot;The Last Express,&quot; an adventure game from Broderbund (Windows/DOS/Macintosh, $40, http://www.lastexpress.com), where players help Cath mingle with the assortment of characters riding the train, many of whom have hidden motives for making the trip from Paris to Constantinople on the eve of the First World War.</p>
<p>Through wit and cunning, a couple of excursions outside the train while it is barrelling down the tracks at full throttle, plus more than a few unauthorised searches in the compartments of your fellow travelers, you can start to unravel what Whitney was up to and why you might have been better off catching a steamer to some warm tropical island.</p>
<p>From the box, &quot;The Last Express&quot; looks like an animated cartoon with wonderfully-detailed backgrounds that match the opulence of the legendary train. The backgrounds are certainly lush -- players will need to know how to reset their computers for 16-bit colour instead of the 256 colours that most multi-media games use.</p>
<p>But there is much less animation that you would expect, which makes &quot;The Last Express&quot; more like an interactive comic book. The characters' lips don't move and, except in some cases such as the fighting scenes, you don't have the fluid movement you get with a cartoon.</p>
<p>But it's the story that makes &quot;The Last Express&quot; interesting and the sound effects that give the story life. There's plenty of sophisticated programming behind this game, as people come and go through the train regardless of what you do.</p>
<p>Most of the time it's easy to move through the story. A double-click in the corridor gets you to the next train car. Pulling something out of your inventory is simple. But mastering the system for fighting can be frustrating until you get the hang of it.</p>
<p>Fortunately, if you die, you can always turn back the hands of the clock, return to an earlier point in the game and try again.</p>
<p>If you're more interested in a good story and international intrigue than you are in seamless computerized animation -- and you're not going to be disappointed that you can't prevent World War I -- &quot;The Last Express&quot; is worth the ride.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Broderbund, which aggressively repackages and mixes previously-released educational titles to produce more combos than a Burger King menu, has rejuggled the contents of the first two volumes of its &quot;Learning Advantage Libraries&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $60 each) and added two new ones.</p>
<p>Most of the programmes in the series are excellent. But the juggling could cause problems for consumers who invested in the old Volumes 1 and 2 when they were released last year.</p>
<p>For example, if you're thinking of buying Volume 2 in the series because you have the old Volume 1, you're going to end up with two copies of &quot;Carmen Sandiego, Junior Detective Edition&quot; because that programme was originally in Volume 1.</p>
<p>And if you're thinking of buying Volume 3 because you already have Volumes 1 and 2, you're going to get burned. Volume 3 has precisely the same four programmes that were in the old Volume 2.</p>
<p>The juggling allows Broderbund to slap the word &quot;New&quot; on all four volumes.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>You might imagine that the crayon company Crayola, which built part of its reputation on having an extraordinary rainbow of colours, wouldn't lend its brand name to a computerized colouring product that has only 21 colours to choose from.</p>
<p>If you did, you'd be wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;Crayola Magic 3D Colouring Book&quot; (IBM, Windows, $30) offers fewer than two dozen colours and 13 patterns for the 70 pictures that come with this product, which is designed for ages 3 to 8.</p>
<p>Like other computerized colouring books, &quot;Crayola Magic' automatically prevents a child from colouring outside the lines (although you have the option of telling it to do otherwise).</p>
<p>This programme usurps a child's creativity in other ways. As soon as a child assigns a colour to one stripe on a fish, all the alternating stripes are automatically assigned the same colour. If a child colours the bland, featureless outline of a dinosaur, for example, it will ultimately appear to have a three-dimensional quality because the shading that depicts eyes, a crest and a big belly automatically appears.</p>
<p>There's a certain charm in the drawings of children, no matter how crude. This product strips their pictures of such charm because the images it produces are too good.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
