<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="620527" id="root" date="1997-05-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CD-ROMs from other worlds.</title>
<headline>CD-ROMs from other worlds.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Today's topics: moonshine, the Fonz and space aliens.</p>
<p>First, imagine if &quot;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&quot; had been an episode of &quot;Happy Days.&quot; Considering what the alien ships deposited on the Earth in &quot;Close Encounters,&quot; what might they have brought Richie Cunningham?</p>
<p>A.) Warnings about &quot;Joanie Loves Chaci,&quot;</p>
<p>B.) Hundreds of evil Richie clones,</p>
<p>C.) The head of Arthur Fonzarelli,</p>
<p>D.) His brother, who vanished after two seasons.</p>
<p>Sure, the question is loopy. But what else would you expect from the folks responsible for the &quot;You Don't Know Jack&quot; series of warped trivia games. Now the people at Berkeley Systems and Jellyvision have come up with over 800 delightfully demented questions about television and films for &quot;You Don't Know Jack: Movies&quot; (Berkeley, Windows/Macintosh, $30, http://www.berkeleysystems.com).</p>
<p>With bizarre categories such as &quot;What kind of pervert romances a stone?&quot;, up to three players at the same keyboard can get involved in this fast-paced TV game show-style game, complete with crazy commercials and a host who makes wisecracks.</p>
<p>None of the sequels in the &quot;You Don't Know Jack&quot; series have been quite as good as the original. The humour hasn't seemed as biting, the snide comments from the host aren't as clever, and the raciness of the material seems to have been toned down.</p>
<p>But the entertaiment value of this series is so superior to most computer games, it hardly matters. If you know what's good for you (and you're not bothered by suggestive sexual references), you'll get to know this &quot;Jack.&quot;</p>
<p>(The answer, by the way, is D. The alien ships in &quot;Close Encounters&quot; brought back things that had mysteriously disappeared years earlier, and Richie's brother, Chuck, disappeared after the second season.)</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Moonshine and space aliens are two key ingredients if you want to get involved in a little &quot;Redneck Rampage&quot; (Interplay, DOS, $50).</p>
<p>This shoot-'em-up game is what you get when you cross Jed Clampett's stupid cousins with &quot;Doom,&quot; &quot;Descent,&quot; &quot;Quake&quot; or &quot;Duke Nukem 3D.&quot; The premise is that space aliens visiting Hickston, USA, have kidnapped Leonard and Bubba's prize pig and turned every other living creature into malevolent alien sympathisers.</p>
<p>And NOBODY takes on Leonard and Bubba's pig without gettin' their butts whupped.</p>
<p>This means that you get to shoot down or blow up every other person, dog, pig, cow, chicken and extraterrestrial on the premises because they're either evil space aliens or possessed by evil space aliens.</p>
<p>When &quot;Redneck Rampage&quot; promises &quot;All the killin', twice the humour, half the intelligence,&quot; it delivers.</p>
<p>&quot;That boy blowed up real good,&quot; Leonard says as the dynamite crossbow blasts the blood of one burly backwoods type against a barn. And if you get tired of fighting with crowbars, shotguns and ripsaws, you can try mowing down people with the alien bra gun.</p>
<p>If your health wanes because you've caught too many bullets, you can recharge by finding (and consuming) pork rinds, cow pies, moonshine, whiskey or a six-pack. But if you eat too much, you lose your ability to run, and if you drink too much, you're not always able to walk in the direction you intend to.</p>
<p>If you find the lead content of your body rising to unhealthy levels, try these cheat codes: typing RDELVIS makes you invulnerable, RDALL gives you all the items you'll need plus full health, and RDUNLOCK unlocks (or locks) all the doors.</p>
<p>The booze and the blood are two reasons why this game is rated for ages 17 and older. A third is the language, which isn't appropriate for younger teenagers and certainly isn't acceptable in polite company.</p>
<p>The really shocking thing about &quot;Redneck Rampage&quot; and its equally violent cousins is that despite my disapproval, I find them addicting. Maybe it means there's a little bit of redneck in all of us.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>A few slugs of moonshine may be behind Omnimedia's full-page ad in the May issue of HomePC suggesting that the CIA is behind the infamous &quot;Alien Autopsy&quot; movie that purported to show the autopsy of a real extraterrestrial. It's all part of the hype to sell &quot;Incident at Roswell&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $20), the CD-ROM version of a documentary that aired on Britain's Channel Four Television in 1995.</p>
<p>Unlike the three hokey &quot;specials&quot; aired that year on the Fox network, which ignored virtually everyone who thought the film was a hoax (and that was most of the experts who viewed it), the Channel Four production points out some flaws in the movie.</p>
<p>But the video on this CD-ROM is so grainy that much of the detail is lost. I even had trouble reading the names that were superimposed on the screen.</p>
<p>If you're interested in this stuff, save your money and take a look this sobering World Wide Web site: http://www.trudang.com/autopsy.html your life.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-05-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-05-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
