<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63244" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Novell to flatten management structure.</title>
<headline>Novell to flatten management structure.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novell Inc President and Chief Operating Officer Joe Marengi said on Thursday a 12-person management team will be responsible for decisions at the software company in order to better present a &quot;single face to the customer&quot; and flatten the management team.</p>
<p>He also told a teleconfernce call that the announced departure on Thursday of executive vice president and general manager of Novell Products Group, Steve Markman &quot;had been looked at for a while.&quot; Markham left after nine months with Novell, which has seeng several top executives depart in recent months.  </p>
<p>Marengi, who defended the new structure, said the group will be able to make decisions with the kind of speed needed in today's market.</p>
<p>Marengi became president when Chief Executive Officer Bob Frankenberg resigned in late August.</p>
<p>Marengi said he recently met five chief information officers from &quot;major companies&quot; in Europe whom he said are committed to Novell's Netware 4.0 product.</p>
<p>Marengi did not identify the chief information officers or the companies during the conference call.</p>
<p>Novell has been beset with problems and its stock price has been languishing around the $10 level. Shares closed trading today at 10-5/8, off 5/8 in exchange trading.</p>
<p>The company is searching for a chief executive and that goal is still on course, Marengi told reporters.</p>
<p>Among those reporting to Marengi will be Mary Burnside, executive vice president for corporate services, chief technology officer Glenn Ricart and Jim Tolonen, chief financial officer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
