<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="63363" id="root" date="1996-09-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PC makers cheered by pre-holiday demand.</title>
<headline>PC makers cheered by pre-holiday demand.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Personal computer makers are looking forward to a brighter holiday season this year, thanks to a stronger economy and recent technological improvements for businesses and consumers alike.</p>
<p>After suffering from an oversupply of PCs last Christmas, PC manufacturers adopted a more conservative production schedule this year. But now, with signs of PC demand picking up, they are beginning to pick up the pace on the assembly line.</p>
<p>&quot;Typically the PC market has its best months in the last two months of the year,&quot; said Cliff Apsey, director of product marketing at NEC Computer's commercial systems unit.</p>
<p>&quot;This year in particular, 1996, there are a couple of other factors that are leaning heavily (toward a year-end sales boost),&quot; he said. &quot;It's going to be very competitive.&quot;</p>
<p>NEC Computer is a unit of Japan's NEC Corp.</p>
<p>Intel Corp., the world's largest computer chip maker, provided the latest hint of a stronger market Monday when it told investors sales for the third quarter ending in September would be better than previously forecast.</p>
<p>The news provided a boost to the technology sector, with many experts predicting the industry is heading for an upturn.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the doom and gloom early in the year has lifted,&quot; said John McCarthy, a research director at Forrester Research.</p>
<p>The overall strength of the U.S. economy, with high levels of both consumer and business confidence, is seen as the primary driver behind the improved sales outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of what's driving the consumer market right now is really external to the industry: consumer confidence is at an all-time high,&quot; said Steve Foster, who tracks the consumer market at NEC Computer.</p>
<p>Also driving sales growth are technological improvements, such as Microsoft Corp.'s new Windows NT 4.O operating system targeted at business use, and the development of more consumer-friendly products for the home market.</p>
<p>Analysts said rising sales may also reflect greater price competition in the cutthroat PC market, which McCarthy said is vulnerable to any future economic downturn.</p>
<p>&quot;When the economy goes south, you'll see a bloodbath that's going to reverberate through all levels of the industry,&quot; he said. &quot;Consumers will stop buying (computers) when the choice is buying a new machine or paying the mortgage.&quot;</p>
<p>In the meantime, the industry is hoping a new round of &quot;packaging,&quot; adding new whiz-bang features to their PCs, will attract customers during the critical pre-holiday period when more than 40 percent of home PCs are sold.</p>
<p>San Jose, Calif.-based Dataquest, whose forecast early in the year that home PC market growth would slow to 8 percent in 1996 had chilled the market, is revising that upward and now expects the U.S. home market to grow by around 12 percent, said Van Baker, director of consumer research.</p>
<p>&quot;We're pretty optimistic on the Christmas season for several reasons,&quot; said Baker. He said PC makers are beginning to develop new categories and price ranges, including machines selling for below $1,000.</p>
<p>&quot;We definitely think the second half is going to see better growth than the first&quot; in the home market, he said, noting that PCs coming out soon will be more customized for home use.</p>
<p>Overall, he said, Dataquest expects U.S. sales momentum to build toward the end of the year. For the first six months of 1996, U.S. home PC sales rose 11.8 percent to 3.3 million units, a slower rate than the 24.4 percent growth in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>Shipments of PCs for businesses grew 17.6 percent to nearly 6.5 million units in the same period, off slightly from 19.8 percent growth in 1995's first half. The government and education sectors grew 12.2 percent and 8.1 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Intel spokesman Tom Waldrop said that although the company does not publish its own PC market forecasts, it has from the beginning of the year stated it agreed with estimates of 1996 PC unit shipments &quot;in the high teens to 20 percent growth&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
