<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="641208" id="root" date="1997-06-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Electronic Arts to buy Maxis for $125 million.</title>
<headline>Electronic Arts to buy Maxis for $125 million.</headline>
<byline>Kourosh Karimkhany</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Electronic Arts Inc. agreed to buy rival video game software company Maxis Inc. and its hot-selling line of &quot;SimCity&quot; products for about $125 million in stock, the companies said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Under the transaction, Electronic Arts, the biggest video game software company, will pay 0.3644 of its shares for each of Maxis' 11.26 million shares outstanding. Based on Electronic Arts' closing stock price of $30.375, Electronic Arts would pay about $11.07 for each Maxis share.</p>
<p>Maxis, based in Walnut Creek, California, is best known for its line of &quot;Sim&quot; games, which allow players to construct and run cities, ant colonies, planets or golf courses. Its &quot;SimCity&quot; product is one of the best-selling titles in the software industry.</p>
<p>Although Maxis' products consistently land in top-10 software charts, the company has struggled in recent quarters. It has had to cut prices and has been elbowed aside by bigger video game companies like Electronic Arts and Microsoft Corp. on retail shelves.</p>
<p>&quot;This will allow Maxis to have access to EA's worldwide distribution organisation, one of the strongest in the industry,&quot; said Sam Poole, Maxis chief executive.</p>
<p>Electronic Arts is getting a top company for a relatively cheap price, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;'SimCity' is one of the best-known brands in the industry ever,&quot; said Mike Wallace at investment bank UBS Securities in New York. &quot;SimCity 3000&quot;, a new version of the product expected to be released by Christmas, could alone generate $40 million in its first year of sale, Wallace said.</p>
<p>In recent years, Electronic Arts, based in San Mateo, Calif., has been acquiring or investing in smaller software companies to insure it a steady supply of hit video games.</p>
<p>&quot;'SimCity' is one of the most valuable franchises in our industry,&quot; said Larry Probst, Electronic Arts CEO. With the acquisition, Electronic Arts could construct a whole universe of &quot;Sim&quot; products, including online versions, he said.</p>
<p>The companies said they expect to complete the transaction in August. Electronic Arts said it expects the deal to be tax-free.</p>
<p>Probst said it was too early to tell how big of a charge Electronic Arts will have to take to cover acquisition expenses and that it was premature to discuss job cuts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
