<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="646984" id="root" date="1997-06-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft expands cable TV reach with Comcast deal.</title>
<headline>Microsoft expands cable TV reach with Comcast deal.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. Monday agreed to invest $1 billion in cable operator Comcast Corp. in what executives called a bid to speed the convergence of the television and the personal computer.</p>
<p>The investment, which gives Microsoft an 11.5 percent stake in the nation's No. 4 cable television company, is the biggest ever for the software giant, underscoring its determination to shape the development of both the Internet and emerging digital television technology.</p>
<p>&quot;What we're looking at here is a vision where not only can the PC experience be better with the high-speed connection, but also there can be a new generation of TV experience,&quot; Microsoft Chairman Bill Gates said in a conference call with reporters and analysts.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said the move reflected Microsoft's interest in expanding the available &quot;bandwidth&quot; into homes to speed the development of interactive programming and drive sales of various versions of its Windows software.</p>
<p>&quot;They need to find new reasons for people to buy PCs or to buy TV sets with operating systems installed,&quot; said Scott McAdams of Ragen MacKenzie. &quot;This is really all a part of trying to find that market.&quot;</p>
<p>Both Gates and Comcast President Brian Roberts said they hoped the investment would &quot;galvanize&quot; the cable television industry to speed the rollout of interactive services.</p>
<p>Despite the size of the investment, the latest of several high-profile ventures into television, Gates insisted Microsoft was not becoming a media company and would remain focused on its core business of developing computer software and &quot;interactive content.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are not in the cable business ourselves, we will never be in the cable business ourselves,&quot; Gates said. &quot;This is not an expansion of the businesses that Microsoft is in.&quot;</p>
<p>In April Microsoft agreed to pay $425 million for WebTV Networks, and Microsoft also is investing at least $250 million over five years in MSNBC, an internet and cable news venture jointly owned with NBC.</p>
<p>Philadelphia-based Comcast, which serves 10 million cable subscribers, had not been looking for a capital infusion when Roberts and Gates began discussing a collaboration two months ago, Roberts said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We sat down with Microsoft and heard their plans, and they dovetailed exactly with our plans,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the Microsoft backing would allow the company to accelerate its deployment of cable modems, which allow high-speed Internet access, as well as reduce its debt and buy back stock.</p>
<p>Under the deal, which is expected to close in &quot;weeks,&quot; according to a Microsoft executive, the software giant will buy 24.6 million shares of Comcast Class A special common stock for $500 million, and $500 million of a new issue of Comcast Series B convertible preferred stock.</p>
<p>The Series B shares will pay a 5.25 percent in-kind dividend and will be initially convertible into 21.2 million shares, which equals an initial conversion price of $23.54 a share. The conversion price will rise as the dividends accrue.</p>
<p>Comcast Class A shares surged $2.875 to $21.125 on Nasdaq, where Microsoft added $1.0625 to $125.125.</p>
<p>Anna-Maria Kovacs, an analyst at Janney Montgomery Scott, said the rollout of Internet services could provide a real boost to Comcast and other cable companies, which have been slow to reap the promised rewards of new interactive services.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of us who use the Internet are really frustrated to death by the slowness,&quot; she said. &quot;And, clearly, when you upgrade your networks for the Internet, you are also upgrading them for more video channels as well.&quot;</p>
<p>In the conference call, Gates referred repeatedly to the parallel developments of the &quot;connected PC&quot; and the &quot;connected TV&quot; and indicated Microsoft intends to be a player in both worlds as they converge.</p>
<p>&quot;Microsoft is in the business of selling software and taking over the world,&quot; said Mark Carleton, director of the cable television practice of consulting firm KPMG Peat Warwick. &quot;Having a direct line into the distribution network isn't going to contradict that view.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
