<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="649948" id="root" date="1997-06-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intuit to restructure operations, lay off 10 percent.</title>
<headline>Intuit to restructure operations, lay off 10 percent.</headline>
<dateline>MOUTAIN VIEW, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intuit Inc., facing slowing sales of its financial software, said Tuesday it plans to cut about 270 jobs, or 10 percent of its work force, and consolidate its technical support centres around the world.</p>
<p>The job cuts will help the company concentrate its financial resources on developing new products, particularly on the Internet, said Intuit President Bill Campbell.</p>
<p>Intuit publishes the best-selling financial computer programmes Quicken and Turbotax. Although its products consistently land on top-10 software sales charts, Intuit has been struggling in recent quarters because prices for consumer software are tumbling.</p>
<p>The Mountain View, Calif.-based company is placing its bets on the Internet. It is developing services that would enable consumers to shop for insurance policies, mortgages, retirement plans and other financial products online.</p>
<p>But it may take at least a year before the online products provide revenue growth again, company executives said.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of these moves are to focus our resources on growth,&quot; Campbell said. &quot;We're not looking for real fast growth in the short term.&quot;</p>
<p>To save costs, Intuit will close a technical centre in Rio Rancho, New Mexico, where 300 people answer calls about software problems. In its place, the company will add 150 jobs to a Tucson, Ariz., facility. In northern California, Intuit will fire 50 people.</p>
<p>The company also will centralize its European operations in Munich, Germany, cutting about 70 jobs throughout Europe.</p>
<p>Intuit has taken other cost-cutting moves in recent months. In late May, it agreed to sell its Parsons Technology unit, which publishes family-oriented software, to another company for undisclosed terms.</p>
<p>Intuit has told investors to lower their expectations for growth this year. Earlier this year, the company had said it would have revenue of between $600 million and $620 million for the year. Two weeks ago, executives said the figure would be closer to $600 million.</p>
<p>Intuit announced the job cuts after the market closed. Its shares fell 87.5 cents to $25 on Nasdaq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOUTAIN VIEW, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
