<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653462" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Autodesk seeks growth with AutoCAD &quot;flavors&quot;.</title>
<headline>Autodesk seeks growth with AutoCAD &quot;flavors&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Kourosh Karimkhany</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>By all accounts, AutoCAD is a nifty computer programme.</p>
<p>With this $3,750 product running on standard Windows PCs, engineers have drawn blueprints for everything from the world's tallest skyscraper to a personal submarine to opera stage sets. Engineers say AutoCAD is to the drafting table what the word processor was compared with the typewriter: A miracle.</p>
<p>Autodesk Inc., a company based in San Rafael, Calif., began selling AutoCAD 15 years ago. Based on its popularity, Autodesk is now the world's fifth-largest PC software company based on revenue.</p>
<p>Trouble is, AutoCAD accounts for about three-quarters of Autodesk's sales, and the company is having an increasingly hard time getting customers to buy new versions of AutoCAD when they come out about once every two years. Partly because of that, Autodesk revenue last year declined 7 percent to $496.6 million from the year before.</p>
<p>Autodesk executives said they think they have a strategy to get long-term growth going again -- introduce &quot;flavors&quot; of AutoCAD to suit the tastes of engineers in various fields.</p>
<p>&quot;In drafting with AutoCAD, a line could be a door for an architect, or it could be a flange for a mechanical engineer,&quot; said Robert Carr, Autodesk vice president in charge of AutoCAD. &quot;But walls, doors and windows are worse than useless for the mechanical person.&quot;</p>
<p>So the company later this year will introduce AutoCAD flavors for map makers, architects and mechanical engineers, each with design elements specific to the respective fields.</p>
<p>Last month, Autodesk also introduced a new version of AutoCAD, dubbed AutoCAD Release 14, to fix significant shortcomings in the preceding version, Release 13.</p>
<p>&quot;Release 14 blasts past Release 13,&quot; said Jose Gomez, an electrical designer for the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey. Gomez said he had been happy with Release 13 and had no plans to upgrade. But after testing Release 14, he and about 1,000 other Port Authority designers will switch to the new version.</p>
<p>Based on the new products, Autodesk's revenue could rise 20 percent this year, said Christine Tsingos, Autodesk treasurer. Autodesk's stock has jumped 80 percent since last August, partly in anticipation of the new product cycle.</p>
<p>Still, even with all the things Autodesk has going for it, the company does not have many fans among Wall Street analysts.</p>
<p>Just like Release 14, Release 13 had good word-of-mouth and Autodesk executives were bullish. But Release 13 turned out to have several huge shortcomings, and the company had lapses in customer service, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are (investors) out there that frankly got burned,&quot; said Autodesk Chief Executive Carol Bartz. &quot;These people are now saying, 'I'll sit out this time and see what happens.' It's up to us to prove ourselves.&quot;</p>
<p>Of the 16 analysts who track Autodesk, seven have a &quot;hold&quot; rating on the stock, five have a &quot;buy&quot; and four have a &quot;strong buy,&quot; according to Zacks Investment research.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sceptical they can sustain a growth rate of 20 percent for long,&quot; said Ben Rose, analyst at investment bank Adams, Harkness &amp; Hill in Boston. &quot;I would say in general their diversification effort has failed to produce a major hit outside of design.&quot;</p>
<p>Bartz said people like Rose have a right to be sceptical, but she is happy to take on the challenge of proving them wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;We've learned a lot as a company,&quot; Bartz said. This is a defining moment for Autodesk.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
