<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="653528" id="root" date="1997-06-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Trek game better late than never.</title>
<headline>Trek game better late than never.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>All the &quot;Star Trek&quot; television programmes are in reruns and there are no Trek movies being released in the near future, but fans of the legendary space adventure franchise who own a PC will be able to buy a lot of Trek-based CD-ROMs between now and the end of the year.</p>
<p>New on the shelves is MicroProse's &quot;Star Trek Generations&quot; (Windows 95, $50, 800-695-4263, http://www.microprose.com). The game is based on the movie that featured both captains of the USS Enterprise, James T. Kirk and Jean-Luc Picard.</p>
<p>It's about time.</p>
<p>&quot;Star Trek Generations&quot; (the movie) was released so long ago that the Trek gang have since come out with another film, &quot;Star Trek: First Contact,&quot; which is already in video stores.</p>
<p>In one way, &quot;Star Trek Generations&quot; (the CD-ROM) goes not-so-boldly where the movie has already gone before. The evil scientist Dr. Tolian Soran has found a way back to an idyllic dimension known as the Nexus and he is willing to destroy whole star systems to get there. As the crew of the Enterprise, it's your mission to stop him.</p>
<p>But the game expands on the plot of the movie, forcing you to visit several new worlds in search of Soran and the trilithium he will use to destroy stars and the inhabited worlds that surround them.</p>
<p>At each stop, individual members of the &quot;Next Generation&quot; crew get to beam down on a mission. For example, Data explores an abandoned mining facility guarded by robots, Worf has to sneak around at a Klingon base, and Troi has to go undercover to a Romulan base.</p>
<p>There are several reasons to recommend the game. First, it has single-person &quot;away&quot; missions, a feature that eliminates the clunkiness of past Star Trek CD-ROMs in which you had to try to control several crew members who beamed to a planet or space ship.</p>
<p>It has the voices of &quot;The Next Generation&quot; crew, the animation is fine, the video sequences (most taken from the film) are well done, and the musical score is first rate -- dramatic but not overbearing.</p>
<p>&quot;Generations&quot; can be challenging to play. The Enterprise controls seem cumbersome and clunky, at least at first. In the initial section aboard the Amargosa solar observatory, I kept getting shot by the Romulans no matter how I moved through the corridors looking for equipment, survivors and Soran.</p>
<p>Usually, these games let you save your position. If things don't go well, you can return to that spot in the story and try again.</p>
<p>Not in &quot;Generations.&quot; The game may give you a &quot;save&quot; option, but it is not what you would expect. I made it through two levels of the solar observatory, dutifully saving my position as I went along, only to discover that when I tried to reload a saved game, &quot;Generations&quot; took me back to the beginning of the section. I had to replay the two levels I had already mastered. This is a major source of frustration.</p>
<p>Adding insult to injury was the two-minute delay required to get back to each &quot;save&quot; point, a surprisingly long wait on a computer with a Pentium 90 chip and a quad-speed CD-ROM drive.</p>
<p>But, overall, there's enough here to keep Trek fans busy -- until the next Trek game comes along.</p>
<p>And that won't be long.</p>
<p>Due out in about a week is Interplay's &quot;Starfleet Academy,&quot; which has been hyped in dramatic full-colour magazine ads as &quot;The first-ever Star Trek space battle simulator.&quot; It has four Federation ships to fly and 25 missions.</p>
<p>Later in the year, Interplay is coming out with &quot;Star Trek: Secret of Vulcan Fury,&quot; which will include the voices of the original cast and a story by veteran Trek writer D.C. Fontana. &quot;Vulcan Fury&quot; looks at the history of the Vulcan and Romulan races. It's due in November for Windows 95 computers.</p>
<p>Simon &amp; Schuster Interactive says it will be releasing two Trek titles around the same time.</p>
<p>&quot;Star Trek Interactive Encyclopaedia&quot; will include 3,000 photos, 200 videos, and data and episode guides on all &quot;Star Trek&quot; movies and series through the 1996-1997 television season.</p>
<p>&quot;Star Trek Captain's Chair&quot; promises a virtual tour of five Starfleet ships: the original Enterprise, the two versions of the Enterprise piloted by Capt. Picard, the USS Voyager, and the Defiant from &quot;Star Trek: Deep Space Nine.&quot; Both Windows 95 and Macintosh versions are promised.</p>
<p>MicroProse is planning to preview a &quot;Star Trek: First Contact&quot; game at the upcoming Electronic Entertainment Expo in Atlanta. No release date has been given.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>A column two weeks ago on the &quot;You Don't Know Jack: Movies&quot; CD-ROM trivia game had a not-so-trivial mistake. The correct World Wide Web address for Berkeley Systems is http://www.berksys.com).</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
