<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="664676" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: FEATURE - Irish graduates take on Silicon valley.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Irish graduates take on Silicon valley.</headline>
<byline>Carmel Linnane</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Dublin graduates have taken on America's Silicon Valley and developed a product that has made even U.S. computer experts sit up, take notice, and invest in their ideas.</p>
<p>Ireland's 3.6 million population could fit neatly into a corner of some U.S. state. So too could a tiny Irish company called Iona Technologies.</p>
<p>But that is not how things have happened for Iona, a developer of highly sophisticated systems software, and the brainchild of Chris Horn and Annrai O'Toole, while both were based in Trinity College, Dublin.</p>
<p>Fascinated by computer technology they dabbled with the idea of simplifying a method of allowing different computer systems to talk to each other.</p>
<p>Iona broke new ground when it developed a novel product, ORBIX, which provides a tool kit for developers enabling them to access and distribute information in diverse systems.</p>
<p>Their product provides the &quot;communicative glue&quot; to mesh different products, whether deemed &quot;compatible&quot; or not, to allow a user to pick and choose across systems.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an age-old problem...people have been trying to connect different kinds of component software applications together,&quot; Horn, Iona's chief executive, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;As an analogy we are providing the pipework which allows you to build your plumbing systems. They can be simple or highly complex,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Iona, still with just a handful of staff, laboriously prepared the paperwork for its Initial Public Offer (IPO) on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>Such was their product's success that when their zero-funded &quot;campus start-up&quot; of the 1980s was launched on New York's stock exchange in February 1997 it was snapped up and is now capitalised at almost $400 million.</p>
<p>FIRST MAJOR BREAK</p>
<p>The company got its first major break at a trade show in the United States in 1992, when Sun Microsystems Inc displayed keen interest in their product to the point that six months later Sun bought a 25 percent stake in Iona for just $600,000.</p>
<p>&quot;Having Sun as an investor was a significant vote of approval from a major American player and probably gave us more leverage than a venture capitalist could have done at that time,&quot; Horn said.</p>
<p>Horn said Sun later offered to buy 100 percent of the company but after lengthy discussions it was decided that Iona would go it alone.</p>
<p>Response to its launch was such that its indicative launch price of $18 per share was ignored as the stock jumped to $22 right from the open.</p>
<p>Despite a downturn in the entire technology sector shortly after the launch, Iona reported a rise of 145 percent in total revenues to $9.1 million for the first quarter to March 30 when it released results on April 21.</p>
<p>&quot;We had an excellent first quarter and beat all analysts' expectations. I am confident our business is going very well for us. It continues to grow well and we are looking forward to substantial growth in the future,&quot; Horn said.</p>
<p>Horn said he believes his company has an 18-month technology lead over the competition and is going to fight hard to keep it that way.</p>
<p>LOOKING FOR SUITABLE PARTNERS</p>
<p>In a sector where mergers and acquisitions are rife, Horn said Iona was on the lookout for suitable bed-fellows as a matter of course.</p>
<p>&quot;We have raised over $60 million in cash and we have no debt</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
