<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666794" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China can win in virtual Opium War against Britain.</title>
<headline>China can win in virtual Opium War against Britain.</headline>
<byline>Mure Dickie</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Multimedia game technology is allowing China to refight the 19th century Opium War that led to the loss of Hong Kong to Britain -- and this time Beijing can win.</p>
<p>Officials of Chinese software developer Golden Disc Ltd said on Tuesday their Opium War computer game would boost patriotism among the nation's youth as more than 150 years of colonial humiliation come to an end with the return of Hong Kong on July 1.</p>
<p>The game, which takes potshots both at Britain's 1840-42 aggression and at the corruption and incompetence of the Qing dynasty (1644-1911) it defeated, would go on sale on June 28, said Golden Disc's games department manager Yang Nanzheng.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim of this game is to make children understand this period of history, because if the country is weak or backward it will be bullied and beaten,&quot; Yang said in an interview.</p>
<p>In the game, modern-day Chinese virtual Opium Warriors could seek funds to strengthen the nation's defences before sailing and marching into battle against the invading British, he said.</p>
<p>Beijing has been eager to use the end of London's colonial rule in Hong Kong to bolster patriotic fervour, unveiling films, television programmes and events aimed at underlining Chinese valour and British villainy.</p>
<p>Computer company officials said their game would introduce a new generation to heroes such as Lin Zexu, who triggered the Opium War by destroying Western-owned opium in 1839.</p>
<p>The conflict ended in 1842 with humiliating defeat for China's imperial rulers, who were forced to cede Hong Kong to the British invaders.</p>
<p>The new game makes clear that it was the corruption and complacency of Qing society that left it vulnerable to British assault, said Yang, who worked as a war games developer during his 23-year stint in China's People's Liberation Army.</p>
<p>Players meet widespread indifference from Qing officials as they search for funds for ships and cannon, Yang said.</p>
<p>A wrongly phrased appeal to the emperor could result in a virtual beating or even execution -- the kind of fate familiar to heroes such as Lin Zexu, who was sent into internal exile for his anti-narcotics efforts, he said.</p>
<p>Golden Discs Ltd, a venture by China's Qinghua University, expects to release a flight simulator game this year that will allow patriotic players to fly into combat against the U.S. Air Force in a rematch of the 1950-53 Korean war in which Beijing and Washington both took part.</p>
<p>Golden Disc also plans a game based on the Long March of China's communist revolutionaries in the 1930s and another on the 1931-45 war against Japan, officials said.</p>
<p>There was an urgent need for games that gave an alternative view from the warlike and hegemonistic U.S. and Japanese software that dominated much of the domestic market, said Yang.</p>
<p>&quot;Chinese children all love their country and they want to be educated in their history,&quot; he said, adding that Golden Disc expected initial sales of the 78-yuan ($9.40) Opium War game to reach around 20,000 units.</p>
<p>While skilful players of the Opium War game could beat back British attacks and retain sovereignty over Hong Kong, the game made clear that China's only road to strength had been through the communist-led abolition of feudalism, Yang said.</p>
<p>&quot;We stuck close to history in the game,&quot; he said. &quot;No matter whether you win or lose, the best possible result you can achieve is that Hong Kong is not ceded -- but China remains a weak nation.&quot;</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
