<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670733" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish graduates take on Silicon valley.</title>
<headline>Irish graduates take on Silicon valley.</headline>
<byline>Carmel Linnane</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN, Ireland</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Dublin university graduates have taken on America's Silicon Valley and developed a product that has made even U.S. computer experts sit up, take notice and invest in their ideas.</p>
<p>Ireland's 3.6 million population could fit neatly into a corner of Silicon Valley. So, too, could a tiny Irish company called Iona Technologies.</p>
<p>But that is not how things have happened for Iona, a developer of highly sophisticated systems software, and the brainchild of Chris Horn and Annrai O'Toole, while both were based in Trinity College, Dublin.</p>
<p>Fascinated by computer technology, they dabbled with the idea of simplifying a method of allowing different computer systems to talk to each other.</p>
<p>Iona broke new ground when it developed a novel product, ORBIX, which provides a tool kit for developers enabling them to access and distribute information in diverse systems.</p>
<p>Their product provides the &quot;communicative glue&quot; to mesh different products, whether deemed &quot;compatible&quot; or not, to allow a user to pick and choose across systems.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an age-old problem ... people have been trying to connect different kinds of component software applications together,&quot; said Horn, Iona's chief executive.</p>
<p>&quot;As an analogy, we are providing the pipework that allows you to build your plumbing systems. They can be simple or highly complex,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Iona, still with just a handful of staff members, laboriously prepared the paperwork for its initial public offer on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>Such was their product's success that when their zero-funded &quot;campus start-up&quot; of the 1980s was launched on Nasdaq in February 1997 it was snapped up and is now capitalised at almost $400 million.</p>
<p>The company got its first major break at a trade show in the United States in 1992, when Sun Microsystems Inc. displayed keen interest in their product. Six months later, Sun bought a 25 percent stake in Iona for just $600,000.</p>
<p>&quot;Having Sun as an investor was a significant vote of approval from a major American player and probably gave us more leverage than a venture capitalist could have done at that time,&quot; Horn said.</p>
<p>Horn said Sun later offered to buy 100 percent of the company but after lengthy discussions it was decided that Iona would go it alone.</p>
<p>Response to its initial public stock offering was so strong that its suggested price of $18 per share was ignored as the stock jumped to $22 at the open.</p>
<p>Despite a downturn in the entire technology sector shortly after the launch, Iona reported a rise of 145 percent in total revenues to $9.1 million for the first quarter ended March 30.</p>
<p>&quot;We had an excellent first quarter and beat all analysts' expectations. I am confident our business is going very well for us. It continues to grow well and we are looking forward to substantial growth in the future,&quot; Horn said.</p>
<p>Horn said he believes his company has an 18-month technology lead over the competition and is going to fight hard to keep it that way.</p>
<p>In a sector where mergers and acquisitions are rife, Horn said Iona was on the lookout for suitable bedfellows as a matter of course.</p>
<p>&quot;We have raised over $60 million in cash and we have no debt on the balance sheet,&quot; Horn said. &quot;At this point in time, I am not aware of any acquisition offers to Iona nor are we in formal discussions on us acquiring anyone.&quot;</p>
<p>It is not Ireland's only success in the high-tech field. Investment incentives, a skilled English-speaking work force and a vigorous state investment body, IDA Ireland, have succeeded in making Ireland the software capital of Europe.</p>
<p>IDA Ireland says Ireland has become the market leader, attracting 30 percent of U.S. companies undertaking a new investment investment in Europe and is now the first choice of U.S. companies investing in Europe.</p>
<p>International conglomerates such as Intel Corp., Microsoft Corp., Hewlett-Packard Co., Novell Inc., Electronic Data Systems Corp. and International Business Machines Corp. have invested large amounts in facilities in Ireland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN, Ireland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
