<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673157" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GT Interactive to wean itself from Wal-Mart.</title>
<headline>GT Interactive to wean itself from Wal-Mart.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>GT Interactive Software Corp will make several moves by the end of the year to rely less on sales through Wal-Mart N Stores Inc  WMT. the chief executive of the video game software company said Thursday.</p>
<p>GT Interactive sells video games like &quot;Doom II&quot; and &quot;Duke Nukem.&quot; It also distributes software for other companies, mainly to Wal-Mart. In 1996, GT Interactive got about 45 percent of its $365 million in revenue from sales through Wal-Mart.</p>
<p>GT Interactive's goal is to reduce the total of its sales through Wal-Mart to 25 to 30 percent by the end of the year, said Ron Chaimowitz, the company's chief executive.</p>
<p>&quot;We will add more mass-merchant retailers by the end of the year,&quot; Chaimowitz said in an interview at the Electronic Entertainment Expo in Atlanta.</p>
<p>GT also will beef its business of bundling software with new personal computers and game consoles, he said.</p>
<p>In recent months, GT Interactive's stock has declined sharply, partly amid concerns that Wal-Mart is planning to rely less on GT for its software supply. In March, Wal-Mart said it would experiment with getting software directly from three publishers, instead of using GT Interactive as a middleman.</p>
<p>Chaimowitz said new business through additional retailers and OEM sales should offset any loss of business from Wal-Mart.</p>
<p>The company also is about to release seven major video games. The games could help GT Interactive meet its goal of increasing revenue by 30 to 35 percent in 1997, Chaimowitz said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
