<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="677388" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Gates open for Australia's Packer step into cyberspace.</title>
<headline>Gates open for Australia's Packer step into cyberspace.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's richest man Kerry Packer teamed up with America's wealthiest man Bill Gates on Friday to form an Internet alliance between Packer's television and publishing empire and Gates' computer software powerhouse.</p>
<p>Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd (PBL) and Gates' Microsoft Corp had formed a joint venture, which would provide on-line news, sport, entertainment and weather shows as well as financial and retail services.</p>
<p>The venture will utilise Microsoft's online technology as well as draw content from the U.S. software giant's products and from PBL's television arm Nine Network and magazine business Australian Consolidated Press (ACP).</p>
<p>&quot;We are very excited about the opportunity to partner with a world class media organisation like PBL,&quot; Microsoft chairman Bill Gates said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>Nine is Australia's highest rating TV network and ACP is the country's largest magazine group. ACP's publications include the Australian Women's Weekly, Woman's Day, The Bulletin, Cleo, Cosmopolitan, Dolly and Australian Personal Computer.</p>
<p>The Australian online service would be launched in the next two to four months, PBL said.</p>
<p>The service will include Microsoft products -- Microsoft Network (MSN), entertainment guide Sidewalk, travel service Expedia and financial product Investor.</p>
<p>PBL unit PBL Online chairman Daniel Petre said that economies of scale were a major reason behind the reason to form the joint venture.</p>
<p>&quot;Each partner could have embarked upon this online route individually, but the task becomes considerably less difficult as a single entity,&quot; said Petre, who was a former managing director of Microsoft Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;PBL already has a large and diverse range of Australian content, including a top rating television network and a stable of successful publications, whilst Microsoft has proven itself to be a world leader in online technology,&quot; Petre said.</p>
<p>The companies did not provide any financial details on the venuture, but MSN International director Alan McGinnis told Reuters: &quot;It is a serious investment for both companies.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to be making any money out of it for the next two to three years,&quot; McGinnis said.</p>
<p>About 20 percent of Australian homes own computers, one of the world's highest levels of home computer ownership and making it one of MSN's fastest growing markets, McGinnis said.</p>
<p>Australian MSN membership was expected to reach 75,000 by July 1, with local subscriber numbers increasing faster on a per capita basis than any other MSN affiliate, he said. MSN operates here and in the U.S. Britain, Canada, France, Japan and Germany. However, this is not the first time Microsoft has set up an on-line venture with a major Australian group.</p>
<p>In February 1996, the six-month old A$23 million On Australia joint venture between Microsoft and Australian state-owned telephone carrier Telstra Corp Ltd fell through when the two failed to agree on strategy.</p>
<p>On Australia was formerly the Australian arm of MSN.</p>
<p>Microsoft revamped its MSN on-line service last October after the orginal launch in August 1995 failed to live up to the Richmond-Washington-based software group early expectations.</p>
<p>Packer has a personal fortune of A$3.9 billion (US$3.0 billion), but this is dwarfed by Gates estimated fortune of about US$30 billion based on his 23.6 percent stake in Microsoft.</p>
<p>A$=US$0.75</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
