<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="677421" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Packer has online deal with Microsoft.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Packer has online deal with Microsoft.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kerry Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd (PBL) said on Friday that it had formed an online joint venture with Microsoft Corp which would include PBL products and Microsoft's MSN service.  </p>
<p>PBL, which owns the leading Nine television network as well as a string of magazines, said the Australian online product would be launched in the next two to four months.</p>
<p>The product would include news, sport, weather as well as entertainment and lifestyle shows. Online users would also have access to retailing and financial services, PBL said.</p>
<p>Any future online Microsoft products would be part of the joint venture while its current products such as The Microsoft Network (MSN), the entertainment guide Sidewalk, travel services-based Expedia, and financial product Investor would be part of the new group.  </p>
<p>MSN International director Alan McGinnis said MSN membership in Australia was expected to reach 75,000 by July 1 this year, with local subscriber numbers increasing faster on a per capita basis than any other MSN affiliate.</p>
<p>McGinnis said there was a huge marketing opportunity in Australia due to the high penetration of personal computers and the trend for Australians to be early adopters of technology.</p>
<p>The board of the joint venture would be chaired by PBL Online chairman Daniel Petrie and include two Microsoft officials Laura Jennings and John Nielsen. Financial terms were not disclosed. -- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
