<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="679039" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Third Age Web site targets growing 50+ set.</title>
<headline>Third Age Web site targets growing 50+ set.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>The startup Third Age Media is expected to formally launch its sponsor-backed Web site Monday as it aims to tap into the interests of the nation's growing numbers of wired baby boomers over 50.</p>
<p>Drawing on statistics that show an American turns 50 every seven seconds, a rate that's set to increase over time, Third Age is targeting the ageing baby boomer generation, which the company's president, Mike Edelhart, said has &quot;defined what is hip and hot in the market&quot; for years.</p>
<p>A Nielsen/CommerceNet report in March found that 7.6 million of the 50.6 million Internet users in North America are age 50 or older -- and this group is more likely to have more time to spend on-line, Edelhart said.</p>
<p>&quot;They represent the sweet spot in the market today,&quot; he said recently, noting that those 50 and over are twice as likely to read news online and 30 percent more likely to have bought a product over the Web.</p>
<p>&quot;Their lives are not at an end, but at a dramatic new beginning,&quot; Edelhart said. &quot;Third agers crave media that reflect their active reality.&quot;</p>
<p>The site is one of the most focused effort to use the Internet to create affinity groups of online communities which draw people together around common interests.</p>
<p>Third Age founder and CEO Mary Furlong, a 48-year-old University of San Francisco professor, said the new online service aims to provide a combination of community, content and a marketplace for older individuals who are looking to make the most of their later years.</p>
<p>&quot;It is like an island where people want to go in the middle of the Internet ocean -- a harbour or place that people want to come back to,&quot; she said of the concept.</p>
<p>Third Age Media has already lined up an extensive list of corporate sponsors -- ranging from Quaker Oats to Toys &quot;R&quot; Us -- to provide sponsorship, advertising and products over through the site.</p>
<p>In addition to its site (http://www.thirdage.com), Third Age has also rounded up partnerships with Yahoo Inc., Microsoft Corp.'s Microsoft Network, MSN, and Netscape Communications Corp..</p>
<p>Third Age provides a daily news and features package to Microsoft, produces the Seniors Forum on MSN and is a participant in Netscape's In-Box Direct programme.</p>
<p>Third Age also produces a news service distributed by Universal Press Syndicate to more than 200 newspapers.</p>
<p>On its own Web site, sponsors will provide a variety of offerings, ranging from an online dating and personals service from Match.com to books from Amazon.com, which like many sponsors will be offering discounts.</p>
<p>Toys &quot;R&quot; Us is developing a co-branded area with Third Age to be dubbed Grandparents R Us, including features on grandparenting and gift ideas for grandchildren.</p>
<p>Hallmark Cards Inc.'s technology brand, Hallmark Connections, is sponsoring a &quot;Share a Moment&quot; area where people who enter the Third Age site can share stories and send electronic greetings with family and friends.</p>
<p>Other products and services range from financial research publications to video phone products and direct delivery of grocery and produce to homes in seven cities.</p>
<p>Furlong was founder and president of SeniorNet, a non- profit membership organisation dedicated to educating older adults about computer technology, and served for ten years as president of the organisation.</p>
<p>The company raised $3 million in first round financing in January from Softbank, Advance Publications and nearly two dozen individual investors and is currently looking to raise up to $8 million in a further round.</p>
<p>Furlong said the company is targeting to become cash flow positive in 1998 and to achieve profitability a year later, with the prospect of an initial public offering perhaps in a three to five year range.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
