<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="679373" id="root" date="1997-06-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cisco, Alcatel in broad strategic pact.</title>
<headline>Cisco, Alcatel in broad strategic pact.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alcatel Telecomm and Cisco Systems Inc said Monday they agreed to a broad pact to develop networking equipment to meet the growing demand to integrate the Internet with public telecommunications networks.</p>
<p>Executives of the two companies said the alliance would result in 10 to 12 products over the next two years covering several areas of communications technology.</p>
<p>Officials said the primary focus of the pact would be in developing products for the network backbones used by phone carriers to handle large volumes of customer traffic.  It would also focus on network access systems.  </p>
<p>Alcatel said it plans to integrate Cisco's core operating system software into several products used by telecom service providers. Initial applications would include adding Cisco routing technology to Alcatel's ATM and ISDN switches.</p>
<p>ATM, which stands Asynchronus Transfer Mode, is a method for transmitting voice, data and video at high-speedsover networks that has gained popularity among phone carriers especially in the backbone portion of their networks.</p>
<p>ISDN, or Integrated Services Digital Network, is a modem technology that offers data access to public networks at higher speeds than analog modems that most PC users now use.  </p>
<p>The companies said the pacts may be extended to include Alcatel's Sonet/SDH fiber-optic transmission systems and the GSM international mobile network equipment.</p>
<p>Alcatel plans to use Cisco's new routing technology known as Tag Switching to transmit high-speed Internet Protocol traffic over ATM networks.</p>
<p>Alcatel and Cisco said they plan to work with standard setting bodies such as the Internet Engineering Task Force, to develop a common set of standards for fusing routing and switching technologies.  </p>
<p>Cisco intends to back Alcatel's high-speed network access technology known as Asynchronus Digital Subscriber Line (ADSL) and to integrate and market Alcatel's ADSL modems, chips and products in its own systems.</p>
<p>ADSL allows high-speed data transmission to residential customers over standard copper wires.</p>
<p>In late 1996, Alcatel was awarded the industry's largest contract to date to build ADSL systems for a consortium of four U.S. baby bells, including Ameritech Corp, BellSouth Corp, Pacific Bell, and Southwestern Bell.  </p>
<p>Cisco said it also plans to incorporate Alcatel's voice communications technology for private corporate networks into network systems that Cisco offers to both large enterprises and small- and medium-sized business.</p>
<p>Speaking at a news conference in New York, Cisco Chief Executive John Chambers told reporters that the Alcatel strategic partnership could result in more than $500 million in additional revenues for Cisco over time.</p>
<p>&quot;By the year 2000 it ought to result in $500 million plus of incremental revenue that would not have come to us otherwise,&quot; Chambers said.  </p>
<p>Chambers, who is also chairman of Cisco, said Alcatel is one of nine to 10 major strategic partners that Cisco plans to work with in the coming years.</p>
<p>To date, Cisco has announced major strategic partnerships with technology providers Intel Corp, Microsoft Corp, Hewlett-Packard Co and now Alcatel. Last month, Cisco announced a pact with phone service provider GTE Corp to provide end-to-end network systems valued at more than $1 billion.</p>
<p>The Cisco executive said he expects to announce three additional strategic partnerships in the next 12 to 18 months.</p>
<p>&quot;You will see a couple of systems integrators and a major multi-national carrier,&quot; Chambers told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the unnamed international phone carrier would use Cisco equipment to bring together incompatible network systems into a single fabric similar to the deal with GTE.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
