<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="683964" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Delcam plans July AIM float and overseas expansion.</title>
<headline>Delcam plans July AIM float and overseas expansion.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computer software group Delcam Plc said on Tuesday it was planning to float on the London Stock Exchange's Alternative Investment Market in July and pledged to raise its profile overseas.</p>
<p>The Birmingham, England-based company expects to raise 2.3 million stg from the flotation, of which about 1.9 million stg will be new money. Its market capitalisation is expected to be around 15 million stg.</p>
<p>The company said it will use the funds to develop its existing product portfolio and to promote sales growth in overseas markets.</p>
<p>Delcam develops and supplies software for the design and manufacture of complex shapes, typically plastic injection moulds in the automotive industry.</p>
<p>It currently markets its products in over 40 countries and they are used by more than 1400 companies world-wide. Its customers include Mercedes-Benz, Nissan, Volkswagen, Gillette Co and Sharp Corporation.</p>
<p>The company said it had been profitable in every year since 1989 and made a pre-tax profit of one million stg to the year end December 31, 1996.</p>
<p>Tilney and Co has been appointed as nominated broker.</p>
<p>-- Andrew Langlands, London Newsroom +44 171 542 3496</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
