<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684392" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-SAP counts on new staff to grow.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-SAP counts on new staff to grow.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>German software developer SAP AG has had little trouble boosting sales impressively, but its future may ride on finding and hiring new programming talent, company officials and analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>To tweak its R/3 business application software for untapped markets, and to help new customers install the sprawling programme, SAP expects to need 3,000 new employees this year -- or 12 new hires every working day.</p>
<p>&quot;We certainly need a lot of people to grow,&quot; Hartmut Hillebrand, SAP personnel chief in Germany, said in an interview. &quot;We are going into a lot of new market areas. It's a challenge to bring in qualified people, but we are confident.&quot;</p>
<p>SAP has forecast a 25 to 30 percent rise in sales this year, with pretax profits increasing at a slightly higher rate. But analysts said that outlook was too cautious.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais's Hans-Peter Wodniok said he expected a 40 to 45 percent increases in sales and pretax profit when SAP details first-half results on July 24. Orders would rise at a slightly higher rate, boosted by recent contracts to install R/3 at Volkswagen AG and Daimler-Benz AG.</p>
<p>Wodniok and other analysts have been watching SAP's headcount as an indicator of both sales and profit development.</p>
<p>The company needs software engineers to simplify R/3 for the small and medium-sized companies SAP has just begun to target, and to help those customers install and learn to use R/3 -- a process that can take six months or more.</p>
<p>It also needs programmers to write new parts of the software to serve markets like financial services, government and healthcare.</p>
<p>To hit growth targets, SAP &quot;must quickly recruit and integrate enough highly motivated and capable employees,&quot; board member Henning Kagermann said at SAP's May 7 annual meeting.</p>
<p>But analysts would be concerned if personnel costs rise faster than sales because that could hinder profit growth.</p>
<p>&quot;They must be cautious,&quot; Wodniok said. &quot;We are watching to see if sales (growth) stays ahead of the payroll.&quot;</p>
<p>First-quarter sales rose 49 percent to 1.03 billion marks ($599 million), a point faster than costs, which rose 48 percent to 886 million marks. Pretax profit rose 54 percent to 181 million marks.</p>
<p>Juergen Elfers at BHF Bank said SAP was easing dependence on new employees by partnering with consultants who can fill in development gaps and smooth the installation process.</p>
<p>Last week SAP bought 25 percent of IDS Prof. Scheer GmbH, a consultant that installs R/3 and has helped SAP develop software in the past. &quot;SAP is not growing on its own payroll alone,&quot; Elfers said.</p>
<p>So far this year SAP has added 1,700 employees worldwide, Hillebrand said. In Germany it has added 550 of an expected total of 700 new recuits this year.</p>
<p>Hillebrand said SAP, because of its dominant market position and high profile, had little trouble drawing qualified software engineers and marketers.</p>
<p>SAP's R/3 dominates the world market for so-called enterprise software -- vast programmes that many multinational companies use to tie together computer systems that control financial, purchasing, manufacturing, sales and personnel data.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150 ($ = 1.719 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
