<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="685151" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spyglass falls on earnings warning.</title>
<headline>Spyglass falls on earnings warning.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Spyglass Inc fell about 11 percent on Wednesday after the company warned its third quarter loss would be more than twice what Wall Street had expected.</p>
<p>But analysts said the stock was holding up well considering the warning.</p>
<p>&quot;These types of warnings are not unexpected with developmental stage technology,&quot; said Rick Berry, an analyst for brokers Malachi Group.</p>
<p>Last year Spyglass said it would focus on providing &quot;embedded software&quot; to make everyday devices such as televisions and cellular phones work with the Internet's World Wide Web. The company previously focused on licensing Internet browser software for use with desktop computers, for example.</p>
<p>The stock has traded recently near its 52-week lows. On Wednesday it was off 1 at 8.</p>
<p>&quot;I think most holders here are in for the long term and quite hopeful for the embedded software market,&quot; Berry said. &quot;I think most of the risk is out of the stock.&quot;</p>
<p>Late Tuesday Spyglass said it expects revenue for its third quarter ending June 30 of between $2 million and $2.3 million.</p>
<p>The company sees a third quarter loss of $0.26 to $0.28 a share.</p>
<p>Abhishek Gami, an analyst for Nesbitt Burns, said he had expected revenues of slightly more than $4 million and a loss of about $0.14, larger than the First Call consensus of $0.12 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;Expenses look like they're not spinning out of control,&quot; Gami said. &quot;If you're looking for a silver lining, there it is, but that's about as far as the silver lining goes.&quot;</p>
<p>During the third quarter, Spyglass has announced various licensing and co-marketing agreements with companies that provide real time operating systems used to run devices. But analysts said it will take time for significant revenues to start pouring in from those deals.</p>
<p>&quot;I frankly think they could potentially still get back to profitability by the last quarter of fiscal 1998 or early in 1999,&quot; said Gami, who rates the company a hold.</p>
<p>((--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
