<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="689493" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: HP launches Internet imaging initiative.</title>
<headline>HP launches Internet imaging initiative.</headline>
<byline>Ruth Morris</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hewlett-Packard Co has unveiled an Internet-imaging initiative it hopes will entice far-flung families to share high-resolution photographs over the Internet and then print them out at home.</p>
<p>Through the initiative, which was launched Wednesday encompasses technology, new products and services, HP is seeking to boost Internet traffic in digital photographs and, in turn, stimulate sales of scanners and printers that can reproduce the images as crisply as they appear on the screen.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we can make more kinds of people want to print more things, we're very happy,&quot; HP Internet Technology Officer Ira Goldstein told Reuters in an interview preceding the company's showcase.</p>
<p>The technology protocol behind the imaging software for home personal computers, called FlashPix, was developed by HP, Microsoft Corp, Eastman Kodak Co and private software firm Live Pictures Inc.  </p>
<p>Goldstein declined to predict how the plan would affect sales, but noted, &quot;If (according to industry estimates) there are 60 billion photographs printed each year and one percent of that market went digital ... you're talking about the ability to double Hewlett-Packard's printer business.&quot;</p>
<p>HP said it would also work together with privately-held PictureVision Inc to expand PictureVision's PhotoNet offering. Customers using PhotoNet can pick up a web-page address and a password when collecting their developed photographs and then pass on that information to friends and family who would also like to see the pictures on their own personal computers.  </p>
<p>Besides downloading photographs, PhotoNet allows customers using participating film finishers to zoom and crop pictures from the Internet.</p>
<p>Goldstein said digital photograph scanners could be particularly attractive to educational institutions and to enterprises that use Internet catalogues to sell their wares.</p>
<p>&quot;Much of Internet commerce depends on being able to see what you buy,&quot; Goldstein said. He added that pictures of digitally scanned merchandise could allow online shoppers the ability to zoom in on stones in a necklace or other such details that would otherwise be impossible to see.</p>
<p>Both the HP PhotoSmart scanner and high resolution printer are priced at just under $500, Goldstein said.</p>
<p>((New York Newsdesk 212 859 1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
