<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693834" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: INTERVIEW-Imagineer to boost education software.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Imagineer to boost education software.</headline>
<byline>Yuka Obayashi</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese game software maker Imagineer Co Ltd is gearing up to boost business in software for the education market through further tie-ups with Japanese publishers.</p>
<p>Imagineer president Takayuki Kamikura told Reuters in a recent interview that the company hopes to expand its revenue from educational software to about half its total earnings in the coming three or four years.</p>
<p>In late May, the company said it saw group sales growing to 12.47 billion yen for the current fiscal year, which started in April, against the previous year's 8.38 billion yen.</p>
<p>Its group net profit was predicted to total 590 million yen for 1997/98, against the previous year's 405 million yen.</p>
<p>In 1996/97, Imagineer, in cooperation with Obunsha Corp, a Japanese publisher known for its college entrance examination text books, released three education software titles for Nintendo Co Ltd's, portable game player Gameboy, which has 15 million users across Japan.</p>
<p>Imagineer sold a total 40,000 of the three titles in 1996/97 and plans to tie up with other Japanese publishers to release 15 titles this year, Kamikura said.</p>
<p>The company aims to sell a total 300,000 of the 15 new titles, he added.</p>
<p>Kamikura also said the company is preparing to establish a school in Tokyo by the end of this year where students will use digital software in their studies.</p>
<p>He said: &quot;The Japanese education system still forces children to memorise, while the Americans teach students how to search for information using computers. In this sense, Japan is far behind. There is a need to show students how to work in a digital environment.&quot;</p>
<p>Although he did not elaborate on plans for the school, he said he had visited schools in the United States, Israel and Denmark for research.</p>
<p>Imagineer plans to release 82 titles including eight game software titles for the 64-bit game machine Nintendo 64, 10 for Sega Enterprises Ltd's Sega Saturn game player and six for Sony Corp's PlayStation this business year, he said.</p>
<p>The company aims to double its total software sales to 2.8 million units this business year from the previous year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
