<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693851" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Economic success of Internet unproven -Novell exec.</title>
<headline>Economic success of Internet unproven -Novell exec.</headline>
<byline>Christina Toh-Pantin</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite the glut of cyberspace-related products, the economic success of the Internet remains unproven, and many businesses have failed to make it profitable, a U.S. software executive said on Friday.</p>
<p>Glenn Ricart, chief technology officer of Novell Inc, said the fact that there is &quot;no proven economic model&quot; for the Internet is the biggest challenge the high-technology communications facility faces.</p>
<p>Addressing the Internet Society's annual conference, Ricart said, &quot;We have most companies losing money in this.&quot;</p>
<p>He noted that software giant Microsoft Corp is giving away Internet products including its browser Internet Explorer.</p>
<p>None of the companies involved in Internet &quot;are making a reasonable profit&quot;, he said. Even those which have attempted subscription services have not been very successful, he said.</p>
<p>One problem is that advertising in cyberspace has been losing its effectiveness, Ricart said. He said that in the past 90 days, he has found the &quot;click through&quot; rate of Internet users clicking on advertising banners on Web sites to see their contents has been declining.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a novelty factor&quot;, he said, noting that Internet users were inclined to lose interest in such ads the more they surfed the Net.</p>
<p>Companies like Yahoo! Inc which sell such advertising are &quot;finding the rate they can charge is going down&quot;, Ricart said.</p>
<p>Yahoo! said in April it had 700 advertisers, up from 550 at the end of 1996. It had been getting about $0.02 to $0.06 per advertisement viewing, with slightly higher rates for Yahoo! services aimed at specialty markets.</p>
<p>Targeted advertising, which focuses on a set group of customers instead of randomly placed cyberspace promotions, could be the way to go, Ricart said.</p>
<p>This form of advertising &quot;could be a means for financing the Internet&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>Novell itself has boosted its Internet focus and makes Web servers.</p>
<p>Ricart's speech at the end of the three-day Internet conference that drew over 1,000 participants from 120 countries also outlined nine other challenges the 25-year-old Internet faces.</p>
<p>Among these are governments feeling threatened, difficulty in finding people and companies, an ageing design for Internet, security, and inefficient bandwidth use, Ricart said.</p>
<p>Earlier in the week, the Internet Society held panel discussions on electronic commerce, and heard Ira Magaziner, special adviser to U.S. President Bill Clinton, outline a forthcoming report on global cyberspace commerce.</p>
<p>A handful of companies also unveiled Internet-related products such as an Asian-based Web search site, Internet Web pages in local languages and an electronic shopping mall.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
