<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702237" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Don't be fooled by 'Illusion'.</title>
<headline>Don't be fooled by 'Illusion'.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vision is a fascinating sense.</p>
<p>If the eyes are forced to stare at the same point, the objects we perceive fade to nothing. If you put lenses over the eyes to make everything appear upside down, the brain will gradually adapt to make the world seem right side up again. Magic tricks and optical illusions illustrate that anyone who insists that &quot;seeing is believing&quot; doesn't know much about vision.</p>
<p>The computer, with its ability to animate such illusions, is an ideal tool for teaching people about our most precious and complex sense. That's why &quot;Illusion&quot; from the Scientific American Library is such a disappointment.</p>
<p>This CD-ROM from Byron Preiss (Windows/Macintosh $30) fulfils some of its potential when it shows a ball that endlessly bounces down four flights of stairs or demonstrates how &quot;impossible&quot; three-dimensional objects are built (the secret is revealed when the computer rotates them). No book can provide that type of perspective.</p>
<p>But far too often, &quot;Illusion&quot; squanders its potential.</p>
<p>One problem is sloppiness. In the puzzle where you have to identify sticks buried deeper and deeper in a pile, two of the sticks are mislabeled. In some sections where the text is italicised, the &quot;a&quot;s are almost indistinguishable from &quot;o&quot;s, an ironic faux pas in a CD-ROM devoted to the misperceptions of vision.</p>
<p>Based on two books, Irvin Rock's &quot;Perception&quot; and David Hubel's &quot;Eye, Brain and Vision,&quot; &quot;Illusion&quot; sometimes looks like its developers simply tagged the multimedia elements onto the books instead of thoroughly integrating them into the product the way they should have.</p>
<p>For example, the introduction that explains how to manoeuvre through the CD-ROM is long, talky, and has virtually no animation to illustrate what the narrator is describing.</p>
<p>Magician Teller of the performing duo Penn &amp; Teller talks about ways to visually deceive an audience with no video or animation to illustrate the key points he's talking about. Another set of interviews sounds like it was done over the telephone.</p>
<p>The system for manoeuvring through &quot;Illusion&quot; -- software programmers call it the &quot;user interface&quot; -- is described by Byron Preiss as &quot;innovative.&quot; Cumbersome or confusing are better descriptions. In some areas, if you want to see a list of topics, you have to click on a weathervane-like object labeled &quot;text.&quot; If you want to see the text, you have to click on &quot;topics.&quot;</p>
<p>Consumers who buy &quot;Illusion&quot; expecting a well-thought-out educational experience will see red.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>It must be a frustrating time for the people at P.F.Magic, the folks who gave the world computerized dogs and cats back in 1995. They went to all the trouble of producing virtual pets who are lovable and respond like real animals do, only to watch helplessly as Tamagotchis, Nano Babies, Nano Kitties and Nano Puppies become the hottest thing since Tickle Me Elmo.</p>
<p>For the uninitiated, Tamagotchis and Nanocreatures are two-inch pieces of plastic with a few buttons and a wristwatch-size screen that shows a crude outline of a dog, cat, baby or nondescript space creature.</p>
<p>Symbols on the tiny black-and-white screen show whether they need to be fed, given medicine, disciplined or played with. If you treat them right, they'll &quot;live&quot; for about three weeks. Neglect them by ignoring their beeps and they'll &quot;die.&quot; Then you have to create a new one.</p>
<p>Folks (especially children) love them, hanging them from key chains or belt loops. Toy stores sell them faster than they come in.</p>
<p>But the creatures on the tiny screen are like stick figures compared with the rich animation in products like P.F.Magic's &quot;Dogz&quot; and &quot;Catz&quot; (Windows/Macintosh), which now sell for about $20 and give you something that really looks like a dog or a cat on the computer screen.</p>
<p>If you use your hand icon to scratch this cat, it purrs. If you throw a toy ball around the screen, the dog chases after it. You can even train the dog to do tricks.</p>
<p>(This fall, the company is releasing &quot;Dogz II&quot; and &quot;Catz II&quot; for Pentium owners with Windows95. Both products let you have more than one pet on the screen, allows dogs and cats to mingle, and gives customers the ability to download new breeds over the Internet.)</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Fujitsu Interactive released a similar product, &quot;K-9 Cyber Companion&quot; (Windows95, $20), but this puppy is more surreal than real. It has a head, body and paws, but you have to imagine the neck or legs.</p>
<p>But because these pets have to be kept on a short leash because the computers where they reside can't hang from a key chain or a belt loop, P.F.Magic and Fujitsu will have to watch helplessly as the Tamagotchi craze continues.</p>
<p>It shows there's power (and profit) in portability.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
