<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702906" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Basic humour key to success for international ads.</title>
<headline>Basic humour key to success for international ads.</headline>
<byline>Helen Jones</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite the rise of increasingly sophisticated consumers around the world with a wealth of information at their fingertips, the advertising industry is finding the most basic humour its most effective tool in international ad campaigns.</p>
<p>Toilet humour and slapstick are two of the easiest ways of communicating an international advertising campaign, while more sophisticated humour often fails to cross borders, according to a consultant who advises companies on their global ad strategies.</p>
<p>&quot;Basic childish jokes featuring people falling over or anything scatological are universal and will raise a smile with people across continents,&quot; Simon Anholt, director of World Writers, told Reuters in a interview. World Writers advises companies such as Microsoft, Nike and Coca-Cola on global advertising strategies.</p>
<p>A good example of an ad that could cross cultural borders is one for an Argentinean brand of spicy tuna sauce. &quot;It featured a shot of a pair of underpants on a washing line, with a ragged hole burnt through the rear,&quot; Anholt said.</p>
<p>Humorous ads often win prizes at the annual International Advertising Festival, which ended last Saturday in Cannes, because they are universal.</p>
<p>But many ads that are very popular in their home markets and use fairly sophisticated humour do not travel well.</p>
<p>&quot;Ninety percent of the ads that we think are really funny in Britain are incomprehensible when translated. It's not about language but about culture,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Because much international advertising is merely translated into local languages, it often does not work because it does not address local cultures.</p>
<p>&quot;People think that creating an ad that will appeal to youth across Europe -- the MTV generation -- is the easiest sort of international advertising, but that is a fallacy,&quot; Anholt said. &quot;They all have their own cultures and attempts to talk to them as one group are crass,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>To appeal to as a wide an audience as possible some advertisers avoid humour altogether and use very simple images to convey their message. As a result, much international advertising is very bland and features a succession of impossibly glamorous people using toiletries products or drinking in unrealistic settings, said Anholt.</p>
<p>The most difficult market for foreign advertisers is the Middle East, which Anholt called a cultural minefield.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very tricky. For example, you can't use any shots of partially clothed women, and national flags sometimes have religious significance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But despite the problems associated with international advertising some companies have approached it in the right way, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;International brands succeed when consumers in each market believe they are being spoken to by somebody who knows their needs and not by a foreigner speaking to them through an interpreter,&quot; Anholt said.</p>
<p>Ad campaigns by soft drink rivals Pepsi and Coca-Cola highlight the role of local culture in appealing to consumers.</p>
<p>&quot;In India Pepsi ran an ad campaign featuring cricket and local Indian pop stars,&quot; Anholt said. &quot;It has now established a significant lead over Coca-Cola, which ran a pan-European ad there featuring football which means very little in India.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 4770</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
