<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="703136" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Internet Explorer 4.0 everywhere in browser war.</title>
<headline>Internet Explorer 4.0 everywhere in browser war.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft's Internet Explorer 4.0 is all over the World Wide Web -- even though the Internet navigation software is not even in public beta testing yet and is not scheduled to become a commercial product until later this year.</p>
<p>Anyone harbouring doubts about whether the Internet browser wars have reached an end need only view a flood of advertising hype for the next version of Microsoft's competing browser.</p>
<p>The browser war is important to the two rival companies -- Microsoft and Netscape Communications Corp. -- because the company winning the most users stands to gain a huge outpouring of additional software sales -- for everything from managing e-mail to handling word processors to news-delivery systems.</p>
<p>The Microsoft ads, timed to coincide with rival 's release of its Netscape Communicator 4.0 product now hitting the market, are aimed at blunting Netscape's marketing efforts, analysts say.</p>
<p>Microsoft executives argue they want to remind customers their own next-generation browser software packed full of features will be along soon -- and for free -- before they choose to go with Netscape.</p>
<p>Netscape executives argue Microsoft's ads on popular Web pages are another example of how the Redmond, Wash., software giant tries to freeze customers from buying other brands by persuading them to wait for Microsoft's offerings.</p>
<p>The practice, sometimes referred to as announcing &quot;vaporware&quot; which does not exist or spreading FUD -- &quot;fear, uncertainty and doubt&quot; about a rival's product offering -- is well known in the computer field.</p>
<p>Last week, Paul Maritz, a top Microsoft executive, said he expects Microsoft to spend $1.5 billion to roll out Internet-related products in fiscal 1998 -- a figure Netscape executives discounted as grandstanding.</p>
<p>&quot;Customers buy our products, not promises of future resources, not promises of future products, not all that fear, uncertainty and doubt' that Microsoft is the best in the world at spreading,&quot; grumbled Netscape Chief Executive James Barksdale.</p>
<p>&quot;We're adding about 600,000 new users every week,&quot; he added, noting this is about 1 percent of the 63 million unique customers it claims.</p>
<p>Rob Enderle, a senior analyst at Giga Information Group, estimates Microsoft is spending up to $10 million on its Internet Explorer 4.0 media blitz, a drop in the bucket for the software giant.</p>
<p>Yusef Mehdi, a marketing director in Microsoft's Internet client group, said the company plans to issue a broad test release of its next browser in July with final release due by the end of summer.</p>
<p>&quot;We want customers, whether you're a corporate customer or an end-user customer, to understand there's going to be a choice,&quot; he said. &quot;Maybe we'll have a great product out there that'll be free.&quot;</p>
<p>Netscape has set high targets for Communicator, aiming to sell 10 million copies within the first 30 days and 30 million by the time Microsoft's product ships in its own broad-based marketing push, said Mike Homer, Netscape's senior vice president of marketing.</p>
<p>That leaves Microsoft no choice but to put out its advertising &quot;because we're five months ahead and they don't have any software to sell,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The battle remains rugged for a browser market which Zona Research estimates at less than 1 percent of the nearly $35 billion spent on Internet-based products in 1996, and which is due to underperform other Internet opportunities.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Barksdale renewed questions about Microsoft's behaviour, which continues to be under Department of Justice scrutiny following a 1994 consent decree Netscape has accused Microsoft of having breached.</p>
<p>&quot;Netscape continues to be the fastest-growing software company in history despite the enormous resurgence from a much larger, government-protected monopoly,&quot; Barksdale said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm just tired of them (federal authorities) not doing anything for something that to me is obviously counter to the best interests of the buyer,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Microsoft has repeatedly denied any wrongdoing and said it is in compliance with the decree.</p>
<p>(sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau 415 846 5400)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
