<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="705503" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft sues resellers over alleged piracy of NT.</title>
<headline>Microsoft sues resellers over alleged piracy of NT.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. said Wednesday it sued two Arizona companies, accusing them of selling illegal copies of the software giant's networking products.</p>
<p>Microsoft said the lawsuits, filed in U.S. District Court in Tucson, Ariz., were part of a new crackdown on piracy of the company's high-end Windows NT and BackOffice products for business computer networks.</p>
<p>&quot;As the popularity of our BackOffice Suite of products is growing, so is piracy, unfortunately,&quot; said Claire O'Donnell, a Microsoft spokeswoman.</p>
<p>Microsoft charges that Tucson reseller Computers Under Retail loaded a counterfeit copy of Microsoft's Windows NT Server operating system on three machines at a fictitious business set up by an undercover investigator hired by the company.</p>
<p>The second lawsuit charges that Tucson reseller Future Information Design installed unauthorized copies of Windows NT Server and two workstations on a network operated by a Microsoft undercover investigator.</p>
<p>Microsoft said it previously had warned the reseller about unauthorized software sales.</p>
<p>Executives of the two resellers could not be reached for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
