<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706022" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: software.net in deals with Netscape, Microsoft.</title>
<headline>software.net in deals with Netscape, Microsoft.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Internet start-up backed by Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen said Wednesday it has landed electronic distribution deals with both Microsoft Corp. and its Web software rival, Netscape Communications Corp.</p>
<p>The software.net subsidiary of the private San Jose company CyberSource Corp. said the deals hinge on its ability to distribute software directly over the Internet and its goal of being a neutral party between the competing companies.</p>
<p>&quot;We like to remain Switzerland here, partner with everyone and let them slug it out,&quot; said Kendall Fargo, software.net's director of sales and marketing.</p>
<p>The deal with Microsoft involves what the company said was the Internet's largest electronic software distribution deal, providing $50 million worth of Microsoft products to be delivered to two Department of Defence agencies over a five-year term.</p>
<p>The two agencies, the Defence Logistics Agency and the Department of Defence Procurement Agency, will save more than $30 million in packaging, shipping, installation and maintenance costs, software.net said.</p>
<p>The deal involves sending software packages, upgrades and updates to as many as 70,000 U.S. employees a year, including selected Microsoft products such as Windows 95, Windows NT, Office, Internet Explorer and Backoffice.</p>
<p>In a separate deal with Netscape, the company said it will join Netscape in a co-branded online service to provide Internet-based electronic distribution and sales of software from key Netscape developers.</p>
<p>The service, to be dubbed the &quot;Netscape Software Depot by software.net,&quot; is to be available by mid-August and will offer a one-stop shop for freely distributed software known as shareware and for so-called Netscape plug-ins.</p>
<p>Plug-ins are software designed to extend the capabilities of Netscape's Navigator browser and other Net software.</p>
<p>Initial software publishers participating in the electronic distribution service include Borland International Inc., Corel Corp., Verity Inc. and private companies Elemental Software and Vital Signs.</p>
<p>All members of Netscape's DevEdge developer programme will be offered a chance to participate in the distribution site, which will be organised by product categories, the companies said.</p>
<p>In the Netscape deal, the two companies will share net margins on sales and also divvy up advertising proceeds from the co-branded section of Netscape's site.</p>
<p>Fargo of software.net declined to provide exact details of the split, but said &quot;we make a higher percentage on sales and they make a higher percentage of advertising.&quot;</p>
<p>Even without the Netscape deal, software.net has been selling more than $1 million of software a month since February and has been on track to break the $2 million-a-month rate in September or October, he said.</p>
<p>The software.net business is expected to account for around $20 million of CyberSource's rougly $25 million in revenues anticipated for 1997, Fargo added.</p>
<p>Privately-held CyberSource was founded in 1994 and is backed by Paul Allen and more than a dozen other individual investors, with 60 percent of the company owned by employees.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
