<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712398" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Networking software shrs hit after EPS warnings.</title>
<headline>Networking software shrs hit after EPS warnings.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A flurry of earnings warnings sent shares in network software and systems tools companies tumbling on Tuesday, with several of the issues losing more than a third of their market value.</p>
<p>Segue Software Inc, DataWorks Corp, XcelleNet Inc and Wall Data Inc were all off about 35 percent at midday, a day after each of them warned investors upcoming earnings would fall short of Wall Street estimates.  </p>
<p>Early today, analysts began ratcheting back expectations for the companies, with Segue Software receiving the majority of the early attention.</p>
<p>SoundView Financial cut estimates on Segue for fiscal 1997 and 1998 but kept its rating on the shares at buy.</p>
<p>Alex. Brown analyst James Moore was more pessimistic, downgrading the shares to market perform from buy and expressing doubts over Segue's ability to bounce back soon.</p>
<p>&quot;It gets down to an inability to execute,&quot; Moore said. &quot;The management team has not proven they are capable of selling software.&quot;  </p>
<p>Moore discounted the notion that industry-wide issues were behind the earnings problems faced by Segue, the only one of the four companies he follows.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very robust market and demand is strong,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wall Data, in addition to forecasting weak results, surprised analysts by announcing its chairman Jim Simpson would retire at the end of the month.</p>
<p>The earnings preview marked the third time in a little more than two years that Wall Data had warned it would miss estimates.  </p>
<p>Last October, the company lost about a third of its value after an earnings shortfall.</p>
<p>DataWorks, in its statement disclosing the second quarter earnings weakness, cited &quot;timing delays&quot; on customer orders including a large order moving out of the second quarter.</p>
<p>XcelleNet said in its statement that its year-over-year revenue growth in the quarter was a &quot;clear disappointment&quot; at about 19 percent, down sharply from more than 40 percent in each of the two preceding quarters.</p>
<p>XcelleNet was downgraded by Alex. Brown analyst Chris Mortenson to market perform from buy early today.</p>
<p>Shares in Segue Software tumbled 4-7/8 to 8-1/4, the steepest decliner on Nasdaq. XcelleNet stood second on the Nasdaq percentage losers list, sliding 5-1/8 to 8-3/4.</p>
<p>Dataworks shed seven to 12-1/2 to stand third among decliners and Wall Data fell 9-3/4 to 18, good for fourth place.</p>
<p>((-- R. Melville, Wall Street desk, 212-859-1731))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
