<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713270" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall Data shares plunge on earnings outlook, lawsuit.</title>
<headline>Wall Data shares plunge on earnings outlook, lawsuit.</headline>
<byline>Kourosh Karimkhany</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Data Inc. shares fell as much as 38 percent Tuesday after the software company said it expects to report second-quarter earnings just half of what Wall Street expected.</p>
<p>Wall Data also said Monday it will pay $11.25 million to settle a shareholder lawsuit, an amount that raised concerns among some investors about the company's integrity.</p>
<p>On top of that, the Kirkland, Wash.-based company unexpectedly announced that Chairman and Chief Executive Jim Simpson, 58, will retire at the end of the month.</p>
<p>Stock in Wall Data was down $9.125 at $18.625 on Nasdaq in midday trading of more than 3 million shares, making the stock one of the most active in U.S. markets and one of the biggest percentage losers on Nasdaq. Earlier, the stock traded as low as $17.25.</p>
<p>Wall Data specialises in software that connects networks of personal computers to mainframes, a niche that was growing explosively until a few years ago. But increasingly, companies are using cheap Internet browsers from companies such as Netscape Communications Corp. and Microsoft Corp. to tap information stored on mainframes.</p>
<p>&quot;It's getting very easy to make that connection&quot; between PCs and mainframes, undercutting the price of expensive networking products like Wall Data's Rumba, said Eric Brown, senior analyst at market researcher Forrester Research Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;Welcome to the Internet,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>After the market closed Monday, Wall Data said it expected to report earnings, before charges, of 17 to 20 cents a share for the quarter ended June 30. Analysts expected Wall Data to earn 34 cents a share, according to a recent survey by Zacks Investment Research.</p>
<p>Second-quarter revenue will be about $35.5 million, compared with $34.8 million in the same quarter a year ago, the company said. Rob Owens, analyst at brokerage Pacific Crest Securities, said revenue in the most recent quarter will be about $3 million less than he expected.</p>
<p>Wall Data said it is taking longer for it to sell its products because customers are taking their time evaluating how to deal with the Internet.</p>
<p>The company also said it will take a $10.7 million charge in the second quarter mostly to cover the cost of settling a shareholder lawsuit filed two years ago. The lawsuit was filed shortly after Wall Data announced another earnings shortfall and suffered a huge stock drop.</p>
<p>Under terms of the settlement, Wall Data will pay $11.25 million to the plaintiff. The company's insurance will pay $3 million of that amount. Wall Data will pay the balance with cash on hand.</p>
<p>The size of the settlement raised concerns among some investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Normally these things get settled for a paltry amount,&quot; not millions, said one investor.</p>
<p>But company Chief Financial Officer Richard Van Hoesen said the settlement was not unusual. &quot;We were spending $100,000 a month on this. It was a huge burden on management,&quot; he said, adding that it was better to settle than to continue fighting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
