<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720749" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SAP shares have room to rise - analysts.</title>
<headline>SAP shares have room to rise - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in German software group SAP AG are likely to continue climbing over the medium term, resuming a breakneck rise since early June after a short pause, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>SAP shares were taking a breather on Thursday, down 8.30 marks at 398.20 in midday trade, but were still up about 100 marks, or 33 percent, since June 1. Frankfurt's blue-chip DAX index has risen about 12 percent in the same period.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very hard to tell what the stock is going to do over the next few weeks after this rise, but it can still go up in the medium term,&quot; said Juergen Hackenberg, a Deutsche Morgan Grenfell analyst in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Peter Thilo Hasler of Bayerische Vereinsbank in Munich also said it would be difficult to predict the share's short-term course.</p>
<p>&quot;It's possible for SAP to get to 450 (marks), but whether that happens in 1997 or 1998, I couldn't say,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hackenberg said SAP was benefiting from a boom in the market for its main product, enterprise software -- vast programmes that bring together information from manufacturing, purchasing, accounting and personnel operations.</p>
<p>&quot;This market is booming right now,&quot; he said, noting that competitors Baan Co. and PeopleSoft Inc. were also seeing strong gains.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, SAP said its second-quarter profit growth would match the levels of the first, encouraging investors. In the first three months of 1997, SAP sales rose 49 percent to 1.032 billion marks ($585.2 million), while pretax profit leaped 54 percent to 181 million marks.</p>
<p>The company, which is due to release second-quarter numbers on July 24, also said it expected growth in the second half of the year, but not at similar rates.</p>
<p>SAP's six-week gallop began in June after it announced new global contracts with German car makers Daimler-Benz AG and Volkswagen AG.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150</p>
<p>($ = 1.763 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
