<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72295" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - i2 Tech gunning for growth.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - i2 Tech gunning for growth.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>IRVING, Texas 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>i2 Technologies Inc is focusing on Asia, Europe and new vertical markets in its all-out search for revenue growth, said Chief Executive Officer Sanjiv Sidhu.</p>
<p>Sidhu said i2's supply chain management software is being well received in the largely-untapped Japanese market.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel really good about Japan,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview last Friday, adding that i2's existing software contract with Toshiba should help open doors for further successes there.  </p>
<p>Sidhu said neither i2 nor its competitors had yet exploited business opportunities with a long list of giant Japanese electronics, steel and manufacturing corporations.</p>
<p>Contracts with Siemens AG and British Steel have boosted i2's profile in Europe, Sidhu said, adding that i2 plans to build on its joint marketing and development agreements with German software group SAP AG with a distribution deal to help European sales.</p>
<p>In the United States, the Irving, Texas-based company is now targetting vertical markets like foods, retail and consumer packaged goods for its software.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are penetrating those strongly now with new product offerings ... We are looking for retail customers, we feel we have very attractive solution for them,&quot; Sidhu said. He said retailers like Kmart, Wal-Mart and Circuit City Stores &quot;would benefit a lot from our software&quot;.</p>
<p>Sidhu said i2 is also working on the development of new products which would go beyond scheduling production and distribution operations to &quot;large-scale market simulations&quot; which would, for example, help clients set pricing policies.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be the decision-support vendor for the entire supply chain, and later the entire enterprise,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IRVING, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
