<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724795" id="root" date="1997-07-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: RESEARCH ALERT-Formula rated strong buy.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT-Formula rated strong buy.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-07-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Carnegie Emerging Markets initiated coverage of Formula Systems Ltd with a strong buy recommendation, saying the Israeli stock remains significantly undervalued despite a doubling in price in the past year.</p>
<p>&quot;As the company gains more international exposure following its imminent ADR listing on Nasdaq, we would expect the stock to continue on its upward path,&quot; analyst Stephen Levey said in a report made available to Reuters on Sunday.</p>
<p>The software and hardware holding company has brought seven of its subsidiaries to the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange and Nasdaq.</p>
<p>&quot;Much of the current interest in Formula stems from its (31 percent) holding in Crystal. Crystal specialises in the development of software tools for reprogramming software and databases. Formula purchased this company four years ago and quickly identified the potential for developing a software tool that could convert computer systems that had not been programmed to deal with the 'Year 2000' problem,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Carnegie expects Formula's revenues to rise 61.5 percent in 1997 to 575 million shekels. Earnings per share are forecast to rise to 7.34 shekels in 1997 and to 7.72 in 1998 from 3.08 in 1996.</p>
<p>Carnegie set a six-month price target of 85 shekels for the shares, which closed last Thursday at 63.44.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.55 shekels)</p>
<p>-Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
