<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726088" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft seen reporting 80 percent growth in net.</title>
<headline>Microsoft seen reporting 80 percent growth in net.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. is expected to report Thursday that earnings in its latest quarter grew more than 80 percent, but industry analysts say the company's growth inevitably will slow over the next year.</p>
<p>On average, analysts expect Microsoft to report operating earnings of 79 cents a share for its fiscal fourth quarter ended June 30, up from 43 cents a share in the comparable 1996 period, according to First Call, which tracks estimates.</p>
<p>The results will close out a year in which Microsoft earnings grew more than 50 percent, according to estimates, on strong sales of personal computers and new versions of its Windows NT operating system and Office suite of applications.</p>
<p>Microsoft stock has responded by more than doubling from about $60 at the end of June 1996. On Monday, the stock surged $6.19 to a record $135.94 amid a big technology stock rally on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>But industry analysts estimate Microsoft's earnings growth could slow to 20 percent in the year to come, with the software giant's release schedule devoid of products expected to match the blockbuster performance of past bestsellers like Windows 95 and Office 97.</p>
<p>&quot;This is probably the last of the real strong growth quarters benefiting from recent new product cycles,&quot; said analyst Rick Sherlund of investment bank Goldman Sachs. &quot;I do anticipate over the next year you'll see a slowing in momentum.&quot;</p>
<p>Microsoft executives are legendary for issuing similar cautionary remarks in the past, only to shatter all estimates later by reporting record earnings. Just three months ago, Microsoft reported blowout earnings 23 percent higher than the average estimate.</p>
<p>But Microsoft officials have been adamant in saying they will not be able to duplicate that performance for the quarter just ended. In fact, Microsoft representatives took the unprecedented step of calling analysts several weeks ago to squelch a rumour that fourth-quarer earnings would be far higher than estimates, several analysts said.</p>
<p>Sherlund said Microsoft's fourth-quarter revenues would have been likely to show a slight sequential decline from the third quarter except for the company's practice of deferring recognition of revenues for software such as Office that is updated regularly.</p>
<p>While Microsoft's growth is slowing, its stock price has risen to an estimated 42 times fiscal 1998 earnings, far higher than average, reflecting investors' confidence that the company will produce steady, predictable results, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's implicitly saying it's willing to pay a premium for stable earnings,&quot; said Scott McAdams of Seattle-based brokerage Ragen MacKenzie. &quot;The odds of having a negative earnings surprise are fairly slim.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, he said investors are betting that Microsoft's investment in the Internet, including news, entertainment and television, will put it at the hub of the coming &quot;digital convergence.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, Microsoft could begin seeing significant revenues beginning in fiscal 1999 if it succeeds in providing the operating system for a new generation of television set-top boxes and in generating fees from transactions completed over the Internet, McAdams said.</p>
<p>But he argued that as Microsoft diversifies from its core business in software it will become increasingly difficult for investors to assign it a valuation.</p>
<p>&quot;Typically, the stock market has a hard time valuing enterprises that are not pure plays,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((-- Reuters Seattle bureau 206-386-4848))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
