<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729332" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Earnings, splits drive options. [CORRECTED 22:01 GMT]</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Earnings, splits drive options. [CORRECTED 22:01 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Much of Tuesday's individual options activity, particularly in the technology sector, was driven by second quarter earnings, traders said.</p>
<p>Investors also continued to pile into call options of companies that have announced stock splits, particularly Oracle Corp, which announced a three-for-two split late Monday.</p>
<p>Leading the pack were chip maker Intel Corp and software giant Microsoft Corp. Intel is scheduled to report quarterly profits after today's market close, and Microsoft on Thursday.</p>
<p>(Corrects to make clear that Microsoft reports on Thursday, not Tuesday).  </p>
<p>Most of the action in those two options was on the call side, in what traders said was an indication of investor bullishness.</p>
<p>Activity in Intel was heavy across the board, led by the July 80 call, which traded 20,855 contracts alone by late afternoon.</p>
<p>Other busy Intel options included the July 82-1/2 call, with volume of 15,740 and the July 85 call, with volume of 12,680.</p>
<p>Intel shares were ahead 2-3/8 at 81-1/8 on around 33 million shares.  </p>
<p>According to First Call, analysts' consensus estimate for Intel's second quarter earnings is $0.90 a share, up from $0.59 a year ago, adjusted for a stock split.</p>
<p>The most active Microsoft option was the July 140 call, which traded 5,045 contracts. The July 135 call, August 140 call and August 145 call all were actively traded.</p>
<p>Microsoft gained 2-17/64 to 138-15/64.</p>
<p>Analysts' consensus forecast for Microsoft's fiscal fourth quarter operating earnings is $0.79 a share, up from $0.43 in the same period last year, according to First Call.  </p>
<p>In other trading, options on Oracle were busy after the company late Monday announced a three-for-two stock split in the form of a dividend payable on August 15 to shareholders of record August 1.</p>
<p>Pat Hickey at LETCO said investors were buying a lot of at-the-money calls in August and September.</p>
<p>&quot;On the opening we had a buyer of 1,000 August doubles (55) and 1,000 September doubles (55),&quot; he said. &quot;It's been basically small orders ever since.&quot;</p>
<p>By late afternoon, the August 55 call traded 4,870 contracts and the September 55 call traded 3,400.  </p>
<p>Options traders and analysts have said a new trend in the market is heavy call buying in options of companies that have announced stock splits as investors seek to take advantage of an expected continued rise in the underlying shares.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, options on American Depositary Shares of Brazil's Telebras were busy as the shares fell.</p>
<p>Hickey said the Telebras option activity was dominated by call buying and put selling.</p>
<p>&quot;People are trying to get long with options down here at what they perceive to be a bottom,&quot; he said. In late trade, Telebras shares in the U.S. were down 11-1/2 at 134-3/4.</p>
<p>((Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
