<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732429" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Parody Celebrates the Dork Side of 'The Force'.</title>
<headline>Parody Celebrates the Dork Side of 'The Force'.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Combine one part &quot;Star Wars&quot; with one part &quot;Wayne's World&quot; and you've got &quot;Star Warped&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $20) a wacky parody of the George Lucas saga and a wicked sendup of folks obsessed with the &quot;Star Wars&quot; universe.</p>
<p>Although it comes from Parroty Interactive, the folks who gave us an anaemic lampoon of the computer game &quot;Myst&quot; (Parroty called it &quot;Pyst&quot;), &quot;Star Warped&quot; is not only on-target, it has a lot more depth and works on a couple of levels.</p>
<p>Instead of making fun of the &quot;Star Wars&quot; trilogy directly, this CD-ROM is a celebration of the Dork Side of the Force. It shows the work of Brian and Aaron, two &quot;Star Wars&quot; fanatics who haven't had a normal life since Luke Skywalker first appeared on movie screens on May 25, 1977.</p>
<p>The pair have collected rare (and sometimes-bizarre) memorabilia, including unpopular action figures like the anatomically-correct Jabba the Hut and Peeping Tom Yoda. There's a fighting game featuring Leia-I-Joe (who attacks with a flying hair bun) and Cool Handless Luke (the Jedi who tries to fight with his right hand cut off).</p>
<p>&quot;Good job,&quot; Brian tells you when Luke wins. &quot;Luke would applaud -- if he could.&quot;</p>
<p>Other features:</p>
<p>-- Gene Splicer, where you can combine the genetic material of &quot;Star Wars&quot; characters and see what you get. Mix the strength of Chewbacca and the soft-spoken speech of Yoda and you get, for example, Mike Tyson.</p>
<p>-- U Dont No Jedi, a trivia game with wacky questions. At one point, you must decide whether an alien-sounding word is a Star Wars creature or a sexually transmitted disease.</p>
<p>-- Ranch Cam, a series of ersatz videos taken from the security camera network at George Lucas' Skywalker Ranch, where everyone is trying to steal the script of the next &quot;Star Wars&quot; movie, writers spend a little too much time playing with &quot;Star Wars&quot; action figures, and one male writer does a hilarious cross-dressing impersonation of Princess Leia before getting locked up in his office for making too many jokes about &quot;Howard the Duck&quot; (a Lucas film that was one of the biggest bombs of the 1980s).</p>
<p>The best comedy bits are the comic book-style scenes showing how &quot;Star Wars&quot; would have been different if it had been directed by Spike Lee, Jerry Seinfeld, Woody Allen or Quentin (&quot;Pulp Fiction&quot;) Tarantino. A few of the scenes misfire, but most are dead-on.</p>
<p>Rated for ages 13 and older because of its sometimes-suggestive themes, &quot;Star Warped&quot; has very little animation. But what it lacks in animation, it makes up in imagination.</p>
<p>May this Farce be with you.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>The good news for lovers of the syndicated science fiction soap opera &quot;Babylon 5&quot; is that Sound Source Interactive has come out with a limited edition screen saver/arcade game that includes photos, wallpaper, sound effects and 25 video clips from the third and fourth seasons.</p>
<p>The bad news: you might want to wait to buy it.</p>
<p>A Sound Source spokeswoman called to warn that the first 5,000 copies of the &quot;Babylon 5 Arcade Series Entertainment Utility&quot; (Windows, $30), which are now in stores, have a glitch.</p>
<p>The problem: as the days pass, the programme adds empty folders to your hard drive, slowly filling it up.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very embarrassed by this,&quot; said spokeswoman Elizabeth Olson. The folders are easy to remove, but they might confuse novice users who don't know if they can safely delete them.</p>
<p>Because all the packages are numbered, fans who don't want to deal with the glitch can wait for a serial number over 5,000. (One hundred thousand are being manufactured.) &quot;If it's over 5,000 it should be okay,&quot; said Olson.</p>
<p>Sound Source is offering customers several ways to patch up the programme if they own an earlier version. By now, they should be able to go to the company's Internet site at http://www.soundsourceinteractive.com and download a mini-programme that corrects the glitch. Or, they can have a disk with the mini-programme mailed to them by calling the company directly at 818-878-0505, sending a fax to 818-871-1972, or by mailing the registration card.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;Astro Algebra&quot; teaches a host of algebra concepts and problem-solving skills usually covered in grades 7, 8 and 9. It's part of Edmark's math series that's available for kids as young as 5 (Windows/Macintosh, $35, 800-691-2985, http://www.edmark.com).</p>
<p>&quot;Pajama Sam's SockWorks&quot; -- An arcade game where you must help Pajama Sam sort a mountain of socks. The game randomly selects from 250 possible levels. It's for ages 3 to 8 and from Humongous Entertainment (Windows/Macintosh, $15, 800-499-8386, http://www.humongous.com).</p>
<p>&quot;Reader Rabbit's Toddler&quot; (for ages 18 months to 3 years), &quot;Reader Rabbit's Preschool&quot; (ages 3 to 5) and &quot;Reader Rabbit's Kindergarten&quot; (ages 4 to 6) are three titles from the popular &quot;Reader Rabbit&quot; series designed to help the youngest children hone a few computer skills as they practice learning about letters, numbers, shapes, colours and other things. Each Windows/Macintosh CD-ROM is $10 with a mail-in rebate sent to The Learning Company (800-227-5609, http://www.learningco.com).</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
