<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732633" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow powers past 8,000 after earnings, price data.</title>
<headline>Dow powers past 8,000 after earnings, price data.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial Average shattered the 8,000 mark on Wednesday after strong corporate profits and mild inflation data combined to trigger a buying frenzy.</p>
<p>The Dow finished up 63 points, or 0.79 percent, at 8039, taking just over five months to rise from the 7,000 level passed on February 13.</p>
<p>Technology stocks extended their torrid run, driving the Nasdaq composite to its biggest single-day point rise. It jumped 38.5 points, or 2.5 percent, to 1581.  </p>
<p>The Nasdaq index's previous largest point rise came on May 2, when it gained 34.83.</p>
<p>Record closing highs were set across all major U.S. stock indices, including the Dow, the Nasdaq composite, the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 and the New York Stock Exchange composite.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a powerhouse day for the stock market in general,&quot; said Robert Stovall, president of Stovall/21st Advisers. &quot;The Dow is the focus, but it's really the junior stocks and the tech stocks that have done so well.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dow's gain came despite a sharp selloff in one of its 30 component stocks, Eastman Kodak Co.  </p>
<p>Kodak fell 8-3/4 points to 68-1/8 after it reported second-quarter earnings well below Wall Street analysts' forecasts. The drop was the equivalent of over 32 Dow points.</p>
<p>Still, disappointment over Kodak's results was offset by strong earnings elsewhere and further evidence that there are no signs of accelerating inflation in the U.S. economy.</p>
<p>The Labor Department reported the June Consumer Price Index, a gauge of inflation at the retail level, rose 0.1 percent. Wall Street economists had expected the CPI to rise 0.2 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Inflation continues to be tame...and profits seem to be really good,&quot; said Arun Kumar, senior U.S. equities strategist at Lehman Brothers. &quot;So it's a very good recipe for the stock market to perform very well.&quot;</p>
<p>Underpinning the rise by stocks was a sharp drop in long-term interest rates after the inflation data. The 30-year bond was up 28/32 in late trading, its yield falling to 6.48 percent, dipping below the key 6.50 percent level.</p>
<p>Stronger-than-expected earnings announced late Tuesday by semiconductor maker Intel Corp provided the catalyst for the huge rally in technology shares.  </p>
<p>Intel surged 7-15/32 to 88-3/8. Microsoft Corp, due to report earnings Thursday, rocketed 9-31/32 to 148-7/32. Compaq Computer Corp rose 6-1/4 to 133-1/2 and Sun Microsystems Inc rose 3-7/16 to 45.</p>
<p>The frenzied buying, particularily in the technology group, had some analysts questioning whether Wall Street stocks had gone too far, too fast.</p>
<p>&quot;It's got all the markings of a blow-off rally,&quot; said Bob Walberg, chief equity strategist at Briefing.Com, an online market research and analysis firm. &quot;There's just no regard for valuations in this marketplace.&quot;  </p>
<p>ITT Corp rose 4-5/16 to 66-15/12 after saying it will split into three separate companies to fend off a $6.5 billion takeover bid from rival Hilton Hotels Corp. ITT said also announced a share buyback program.</p>
<p>Columbia/HCA Healthcare Corp fell 4-12/16 to 34-3/16. It said some of its facilities had been served with with federal search warrants requesting hospital laboratory billing and homecare documents.</p>
<p>Lucent Technologies Inc gained 5-15/16 to 88-11/16 after it reported that its third-quarter earnings tripled to $0.33 a share, up from $0.11 in the year-earlier period.  </p>
<p>Time Warner Inc reported a second-quarter loss of $0.09, versus a loss of $0.28 in the 1996 quarter and compared with analysts' consensus expectation of a loss of $0.14. Its shares rose 4-1/4 to 49-5/8.</p>
<p>Ford Motor Co reported the highest quarterly profit in U.S. corporate history, $2.53 billion, while General Motors Corp overcame two strikes to post stronger-than-expected earnings for the second quarter. Ford ended off 1-1/2 to 40-5/8, and GM rose 1/8 to 54-3/8.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 index rose 10.83 points to 936.59, a record.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite rose 38.52 to 1580.63, a record.</p>
<p>((-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
