<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73303" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FUND VIEW - Franklin Health likes software stocks.</title>
<headline>FUND VIEW - Franklin Health likes software stocks.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Benkoe</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Looking into his crystal ball, Kurt von Emster, portfolio manager of the Franklin Global Health Care Fund, sees a robust future for stocks in the health care software/information systems sector.</p>
<p>But von Emster is unenthusiastic about traditionally safer choices among the giant U.S. pharmaceutical companies.</p>
<p>Von Emster feels that while the drug companies will likely post earnings growth in the high single digits in the near term, it will not be enough to ignite their stocks.  </p>
<p>To hedge his bets, he owns two of the bigger U.S. issues: Pfizer Inc, and Schering-Plough Corp, which together comprise about 2.8 percent of the portfolio.</p>
<p>But the software/information group is all about growth, von Emster believes.  The group includes companies that link up doctors, hospitals and insurers via computer and firms that offer computerized services, like monitoring hospital costs.</p>
<p>Von Emster believes stocks in the sector will grow about 30 percent over the near term.  </p>
<p>&quot;The stocks are underfollowed, not covered by Wall Street,&quot; said von Emster, who at age 29 is among the younger managers in the U.S.  &quot;They're in businesses where there is tremendous demand, and they can barely keep up.  And we're talking about earnings growth of about 35 percent annually.&quot;</p>
<p>Among his favorites are IDX Systems Corp, a provider of healthcare information software to doctors, at about 2.13 percent of the portfolio; and Transition Systems Inc, providing computer systems that provide clinical and financial data to hospitals, at about 1.66 percent.  </p>
<p>Overall, the fund focuses on small-cap stocks, with about two thirds under $1 billion in capitalization and the other third above $1 billion.</p>
<p>In all, the portfolio holds about 60 stocks. The top five holdings include: PacifiCare Health Systems Inc; Health Systems International Inc ; Amgen Inc ; Boston Scientific Corp ; and Serologicals Inc.</p>
<p>Von Emster has about seven percent of fund assets in cash, down from about 25 percent in May.  The curent level is just about right to cover redemptions, he said.  </p>
<p>But investor cash-outs have hardly been a problem.  Von Emster said about $1 million has been flowing into the fund each day, and $100 million has poured into the fund in the last six months. Assets currently stand at about $145 million.</p>
<p>Von Emster theorizes that in the U.S. market correction in June-July, HMOs were especially hard hit, as some companies warned of upcoming bad quarterly results.  That, in turn, &quot;spawned an overall selloff in the group,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Amgen and other large-cap companies went down as well,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;You had a 10 percent correction on solid companies with strong earnings.  It was an opportunity for institutions like us to get into the market.&quot;</p>
<p>But there were others who decided that health-care and related stocks were a safe, defensive haven.</p>
<p>Von Esmter buys into the notion that the overall health-care industry would have continued demand and would not suffer through any business downturns.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a flight to quality when there's a correction,&quot; he said. &quot;Health care is viewed as a quality sector in the overall market.&quot;</p>
<p>According to Morningstar Inc, the fund has returned about 15.60 percent year to date; for 1995 it returned about 54.59 percent; and for three years it has gained 33.43 percent on an annualized basis.</p>
<p>The average specialty health care fund has a year-to-date return of 8.48 percent, a 1995 gain of 47.20 percent, and a three-year annualized return of 23.60 percent.</p>
<p>-- Jeff Benkoe,  212-859-1735</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
