<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733773" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Teledesic seeking equity investments from telecoms.</title>
<headline>Teledesic seeking equity investments from telecoms.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Teledesic Corp. is talking to major telecommunications companies seeking equity investments that could meet nearly half the $9 billion cost of its planned global satellite network, a company executive said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Teledesic also expects to raise money by selling stock to the public, although such an offering would not be made before the project reaches its launch phase in 2001, executive vice president John Wolf told reporters at a briefing.</p>
<p>Teledesic, brainchild of Seattle technology billionaires Bill Gates and Craig McCaw, is scheduled to begin operation by the end of 2002, with 288 satellites in low-Earth orbit providing two-way, broadband communications virtually anywhere in the world.</p>
<p>Wolf said Teledesic executives had only begun talks with big telecommunications companies in the past few weeks after the Seattle-based startup selected Boeing Co. as its prime contractor.</p>
<p>&quot;As you can imagine, we've had a lot of interest,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wolf declined to identify any of the potential equity partners but said Teledesic is in talks with virtually all the world's major telecommunications companies, naming such giants as AT&amp;T Corp., MCI Communications Corp. and Japan's NTT.</p>
<p>He declined to comment on how much Teledesic had spent to date, saying only that cash had not been a problem, thanks to the backing of Gates, co-founder of Microsoft Corp., and McCaw, founder of McCaw Cellular, now part of AT&amp;T.</p>
<p>Overall he said he expected half the project to be financed with equity and half through debt.</p>
<p>Wolf also said Boeing was seeking bids from major aerospace and electronics companies to provide launch vehicles and communications hardware for the network's satellites.</p>
<p>Both contracts are expected to be awarded by the end of the year, although Boeing may sign up with several launch companies to meet Teledesic's aggressive schedule, Ross Dessert, deputy program manager for Boeing, said.</p>
<p>Boeing itself will build and integrate the satellites, probably using facilities it acquired last year from Rockwell International Corp., Dessert said.</p>
<p>Wolf acknowledged that Teledesic's launch schedule, which calls for sending the 288 satellites into orbit over an 18-month period, was &quot;very aggressive.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said the company would have no trouble filling the network's capacity to handle two-way video and data communications, dubbed an &quot;Internet in the sky.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's a potentially huge market that we will not begin to satisfy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be five Teledesics and they would not begin to meet the demand,&quot; he said. &quot;We're amazed there haven't been</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
