<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739104" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft stock dips after posting profit surge.</title>
<headline>Microsoft stock dips after posting profit surge.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. stock lost 6 percent Friday after the software giant reported earnings that just barely beat Wall Street's expectations and warned that growth will slow over the coming year.</p>
<p>Microsoft fell $9 to close at $140.50 on Nasdaq, where it helped trigger a technology sector selloff despite reporting late Thursday an 88 percent increase in fiscal fourth-quarter earnings on a 41 percent increase in revenues.</p>
<p>The company's net income of 80 cents a share was a penny above the First Call consensus estimate of 79 cents a share but disappointed investors, who had bid up the stock hoping for even better results.</p>
<p>The Redmond, Wash.-based company earned $1.05 billion on revenue of $3.18 billion in the quarter ending June 30, compared with profit of $559 million on revenue of $2.26 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;It's tough to be king,&quot; said Barry Randall, analyst at Dain Bosworth.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly the company ran up in hopes of another blowout like they had in the March quarter,&quot; when results exceeded analysts' estimates by 23 percent, he said.</p>
<p>Still, Microsoft's decline gave back only a portion of its gains from earlier in the week, when the stock ran up 15 percent and surpassed Coca-Cola Co. to become No. 2 in market capitalisation behind General Electric Co.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of the quarter was pretty evident, but the stock has been moving up tremendously, so I suppose it's just been a balancing out of those forces,&quot; said Chris Galvin of Hambrecht &amp; Quist.</p>
<p>For the coming year analysts project Microsoft earnings and revenue growth will slow to 20 or 25 percent, compared with the 54 percent growth in earnings and 31 percent in revenue for the fiscal year just ended.</p>
<p>Microsoft executives gave a laundry list of reasons why, including declining sales of the company's Office 97 upgrade after its launch this year and a lack of significant new products until sometime next year, when the new &quot;Memphis&quot; version of Windows 95 is expected.</p>
<p>Chairman Bill Gates and other top executives will provide more details next week in two days of meetings with analysts and reporters, but many observers already are looking to fiscal 1998, when some of the company's recent high-profile investments could begin to bear fruit.</p>
<p>Microsoft's $1 billion investment in Comcast Corp. and planned $425 million purchase of WebTV Networks Inc. have raised the prospect the company could one day dominate television the way it now dominates personal computers.</p>
<p>&quot;Microsoft now is in 40 percent of American households,&quot; said Randall. &quot;If they can somehow insert themselves in as a piece of infrastructure in the next generation of televisions, they could go to 100 percent penetration of American households and eventually the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said they see a good chance Microsoft will outperform expectations once again in the second half of the fiscal year when new versions of Windows 95 and possibly Windows NT are expected.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there still are some very strong opportunities for growth for the company,&quot; said Rob Owens of Pacific Crest Securities in Portland, Ore.</p>
<p>He noted that Microsoft is &quot;knocking the cover off the ball&quot; with sales of its Windows NT Server and BackOffice group of applications for large computer networks.</p>
<p>&quot;(Microsoft) is the PC industry leader,&quot; Galvin said. &quot;It continues to represent a core holding in all technology growth funds, and I don't think Microsoft's conservative comments are going to sway that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
