<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739561" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft reports surge in fourth-quarter profits.</title>
<headline>Microsoft reports surge in fourth-quarter profits.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp. on Thursday reported an 88 percent jump in quarterly earnings, in line with expectations, reflecting surging sales of its Windows systems and other personal computer software.</p>
<p>The Redmond, Wash.-based company earned $1.05 billion, or 80 cents a share, in its fiscal fourth quarter ended June 30, compared with $559 million, or 43 cents a share, a year earlier. Revenues surged 41 percent to $3.18 billion from $2.26 billion.</p>
<p>Microsoft's profits were a penny above Wall Street's consensus estimate of 79 cents a share. However, shares of the software giant fell in after-hours trading after the company failed to produce a &quot;blowout&quot; quarter as it did three months ago, when earnings were some 23 percent higher than estimates.</p>
<p>Traders said Microsoft fell $5.50 to $144 after-hours. Before the results came out, the stock had gained $1.06 to $149.50 on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>&quot;I think investors were concerned because the bottom-line number was only 80 cents, and I think people had hoped for a little more upside,&quot; said Goldman Sachs analyst Rick Sherlund.</p>
<p>Still, Microsoft Chief Financial Officer Mike Brown noted that the 86 percent increase in earnings per share was the company's best performance since 1988, which analysts called an impressive feat given the company's vastly increased size. &quot;It looked good -- the margins were impressive,&quot; said Scott McAdams, an analyst with Seattle-based brokerage Ragen MacKenzie.</p>
<p>Microsoft's operating profits were 49.8 percent of revenues in the quarter, compared with 35.9 percent a year earlier.</p>
<p>But Microsoft executives said the company's growth would slow sharply over the coming year, and analysts concur.</p>
<p>Brown, in a conference call after the earnings were announced, gave a laundry list of reasons why analysts expect fiscal 1998 earnings growth of about 20 percent, compared with 54 percent in the year just ended.</p>
<p>&quot;This would be a good time to resist any temptation, no matter how exciting, to increase estimates,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>Such comments have become a familiar refrain to analysts, investors and others who follow the company.</p>
<p>In the past, investors have turned a deaf ear as Microsoft consistently has outperformed expectations. As a result Microsoft stock has surged some 150 percent over the past year and 15 percent just this week.</p>
<p>Analysts say there are good reasons to expect slower growth, including a release schedule devoid of products likely to match the blockbuster performance of past best-sellers like Windows 95 and Office 97.</p>
<p>But McAdams noted that the expected release of the &quot;Memphis&quot; version of Windows 95 in the first half of next year should provide a good boost to earnings. And he said in the long run Microsoft is poised to benefit from sales of its software on new platforms such as hand-held devices and television set-top boxes.</p>
<p>The fourth-quarter results capped a year that saw Microsoft profits soar to $3.44 billion, or $2.63 a share, from $2.2 billion or $1.71 a share. Revenue rose 31 percent to $11.36 billion from $8.67 billion.</p>
<p>At current levels, Microsoft's stock is trading at a lofty 47 times next year's projected earnings, and Microsoft officials have gone to great lengths to try to dampen enthusiasm.</p>
<p>But analysts say investors are willing to pay a premium for steady, predictable growth in earnings.</p>
<p>In addition, investors are betting that Microsoft's investment in the Internet, including news, entertainment and television, will put it at the hub of the coming &quot;digital convergence&quot; and ultimately lead to a new source of growth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
