<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="749616" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: A different kind of arcade game.</title>
<headline>A different kind of arcade game.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Twinsen's Odyssey&quot; is essentially a video arcade game, a 3-D version of a Super Mario-style epic where you kick things to earn coins and other objects that will help you progress through the story. Meanwhile, you have to dodge deadly projectiles and beat up enemies before you run out of lives or life energy is drained to zero.</p>
<p>But not many video arcade games are so stylish. &quot;Twinsen's&quot; (Activision, DOS/Windows95, $50) has a unique look and a captivating cast of characters, from the benevolent mini-elephants that stroll around on their hind legs, to the hot dogs with faces that try to gun you down.</p>
<p>You control Twinsen, a guy with a topknot who is trying to find medicine to cure his Dino-Fly, a soaring dinosaur that has been struck by lightning and lies dying in the garden.</p>
<p>To fulfil Twinsen's quest, and to eventually defeat some sneaky aliens intent on stealing the magic that permeates his planet, you have to move him through three colourful, beautifully-rendered, three-dimensional worlds.</p>
<p>With a push of a button, you can change his demeanor from normal to sporty (allowing him to jump and run), to aggressive (where he can fight), to discrete (where he can sneak about). A walkthrough of the game is available at http://spoiler.et.ee.</p>
<p>I had two problems with &quot;Twinsen's.&quot; I couldn't get it to install properly, but the technical support person at Activision said its games sometimes act quirky with Trident video cards like mine.</p>
<p>Second, there were times when Twinsen behaved very oddly, such as when he stepped on pointed spikes yet reacted as if he was being repeatedly punched in the head. When Twinsen finds an object he needs, he flails his arms like a little kid trying to fly in a wind storm. And when he runs, he lurches as if his legs were trying to leave his body behind.</p>
<p>But the musical score is superb, you can view much of the action from several camera angles, and the animation is first-rate.</p>
<p>A lot of computer games depict aliens worlds. Very few would be fun to visit in real life. Twinsen's is the exception.</p>
<p>    -    -    -    -</p>
<p>&quot;Norse By NorseWest: The Return of the Lost Vikings&quot; from Interplay ($40 for DOS/Windows95 or $60 for Sega Saturn and Sony PlayStation, (http://www.interplay.com) is a game where three Viking warriors search for a time machine to escape the clutches of the evil Tomator, whose name sounds like the mutant cousin of a spaghetti sauce ingredient.</p>
<p>A player must use the special talents of each Viking to move through the 31 levels. Erik the Swift can run fast enough to break down walls. Baleog the Fierce can use his bionic arm to swing through the air. Olaf the Stout has a shield that stops everything and can fly upwards with the controlled release of intestinal gas.</p>
<p>It's a typical arcade game with two unwelcome twists.</p>
<p>First, you can't install it without being forced to watch a 77-second commercial for &quot;Star Trek: Star Fleet Academy.&quot; If Interplay wants to promote its other products, they should do what other companies do: make watching the previews a voluntary process. Requiring customers to watch commercials before playing a $40 game is a practice that should be strongly discouraged.</p>
<p>Second, the Windows95 version doesn't install properly. The sound was okay, but I got a blank screen. After many minutes of uninstalling, reinstalling and tinkering (and watching the &quot;Star Fleet Academy&quot; trailer), I discovered that you're supposed to press the F4 key and run it in the &quot;full screen&quot; mode to see anything. It's a wholly unnecessary glitch.</p>
<p>    -    -    -    -</p>
<p>After a column two weeks ago, several readers whose children are would-be veterinarians contacted me to say they were having trouble finding a copy of &quot;I Can Be An Animal Doctor&quot; in their local computer store. Cloud 9 Interactive now has a toll-free ordering line: 888-ON-CLOUD-9 (888-662-5683).</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software:</p>
<p>&quot;Congressional Country Club&quot; -- This add-on course for &quot;Links&quot; and &quot;Microsoft Golf&quot; takes you to where presidents, congressmen and senators have golfed for over 72 years and where, the folks at Access Software say, &quot;politicians are applauded for a good lie.&quot; It's for DOS/Windows/Macintosh ($30, 800-800-4880, http://www.AccessSoftware.com).</p>
<p>&quot;Creatures&quot; looks like another attempt to cash in on the Tamagotchi craze, but do it with a real computer programme. This game, which lets colourful beings &quot;grow&quot; on your machine, is sold with the tag line &quot;Create real life on your PC.&quot; Didn't anybody ever teach the folks at Mindscape what the word &quot;real&quot; means? It's for Windows and Macintosh ($40)</p>
<p>&quot;Meat Puppet&quot; -- A woman with a supermodel figure and a skintight outfit discovers that she has been wired with explosive gel sacks that will explode unless she assassinates the leaders of six embassies. This CD-ROM (DOS, $50) is rated for ages 17 and older because of the strong language and animated blood and gore.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
