<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="751845" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft sees marketing expenses rising.</title>
<headline>Microsoft sees marketing expenses rising.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp chief operating officer Bob Herbold expects the company's marketing expenses to rise in the current fiscal year as the company launches new products and continues a brand imaging campaign.</p>
<p>Herbold said at the company's annual brief for financial analysts that the marketing expenses would rise beyond last year's level of 9.5 percent of its $11.4 billion in net revenues.</p>
<p>Marketing expenses peaked at 11 percent of net revenues in fiscal 1995 when the company launched its Windows 95 operating system.  </p>
<p>Herbold also said Microsoft's support costs would rise beyond last year's 3.3 percent of net revenues, further squeezing profit margins. Support costs had fallen from 5.3 percent in fiscal 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to have to spend some money next year,&quot; he said. &quot;That's going to drive those numbers up a bit.&quot;</p>
<p>Microsoft is planning upgrades to both its Windows 95 and Windows NT operating systems in the coming year, but revenue growth is expected to slow to 20 to 25 percent from last year's 31 percent rate, according to analysts.</p>
<p>Herbold said Microsoft spent $24.2 million in online advertising over the past year, making it the No. 1 advertiser on the Internet by far and the company intends to maintain its leadership.</p>
<p>Microsoft group vice president Pete Higgins, who is responsible for selling online advertising among other duties, said he was comfortable with estimates that total advertising revenue on the Internet in calendar 1997 would approach $500 million.</p>
<p>Higgins said Microsoft would lose &quot;hundreds of millions&quot; of dollars on its interactive media ventures in the coming year, but he said losses are declining. He said the company is &quot;tightening the screws&quot; to keep costs down, but he was confident the company was in all the right areas with its Microsoft Network online service, Sidewalk local entertainment product and Web sites focusing on travel, investment, autos and gaming.</p>
<p>Other business units that report to Higgins are profitable including hardware, which he said generated more than $400 million in revenue last year, and reference, which generated $100 million last year through versions of its Encarta encyclopedia alone.</p>
<p>The company has high hopes for an unusual hardware product due to hit stores in September -- a talking &quot;Barney&quot; doll that can interact with special computer software and videos.</p>
<p>Higgins said MSN, the No. 2 online service behind America Online Inc., has more than 2.3 million subscribers and the company's MSNBC news joint venture has more than 1.2 million unique users each month.</p>
<p>Microsoft executive vice president Steve Ballmer said the company would stick with the interactive businesses even though they may continue to lose money through fiscal 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;If we do it right, we'll figure out how to make money over time,&quot; Ballmer told reporters outside the meeting.</p>
<p>Ballmer also said Internet Explorer version 4.0 was on track for final release in September.</p>
<p>((--Seattle bureau, 206-386-4848))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
