<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752292" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Corporate America to act on Africa investment plea.</title>
<headline>Corporate America to act on Africa investment plea.</headline>
<byline>Juliette Saunders</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Corporate America responded to pressure from African leaders by pledging on Thursday to invest in the world's poorest in return for political and economic reforms.</p>
<p>Kenneth Derr, chairman and chief executive officer of Fortune 500 company Chevron Corp, led the field with a commitment to spend on Africa, which hopes to match the growth of the Asian Tigers early in the new century.</p>
<p>&quot;Do we believe in Africa's future? Over the next five years, we plan to invest nearly $10.5 billion,&quot; Derr told the four-day African/African American summit in Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>&quot;Africa is at a momentous juncture. I am certain that investors willing to take risks in Africa today will be the biggest winners tomorrow -- sub-Saharan Africa is one of the world's greatest untapped markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Top Chevron officials told Reuters the oil and gas exploration company planned to increase oil production in Angola and Nigeria by 50 percent to 600,000 barrels a year in each of the countries over the next three to five years.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola senior vice president and president of its Africa group, Carl Ware, was no less upbeat. He said the soft-drinks giant expected to double its business in Africa in the next five years.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe very strongly that Africa as a whole is setting forth the necessary preconditions for investment, that is economic and political reform,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Not to be outdone, software group Microsoft Corp said it was planning to invest &quot;millions of dollars&quot; to expand its business in Africa while Owens Corning -- already active in Botswana and South Africa -- said it was in negotiations with Zimbabwe for a joint $10 million project.</p>
<p>African leaders took the stage for the whole of Thursday to urge black Americans to lobby corporations and the U.S. government for investment. In exchange, they gave assurances they would promote moves towards democracy and peace across the continent.</p>
<p>Dotting their speeches with repeated references to Africa as the &quot;homeland&quot; of black Americans, at least one delegate was prompted to respond with fervour.</p>
<p>White former Republican member of Congress and Secretary of Housing Jack Kemp said: &quot;I feel too that I am home because this is the home of civilisation&quot;.</p>
<p>Sentimentally dubbing the conference &quot;a summit of humanity&quot;, he pronounced it was time for a Marshall-type plan for Africa, adding: &quot;I plan to tell the American people and my party...to get busy building trade and investment in Africa.&quot;</p>
<p>The Marshall Plan was a U.S.-financed aid programme which helped to revive Western Europe's economy after the ravages of World War Two.</p>
<p>Namibian President Sam Nujoma said it was time for &quot;action, not excuses&quot; to build the hoped-for &quot;African Renaissance&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot afford to fail at the point where our continent is at the threshold of success,&quot; he said. &quot;If we fail... we will have killed hope itself, and our failure will give rise to the inevitable consequences which are too ghastly to contemplate.&quot;</p>
<p>Economic reforms appear to have paid off for Africa in recent years. The continent's aggregate growth rose from an average of 1.6 percent for the period 1990-1994 to 4.8 percent last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24794">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
