<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="753974" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS-Netscape shares slide on spending concerns.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Netscape shares slide on spending concerns.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Netscape Communications Corp. slid nearly 11 percent Wednesday as some Wall Street analysts lowered earnings forecasts, saying the company will need to spend heavily to boost software sales.</p>
<p>Netscape stock tumbled $4.875 to close at $39.625 in active trading on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>Some analysts who were already bearish on the stock, like Volpe Brown Whelan &amp; Co.'s Charles Finnie, said unexpectedly high spending will disappoint investors who had hoped for expanding profit margins on new products.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe it's the last rabbit they can pull out of a hat,&quot; he said of Netscape's second-quarter results. &quot;While we admire the company and we admire its vision, we think the stock is wildly overvalued.&quot;</p>
<p>After the market closed on Tuesday, the company reported second-quarter revenues of $135.2 million, up from 75 million a year earlier and ahead of most analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>Netscape posted income prior to one-time charges of $8.8 million, or 10 cents a share, a 52 percent increase from $5.8 million, or 7 cents a share, prior to charges in the year-ago quarter and even with Wall Street forecasts.</p>
<p>Shares of the Internet software company, based in Mountain View, Calif., have sparked debate among investors and analysts, some of whom have been recommending the stock and others who say the company's growth will slow.</p>
<p>The stock has traded between $25 in late April and nearly $48 last week.</p>
<p>But after a conference call with the company late Tuesday, several analysts trimmed earnings projections, saying they expected Netscape to expand its sales and marketing force to boost sales of its latest products while they are fresh.</p>
<p>Hambrecht &amp; Quist analyst Daniel Rimer said he raised his 1997 sales estimates due to new products but he pared his earnings estimate to 47 cents a share from 52 cents a share due to the need for heavy investments.</p>
<p>&quot;The products seemed to be exciting in the marketplace,&quot; Rimer said of the company's new Communicator software, used on computers connected to networks, and its updated SuiteSpot software for servers that connect computers across a network.</p>
<p>&quot;They're definitely going to be reinvesting in this business to take advantage of this momentum,&quot; said Rimer, who repeated his &quot;strong buy&quot; recommendation and said he remains &quot;bullish&quot; on Netscape's opportunity to grow its business.</p>
<p>Alex. Brown analyst Mary McCaffrey repeated her buy rating, but also lowered her earnings estimates by a nickel each for 1997 and 1998, to 45 cents a share this year and 85 cents a share next year, citing higher spending.</p>
<p>Netscape Chief Executive Officer Jim Barksdale said on Tuesday he has centralized management to better coordinate sales and marketing efforts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
