<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75725" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New muppet treasure best left to children.</title>
<headline>New muppet treasure best left to children.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Ah the life at sea! There's salt in the air! There's wind in the sails! And there's jellyfish in my shorts!&quot;</p>
<p>As you might expect when you hear a comment like that, there are Muppets on the loose.</p>
<p>&quot;Muppet Treasure Island&quot; (Activision, Windows, $45) is a computerized adventure game based on the Disney movie that's just been released on video.</p>
<p>Packed onto three CD-ROMS, it lets players assume the role of Hawkins, the young boy who discovers a treasure map and must find his way to Treasure Island before Long John Silver and his co-conspirators make off with the booty.</p>
<p>It features live-action performances by the main characters from the film, including Kermit, Miss Piggy and Tim Curry, who plays Long John with nefarious glee.</p>
<p>The Muppets are loved by young and old alike because much of their humour has a dual edge to it, and this game has several jokes that will fly over the heads of children.</p>
<p>&quot;Treasure Island,&quot; however, suffers from a generational problem. For most people, the puzzles they need to solve to get through the adventure are much too easy, and not particularly creative.</p>
<p>Before the ship sets sail, for example, you must put apples in a pie plate, shoot a cannon, hang some barrels onto a moving hook, and raise and lower the anchor by pressing a few buttons. Few players will be stumped for long.</p>
<p>The only real challenge comes toward the end of the game when you must discover how to get into the secret entrance of the Treasure Island cave. Anyone who is stumped can use their mouse to click on Stevenson the Parrot, who offers hints for solving a troubling puzzle.</p>
<p>&quot;Treasure Island&quot; is recommended for ages 5 and up but only youngsters at the lower end of that age range will be truly captivated.</p>
<p>There are, however, other features to recommend it. The music is wonderful, the artwork is lush and delightfully surreal, and there are some amusing comic bits, such as the pirate's chest that seems to have an endless supply of junk, and the picture of the pirate's mother that comes alive to ask, &quot;Billy! Did you remember to brush your tooth?&quot; There are also clips from the movie.</p>
<p>Even when you think you've seen it all, the game still packs a few surprises. Only after I stumbled back into the room with the cannon did Dr. Livesey, played by Dr. Bunsen Honeydew, proudly offer details of his Cannonblaster Pro. It's &quot;the latest in 16-bit technology,&quot; he explained. &quot;Guaranteed to blow anything into 16 bits.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Muppet Treasure Island&quot; won't blow you away. But in an age when too many computer products for kids look like they're slapped together with scissors, glue and crayons, it's nice to see a game for youngsters that's as technically sophisticated as some of the top adventure games for grownups.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>&quot;Green Eggs and Ham&quot; is on the loose!</p>
<p>Based on the book by Dr. Seuss</p>
<p>It tells the classic children's story</p>
<p>Of eating coloured food that's gory.</p>
<p>With gross gray fruit and hamburgs white,</p>
<p>The animation will delight.</p>
<p>The matching game, a rhyme game, too,</p>
<p>Will keep attention stuck like glue</p>
<p>To Sam-I-Am, his mouse and fox,</p>
<p>All packed into this coloured box.</p>
<p>The music's great. The story's cute.</p>
<p>(Includes a parent's guide to boot).</p>
<p>It's for the 3 to 7 crowd</p>
<p>And all those kids will laugh out loud</p>
<p>As treats and tricks pop from the screen</p>
<p>And Sam-I-Am hawks food that's green.</p>
<p>It works on Windows or a Mac,</p>
<p>Costs $30 bucks -- less than a yak!</p>
<p>But maybe I should be concerned</p>
<p>'Cause kids should know (as I have learned)</p>
<p>That food with colours of the prism</p>
<p>Just sets the stage for botulism.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Other recently-released CD-ROM products for youngsters:</p>
<p>&quot;Friendly Forest Reading Club&quot; (IBM, Windows, $90) -- Billed as a comprehensive reading programme for ages 4 to 7, these two CD-ROMs are supposed to offer 120 activities, lessons and games. It also lets parents review a child's progress from behind the scenes and includes 5 printed workbooks and 12 storybooks.</p>
<p>&quot;The Great Word Adventure&quot; (Windows, $40) -- Comic Howie Mandel stars in a game for ages 6 to 9 that uses animated characters to teach word recognition, compound words, rhyming and alphabetization. It also has scary stories. The folks at 7th Level claim it's &quot;more fun than Saturday morning cartoons.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Sesame Street: Elmo's Preschool&quot; (Creative Wonders, Windows, $35) -- The loveable childlike creature from the PBS programme offers 15 learning activities for youngsters 3 to 6. Here's a big plus: the game also allows you to tickle Elmo.</p>
<p>&quot;Elroy's Costume Closet&quot; (Headbone Interactive, Windows/Macintosh, $20) lets you paste costumes on Elroy and his friend Syd. The combination you choose determines which of 75 animated skits is shown.</p>
<p>&quot;Mighty Math Carnival Countdown&quot; (Edmark, Windows/Macintosh, $40) is for ages 5 to 8. It uses bumper cars to teach about sorting, clowns to teach about addition and subtraction, and a three-piece band for a lesson on place value.</p>
<p>&quot;World Munchers Deluxe&quot; (MECC, Windows/Macintosh, $25) -- An educational game where children ages 6 to 11 get to &quot;munch&quot; the correct answers to questions, such as finding all the antonyms for &quot;messy.&quot;</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
