<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763026" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FTC will not poach on Justice's look at Microsoft.</title>
<headline>FTC will not poach on Justice's look at Microsoft.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Trade Commission told three senators Tuesday it will not conduct an investigation of Microsoft Corp. because to do so would duplicate efforts of the Justice Department.</p>
<p>Three Republican senators wrote FTC Chairman Robert Pitofsky on June 25, telling him they thought the Justice Department had fallen down on the job of enforcing a consent degree with Microsoft.</p>
<p>In July 1994, Microsoft and the Justice Department reached a consent decree, with Microsoft agreeing to some relatively narrow changes in the way it offered volume discounts to personal computer makers which bundle its operating system with their machines.</p>
<p>The settlement banned a Microsoft sales technique that offered PC makers steep discounts on operating system software if they agreed to pay Microsoft a royalty for each PC sold, even if another operating system was installed.</p>
<p>Republican Sens. Ted Stevens of Alaska, Conrad Burns of Montana and Craig Thomas of Wyoming asked Pitofsky to investigate Microsoft's compliance with the decree. The three said computer manufacturers complained to them Microsoft had violated the decree.</p>
<p>Pitofsky wrote back in a letter delivered Tuesday, telling the senators, as he was expected to do, that the FTC does not check up on the Justice Department.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission has determined that it cannot responsibly commence the investigation you have requested,&quot; Pitofsky said.</p>
<p>Pifosky said the FTC &quot;has concluded that to exercise its authority ... could involve a substantial duplication of effort.&quot;</p>
<p>Pitofsky said so far as he knew the FTC had never invoked its authority to investigate &quot;in the context of an active investigation of the same subject by the Department of Justice.&quot;</p>
<p>Pitofsky declined to say specifically that the Justice Department was in fact conducting such an investigation, although the letter certainly left the door open to that possibility.</p>
<p>A Justice Department spokeswoman said such an investigation was indeed under way.</p>
<p>One of the Senate aides who helped draft the letter said the response was as expected.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not particularly a surprise,&quot; said the aide.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
