<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="778972" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Back-to-school supplies, games.</title>
<headline>Back-to-school supplies, games.</headline>
<byline>Judith Schoolman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>While much of the country is sweltering in summer heat, producers of new products are busy introducing wares for back to school.</p>
<p>Day-Timers Inc., of East Texas, Pa., has packaged the Ultimate Back to School Survival Pack, a collection of new products to help students organise their lives.</p>
<p>The Day-Timer Student Planner ($5.99 to $19.99) contains a calendar, note pads, telephone book and pockets for clippings and other necessities of school life.</p>
<p>Hot Clips ($2.49) and Megaclips ($1.99) hold stacks of notes or reports and can be used as bookmarks.</p>
<p>Zazzle Highlighters ($7.50) make underlining and highlighting easy.</p>
<p>For information on the products, contact the company at 610-398-1151 or at www.daytimer.com.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>New for back-to-school from Fisher-Price is The Magna Doodle Learning Bus, designed for chidren aged 2 to 5. Shaped like a yellow school bus, this addition to the Magna Doodle line comes with a magnetic yellow pencil for use as a stylus and black magnetic shapes for stamping and decorating. One of the bus wheels acts as the magical eraser bar. Magic Learning Cards are placed onto the magnetic screen. Children stencil the letter shape, and then lift up the card to find a picture surprise.</p>
<p>Additional card sets include Magic Learning Numbers and Magic Learning Math.</p>
<p>The Learning Bus costs $29.99 and additional cards cost $6.99.</p>
<p>For more information, call 800-367-8926.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Natural Science Industries, a West Hempstead, N.Y.-based designer of educational toys, is introducing new toys for the 1997 holiday season.</p>
<p>For children aged 5 and up, NSI has Noah's Ark Sand Art ($12.99). Fill animal-shaped bottles with coloured sand and recreate Noah's journey.</p>
<p>For children aged 6 and up, Dream Catchers with Native American Baskets ($12.99). Kids can make Dream Catchers, used to drive away bad dreams, and weave colourful baskets using feathers, a thunderbird ornament, leather lacings, lanyard, an arrowhead and beads.</p>
<p>For ages 7 and up, there is Popular Mechanics Construction Zone ($12.99). Using more than 210 reusable pieces, children can build skyscrapers and other buildings. The set, including a working crane, costs $21.99.</p>
<p>For kids 8 and older, Merlin's Magic Tricks are six sets of tricks, containing three each. Each set costs $4.00.</p>
<p>For older children, there is Smithsonian Mega Science Lab, where they can learn about chemistry, biology, volcanoes, crystal growing and weather ($27.99).</p>
<p>For information on these and other NSI toys, contact the company at 516-678-1700.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Lovers of dried flower arrangments can learn the secrets of the art from a new video, &quot;Secrets of the Garden,&quot; hosted by floral designer Kim Unsworth. The 100-minute video shows viewers how to make five different arrangements. It also includes tips and tricks on growing and drying flowers, where to find the best dried materials and the best tools to use.</p>
<p>The video sells for $24.95. For more information contact Unsworth Productions in Canton, Ohio. Telephone 1-800-983-7233.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>King Koil, manufacturer of mattresses, has introduced to the consumer market mattresses that contain a fabric resistant to open flames.</p>
<p>Citing statistics from the Consumer Product Safety Commission, King Koil said that bedding items remain one of the major causes of residential structure fire deaths, claiming an estimated 610 civilian lives in a total of 31,300 residential structure fires per year.</p>
<p>The SpunGold Residential fire barrier, created in conjunction with Ventex, a fabric manufacturer, is a fabric that contains Kevlar (which is used in bullet-proof vests) and can be used as an additional layer in any mattress King Koil makes.</p>
<p>James Wyatt, vice president of King Koil West in Santa Ana, Calif., said the SpunGold layer adds about $80 to $100 to the price of a queen-size mattress.</p>
<p>For more information on the SpunGold material, contact King Koil at 714-KING-KOIL (546-4564). In California, call toll free 888-KING-KOIL (546-4564).</p>
<p>Wyatt said Ventex, based in Reston, Va., is hoping to expand the use of SpunGold to other manufacturers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
