<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780933" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft details Apple investment.</title>
<headline>Microsoft details Apple investment.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chief financial officers of Microsoft Corp and Apple Computer Inc said Microsoft's investment of $150 million in Apple and a cross-licensing deal will bolster Apple's turnaround efforts.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this business partnership announced this morning strengthens Apple's viability,&quot; Apple CFO Fred Anderson said in a conference call with analysts and media.</p>
<p>Anderson and Microsoft CFO Greg Maffei said Microsoft's $150 million investment in newly issued nonvoting preferred stock will be priced at an average of the stock's recent trailing days' trading levels.  They would not elaborate.  </p>
<p>&quot;We bought at an average of the recent trailing trading days, which has been pre-negotiated, so we're slightly below the market, because the stock has run the last few days,&quot; Maffei said in the conference call.</p>
<p>Nancy Paxton, a spokeswoman for Apple's investor relations department, said afterwards &quot;the investment is expected to be concluded within the next couple of days.&quot;</p>
<p>Maffei said Microsoft's cash investment was at least in part motivated as a response to a request from Steven Jobs, who asked &quot;for us to make a visible commitment to Apple, a visible commitment to the Mac, and he wanted us to become an investor.&quot;  </p>
<p>Jobs, Apple's co-founder, has stepped in to orchestrate much of the company's new strategy in the last month, after the board ousted chairman and chief executive Gil Amelio.</p>
<p>Apple said Microsoft will pay it an undisclosed sum related to the patent cross-licensing agreement between the two, but the executives said the amount would not be material to either of the companies.  Apple said details were still to be worked out but the payments will probably run for two to three years.</p>
<p>Apple said stock issued to Microsoft is in preferred shares that could be converted to commmon stock, but not for at least the term of Microsoft's three-year commitment to hold them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
