<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780975" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Apple gets mixed review.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Apple gets mixed review.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Options investors held a mixed view of Apple Computer Inc on Wednesday as the stock rocketed higher on news that Microsoft Corp will buy $150 million in Apple stock and take other steps to help the company, options traders said.</p>
<p>By about 1040 CDT/1540 GMT, shares of the computer maker were up seven points at 26-3/4. With turnover of 18.1 million shares, it was the most active stock on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>&quot;Brokers that are doing (some of the options trading) don't think the story's going to hold,&quot; said one options trader at a U.S. brokerage firm.  </p>
<p>&quot;A lot of people were just selling calls&quot; against underlying stock positions, the trader said, citing the 20 and 25 strikes in particular.</p>
<p>But Hank Nothnagel, senior vice president of options trading at EVEREN Securities, said his desk had customers buying and selling calls, with most larger orders on the buy side.</p>
<p>The August 20 call was the most active Apple option, with turnover of nearly 3,400 contracts. The September 20 call traded 2,250 and the October 20 call traded 2,025. The January 20 and 30 calls were also busy, with volume of about 2,210 and 2,040 contracts, respectively.  </p>
<p>&quot;We were doing some size buying in the August 25s,&quot; Northnagel said, noting that those were newly added strike levels.</p>
<p>He said the stock's surge suggested Wall Street believed the news on Apple would make a difference for the company.</p>
<p>&quot;A week ago you couldn't give it away and now everybody wants it,&quot; he said of the shares. &quot;Seven dollars is a big move in that one.&quot;</p>
<p>Lawrence McMillan, who runs McMillan Analysis Corp, said Apple options had been active recently, but it appeared investors were responding to earlier news reports that Apple co-founder Steve Jobs would be named chief executive and other news.  </p>
<p>&quot;They kept parceling out news everyday and it looked like people were just responding to that,&quot; said McMillan, who publishes the Daily Volume Alert.</p>
<p>On Monday, for instance, Apple options volume rose to 12,424 from an average of 3,050, according to McMillan. Most of that increase was on the call side.</p>
<p>In addition, historic volatility in the options rose to about 54 percent in July from about 28 percent in May.  </p>
<p>Implied volatility in the August 22-1/2 and 25 calls was in the 70 to 80 range Wednesday.</p>
<p>In addition to the Microsoft cash infusion, the Cupertino, Calif.-based company named Jobs, who is currently a strategic advisor to the company, Oracle Corp Chairman Larry Ellison, former International Business Machines Corp Chief Financial Officer Jerome York and Inuit Inc Chief Excecutive Bill Campbell to its board.</p>
<p>Three current board members, Mike Markkula, Katherine Hudson and Bernard Goldstein, resigned.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
