<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781869" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft to invest in Apple, ending feud.</title>
<headline>Microsoft to invest in Apple, ending feud.</headline>
<byline>Therese Poletti</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Apple Computer Inc. and Microsoft Corp. shocked the computer industry and Wall Street Wednesday by ending their bitter rivalry and saying Microsoft will invest $150 million in the troubled computer maker.</p>
<p>The announcement, delivered by Apple co-founder Steven Jobs to thousands of Apple customers here, could prove crucial for the survival of Apple, the company that helped popularise the personal computer.</p>
<p>For years, Apple and Microsoft competed furiously, with each company trying to destroy the other. But Microsoft quickly got the upper hand when it agreed to license its Windows operating system to personal computer makers while Apple tried to hold onto its own technology.</p>
<p>After more than $1.6 billion in losses over the past 18 months, Jobs, who recently returned to Apple as a special adviser, said the time had come to put an end to the feud.</p>
<p>&quot;If we want to move forward, we have to let go of a few things,&quot; Jobs told the MacWorld trade conference. &quot;We want to let go of this notion that for Apple to win, Microsoft has to lose. We need all the help we can get. We better treat Microsoft with a little gratitude.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the deal, Microsoft will invest $150 million in Apple stock and develop more programmes for the Macintosh. The world's largest software company also will develop a new version of its Office package of business software, widely used in the corporate world, for the Macintosh.</p>
<p>Microsoft also will include its Internet browser in the Macintosh operating system.</p>
<p>Jobs, who is serving as a strategic adviser while Apple looks for a chairman and CEO, said Microsoft's stake would be a non-voting interest in Apple and that Microsoft agreed not to sell its shares for at least three years.</p>
<p>Apple also revamped its entire board, which had been heavily criticised by shareholders for fumbling the company's long-term strategy.</p>
<p>The new members are Jobs, Oracle Corp. Chairman Larry Ellison, former International Business Machines Corp. Chief Financial Officer Jerome York and Intuit Inc. Chief Executive Bill Campbell.</p>
<p>Three current board members -- including early Apple investor and one-time chairman A.C. &quot;Mike&quot; Markkula, Katherine Hudson and Bernard Goldstein -- resigned.</p>
<p>News of the alliance and the board changes brought cheers and jeers from Apple loyalists at the conference, but it was a hit on Wall Street, where shares of Apple surged as much as 40 percent to $27.75, the highest level in more than a year.</p>
<p>The stock stood at $26.50, up $6.75 on Nasdaq, where it was the most active issue with 33 million shares traded.</p>
<p>Investors said the changes could be the best moves Apple has made in the last three years to halt its slide. While getting help from Microsoft -- the company that did the most to destroy Apple's lead in easy-to-use computers -- will not endear die-hard Macintosh fans, it could goad the rest of the industry and corporate computer users to continue to support Apple.</p>
<p>&quot;That should ensure Apple being around for a while,&quot; said Arnie Owen, managing director at investment bank Cruttenden Roth. Microsoft &quot;is the biggest guy you could get to support you. That doesn't say that Apple is a great company, but there are parts of it that are worthwhile.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, with over 8 million Mac users worldwide, Apple represents one of the biggest markets for Microsoft.</p>
<p>Microsoft Chairman Bill Gates appeared at the conference via satellite to a mixture of boos and applause from the audience, which included Mac customers, software developers and investors.</p>
<p>&quot;We think Apple makes a huge contribution in the computer industry,&quot; Gates said. &quot;And we think it's going to be a lot of fun helping out.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the investment was a shrewd move by Gates to deflect criticism that Microsoft was stifling competition in the computer industry. Federal antitrust regulators have been investigating Microsoft since 1989. Having Apple as a healthy competitor would make it tougher to prove Microsoft has a monopoly in the software business, analysts said.</p>
<p>Jobs, rumoured to be a candidate to replace former Chairman Gilbert Amelio, who was ousted last month, said the company would not name a chairman for now. The move leaves open the possibility that Jobs himself might eventually take the position, as many in the industry have speculated.</p>
<p>The board changes pleased investors.</p>
<p>&quot;I consider (Markkula) being mainly accountable for the disasters that have befallen Apple,&quot; said Richard Ash, an individual investor who owns 2,000 Apple shares. He said he would &quot;absolutely&quot; keep his Apple investment now.</p>
<p>Macintosh fans were stunned that Apple aligned itself with Microsoft, its arch-enemy. For years, Apple fought a bitter lawsuit accusing Microsoft of stealing the easy-to-understand metaphors used in Macintosh software. Apple lost.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
