<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781947" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft investment reflects end of long rivalry.</title>
<headline>Microsoft investment reflects end of long rivalry.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The battle for control of the desktop computer market ended long ago, but Microsoft Corp.'s $150 million peace gesture to Apple Computer Inc. Wednesday still came as a shock to many.</p>
<p>Yet industry analysts say the deal makes sense for Microsoft, protecting its investment in software for Apple's Macintosh platform and possibly easing antitrust concerns of U.S. regulators.</p>
<p>Microsoft has never stopped producing software for Apple computers, even during the seven years Apple fruitlessly pursued a lawsuit charging that Microsoft's market-dominating Windows interface was based on the trademarked &quot;look and feel&quot; of the Macintosh.</p>
<p>&quot;This is one of those deals that does make a lot of sense for Microsoft,&quot; said consultant Tim Bajarin, president of Creative Strategies. &quot;Considering that Microsoft does not feel threatened by Apple in any way, shape or form, why not not work with Apple?&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts say the deal ensures that Microsoft's Internet Explorer browser will be installed on virtually every new computer, further eating into rival Netscape Communications Corp.'s leading market share.</p>
<p>Microsoft protects its business of providing word-processing, spreadsheet and other software for the Macintosh platform, which generates &quot;several hundred million&quot; dollars in sales annually, according to Microsoft chief financial officer Greg Maffei.</p>
<p>And Microsoft gets access to Apple's patent portfolio, making it more likely the companies will unify their approach to computer video and graphics, Bajarin said.</p>
<p>All this for an investment that will hardly be missed from Microsoft's $9 billion cash hoard.</p>
<p>The investment also sends a strong message to Macintosh loyalists, many of whom booed Gates when he appeared by satellite at the Macworld conference in Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically this is his way of saying, 'There is no Apple blood on my hands,'&quot; said Michael Gartenberg, research director of Gartner Group. &quot;'If the company goes under, if Apple dies, there will nobody who can say we put them under.'&quot;</p>
<p>Many analysts also said the deal could help boost Microsoft's standing with the Justice Department, which for years has investigated complaints that the Redmond, Wash.-based company has used anti-competitive practices to achieve a near-monopoly in its core market.</p>
<p>&quot;Call me cynical, but I think this has almost everything to do with keeping the Department of Justice at bay and very little to do with leveraging future business out of the Macintosh universe and into the Windows camp,&quot; said Dain Bosworth analyst Barry Randall.</p>
<p>Maffei declined to comment on antitrust implications of the Apple investment but said he did not anticipate any regulatory challenges.</p>
<p>&quot;Frankly we weren't driven as much by those kind of considerations as looking at it as a platform for our applications,&quot; he told reporters in a conference call.</p>
<p>Microsoft and Apple executives say the latest rapprochement between the two companies began last year under the tenure of Gil Amelio, who stepped down in July as chief executive after 17 months in the job.</p>
<p>Negotiations accelerated about a month ago when Apple co-founder Steve Jobs returned to an active management role with the computer maker and telephoned Gates, sparking a series of meetings that led to the investment.</p>
<p>Microsoft's Maffei spoke of a new &quot;pragmatism&quot; in relations between the two companies.</p>
<p>&quot;This company has done so many wonderful things, and we believe it's going to continue to do many wonderful things,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Such friendly comments stand in contrast to events of two years ago, when the companies sued each other over video technology and Gates complained about Apple's &quot;lack of honesty and candor&quot; to then-chief executive officer Michael Spindler.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
