<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781915" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apple prospects brighten, but not much.</title>
<headline>Apple prospects brighten, but not much.</headline>
<byline>Kourosh Karimkhany</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>It was a true moment in the history of the computer industry: Microsoft Corp. agreed to help out arch-enemy Apple Computer Inc. by investing $150 million in the ailing computer maker.</p>
<p>As word of the deal spread at the Macworld trade show in Boston, an important pilgrimage for Macintosh fans, thousands of people audibly gasped. President Bill Clinton even weighed in by telling reporters on Wednesday he was watching developments closely for any antitrust violations.</p>
<p>But as the Macworld surprise made great drama, it also highlighted Apple's fall as a leader in the computer industry. Apple has turned to its bitterest enemy for help, symbolically declaring defeat.</p>
<p>In addition, industry analysts say Apple's long-term prospects are not significantly brighter, with or without Microsoft. The company has yet to figure out how to keep its computer sales from plunging. And Apple will still have a tough time finding a veteran chief executive that can head a turnaround.</p>
<p>Microsoft's investing in Apple &quot;is a bit like NASA trying to rescue Mir,&quot; said one prominent Silicon Valley investor.</p>
<p>Under terms of the transaction unveiled Wednesday, Microsoft agreed to buy a special class of Apple stock in exchange for $150 million in cash. The world's largest personal computer software company also pledged to continue writing its Office business software for the Macintosh.</p>
<p>Microsoft's backing provides a huge psychological boost, which could keep other software companies and Mac customers from defecting, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;That should ensure Apple being around for a while,&quot; said Arnie Owen, managing director at investment bank Cruttenden Roth. Microsoft &quot;is the biggest guy you could get to support you.&quot;</p>
<p>But the alliance with Microsoft crushes some of the fundamental spirit that has kept Apple going through tough times, which could turn off some Mac customers.</p>
<p>In the late 1980s, Apple fought a bitter lawsuit against Microsoft, accusing the software giant of stealing the easy-to-use metaphors of the Macintosh. Since then, Microsoft and its chairman, Bill Gates, have been enemy No. 1 with Mac fans. Apple even had an unofficial selling point by being outside Microsoft's camp.</p>
<p>When Gates appeared on a giant video screen at Macworld today to announce the investment, thousands booed and hissed.</p>
<p>&quot;It was anathema,&quot; said Lou Mazzucchelli, analyst at Gerard Klauer Mattison. &quot;It was like putting Darth Vader up at a Star Wars convention.&quot;</p>
<p>Microsoft also made it clear that it has not yet decided to support Apple's upcoming software strategy.</p>
<p>Apple is betting the farm on a next-generation software operating system code-named Rhapsody, slated to be released in a year. The goal is to make Rhapsody so much more powerful and easy to use than the Windows operating system that Apple computers would fly off the shelf again.</p>
<p>So far, however, no major software company has committed to making products for Rhapsody.</p>
<p>Apple also has a thorny relationship with its hardware allies. Three years ago, Apple decided to license its technology to so-called clone makers as part of a strategy to expand the Mac's market share and attract software developers.</p>
<p>The strategy worked reasonably well, with companies such as Power Computing Corp. boosting Mac sales. But sales of Mac clones came at a huge expense to Apple, which could not make machines as cheaply.</p>
<p>Steve Jobs, the Apple co-founder who was instrumental in getting the Microsoft investment, has said he would rather that Apple not license its technology.</p>
<p>Executives at the clone makers said they are worried about the growing influence of Jobs, who was also named a director on Wednesday. They warn it would a &quot;disaster&quot; for the Mac if Apple pulls back from licensing.</p>
<p>Finally, Apple still does not have a chairman and chief executive. Finding one with enough experience to turn the company around will be a tough trick, industry executives said.</p>
<p>The one bright spot is that Apple revamped its entire board of directors by naming four industry heavyweights including Oracle Chairman Larry Ellison, one-time International Business Machines Corp. Chief Financial Officer Jerome York, and Intuit Corp. President and Chief Executive Bill Campbell.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday I would say this company has no future,&quot; said David Wu, analyst at ABN AMRO Chicago Corp. &quot;But today I would say it does&quot; with the new all-star board.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
