<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781910" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Macintosh users welcome Microsoft's help.</title>
<headline>Macintosh users welcome Microsoft's help.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Long considered the archenemy of Apple Computer Inc., Microsoft Corp. Chairman Bill Gates turned from pariah to hero Wednesday with his surprising investment in the struggling computer company.</p>
<p>Loyal users of Macintosh computers booed and hissed when Gates' face appeared on a giant screen at the annual Macworld Expo in Boston, but many welcomed the news he delivered.</p>
<p>After a year of huge losses at Apple, a further dwindling share of the personal computer market, another corporate restructuring and a sinking share price, most Macintosh fans said they were willing to accept Gates' help.</p>
<p>&quot;These two companies have been in a love-hate relationship with each other for 10 years,&quot; said a software developer who used to work for Apple. &quot;For Apple to survive, Microsoft does not have to die. They can work together.&quot;</p>
<p>With a visibly uncomfortable Gates looking down from the huge screen, Apple co-founder Steve Jobs announced the deal with Microsoft that would put an end to their long feud.</p>
<p>Microsoft agreed to invest $150 million in Apple stock and develop more programmes for the Macintosh. The world's largest software company also will develop a new version of its Office package of business software, widely used in the corporate world, for the Macintosh. Apple will bundle Microsoft's Internet browser software as the primary browser for the Internet in the Macintosh.</p>
<p>Despite Apple's many missteps over the years, Macintosh enthusiasts, known as Macheads, are known for their rebelliousness, near-fanatical devotion to their computers and vocal confidence in its superiority over Microsoft's Windows platform. At the trade show, T-shirts, jeans, ponytails and birkenstocks usually outnumber suits and ties.</p>
<p>As Microsoft has grown to dominate the personal computer market, poking fun at the software giant has become a favourite sport at the annual Macworld conference.</p>
<p>But Jobs, who was greeted with a partial standing ovation, whistles, shouts, and screams of delight, signalled a new era when he implored Mac fans to tone down the jeering and accept the new relationship.</p>
<p>&quot;We need all the help we can get,&quot; Jobs said. &quot;We better treat Microsoft with a little gratitude.&quot;</p>
<p>Some Macintosh users, noting the 33 percent jump in Apple stock following the news Wednesday, readily put aside their past differences with the software giant.</p>
<p>&quot;Slowly but surely, he has destroyed Apple, but you can't deny his presence,&quot; said Greg Albright, a computer systems administrator from Greenwich, Conn., referring to Gates.</p>
<p>&quot;One way or another, his presence was going to be felt. So for Apple's sake, it seems better to have him on your team than against you.&quot;</p>
<p>Even diehard Mac groupies would grudgingly accept Microsoft's gesture of peace, the software developer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the most rabid Mac fans are tempering their attitude,&quot; he said. &quot;They're tired of beating their head against the wall. Apple is its own worst enemy. Microsoft is its second-worst enemy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
