<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784408" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Revived Apple seen feeding Euro-competition.</title>
<headline>Revived Apple seen feeding Euro-competition.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>A revitalised Apple Computer Inc would spur more fierce rivalry in Europe's personal computer market, experts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>But some wondered whether its deal with Microsoft Corp had more to do with protecting the world's biggest software company from legal problems than breathing fresh life into ailing Apple.</p>
<p>Microsoft's plan to invest $150 million in Apple would not only underpin fragile finances, but repair its recently flimsy credibility among personal computer buyers, software developers and assemblers, said Emmanuel Lalloz, senior PC analyst at market researcher CONTEXT.</p>
<p>The news, announced Wednesday at the MacWorld Expo convention in Boston, Massachusetts, included a pledge by Microsoft to develop more software for Apple Macintosh computers. Apple agreed to make Microsoft's Explorer browser the easiest way to access the Internet from the Macintosh.</p>
<p>&quot;This is good news for both companies, certainly for Apple,&quot; said Lalloz.</p>
<p>However Julio Abella, research associate with Gartner Group's Dataquest, saw the deal as really only favouring Microsoft. &quot;This will not affect Europe differently than the rest of the world. Microsoft is trying to keep Apple alive,&quot; Abella said.</p>
<p>&quot;This keeps alive the impression of competition in the market, keeps the merger authorities in the U.S. away.&quot; Earlier today the European Commission said it is unlikely to review the deal under competition law.</p>
<p>London's Financial Times also viewed the deal with a jaundiced eye.</p>
<p>&quot;When you have beaten your bitter rival into a pulp and he is gasping for air, why extend a helping hand?&quot; asked the Financial Times' Lex column.</p>
<p>&quot;The real advantage in resuscitating Apple is that Microsoft can argue its operating system does not have a monopoly; that may keep the anti-trust authorities off its case,&quot; Lex said.</p>
<p>&quot;Another benefit from striking a deal with Apple is it  stops the group falling into hostile hands.&quot;</p>
<p>CONTEXT's Lalloz shrugs off this cynical view.</p>
<p>&quot;As well as bringing in a lot of cash, there are lots of synergies for developing software. The whole Mac world will benefit and the Mac assemblers -- UMAX (Computer Corp), Motorola and Power Computing (Corp) PWRC.O ),&quot; Lalloz said.</p>
<p>&quot;Apple was at a disadvantage with a lot less software available, so with Microsoft behind it, it will give Apple a serious credibility boost.&quot;</p>
<p>And this new lease of life promises to ratchet up the already tempestuous competition in Europe's personal computer market, according to Lalloz.</p>
<p>Apple had already begun a recovery in Europe in the first half of this year, holding on to ninth place in the pecking order. Compaq Computer Corp easily held on to its lead with market share of 14.6 per cent in the first six months of 1997, CONTEXT data shows.</p>
<p>But behind Compaq, there was a vicious dog-fight for sales with International Business Machines Corp in second place with 9.3 per cent, closely followed by Hewlett-Packard and Siemens Nixdorf . Only 2-1/2 percentage points separate Dell Computer Co at 5.5 per cent in fifth place, and Apple's ninth place 3.0 per cent.</p>
<p>Another analyst who declined to be named also believed the combination would boost Apple's fragile fortunes in Europe and lead to greater competition.</p>
<p>CONTEXT's Lalloz said competition would be enhanced, but it would take time for this to lead to any shakeout.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of the smaller (personal computer) assemblers have been suffering a lot from the recession and are running on no (profit) margin at all, But it will take time before any victims become apparent,&quot; Lalloz said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302015">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
