<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784965" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: APPLE-MICROSOFT DEAL SPARKS LITTLE ASIAN REACTION.</title>
<headline>APPLE-MICROSOFT DEAL SPARKS LITTLE ASIAN REACTION.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Microsoft Corp's US$150 million investment in troubled computer maker Apple Computer Inc sparked little reaction from technology companies in Asia on Thursday.</p>
<p>Contract manufacturers said they saw little immediate impact on their businesses while analysts were divided in their views.</p>
<p>The announcement by Apple co-founder Steve Jobs late on Wednesday involved a cross-licensing deal between two firms which were antagonists for years.  </p>
<p>Under a five-year development agreement, Microsoft will bring out as many major product upgrades for Apple's Macintosh operating system as it does for its own Windows systems. Microsoft's Internet Explorer becomes the default Web browser for Apple.</p>
<p>Apple will issue preferred shares to Microsoft that could be converted to common stock but not for at least Microsoft's three year commitment to hold them.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is good for Apple but in the short term there is no impact for us,&quot; one leading Singapore contract manufacturer who supplies to Apple told Reuters.  </p>
<p>The contract manufacturer, who declined to be named, said the longer-term impact depended on Microsoft's actions.</p>
<p>&quot;The question is why Microsoft wants to buy into Apple. I suspect it is because they have some very good software which they want to make use of,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the future impact on suppliers would depend on whether Apple would grow in terms of hardware.</p>
<p>He was watching to see whether Microsoft encouraged Apple to develop personal computers (PCs) based on Intel's chips or rival companies chips like from AMD.  </p>
<p>Frank Huang, chairman of UMAX Computer Corp, a Taiwanese Apple clonemaker, said he was pleased with the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a new Steve Jobs,&quot; Huang said. &quot;He wants to save Apple. It's the end of the visionary Steve Jobs. It's the practical Steve Jobs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some impact for Singapore in terms of the customer base for companies like Venture Manufacturing and Fu Yu who supply to Apple,&quot; said Greg Tarr, Singapore-based technology/electronics analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.  </p>
<p>Another analyst from a foreign broking house said the deal raised concerns of whether multimedia companies like Creative Technology and Aztech could see competition from Microsoft in future.</p>
<p>&quot;The Apple platform has interesting multimedia capabilties which could be transferred to the Microsoft platform. It raises the question of whether Creative will have the ability to sustain its sound standard,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>He said Creative could lose some business if Microsoft integrated sound and video capabilities into its operating system.  </p>
<p>Creative's Sound Blaster audio card is currently considered the standard for audio capability on PCs.</p>
<p>&quot;Microsoft will probably write new specifications and everybody will have to make the hardware according to the specifications. We're talking about loss of future opportunities from existing standards,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tarr of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell said any developments in audio capabilities would enhance business for Creative and Aztech as there would be more demand for good sound quality.</p>
<p>Officials from Creative, Aztech and Apple Singapore were not available for comment.  </p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302015">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
