<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788768" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Microsoft rivals undaunted by Gates' Apple deal.</title>
<headline>Microsoft rivals undaunted by Gates' Apple deal.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oft repeated words of wisdom circulating Silicon Valley's technology elite are never, ever drive your business onto Microsoft Corp. Chairman Bill Gates' radar screen.</p>
<p>If you stray into his target sights, he'll either blast you out of business or, if you're lucky, he might just buy you out, they say.</p>
<p>A frequently-cited example is Apple Computer Inc., whose easy-to-use Apple II spawned the market for personal computers that fit on people's desktops or at home.</p>
<p>Apple popularised many of the features which have made personal computers accessible to laymen, like use of a mouse as a pointing device and a graphical interface with click-on icons, but Microsoft's ever-improving Windows software eventually brought these to the broadest market.</p>
<p>Now, with Microsoft investing $150 million in Apple, the Cupertino, Calif.-based company, whose percentage market share has dwindled to single digits, is benefiting from the more charitable side of its cash-flush one-time archrival.</p>
<p>That investment was hailed as an end to a bitter rivalry.</p>
<p>But it is not all altruistic. The move also helps secure the future of the Macintosh system, for which Microsoft sells an estimated $300 million to $500 million of software a year.</p>
<p>By Thursday Microsoft's stake had risen to around $270 million, as Apple stock gained $2.875 to $29.1875 on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>As Microsoft continues to expand its reach into new areas such as cable, broadcasting and local information services, some high tech executives and investors are speculating over which companies will next loom in its path.</p>
<p>Netscape Communications Corp., whose Navigator browser two years ago is credited with helping commercialize the Internet software business and with waking Microsoft to the opportunity of the Web, is tops on many people's list.</p>
<p>Apple, based in Cupertino, Calif., agreed to bundle the Microsoft Internet Explorer browser with the Mac OS, making it the default browser in future operating system releases.</p>
<p>Analysts and executives note the deal struck after a conversation between Gates and Apple co-founder Steve Jobs means Internet Explorer will now be shipped free on virtually all new personal computers, a fresh challenge to Netscape.</p>
<p>&quot;It definitely puts a lot more pressure on Netscape now that the two founders of the personal computer era -- Bill Gates and Steve Jobs -- are linked together,&quot; said Dale Fuller, chief executive of Internet directory firm WhoWhere? Inc.</p>
<p>But Dave Rothschild, director of client product marketing at Netscape, cited a recent survey finding that only 10 percent of computer users on the Internet are using software that came preinstalled in their machines. Apple has also said it expects to continue to offer Netscape Communicator as well.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been shipping Mac products for a long time,&quot; he said, noting Netscape's market share remains above 70 percent in independent surveys.</p>
<p>Another company appearing on Microsoft's radar screen is Sun Microsystems Inc., whose chairman, Scott McNealy, deliberately taunts Gates in public speeches and which reportedly nearly acquired Apple 18 months ago.</p>
<p>But far from steering clear of the Redmond, Wash.-based Microsoft, McNealy's strategy has been to position Sun as an alternative to computers that use Microsoft's Windows systems.</p>
<p>&quot;We are on a roll. By the way, we are now Microsoft's No. 1 concern,&quot; he wrote in an electronic mail comment on the Microsoft-Apple collaboration, which in part includes working together on Sun's Java technology.</p>
<p>Given Microsoft's competitive zeal, not many Silicon Valley executives would relish that position. But so far the market has not fretted much over either company's stock price.</p>
<p>Both shares gained for the second straight day after the deal's unveiling, with shares of Sun gaining $1.50 Thursday to close at $49.875 after briefly reaching a record of $50.375 earlier. Netscape gained 50 cents to $40.375.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a stake in the heart for Sun and Netscape at the moment,&quot; said Ron Rappapport, analyst at Zona Research. But he added that by taking Microsoft's money, &quot;Apple has finally fallen out of the ABM world -- Anybody But Microsoft.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
