<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79411" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BEFORE THE BELL - Silicon Graphics tumbles.</title>
<headline>BEFORE THE BELL - Silicon Graphics tumbles.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silicon Graphics Inc shares fell to 21-1/2 from 23-5/8 in U.S. pre-open trade Thursday as investors sold on the company's warning of below-expectation results for the fiscal first quarter, traders said.</p>
<p>After Wednesday's market close, Silicon Graphics said it expects profits for the quarter ending this month to fall &quot;materially below&quot; market expectations because of product transitions and microprocessor production problems.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected the company to earn $0.29 a share for the first quarter of fiscal 1997, according to First Call. The company earned $0.33 a share in the year-ago period.  </p>
<p>The company also said expects revenues to be only slightly above the combined $758 million posted a year ago by Silicon and Cray Research, which was acquired July 1.</p>
<p>With the decline, the stock approached its year-low of 20 hit in July. The year-high is 38-3/4, notched in early December.</p>
<p>Transport Holdings is &quot;looking at least 10 points higher&quot; after Conseco Inc said it agreed to buy it for $70 per share in stock, or $311 million deal, a trader said.</p>
<p>Transport shares were untraded early in the pre-open session, but were bid 66, ask 65-1/2 amid heavy buying interest.</p>
<p>The stock finished yesterday's Nasdaq session at 51-3/4.  </p>
<p>Conseco made no moves preceding Thursday's regular-market open, traders said.</p>
<p>Also, Mentor Graphics Corp stock sold off after it issued an after-market warning about third quarter results.</p>
<p>Ahead of the open, the shares fell to nine from 12-3/8, then inched up to trade in the 9-1/2 to 9-3/4 range.</p>
<p>The company said late yesterday it expects delayed customer purchases to cut third quarter revenues to below year-ago levels and net income to slightly above break even.</p>
<p>Analysts were expecting a third quarter net of $0.24 a share, as compiled by First Call, versus $0.19 a share.  </p>
<p>Year-ago revenues sales were $107.4 million, Mentor said.</p>
<p>Adobe Systems Inc shares added to gains that came during last night's after-hours trading.</p>
<p>The company reported third quarter earnings of $0.40 per share, below the $0.44 year-ago net but above Wall Street's consensus forecast of $0.35 per share.</p>
<p>The shares rose to 38-1/2 early Thursday, up from 35 at the Nasdaq market close yesterday and 1/2 above the level reached after hours last night.</p>
<p>-- Brendan Intindola, Wall Street Desk, 212-859-1734.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
