<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795110" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: HYPERION SOFTWARE SEES BRISK ASIA GROWTH.</title>
<headline>HYPERION SOFTWARE SEES BRISK ASIA GROWTH.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S.-based Hyperion Software said on Tuesday it saw revenues in Asia growing strongly in its current financial year ending June 30, 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Our revenue (in Asia) grew 75 percent in the past year. We're looking for another 75 percent growth this (fiscal) year,&quot; Richard Lisbin, Hyperion's Asia Pacific director of sales, told reporters.</p>
<p>Hyperion develops and markets planning and budgeting, accounting, multi-source consolidation, business reporting and analysis software.  </p>
<p>Lisbin said the company did not report revenues for geographic regions but added that some 35 percent of revenue came from outside the United States.</p>
<p>For the year ended June 30, 1997, Hyperion recorded net profit of US$11.9 million on revenue of US$222.8 million.</p>
<p>Lisbin said the firm was aiming for another 30 new clients in Asia, excluding Japan, by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>It had signed up 24 first-time customers in the same region so far this year.</p>
<p>Including Japan, Hyperion now has 160 clients.  </p>
<p>Its growth in the region would be through both new clients and developing more business within existing ones, Lisbin said.</p>
<p>Hyperion is looking to set up offices in Malaysia and Indonesia after opening offices in Singapore, Hong Kong and Japan.</p>
<p>It has a training centre in Singapore and Hong Kong and a hotline in Singapore that supports the region.</p>
<p>Hyperion was working on providing the ability to do transactions reporting within the Web, Lisbin said.  </p>
<p>A year ago, the firm launched its Spiderman tool which allows a company to share sophisticated financial reports among its subsidaries through Web technologies.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65) 870-3080; Fax (65) 776-8112</p>
<p>-- Email: singapore.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
