<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796760" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 'Real World' Math Problems and 'Extreme' Fun.</title>
<headline>'Real World' Math Problems and 'Extreme' Fun.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>It is called &quot;Math for the Real World,&quot; but this CD-ROM for teaching practical mathematics skills to anyone over 9 years old isn't always grounded in reality.</p>
<p>First, every time you go into the local diner, a submarine sandwich or a plate of fried chicken actually costs less than the $3 cup of coffee. Second, no matter where your rock band is traveling across the country, you always have to eat at the same diner.</p>
<p>But despite its sometimes tenuous touch with real life, &quot;Math for the Real World&quot; (Davidson, Windows/Macintosh, $30, 800-545-7677, http://www.education.com) lives up to its name in other respects.</p>
<p>The band tour provides an excuse to serve up over 4,000 real-life word problems. Figuring percentages, calculating the best bargain or converting units of measurements suddenly becomes more than a seemingly esoteric problem on a high school quiz.</p>
<p>The game asks what time a TV dinner should come out of the oven if you put it in at 5:35 and the cooking time is 80 minutes. It wants to know if the best deal on six concert tickets is $13.50 each, $16.50 each with the third ticket free, or $14.25 each with a 20 percent group discount.</p>
<p>Each time you answer a question correctly, you get more money to make your music video. A wrong answer costs you money, as it often does in real life. If you're stumped, there's a reference section to search for an answer. There's also a built-in calculator.</p>
<p>The motivation behind &quot;Math for the Real World&quot; is laudable because too many people are math illiterates, unable to make change without a cash register and convinced there's a difference between doubling the price of an item and increasing it by 100 percent.</p>
<p>But this CD-ROM is hampered by annoying amount of repetition.</p>
<p>The characters keep saying the same five or six things whenever a new problem is posed. At the diner, where you're supposed to match the food with the bill for each of the six band members, you hear the same annoying background laugh and the phrase &quot;Order's ready&quot; every 15 to 20 seconds.</p>
<p>As you're reading your &quot;recording contract&quot; at the beginning of the game, the humorous intercom messages quickly wear thin after you've heard each one for the fourth or fifth time.</p>
<p>When the developers go to the trouble of generating over 4,000 word problems, you would think they would put a little more effort into creating more than six ways to say: &quot;Now, here's another problem.&quot;</p>
<p>I found one annoying technical glitch: Whenever I took a break from the game and my screen saver came on, the sound on the game stopped working.</p>
<p>If &quot;Math for the Real World&quot; is going to be used in classrooms where students are required to solve the problems, it will probably be welcomed by youngsters.</p>
<p>But outside the classroom, where kids need plenty of variety and novelty to hold their interest, &quot;Math for the Real World&quot; may fall victim to the ever-shortening attention spans in the real world.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>&quot;Extreme Assault&quot; (Blue Byte, DOS/Windows95, $50) lets you pilot a 21st-century helicopter across a volcano, down tunnels inhabited by strange alien machines and across the ice fields of Greenland.</p>
<p>If plot is what you want in a game, look elsewhere. &quot;Extreme Assault&quot; is virtually a pure shoot 'em-up where just about everything you see needs to be blown up before it blows you up. The trick is to do it efficiently enough to avoid running out of ammunition. (When you destroy key targets and touch them, fresh ammo is automatically loaded onto your vehicle.)</p>
<p>Don't expect to find much logic in this game either. For example, once you get deep inside a secret alien complex, there just happens to be a state-of-the-art tank warmed up and waiting for you.</p>
<p>But people don't buy these games because they're frustrated &quot;Jeopardy&quot; contestants. They just want the thrill of blowing stuff up before their chopper or tank becomes a crematorium on wheels.</p>
<p>I ran into only one glitch with the game. When I was in DOS loading it up, the program that adjusts the sound failed to do anything. Only when I activated Windows 95 and ran the sound setup program from there did the sound setup program do its job.</p>
<p>It works on a Pentium 90, but faster machines with MMX technology or 3Dfx cards will display even better graphics.</p>
<p>With easy-to-use controls, plenty of viewpoints to watch the action, the ability to play on a network, and enough opponents to give anyone a nervous twitch, &quot;Extreme Assault&quot; will offer action junkies just what they need to keep their trigger fingers fluttering.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
