<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798002" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW-MICROSOFT SAYS APPLE TIE-UP NOT HOSTILE.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-MICROSOFT SAYS APPLE TIE-UP NOT HOSTILE.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. software giant Microsoft Corp said on Wednesday its US$150 million investment in troubled Apple Computer Inc was not a hostile move.</p>
<p>&quot;Absolutely not,&quot; Natasha Kwan, Microsoft Singapore's marketing manager told Reuters when asked if the tie-up was a hostile move or aimed at a takeover of Apple.</p>
<p>Officials also said there were no current plans to use Apple's technology on Microsoft's platform.  </p>
<p>&quot;This whole alliance, there's nothing covered on the operating system. It's about us developing applications for their platform. There's no mention of such an arrangement,&quot; Kwan said.</p>
<p>On Lee, group program manager of the desktop &amp; business systems division, conceded that while there were no current plans to use Apple's technology, Microsoft could do so in future.  </p>
<p>As part of the deal, the two companies signed a broad patent cross licensing agreement. Lee said Microsoft could use the patents to Apple's core technology for improvisation later on.</p>
<p>Analysts have said Microsoft could be eyeing Apple's software technology, including its multimedia capabilities.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point we will be glad to execute what we have announced already,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Microsoft has promised to develop major product upgrades for Apple's MacIntosh operating system for a period of five years, including its Office software for the Mac 1998 version.</p>
<p>Microsoft's Internet Explorer will become Apple's default Web browser but does not exclude use of Netscape Communications Corp's products.</p>
<p>Kwan said Microsoft was more interested in protecting its own customers who use Apple's machines.</p>
<p>Microsoft has a worldwide installed base of eight million Office suite users on the Mac platform, Kwan said.</p>
<p>She said Microsoft's investment would ensure Apple's survival and pave the way for more software sales for Microsoft.  </p>
<p>&quot;Mac users have to get out of the notion that for Apple to be successful, Microsoft has to fail. In the internet alone, we can't work alone, even Microsoft,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65) 870-3080; Fax (65) 776-8112</p>
<p>-- Email: singapore.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
