<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800722" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Elsevier,Wolters eye new electronic paths.</title>
<headline>Elsevier,Wolters eye new electronic paths.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Kelly</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two of Europe's biggest business publishers, Anglo-Dutch Reed Elsevier and Wolters Kluwer expect steady growth in electronic publishing.</p>
<p>But while Internet-based systems in particular seem to be an article of faith for Reed Elsevier, Wolters Kluwer appears to be taking a more relaxed stance.</p>
<p>Both groups provide &quot;must-have&quot; information which professionals such as lawyers, tax advisers, scientists and doctors need to do their jobs and see high-quality editorial &quot;content&quot; as their core strength.</p>
<p>Electronic publishing accounts for about a fifth of their revenues and in many respects their views on future developments in the professional publishing markets coincide.</p>
<p>But analysts who follow both companies say that when it comes to electronic publishing, there is a difference in emphasis which is explained partly by the nature of their respective markets as well as management visions of the way forward.</p>
<p>The chairman of Wolters Kluwer, Cor Brakel, recently told Reuters the Amsterdam-based company was excited about the new opportunities offered by electronic publishing but was not trying to force the pace at which new media were adopted by customers.</p>
<p>A guiding principle for Wolters Kluwer was not to invest too heavily in software development and to buy in off-the-shelf solutions wherever possible, Brakel said.</p>
<p>Reed Elsevier co-chairman Herman Bruggink said last week his company also sought to outsource software development as far as possible but had set up its own research facility in Cambridge, Massachussets in order to develop some &quot;cutting-edge, Web-based technology&quot; itself.</p>
<p>R&amp;D spending on major electronic publishing projects jumped 40 percent to 28 million pounds ($44.4 million) in the first half of 1997, according to Reed's latest first-half accounts, published last week. Also in May, the company signed a strategic agreement with Microsoft Corp on Internet-based publishing.</p>
<p>Wolters Kluwer, which absorbs development spending as part of normal operating costs, said it was continuing efforts to store its information in &quot;medium-neutral databases&quot; so that it can be distributed rapidly by any means which customers want.</p>
<p>ING Barings analyst Andre Moons said Reed Elsevier had a more ambitious strategy in electronic publishing, illustrated by its plans in Britain to combine on-line information about real estate with a facility for carrying out on-line business deals.</p>
<p>Wolters Kluwer, he said, had chosen instead to focus more on producing authoritative content, believing it would in any case have access to enough distribution channels.</p>
<p>Brakel said Wolters Kluwer had been using electronic media such as computer disks and CD-ROM since the early 1980s and had found some markets took to new media more quickly than others.</p>
<p>&quot;In Germany electronic publishing products are not really sought by the market. We tried a few times but the Germans are not interested, they love (printed) folio material,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brakel said Wolters Kluwer was currently helping some key customers hook up to the company's database and integrate its contents with their own internal information networks.</p>
<p>Analyst Jeff Meys at ABN AMRO Hoare Govett said some of Reed Elsevier's early electronic publishing ventures were reactive and often prompted by initiatives from competitors.</p>
<p>More recent projects, such as the Science Direct on-line service, showed a more pro-active approach, he said.</p>
<p>Meys said Wolters Kluwer was betting that in a world of open communications systems, or sufficiently competitive proprietary systems, it would not have to invest heavily in distribution.</p>
<p>He said this seemed a reasonably safe assumption for the time being but added: &quot;Things are changing quickly out there and you must always be ready for change.&quot;</p>
<p>Happy to use third-party distributors, Wolters Kluwer has recently been talking to competing U.S. on-line legal services operated by units of Reed Elsevier and Thomson Corp about carrying content from Wolters' tax publishing unit CCH. ($ = 0.630 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
