<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801117" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Watchdog mulls piracy charges for Singapore firm.</title>
<headline>Watchdog mulls piracy charges for Singapore firm.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Wong</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Undeterred by an adamant denial of wrongdoing, a computer industry watchdog said on Thursday it was considering pursuing criminal charges against a top Singapore firm it accuses of software piracy.</p>
<p>The Business Software Alliance (BSA), on behalf of Microsoft Corp and two other U.S. firms, accused compact disc maker SM Summit Holdings on Wednesday of being a major player in Southeast Asia's rampant software piracy market.</p>
<p>Summit angrily denied the charge, issued after a 15-hour raid on its premises by Singapore detectives and industry experts.</p>
<p>The raid was approved by the Singapore High Court after the BSA filed civil suits against Summit and another local company, FAS Disc Manufacturing (S) Pte Ltd, accusing them of piracy.</p>
<p>&quot;Both actions are connected to CD-ROM manufacture, illegal CD-ROM manufacture,&quot; BSA's regional lawyer, Lee Cross said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On Thursday, she told Reuters the BSA might take the fight with Summit a step further.</p>
<p>&quot;We filed this civil law suit and we need to look at the evidence and assess whether or not we would make (an) application to commence criminal proceedings. That would be our next step,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>FAS officials said the company would have no comment on the charges against it until managing director Freddy Sim returned from an overseas trip.</p>
<p>The BSA was jubilant on Wednesday after the raid, during which the police and experts took away potential evidence.</p>
<p>&quot;The pirate CD-ROM industry could come to a grinding halt in Southeast Asia following a significant raid on the CD-ROM manufacturing operations of Singapore-listed SM Summit Holdings,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>SM Summit was outraged, saying its security procedures ruled out piracy.</p>
<p>&quot;Irreparable damage has been done to the company and its business as a consequence of the BSA action,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a public listed company, the company is fully apprised of its responsibility to its shareholders and employees and will take all necessary steps to guard their interests,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We've not been served with any writs, summons, just a press release where we are already convicted of software piracy,&quot; director K.K. Teo said.</p>
<p>Cross declined comment on Summit's denial.</p>
<p>A Summit lawyer said the company went to court on Wednesday seeking clarification on the search warrant granted to the BSA. He said Summit believed there was some irregularity in how the search warrant was obtained, but declined further comment.</p>
<p>Asked about Summit's complaints and whether this could throw out evidence on technicalities, Lee said: &quot;There has been no formal application by them to do that.&quot;</p>
<p>Lawyers for Summit could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Summit, listed on the second board of the Stock Exchange of Singapore (SES) is primarily a compact music disc maker. About 20 percent of its business is in CD-ROM manufacture for the computer industry.</p>
<p>The BSA charges led to a drop in Summit shares of nearly 38 percent to S$0.655 on Wednesday and a trading suspension. Summit asked for the suspension to be lifted on Thursday morning and is shares rallied 9.5 cents to S$0.75.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
