<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804468" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Say it ain't so, readers.</title>
<headline>Say it ain't so, readers.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prescription for fun: write a column with the words &quot;Apple&quot; and &quot;woes&quot; in a single sentence and then compose another one with the words &quot;Microsoft&quot; and &quot;winner&quot; together.</p>
<p>For an extra measure of foolhardiness add your e-mail address below the piece.</p>
<p>Your correspondent wrote such a column last week on the outlook for Apple Computer Inc. following its $150 million deal with Microsoft Corp. And the replies were, well, animated.</p>
<p>In fact one could say the responses made you feel a bit like a slab of meat that had been struck by a lighting after being burnt to a crisp on a scorching barbecue -- you can read flamed here.</p>
<p>From the responses, however, it was abundantly clear that Apple as well as Microsoft elicit emotions that few other companies in the Silicon world come close to mustering. People have passionate and, quite often, intelligent, views on where those two companies are now heading.</p>
<p>People lined up on both sides of the issue on the column's lament that Apple's traditional role as the technological leader was in question.</p>
<p>A paragraph from the column read:  &quot;Microsoft of course was the ultimate winner as it steadily if not spectacularly closed the once-glorious gap enjoyed by Apple in software.</p>
<p>But even with all the improvements in the Windows platform, there has always been the feeling that Apple and its khaki clad engineers (sans pocket protectors) were always a few steps ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Steve&quot; from somewhere out in cyberspace wrote: &quot;I read your piece that, like so many others, predicts the demise of Apple. Unfortunately, you're a week or so behind the rest of the sheep in the press. Apple still makes a better operating system than Microsoft. Windows 95 was released two years ago, and in spite of what I see in the papers, it hasn't got any better than when it was first released.&quot;</p>
<p>A &quot;gwbaker&quot; threw cold water on the idea of calling the $150 million deal a bailout and maintained Apple would not have much trouble keeping ahead of those good people in Redmond, Washington. &quot;By the way, when was the last innovation we ever wanted to even look at from Microsoft?&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>But &quot;Paul,&quot; who said he was a scientist and an early &quot;embracer&quot; and &quot;rejecter&quot; of DOS systems, begged to differ: &quot;I personally hope that Gates will buy out Apple. This will allow him to do what he has always craved -- throw out the rickety Windows system and adopt the Mac OS without fear of patent infringement.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Eugene&quot; also seemed to be giving in to a world without Apple: &quot;Too many seem blind to the fact that while Apple's many efforts were flawed, they were flawed because they were ground-breaking. I almost wish they would give up -- so history might start remembering them as the true father of the information age.&quot;</p>
<p>There was also much fear and loathing about life without Apple. Readers, calling your correspondent a &quot;creep&quot; and a &quot;jerk&quot; and even &quot;not cool&quot; (now c'mon!) saw a world without choice where mediocrity would rule under the guidance of Microsoft and its subsidiaries.</p>
<p>&quot;I fear Bill Gates has an ulterior motive, and with his foot in the door, he is looking at Apple as a take-over candidate. And when he takes over, good bye to the Apple OS,&quot; wrote &quot;Lee&quot; from Texas.</p>
<p>&quot;Samo&quot; left one of the more creative e-mails. It was a digital picture showing a scene from Apple's now famous &quot;1984&quot; commercial with a bunch of people looking up at a screen at a dictator and another picture from this year's MacWorld showing a bunch of people looking up at the screen at Microsoft CEO Bill Gates.</p>
<p>Underneath there was a caption from George Orwell's &quot;1984&quot; novel: &quot;He gazed up at the enormous face. But it was all right. Everything was all right, the struggle was finished. He had won the victory against himself. He loved Big Brother.&quot;</p>
<p>(For ideas or comments on the weekly Plugged In column contact: russell.blinch@reuters.com.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
