<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805659" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Progressive Networks subpoenaed in Microsoft probe.</title>
<headline>Progressive Networks subpoenaed in Microsoft probe.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Progressive Networks Inc said Monday it has been subpoenaed in the U.S. Justice Department's antitrust investigation of Microsoft Corp's purchases in the video streaming market.</p>
<p>&quot;Progressive Networks is one of several companies that have been subpoenaed by the Department of Justice for its records related to streaming media and Microsoft,&quot; said Bruce Jacobsen, president of Progressive Networks.  </p>
<p>Jacobsen said the subpoena, served on August 8, was part of an investigation into activities related to &quot;horizontal merger, monopolization of audio and video streaming software.&quot; He said his company would cooperate with the probe.</p>
<p>Earlier, the Department of Justice said it was reviewing Microsoft's acquisition of VXtreme Inc, a Silicon Valley developer of technology for sending audio and video over the Internet, as well as an earlier deal to buy a 10 percent stake Progressive Networks, in a plan aimed at unifying standards for delivering audio and video.  </p>
<p>Also under investigation is Microsoft's investment in VDOnet, the developer of a technology that overcomes key limitations on Internet communications, as well as Microsoft's $150 million investment in former archrival Apple Computer Inc.</p>
<p>Progressive Networks is the maker of RealAudio and RealVideo software, which enable Internet users to listen to sounds and watch video live on the Internet. Streaming technology allows users to listen and watch live material without the option of downloading the files.  </p>
<p>The technology is particularly useful to recording companies and movie studios that want to preview teasers and promotions on the Internet without compromising copyrights.</p>
<p>While VXtreme and VDOnet are both fledgling development companies, Progressive Networks is well known on the Internet with its RealAudio and RealVideo software incorporated into most multimedia sites on the World Wide Web.</p>
<p>Microsoft spokesman Mark Murray said it should not be presumed that there were anti-trust problems just because the Department of Justice was investigating.</p>
<p>&quot;There is intense competition in streaming media technology,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Murray said there were many start-up companies developing streaming technology, as well as large companies such as Oracle Corp, International Business Machines Corp and Sun Microsystems.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident that the Justice Department, once they have reviewed the situation, will agree that all this competition is good for consumers,&quot; Murray said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
