<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805657" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ross Systems sees Q4 net loss.</title>
<headline>Ross Systems sees Q4 net loss.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ross Systems Inc said Monday that its fourth quarter revenues should come in higher than they have in the past four years, but will still fall short of their planned levels for the period.</p>
<p>The company also said it expects to post a net loss for the period of between $2.5 million and $3 million.</p>
<p>Revenues for the quarter ended June 30 are expected to come in at more than $23 million, the company said.  </p>
<p>However, that level is below the company's expectations largely because of a delay in recognition of an agreement with a multi-national German concern. The delay was due to certain contingencies, which were not completed until after the quarter end, Ross Systems said.</p>
<p>The company said it is adjusting its accounts receivable allowances and will also accrue special charges regarding a dispute with its insurer over a settled customer matter.</p>
<p>Results for the fourth quarter are expected to be released on Thursday.  </p>
<p>In the prior year's fourth quarter, the company reported net income of $1.5 million, or $0.09 per share, on revenues of $19.5 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The combination of a previously announced $2.5 million Japanese agreement and the German contract will benefit our historically weak first quarter,&quot; Chief Financial Officer Stan Stoudenmire said in a news release. &quot;Our sales activity continues to be strong and we are beginning to see a greater number of larger deal opportunities. Though the nature of these larger agreements may cause certain revenue deferrals, over the contract term, these factors should help improve the company's earnings consistency.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
