<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808999" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bay Networks seeing broad sales strength - CFO.</title>
<headline>Bay Networks seeing broad sales strength - CFO.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Halfway through its first quarter, Bay Networks Inc is seeing strong sales across its product lines and a solid pricing environment, the company's chief financial officer said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength is quite broad based,&quot; chief financial officer David Rynne said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have some products in the switching area that are doing particularly well,&quot; he said. &quot;Last quarter we did better in shared media than we had expected going into the quarter and that seems to be continuing, and we're doing fine in routing and remote access as well.&quot;  </p>
<p>Thus far, Rynne said, the strong sales are translating into better than expected bottom line performance, as pricing and expense levels are running consistent with expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;Really nothing changed in that regard, we don't see the pricing environment changing from what the expectation was or our spending environment changing,&quot; he said. &quot;We may, in fact, have a slightly more favorable tax rate.&quot;</p>
<p>The continued strength in Bay's shared media product line is a pleasant surprise, he said, but one the company does not expect to last. More sustainable are the sales of newer switching products, which also are outpacing forecasts.  </p>
<p>Previously, the company had expected it would take until the December quarter of this year for switching products revenue to grow fast enough to do anything more than offset the anticipated decline in revenues from shared media products, a shrinking market.</p>
<p>Rynne noted the BayStack 350 switch, a newer product, was &quot;selling extremely well,&quot; prompting the company to raise production targets twice already this quarter.</p>
<p>The early success is not leading the company to modify guidance for the full year yet, however.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope it's fundamental but it's too early to call,&quot; he said. &quot;It's just seven weeks into a new year, so I don't think we should radically change the plan for the next 45 weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>At least one Wall Street firm has done so, however. Salomon Brothers upgraded Bay Networks to buy from hold, citing the company's sales momentum.</p>
<p>Salomon analyst Peter Swartz also raised his earnings estimates by $0.10 per share for each of the next two years, to $1.00 in fiscal 1998 and $1.45 in 1999.</p>
<p>Shares in Bay Networks rose 2-11/16 to 36-11/16 and were the New York Stock Exchange's most active issue at midday.</p>
<p>((-- R. Melville, Wall Street desk, 212-859-1731))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
