<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810776" id="root" date="1997-08-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Creative sees audio sales rise.</title>
<headline>Creative sees audio sales rise.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Multimedia company Creative Technology Ltd said on Saturday it saw revenue from its audio products continuing to grow.</p>
<p>&quot;Our audio revenue has been growing from about over 30 percent to right now over 50 percent. We see this trend will still be able to continue,&quot; Sim Wong Hoo, Creative's chairman said at a news briefing.</p>
<p>Creative is known for its SoundBlaster range of sound cards.</p>
<p>Sim, who is also chief executive officer, said Creative had taken the lead, set new standards and broke new grounds in all five generations of its products since the first 8-bit soundcard in 1991.</p>
<p>Its latest AWE64 soundcard was Creative's largest revenue generator in its fourth quarter ended June 30, 1997. For that quarter it recorded earnings of US$51.2 million on sales of $280 million.</p>
<p>For the full year ended June 30, 1997, it posted record net profit of $167 million on sales of $1.23 billion.</p>
<p>Audio products made up 56 percent of revenue for 1996/1997, upgrade kits 34 percent and 10 percent came from other products.</p>
<p>Sim said Creative aimed to replace the 40 million installed base of sound cards and 20 million of clone cards with its AWE64 in 1997-1999.</p>
<p>Going forward, Creative is working on an &quot;environmental&quot; sound chip which all enable users to hear authentic sounds from instruments played on World music.</p>
<p>It was looking to the original equipment market (OEM) moving towards audio products based on the latest PCI bus standards in the first half of 1998.</p>
<p>Creative is selling its Emu8008 PCI sound chip that goes on a motherboard to OEMs.</p>
<p>Another area Creative was pushing aggressively into was in DVD (digital video disk).</p>
<p>Creative last week launched it next generation PC-DVD kit which includes a decoder card and high performance DVD ROM drive for US$379.99.</p>
<p>Sim said the focal point this Christmas would be on DVD where the company would first focus on the U.S. market.</p>
<p>The company expects unit sales in its PC-DVD kit to reach six-digit this Christmas, he said.</p>
<p>He believed DVD drives would replace CD-ROM drives by the end of 1998.</p>
<p>On its geographical markets, vice president Michael Sulllican said Europe would be a challenge in the first quarter but was expected to pick up later on.</p>
<p>He said Creative would be introducing a programme in Europe in October to encourage users to upgrade their old sound cards to the new AWE64.</p>
<p>He said Creative had substantial market share in Europe ranging from more then 60 percent in Germany and France and exceeding 90 percent for some countries.</p>
<p>Creative has said when it released its fourth quarter results that it expected the first quarter to be flat.</p>
<p>But for the full year 1997/1998 it expected to achieve its projected 10-15 percent revenue growth and gross margins of 30 percent.</p>
<p>On plans for its cash of $417.9 million, Sim said the company was looking at making more strategic acquisitions.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
