<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82478" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Advertisers try to reach Europe's Internet users.</title>
<headline>Advertisers try to reach Europe's Internet users.</headline>
<byline>Kathleen Callo</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Corporations and advertising agencies are frantically trying to figure out how best to reach Europe's growing number of Internet users, ignoring the few who continue to question its value as an advertising medium.</p>
<p>Speakers at a European advertising conference in Rome said the Internet -- which basically enables anyone with a computer, telephone and modem to reach consumers around the world -- would reshape the marketing business.</p>
<p>&quot;The number of Europe's Internet users is growing,&quot; Paolo Guadagni, marketing director for Microsoft in Italy, said.</p>
<p>Until recently, users in the United States accounted for 80 percent of the world's 48 million Internet users, but that has shrunk to 73.4 percent, while 10.8 percent are now in Europe and 8.4 percent are in Canada and Mexico</p>
<p>Guadagni told the annual conference of the European Association of Advertising Agencies (EAAA) which ended on Thursday that the number of Internet users was doubling each year. It now included 30 million people who used the World Wide Web, the graphics-linked part of the Internet, he added.</p>
<p>Guadagni said $45 million had been spent on advertising on the Web -- a small amount compared with television and print advertising, but one that represented rapid growth since the first ad in cyberspace in 1994.</p>
<p>The Web's top 10 advertisers account for 27 percent of all ads on the new medium and are predominantly computer software companies, he said.</p>
<p>A mere 10 Websites are now getting 63.6 percent of all advertising expenditure on the Web, he said. These include Infoseek, Lycos, Yahoo! and Netscape, software companies that all help users navigate around the Web.</p>
<p>But many other kinds of companies are testing out marketing their goods and services on the Internet, including carmakers.</p>
<p>Generals Motors, Ford, Mercedes and some Japanese manufacturers are investing a lot of money in advertising on the Internet, Guadagni told the conference, which grouped advertising agencies and trade bodies from 24 countries.</p>
<p>Mercedes launched a Website four months ago that allows users, through graphics and virtual reality, to enter and &quot;look around&quot; the inside of the latest car model.</p>
<p>But executives from Italian media groups urged delegates at the EAAA conference to keep spending money on television advertising, rather than get excited about the still largely untried world of the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not believe it (the Internet) is the Holy Grail,&quot; Robert Hersov, managing director of Telepiu, the Italian pay-TV group, said.</p>
<p>He said Telepiu, which now has three analogue terrestrial channels, expected -- by moving to digital satellite delivery -- to have 60 to 80 channels by September 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This IS the Holy Grail&quot; for advertisers, Hersov said.</p>
<p>Carlo Momigliano, vice director general of Publitalia, said past forecasts for the growth of Internet users had proven over optimistic.</p>
<p>Publitalia is the &quot;media seller&quot; -- or company that sells advertising space -- for Mediaset, the Italian commercial television group controlled by former Italian prime minister Silvio Berlusconi.</p>
<p>Momigliano told the conference advertisers were also better off reaching consumers through television ads since the average TV viewer was older and had more money than the mostly young people who use the Internet.</p>
<p>Bernardo Notarangelo, special events manager at SIPRA, the media seller for RAI, Italy's state-owned television network, said the Internet was awkward for advertisers because no-one knew how much money was being spent on ads, Websites or Web-based consumer purchases.</p>
<p>&quot;It's mumbo-jumbo economics,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
