<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83559" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IPO VIEW - Advanced Fibre a favorite in calmer week.</title>
<headline>IPO VIEW - Advanced Fibre a favorite in calmer week.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Initial public offerings will flood the U.S. stock market again this week, but the pace should let up slightly after last week's tsunami.</p>
<p>&quot;I've never seen such strong demand from institutional investors, it's just astounding,&quot; said one syndicate manager, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>About thirty companies are scheduled to go public this week, with Advanced Fibre Communications Inc, Dover Downs Entertainment Inc, and Storm Primax Inc vying for the highest initial premiums.  </p>
<p>A slim window of opportunity has opened up in the IPO market. Many of the deals coming to the market this week were prepared weeks ago, when the broader stock market was lower. As a result, their shares were given lower price tags. Since the Dow and Nasdaq have begun reaching back into record territories, many of these stocks now look like bargains.</p>
<p>IPO Aftermarket editor John Fitzgibbon said, &quot;It's a shark frenzy,&quot; after a wave of new issues were snapped up last week, including retailer Abercrombie &amp; Fitch, Cox Radio Inc and Spanish language TV broadcaster Univision Communications.  </p>
<p>Strong cash inflows into mutual funds as well as &quot;window dressing&quot; by money managers, seeking a more fully-invested position in their portfolios to be presented to clients before the close of the third quarter have also cascaded to boost initial public offerings.</p>
<p>&quot;Advanced Fibre could be the screamer of the week,&quot; said Fitzgibbon. The company has pioneered devices allowing phone companies to operate smoothly over the incompatible copper wire, fiber optic and coaxioal cable systems.</p>
<p>The company became profitable in 1995 and has some large customers, including the seven Baby Bells.  </p>
<p>Advanced Fibre seems to have sensed the strong demand in the works for its IPO -- it raised the stakes on Friday to a gross of almost $100 million. It originally filed for an offering of about $56 million.</p>
<p>Storm Primax Inc should also attract buyers. The Sunnyvale California company makes an &quot;easyPhoto&quot; software that allows consumers and small businesses to store and use photos easily on their personal computers.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be a bit slower (this week),&quot; said David Menlow, of the IPO Aftermarket.  </p>
<p>&quot;Underwriters, who were licking their wounds during the third quarter because of the downward revisions, got a small window of opportunity to stay with the ranges they established when they filed the deals. With the market looking robust, there will be more and more upward revisions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Also expected to be hot are Cornell Corrections, Advanced Health Corp, Donnelly Enterprises, Pegasus Communications Corp and Select Software Inc.  </p>
<p>A sports trading card company is also going public -- Pinnacle Brands Inc plans to offer four million shares, or a one-third stake, in an offering by Merrill Lynch &amp; Co.</p>
<p>It has posted losses since 1993 and said baseball and hockey card sales have not yet recovered from a slump suffered after the 1994 Major League Baseball strike and work stoppage at the National Hockey League.</p>
<p>Ingram Micro Inc, the $8 billion computer reseller, had its initial public offering delayed from this week to late October, pending a tax ruling on its split-off from its parent company.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
