<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84263" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Disney sees more 'edutainment'.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Disney sees more 'edutainment'.</headline>
<byline>Julie Vorman</byline>
<dateline>LAKE BUENA VISTA, Fla 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Walt Disney Co's Interactive unit aims to roll out up to 15 new computer &quot;edutainment&quot; titles in 1997 for children and is looking at ways to modify some products for school classroom use, a Disney marketing executive said.</p>
<p>&quot;The demographics of Walt Disney World visitors match up nicely with the demographics of computer users,&quot; Mark Greenberg, marketing director for Disney Interactive, told Reuters in an interview.  </p>
<p>Computer use is growing fastest in the U.S. middle-class and affluent homes with children, the same general group to which Disney markets its theme parks, resorts and other entertainment. The edutainment segment of the software market offers products to help primary school children practice reading, writing and math skills using games, puzzles and other fun approaches.</p>
<p>Until Disney jumped into the interactive computer software market two years ago with its &quot;Lion King Activity Center&quot; software, sales of about 40,000 units was considered a top- selling title for an education product.  </p>
<p>But each title that Disney has rolled out has become a best-seller, typically selling &quot;hundreds of thousands&quot; of units, Greenberg said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Disney Interactive edutainment division plans to have 10 to 15 new products next year,&quot; he said, declining to estimate the revenue targets for the new software titles.</p>
<p>The company is also beginning to modify some of its existing titles for use in the classroom.</p>
<p>According to PC Data, a research firm that tracks software sales, Disney ranks third in education software market share for the past 12 months, but is moving up quickly.  </p>
<p>&quot;Disney is not going away. They have four of the top five education products of the 12-month period ending in August,&quot; said Nicole Brzeski of PC Data. &quot;Branding is becoming more important and everyone knows Winnie the Pooh and Lion King. Disney has all the marketing, sales and distribution tools to compete aggressively.&quot;</p>
<p>Two smaller firms, Softkey and CUC Software, currently rank first and second in market share for education software, she said. Softkey held 22 percent of the market with retail sales totaling $106.5 million during the past 12 months and a popular title named &quot;Reader Rabbit,&quot; Brzeski said.  </p>
<p>CUC Software ranked second with 20 percent of market share and $54.8 million in sales and its most popular product is &quot;Mathblaster.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Disney is the brand name that parents know and trust,&quot; Greenberg said. &quot;Everything else for sale out there is pretty much done by small companies which are unknown to parents.</p>
<p>&quot;We're now working on a product for the early learner aged three to five and something for older pre-teen kids next year.&quot;  </p>
<p>Disney Interactive last week also launched its first software program designed to help families plan a trip to the growing number of attractions at Walt Disney World, the 28,000 acre complex in central Florida now marking its 25th anniversary.</p>
<p>The &quot;Walt Disney World Explorer&quot; includes videotape and sound of founder Walt Disney describing his vision for a theme park in Florida, lets users experiment with their own sound effects for animated films and gives a tour of the scariest rides at the parks. The software retails for $35.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect six-figure sales for this product,&quot; Greenberg said. &quot;This is both a great souvenir from a vacation, or a reference tool in helping families prioritize and plan what to see on vacation.&quot;</p>
<p>In November, Disney Interactive plans to roll out electronic storybooks tied to the movies, &quot;Hunchback of Notre Dame&quot; and &quot;101 Dalmatians.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is a new way for kids to play with their favorite characters,&quot; he said. &quot;One mother told us that her son played with the 'Lion King Activity Center' for 10 hours on the day after Christmas.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAKE BUENA VISTA, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
