<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85078" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan enters the age of multichannel satellite TV.</title>
<headline>Japan enters the age of multichannel satellite TV.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>PerfecTV, set to start Japan's first multi-channel digital satellite broadcasting service, said on Monday it hopes to acquire one million subscribers by next summer, when the entry of rivals will intensify competition.</p>
<p>&quot;Our strategy is to acquire as many subscribers as possible by the time our two rivals launch their services next summer,&quot; PerfecTV president Hiroto Kasahara told a news conference.</p>
<p>PerfecTV, owned by a consortium headed by trading company Itochu Corp, will launch a 57-channel paid service on Tuesday beamed directly via the JCSAT-3 communications satellite. The number of channels will be raised to 70 by December and to 110 next year.</p>
<p>The basic monthly fee is set at 2,900 yen ($26).</p>
<p>The company will be followed by a 150-channel service called J-SkyB, to be launched by Australian media tycoon Rupert Murdoch's News Corp and Japan's Softbank Corp, and a 100-channel service by DirecTV, planned by a unit of Hughes Electronics Corp of the United States.</p>
<p>Compression of data achieved with digital technology allows for far more information to be broadcast than with conventional analog systems.</p>
<p>Kasahara said 20,000 individual subscribers have already signed up for PerfecTV.</p>
<p>&quot;Because there are so many inquiries on the new service, we haven't been able to cope appropriately,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kasahara said there was a possibility the company would go ahead with a proposed tie-up with J-SkyB which would give its viewers access to J-SkyB programmes through a single receiver and dish.</p>
<p>&quot;I have always said it would be a lot more convenient to Japanese viewers if the three service providers use a single decoder and dish,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>PerfecTV may start selling decoders which also allow access to J-SkyB next year, he said. A dish and decoder together currently cost about 50,000 yen ($450).</p>
<p>The launching of digital satellite broadcasting in Japan is expected to spawn a host of related products and create a huge sales opportunity for the nation's top electronics manufacturers</p>
<p>Analysts expect the market for dishes and decoders alone to exceed 70 billion yen ($630 million) within the next few years.</p>
<p>Some analysts say demand will increase further after PerfecTV starts data transmission services using communications satellites, which would allow its subscribers fast access to computer data through their decoders.</p>
<p>PerfecTV has said it plans to start satellite data transmission services within a few years. ($1=111 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
