<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="86487" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Mass market for computers promises turmoil.</title>
<headline>Mass market for computers promises turmoil.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>Two airline pilots are peering complacently out of the cockpit on yet another uneventful flight through the clouds.</p>
<p>One pilot spots an animal and says calmly: &quot;I didn't know mountain goats lived in clouds&quot;.</p>
<p>Frank Gens, senior vice-president of International Data Corp, uses this scenario in a speech to illustrate that unexpected disasters can suddenly loom up and destroy companies in the fast moving world of information technology.</p>
<p>And, according to Gens, there are shocks in store for anyone who feels that recent upheavals mean they can now relax and familiarise themselves with the new ways at their leisure.</p>
<p>Apparently, you ain't seen nothing yet.</p>
<p>&quot;The Internet is triggering revolution, not evolution in the IT marketplace,&quot; Gens told a conference in Paris sponsored by IDC, the U.S. information technology consultancy and publisher.</p>
<p>And new technologies will be triggered by consumers in the coming mass market for devices that will pave the way to the information society.</p>
<p>&quot;The business IT market will be transformed by the massive scale of the consumer market,&quot; Gens said.</p>
<p>IDC says that so far computers have succeeded in two stages.</p>
<p>In the 1970s, company back-offices were automated, mainly with mainframe computers. The second phase, from the 80s until now, saw the computerisation of front-offices, with point-of-sale equipment and mobile lap-top personal computers.</p>
<p>In the third phase, computing devices will enter every home leading to an explosion of high street buying. The information society will have arrived.</p>
<p>According to IDC, by 2000 there will be 160 million people surfing the Internet, the world-wide network of computers linked across telephone lines. In 1996 there are about 35 million Internet users, more than double the previous year's 16 million.</p>
<p>By the end of the century, computers will have ceased to be opaque, unreliable and expensive. Like the telephone, they will be turned off and on instinctively. Households will use enormous computing power without realising it.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it (the computer) is going to be a typical household appliance. All over the house things will be connected. It will make people's home lives much more efficient and easy,&quot; said computing guru Esther Dyson.</p>
<p>Dyson was speaking by telephone while on a trip to Prague.</p>
<p>&quot;You will use E (electronic) mail to do business and for your personal life. You will find out what's on sale at Harrods, what's for lunch at the local restaurant; it doesn't seem revolutionary, it may seem trivial, but it adds up to what people control,&quot; said Dyson, who publishes the U.S. based &quot;Esther Dyson's Monthly Report&quot;.</p>
<p>This belief that the mass market is dawning has set up a desperate race among the world's high technology companies.</p>
<p>They want to be the winners in the struggle to provide cheap and easy-to-use gadgets. Some see a chance to knock over current winners in the personal computer world, like Microsoft, the aggressive U.S.-based software giant.</p>
<p>Not all industry experts are convinced that ordinary consumers will be beating a path to the computer store.</p>
<p>&quot;People who work with computers, they've taken them into their home lives. But those not exposed to the technology, even if they've got the money are not likely to want to get involved,&quot; said Graham Taylor, senior vice-president at high technology consultancy Inteco.</p>
<p>But people could find themselves surfing the net without realising. Televisions will effectively become personal computers by linking them to set-top boxes, or incorporating microprocessors into their design.</p>
<p>&quot;For example, a mobile phone with a little processor inside would let you automatically dial up the cricket scores, share prices, your bank balance. Data would be coming from a web site, but you wouldn't know this,&quot; said Taylor.</p>
<p>The struggle to find the fast lane to the information superhighway is widening to include television, telephone, as well as information technology companies.</p>
<p>Satellite television's BSkyB, 40 percent owned by Rupert Murdoch's News Corp, has said it will offer Internet connections when it starts a digital television service next year.</p>
<p>But currently the inside track is held by the so-called network computer.</p>
<p>Proselytiser-in-chief for the Network Computer is serial Microsoft baiter Larry Ellison, chairman and chief executive officer of database leader Oracle Corp of the U.S.</p>
<p>Oracle's Network Computer is a stripped down version of the personal computer. Costing about $500 compared with upwards of $2,000 for a PC, the Network Computer dials up processing power every time it is used.</p>
<p>Ellison has said that the PC is ridiculously over-powered and over priced. Why pay for power and storage space you are never going to use, when you can dial up just the required brawn and brain power for each use?</p>
<p>Oracle is only just beginning to sell these devices, initially aimed at businesses which are more likely to have the required high-quality telephone lines.</p>
<p>Microsoft has made wrong turns before and come storming back to mangle the competition.</p>
<p>&quot;(Microsoft chairman) Mr (Bill) Gates is not going to lie still and let the Network Computer happen. They will be major players in all this,&quot; said Inteco's Taylor.</p>
<p>But all these devices, however clever, and even if given away, will not succeed unless the services offered are exciting.</p>
<p>&quot;Content will be a big driver in all of these services. If there's stuff people want they will seek it out. But if it is just a mish-mash without any particular context, that will limit the appeal to the mass market,&quot; said David Tee, senior industry analyst at consultants SRI International.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
