<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87437" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Eagle sees Q1 below $0.08/shr estimates.</title>
<headline>Eagle sees Q1 below $0.08/shr estimates.</headline>
<dateline>DUBUQUE, Iowa 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eagle Point Software Corp said Tuesday it expects earnings for its fiscal quarter ended September 30, 1996 to be below analysts' estimates of $0.08 a share.</p>
<p>During the first quarter, Eagle Point said it incurred a one-time charge of about $475,000 for purchased research and development relating to the acquisition of Computer Integrated Building Corp.</p>
<p>Excluding this one-time charge, Eagle Point said it expects the first quarter will show a modest profit but be below the current analysts' estimates of $0.08 a share.  </p>
<p>Eagle Point, which supplies software for graphic design for architectural engineering and construction markets, said sluggish industry conditions persist.</p>
<p>&quot;Our current expectations for this quarter reflect a continuation of the same market conditions that we've previously reported; namely a continued softness in the AutoCAD and AutoCAD-related markets as well as delays in customer purchases of AutoCAD and Eagle Point software as customers continue to invest in the upgrading of their hardware/software from DOS to Windows,&quot; said Rod Blum, chief executive officer, in a statement.  </p>
<p>Based on these market conditions, Eagle Point said it continues to take steps to control operating expenses. The company anticipates that operating expenses for the first quarter to be lower than the pervious quarter and in line with its expectations.</p>
<p>Eagle Point also said fiscal first quarter revenues would fall below analysts estimates of $4.9 million to $5.0 million.</p>
<p>In last year's fiscal first quarter, the company earned $0.14 a share on revenues of $4.8 million.</p>
<p>Eagle Point said that results for its fiscal first quarter are not final. In addition, the company noted that in recent years, a significant portion of its revenues in any quarter, and an even greater portion of its net profit in the quarter, have been generated during the last week of the quarter.</p>
<p>Shares of Eagle Point are trading off 3/4 to 4-1/2.</p>
<p>	     Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBUQUE, Iowa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
