<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90301" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Macromedia targets top-line growth.</title>
<headline>Macromedia targets top-line growth.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Macromedia Inc Chairman and Chief Executive Bud Cololigan said the company is making investments to produce revenue growth in the fast-growing multimedia market its top priority.</p>
<p>&quot;We will put our emphasis on getting our top-line growth rate higher, and because we're in a market that is very dynamic and growing very fast and the opportunity is there, we just need to get our top-line growth rate growing at a faster rate,&quot; he told Reuters after a presentation to investors.</p>
<p>&quot;The profits will take care of themselves, if that happens,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Colligan declined to comment on the company's results in its second fiscal quarter just ended, or on full-year analysts' estimates, noting the company is in its quiet period.</p>
<p>Macromedia shares slid early last month after Colligan said in a meeting with analysts on September 4 the company expected quarterly earnings to be flat to 10 percent below prior year levels.  </p>
<p>As of Monday, analysts' consensus estimates for the company were for earnings per share of $0.14 in a range of $0.12 to $0.18, compared with the prior-year level of $0.16 a share, according to First Call.</p>
<p>&quot;What I said on September 4 I think is good guidance,&quot; he said.  &quot;That's the range that we discussed, however they interpreted that,&quot; he said of the month-ago meeting.</p>
<p>Earlier, Colligan told analysts the company was seeing sales of its products for use on Microsoft Corp's Windows platform increase as a portion of total sales, taking share away from Apple Computer Inc's Macintosh.  </p>
<p>Analysts expect sales of Macromedia products for Windows to account for nearly two-thirds of its total sales, a reversal of the share in recent quarters as some multimedia developers move away from their traditional Mac systems.</p>
<p>&quot;As of the June quarter, our Windows business was up over 100 percent, our Mac business was up 21 percent,&quot; he noted.</p>
<p>Colligan said that while the Macintosh business seemed to have stabilized in the July and August period, this was not generally representative of the full quarter, as data was still coming in on September, a crucial sales month.</p>
<p>&quot;I would withhold comment until we release results on October 17,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Macromedia has been among a number of companies whose products run on Apple Macintosh machines which analysts have seen hurt by the troubles at Apple Computer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
