<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90362" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Summit Medical plunges on earnings view.</title>
<headline>Summit Medical plunges on earnings view.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Summit Medical Systems Inc fell 5-15/16 to 6-13/16 on heavy trading volume after the company said future earnings and revenues were expected to be well short of Wall Street analysts' estimates.</p>
<p>&quot;A couple of large contracts slipped and there was an indirect sales shortfall, combined with a change in the way they're going to be recognizing revenues,&quot; said Volpe Welty health information systems analyst Chris Paul.</p>
<p>&quot;These point to execution errors on the part of management, although management remains confident about the company's long-term future,&quot; Paul said.  </p>
<p>The company is moving from licensing its medical outcomes database systems perpetually to annual licensing, a revenue recognition format that is more predictable, Paul said.</p>
<p>The company could not immediately be reached for comment.</p>
<p>In a press release, Summit said it was in a transition from &quot;a system software sale model to a Continuous Quality Service program.&quot;</p>
<p>Summit chief executive Kevin Green said, &quot;Entering the third quarter, we felt we were on the right track with our CQS methodology and underlying technology and early indications continue to support these assumptions.&quot;  </p>
<p>He added, &quot;We assumed, however, that we could phase in the CQS program throughout 1997.  We now realize that in order for us to effect the changes necessary in our business approach and to properly address the market needs we must accelerate our efforts and move quickly away from a software sale approach.&quot;</p>
<p>The company has told analysts it now expects a loss of $0.03-$0.05 per share for the third quarter on revenues of about $4.1 million, analysts said.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected a third-quarter profit of about $0.07 per share.</p>
<p>--K. Drawbaugh 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
