<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91242" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Poor instructions, ending, mar fine dinosaur adventure.</title>
<headline>Poor instructions, ending, mar fine dinosaur adventure.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I. 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Time Blazers: Devils Canyon&quot; (TeraMedia, Windows/Macintosh, $45) gives players a taste of what it's like to really study dinosaurs. And sometimes, as you'll discover, it's not all fun and games.</p>
<p>Developed in conjunction with top dinosaur experts, &quot;Devils Canyon&quot; begins with the player stranded in the midday desert. The glint of metal in the distance leads to a robotic dinosaur. Climb inside and the &quot;Cyberaptor&quot; carries you (with the gut-wrenching motion of the real thing) into an underground complex.</p>
<p>At that point, you discover that the scientist who created the robot, Marshall Cope, used the Cyberaptor to go back in time to the age of the dinosaurs. But something went wrong. A malfunction in the robot made it impossible to return, so it has stayed there undisturbed for more than 65 million years.</p>
<p>Your job is to reprogram the Cyberaptor so it can send you into the past and recover the scientist.</p>
<p>It's that reprogramming progress that offers new insight into dinosaurs and how scientists have developed their knowledge about these extraordinary creatures.</p>
<p>You'll learn about the types of rocks most likely to contain fossils, how they're dug from bedrock, how they're cleaned, and how the dinosaurs moved, looked and ate. There's even a great section on the sounds they made. The contribution of four real scientists gives &quot;Devils Canyon&quot; an extra aura of authenticity.</p>
<p>Adding to the fun is the excellent music, great graphics and interesting puzzles related to the subject matter.</p>
<p>But &quot;Devils Canyon&quot; may try your patience because there are too many places where the directions aren't clear.</p>
<p>The problems begin in Sector One, where I was told to fire five probes into the terrain. When my first one landed in sedimentary mudstone, the game told me I had chosen the best place to find fossils. So I fired the other four missiles in that layer as well.</p>
<p>Wrong. What the game doesn't tell you is that it wants you to fire each probe into a different rock type so one of the scientists can explain why the others are less likely to contain fossils.</p>
<p>With the next task of digging a fossil out of the mudstone, excavator Jim Kirkland told me to click on &quot;complete&quot; when I'd dug far enough. There was one problem: the word &quot;complete&quot; wasn't anywhere on the screen. Trial and error revealed that &quot;complete&quot; replaces another word on the screen if you stop digging at precisely the right moment.</p>
<p>The most disappointing part of &quot;Devils Canyon&quot; was the ending. After completing all of the tasks, players never get to see the scientist being rescued. Instead, Dr. Cope calls you on the viewphone a few weeks later to simply thank you.</p>
<p>The folks at TeraMedia invested a lot of time, talent and money to produce an interesting, educational game that features real scientists, provides unique insight into their work, and never talks down to the target audience of ages 8 to 12.</p>
<p>With better instructions and a satisfying ending, everyone with an interest in dinosaurs would have found &quot;Devils Canyon&quot; to be a heavenly CD-ROM to visit.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>&quot;Time Commando&quot; (Activision, DOS/Windows95, $40) may be another time travel adventure, but the goal isn't educational.</p>
<p>In this futuristic game, a computer that controls time travel has been infected by an electronic virus. The player's job is to enter the time bubble and collect computer chips needed to get rid of the virus and save mankind.</p>
<p>After a beautifully rendered introduction that explains this silly premise, &quot;Time Commando&quot; becomes nothing more than a fighting game set in nine different historic periods, from the caveman era, to the old West, to the distant future.</p>
<p>The graphics are spectacular and, unlike other &quot;Mortal Kombat&quot;-style games offering a static scene, the vantage point moves across the landscape as you progress through the game.</p>
<p>The time travel computer may have a virus, but this game has a few bugs of its own. In the prehistoric era, I had a sabertooth tiger trying to attack me through a stone wall. Also, there were occasions when I couldn't see my opponent because he stepped off-screen and the computer wouldn't change the vantage point to compensate.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;The Treehouse&quot; (Broderbund, Windows/Macintosh, $40) lets children age 5 to 8 explore science, music, reading and math using several games, including a pirate game where math skills lead to a treasure, and a music studio for experimenting with instruments, pitch, rhythm and music styles.</p>
<p>&quot;Lighthouse: The Dark Being&quot; (Sierra, Windows/DOS, $50) has a &quot;Myst&quot;-like look and takes you into a parallel universe where &quot;you alone must learn the lessons of technology gone mad.&quot; It's for ages 13 and older.</p>
<p>&quot;Star Control 3&quot; (Accolade, DOS, $55) lets you search hundreds of planets in the Kessari Quadrant, look for over 40 ancient artifacts, wage space battles, and &quot;unravel the secret to the universe's oldest and deadliest mystery.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Daggerfall&quot; (Bethesda Softworks, DOS, $60) is the second chapter of &quot;The Elder Scrolls,&quot; boasting &quot;the largest world ever created&quot; for a computer role-playing game. It's for ages 17 and up.</p>
<p>&quot;The Land Before Time Animated Moviebook&quot; (Sound Source Interactive, Windows, $30): a computerized version of the hit movie featuring young talking dinosaurs. It also has puzzles for children up to first grade.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
