<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91724" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Summit Medical sees Q3, Q4 below estimates.</title>
<headline>Summit Medical sees Q3, Q4 below estimates.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Summit Medical Systems Inc said revenues for the third quarter will be about 35 percent below Wall Street analysts' estimates and will result in a net loss for the quarter.</p>
<p>The company, a provider of clinical outcomes databases for medical specialists, said it expected revenues and earnings for the fourth quarter will also likely be below estimates.</p>
<p>Shares in the company were off 6-1/2 at 6-3/8.</p>
<p>&quot;We are disappointed by our third quarter results and the need to adjust downward our financial projections for the remainder of 1996,&quot; said chief executive Kevin Green.  </p>
<p>He added, &quot;This will, however, allow Summit Medical to build a business that both meets the marketplace needs, as well as obtains predictable financial performance.&quot;</p>
<p>Dozens of companies sell software and computer systems to hospitals and physicians. Most focus on administrative and financial records. Summit was one of the first to zero in on outcomes data, which match the costs of treatments with their success rates, giving specialists therapeutic guidlines.</p>
<p>First Call's consensus of three analysts' estimates had forecast earnings of $0.07 per share for the third quarter, compared to $0.01 per share for the year-ago period.  </p>
<p>The company has told analysts it now expects a third quarter loss of $0.03-$0.05 per share, analysts said.</p>
<p>The consensus earnings forecast for all of 1996 was $0.25 per share, compared to a loss of $0.02 per share in 1995.</p>
<p>The company posted revenues in the third quarter of 1995 of $3.6 million and in the fourth quarter of $4.4 million. Summit told analysts it now expects third-quarter revenues of $4.1 million, fourth-quarter revenues of $6.5 million, 1996 revenues of $19.5 million and 1997 revenues of $27 million, analysts said.</p>
<p>--K. Drawbaugh 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
