<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93848" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kodak in talks with Wang over software.</title>
<headline>Kodak in talks with Wang over software.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Gevirtz</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eastman Kodak Co. and Wang Laboratories Inc. said Thursday they were in talks over a possible deal involving Wang's software business, which industry analysts said Kodak may buy for up to $300 million.</p>
<p>Company officials declined to elaborate on the talks, but analysts said Kodak wants to buy Wang's lucrative imaging software business.</p>
<p>In 1995, Kodak's Business Imaging Systems unit set an alliance with Wang to jointly develop and market a set of common standards for document imaging. The products form the core of Kodak's efforts in document imaging software.</p>
<p>Sales of the software, which is popular with banks, financial institutions and other companies, are about $2.5 billion a year in the United States and growing, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very attractive business for Kodak,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst David Zimm. &quot;It has very high gross margins.&quot;</p>
<p>Imaging software allows companies to scan paper documents and put the information into their computer databases. As more companies convert old records into digital form, demand for such software is expected to grow.</p>
<p>Wang's imaging software business had sales of about $50 million last year, which could rise to $75 million in the current fiscal year, Prudential Securities Research analyst Alex Henderson said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a case where Kodak wants to buy, not necessarily where Wang wants to sell,&quot; Henderson said. He said he expected Wang to hold out for $250 million to $300 million, a hefty price tag given the business's sales.</p>
<p>Kodak wants to buy based on expected sales and profit growth in the imaging business, analysts said.</p>
<p>Rochester, N.Y.-based Kodak has seen its microfilm and microfiche business weaken as the imaging business has become computer- rather than film-based, they said.</p>
<p>After forming the alliance last year, &quot;Kodak sees that it is really working out, so it's time to really pony up ... it will give them something else to sell,&quot; Henderson said.</p>
<p>The companies said in a brief statement the talks were ongoing and that it would be premature to comment further at this time. Spokesmen for both companies declined to elaborate.</p>
<p>Investors welcomed news of the talks, and Wang shares jumped $2 to $21.875 on Nasdaq. Kodak added 75 cents to $78.75 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Wang, which emerged from bankruptcy three years ago, has reshaped itself from a computer maker into a software company that intergrates computer and imaging systems and provides services to business and finance companies.</p>
<p>Wang Chairman Joseph Tucci earlier this year said his company was looking for acquisitions. In July, it bought I-NET, a Bethesda, Md.-based company that builds and services computer networks for $167 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
