<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94055" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: News Corp seen exporting U.S. news channel.</title>
<headline>News Corp seen exporting U.S. news channel.</headline>
<byline>Michael Connor</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Third to market, Rupert Murdoch's News Corp Ltd joins the crowded television-news scramble in the U.S. with the launch on Monday of Fox News Channel, a 24-hour all-news cable channel.</p>
<p>Fox News's main rival, CNN, is already big overseas. And MSNBC has some undefined overseas ambitions and possible outlets but nothing definite yet. But Murdoch can make the best use overseas of his U.S. news operation because he has the most outlets and the closest thing to a global television system.  </p>
<p>The audiences for news channels are so small even segment leader Cable News Network seldom pulls audiences larger than a weak broadcast-network situation comedy. Costs are high, and Fox News Channel's debut comes just as ad spending is peaking.</p>
<p>But few on Wall Street believe Murdoch is making a mistake.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the long term the costs of the Fox News Channel will be amortized over a global business,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst John Reidy. &quot;Murdoch will have more faces he can put his news in front of than any other.&quot;  </p>
<p>Murdoch told reporters Tuesday he would be delivering Fox News to Latin America, Asia and Europe by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>News Corp owns 40 percent of British Sky Broadcasting Corp, another satellite service in Asia, and an interest in a Latin American satellite venture, as well as the Fox Television broadcast network in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Fox News is part of a strategy to create many distribution outlets,&quot; said NatWest analyst Gary Farber.  </p>
<p>Neither MSNBC, a rival news channel owned by Microsoft Corp and the NBC network of General Electric Co, nor Fox News expect to break even until after 2000, executives said.</p>
<p>Fox itself is spending more than $100 million on studios, staff and other costs, Fox News chief executive Roger Ailes said in an interview.</p>
<p>Beyond that, Fox is paying a $10 or more bounty for each cable subscriber, an eye-catching offer said by some analysts likely to cost News Corp hundreds of millions of dollars.  </p>
<p>The bounty, like other Murdoch moves in U.S. electronic media during the 1990s, shocked U.S. entertainment and helped prompt the Walt Disney Co last winter to scuttle plans for an all-news channel at its ABC network.</p>
<p>Murdoch several years ago paid shockingly high fees for the right to broadcast U.S. football games. Rivals predicted Murdoch would lose money, but the games were key to luring to his U.S. network stronger local stations from rival networks.</p>
<p>Tele-Communications Inc, the biggest U.S. cable operator, has promised to deliver 10 million subscribers for Fox News.  </p>
<p>Other leading cable operators, such as Comcast, Cablevision Systems, and  Continental have also signed on to deliver some subscribers. Murdoch told reporters on Tuesday he would have 17 million Fox News subscribers by Monday's launch.</p>
<p>MSNBC has more than 20 million subscribers, or roughly a third of those reached in the United States by CNN, a unit of Turner Broadcasting, which will be soon part of Time Warner Inc.  </p>
<p>But few in the industry are convinced that either new service will prevail, with some operators taking a wait-and-see stance before committing fully to either MSNBC or Fox.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll let them slug it out,&quot; Comcast President Brian Roberts said at an industry conference last week.</p>
<p>Murdoch, who last week traded insults with CNN founder Ted Turner, has repeatedly complained that CNN and other U.S. television organizations are too liberal politically.</p>
<p>Ailes said Fox News, with some 16 hours of original programming on weekdays, will be balanced and aim for an audience slightly older than the early-20s audience courted by MSNBC.</p>
<p>Veteran news presenters, such as business journalist Neil Cavuto, formerly of CNBC, have joined Fox News, he said.</p>
<p>In addition to MSNBC and Fox News, several other speciality news channels are readying for launch. Time Warner/Turner and ESPN, a unit of Disney, are both working on their respective sports-news channels.</p>
<p>Partners ITT Corp and Dow Jones &amp; Co will early next year launch WBIS, a regional business and sports service in metropolitan New York City with ambitions for wider distribution.</p>
<p>&quot;There are only so many eyeballs out there and this will fragment the audience further,&quot; Farber said.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1713</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
