<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95834" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Netscape falls on retail investor angst.</title>
<headline>Netscape falls on retail investor angst.</headline>
<byline>Mark Egan</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Netscape Communciations Corp fell more than seven percent on Friday as retail investors sold shares on fears the company may be losing the battle of the Internet browsers to Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>Analysts scoffed at the sell-off saying the browser software war was little more than a side show distracting investors from Netscape's main attraction, the intranet.</p>
<p>&quot;People have over-reacted to the Micrsoft/AT&amp;T announcement,&quot; said Daniel Rimmer analyst at investment bank Hambrecht &amp; Quist.  </p>
<p>Earlier this week, AT&amp;T Corp said it will offer Microsoft's Internet Explorer software as the preffered Internet browser for its AT&amp;T WorldNet Service.</p>
<p>Shares of Silicon Valley-based Netscape fell 3-1/4 to 41-3/4 in brisk afternoon trading on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>Bruce Smith, analyst at Merrill Lynch &amp; Co, said that announcement and other recent articles about the browser battle with Microsoft contributed to the sharp retail sell-off on Friday.  </p>
<p>Both Microsoft and Netscape have been locked in a bitter fight for dominance of the browser market with Netscape holding the lion's share but Microsoft coming on strong. A browser is software that allows a computer user to navigate the Internet.</p>
<p>But analysts said the more important issue is how the companies are positioning themselves for the intranet, which provides computer communication within companies.</p>
<p>&quot;People are still focusing on Netscape's (Internet) browser market share versus what Netscape's business really is which is the intranet,&quot; Smith said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Inside AT&amp;T, Netscape's intranet product suite is being used,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Intranets are corporate networks built on the same protocols as the Internet. Netscape provides the bulk of browsers and Web site server software used in intranets.</p>
<p>&quot;It's already 80 percent of their revenues ... the consumer retail component is under 10 percent,&quot; Smith said. &quot;What they are looking at doing is selling their software to corporations that are reengineering their enterprises.&quot;  </p>
<p>Rimmer said selling Internet browsers to consumers was a nice way to establish the company and its brand name, but now it is a very low priority.</p>
<p>&quot;The retail accounts are not important at this point. The intranet is the most important thing they are doing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The corporate market is really where the business is.&quot;</p>
<p>Rimmer estimated the market for intranet services could grow to about $10 billion in annual revenues in the next five-years.</p>
<p>&quot;The company continues to do well and I think we'll see a good quarter,&quot; Rimmer said.</p>
<p>In September Netscape said it planned to give away free copies of dozens of its business applications and development tools to corporate software developers working on the intranet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
