<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99104" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: News Corp urges NY to void cable pacts.</title>
<headline>News Corp urges NY to void cable pacts.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Locked in a bitter campaign to win New York channel space for its Fox News service, Rupert Murdoch's News Corp Ltd on Monday urged city officials to void cable-television franchises with Time Warner Inc.</p>
<p>News Corp executives told city officials at a hearing that the pending merger of Time Warner and Turner Broadcasting System constituted a change of control of Time Warner's cable systems in New York City and allowed early rebidding for the valuable franchises.</p>
<p>Time Warner holds city cable-television franchises serving 1.2 millions New Yorkers and are due to expire in 1998.  </p>
<p>Time Warner, which denies the merger constitutes a change in management control, has refused to carry the 24-hour Fox News service and instead carries two Cable News Network services owned by Turner and MSNBC, a joint venture of General Electric Co's NBC and Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>Turner and Time Warner are expected to merge on Thursday, creating the world's biggest media organization. Turner chairman Ted Turner will become vice chairman of the new company and will be the company's biggest shareholder.  </p>
<p>Time Warner is also opposing a proposal backed by Mayor Rudy Giuliani that Fox News be carried on a city-owned channel known as CrossWalks.</p>
<p>News Corp general counsel Arthur Siskind said the company had offered the city $300,000 a year and free television technical services for the slot. One city official at the hearing questioned whether or not that was sufficient given that News Corp was paying unprecendented $10-a-subscriber bonuses to cable operators who sign on for Fox News.</p>
<p>Fox News began operations earlier on Monday.</p>
<p>Time Warner executive Richard Aurelio said the CrossWalks channels were meant to carry non-commercial programs and carriage of advertising-bearing Fox News would be illegal.</p>
<p>Giulani said wide dissemination of Fox News throughout New York was important since it was the only all-news channel based within the city and was the source of hundreds of jobs.</p>
<p>The city's Franchise Concession and Review Committee is scheduled to vote on Wednesday afternoon on whether or not the Turner-Time Warner deal should prompt a review of the Time Warner franchises.</p>
<p>Aurelio said 90 percent of the regulators overseeing Time Warner's cable operations, the second largest in the United States, had passed without objection on the Turner-Time Warner merger.</p>
<p>-- Michael Connor 212-859-1713</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
