<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99147" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Computer Assocs merger seen dilutive - analyst.</title>
<headline>Computer Assocs merger seen dilutive - analyst.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computer Associates International Inc's assertion that its $1.2 billion Cheyenne Software Inc merger would have no impact on earnings was greeted with doubt by at least one Wall Street analyst.</p>
<p>Doug Crook, an enterprise software analyst at Montgomery Securities, took issue with CA chairman Charles Wang's assertion in a conference call Monday afternoon that the acquisition would have a &quot;flat&quot; impact on earnings.</p>
<p>The analyst said that with only $200 million in cash on hand at last count, CA will have to fund around $1 billion of the total $1.2 billion purchase price through new debt.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think (the merger) is going to add another $50 million in interest expense,&quot; Crook said. &quot;I don't see how it cannot be dilutive.&quot;</p>
<p>Furthermore, Crook noted that with Cheyenne, Computer Associates is acquiring a company with lower profit margins. He estimated that Cheyenne's margins were about 25 percent versus the 35 percent produced by Computer Associates.</p>
<p>&quot;With the combination of the two, I think there's some dilutiton there,&quot; he argued.  </p>
<p>Crook said he believes Computer Associates long-term prospects remain excellent, but that he expects Computer Associates share price gains to be dampened in the short-term.</p>
<p>Crook maintains a buy rating on the stock.</p>
<p>Montgomery Securities does not distinguish between near-term and long-term ratings as some brokerages do.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a complimentary acquisition, no doubt,&quot; Crook said, but added that, &quot;I think it is going to take some wind out the near-term potential of the stock,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In response to an analysts' question, Wang said he expected &quot;flat&quot; effect on earnigs one year out, excluding an unspecified one-time charge for the costs of the acquisition.</p>
<p>Despite these lingering doubts, the stock gained steam following the conference call, rising by as much as 1-1/2 points on the day in afternoon trading, after lingering in negative territory during much of the morning.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
