<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99190" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Computer Assocs sees no Cheyenne EPS impact.</title>
<headline>Computer Assocs sees no Cheyenne EPS impact.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Computer Associates International Inc said its proposed $1.2 billion acquisition of Cheyenne Software Inc would have a neutral effect on earnings in the first year after the close of the deal, excluding a one-time charge for acquisition costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect it to be flat, no doubt,&quot; said Charles Wang, Computer Associates' chairman and chief executive, of the possible dilutive effect of the planned merger.</p>
<p>Wang was responding to a question during a conference call with analysts and the press on Monday.  </p>
<p>In addition, Wang said Cheyenne Chairman and Chief Executive ReiJane Huai planned to remain as head of Cheyenne once the merger was completed and Cheyenne became a subsidiary of Computer Associates.</p>
<p>During the conference call, Wang characterized Huai as a &quot;dear friend,&quot; someone he has known for several years.</p>
<p>Although the deal between Cheyenne and Computer Associates had been rumored for several months, Wang said serious talks between the two began only one week ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea of doing this in earnest was about a week ago and we approached Cheyenne,&quot; Wang said at the briefing.  </p>
<p>Wang did not specify how much the one-time charge might involve.</p>
<p>Wang said details of its offer for Cheyenne would be made available as early as Friday, when the company planned to reveal further terms of its $30.50 cash tender offer.</p>
<p>The Computer Associates executive said he was attracted to Cheyenne four reasons: its &quot;people, software, distribution and partners.&quot;</p>
<p>He said his company planned to retain all 800 of Cheyenne's existing employee positions. Computer Associates employs about 9,000 people worldwide.  </p>
<p>The CA chairman pointed to significant synergies to be realized between the two companies products and what he described as their complementary distribution models, while noting that there were no existing product overlaps.</p>
<p>He contrasted Computer Associates' focus on &quot;infrastructure software,&quot; used to manage entire corporate enterprises, with Cheyenne's more consumer-oriented focus on supplying storage management, anti-virus and commmunications software products.  </p>
<p>Wang said Computer Associates planned to take advantage of Cheyenne's existing distribution relationships to bolster its own indirect sales distribution efforts.</p>
<p>He said that while 95 percent of Cheyenne revenues comes from indirect distribution and only five percent from direct sales, Computer Associates maintains a strong direct sales force, which accounts for 90 percent of its revenues.</p>
<p>In addition, Wang pointed to Cheyenne's strategic partnerships with several computer industry leaders, including Compaq Computer Corp, Intel Corp and Siemens AG.</p>
<p>Cheyenne's Huai, who appeared at the briefing with Wang, said the $1.2 billion CA offer was &quot;solid&quot; compared with McAfee Associates Inc's offer earlier this year, worth about $1 billion in stock, an amount subject to share price fluctuations.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not shopping the company,&quot; Huai said, adding that when a reasonable merger offer was presented to its board, Cheyenne directors had a responsiblity to maximize shareholder value.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
